<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vitamin C on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/vitamin-c.html</link><description>Recent content in Vitamin C on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vitamin-c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin C is as good as exercise at reducing cardiovascular problems</title><link>/posts/vitamin-c-is-as-good-as-exercise-at-reducing-cardiovascular-problems.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-c-is-as-good-as-exercise-at-reducing-cardiovascular-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="no-time-for-the-gym-eat-an-orangehttpwwwgreenmedinfocomblogno-time-gym-eat-orange-greenmedinfo">&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/no-time-gym-eat-orange">No Time For The Gym? Eat An Orange!&lt;/a> GreenMedInfo&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Snips from the very nice artilce&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;rsquo;taking a 500 mg time-released &lt;span style="color:#F00;">vitamin C&lt;/span> supplement every day can have similar cardiovascular benefits as regular exercise in these adults'&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;But the researchers found that &lt;span style="color:#F00;">vitamin C&lt;/span> reduced ET-1 vessel constriction as much as &lt;strong>walking&lt;/strong> for exercise did. &amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Studies show that, compared to people getting the least &lt;span style="color:#F00;">vitamin C&lt;/span>, those getting the most had a dramatic 80% lower risk of heart attack&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Cofactors in a nutshell</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-cofactors-in-a-nutshell.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-cofactors-in-a-nutshell.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsways-to-improve-health-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-ways-to-improve-healthperspective-of-the-importance-of-vit-d-and-co-factors-to-healtha">&lt;a href="/posts/ways-to-improve-health" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Ways to improve health">Perspective of the importance of Vit D and co-factors to health&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also---a-hrefpostsexcellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlab-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-excellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlabexcellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlaba">See also - &lt;a href="/posts/excellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlab" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Excellent reviews of supplements at ConsumerLab">Excellent reviews of supplements at ConsumerLab&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h5 id="a-hrefpostsglutathione-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-15355glutathionea---the-master-antioxidant-synergistic-with-vitamin-d">&lt;a href="/posts/glutathione" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 15355">Glutathione&lt;/a> - the master antioxidant, synergistic with Vitamin D&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Increased Glutathione (the master antioxidant) - increases both cellular and blood levels of vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin C reduces liver inflammation, which improves vitamin D production</title><link>/posts/vitamin-c-reduces-liver-inflammation-which-improves-vitamin-d-production.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-c-reduces-liver-inflammation-which-improves-vitamin-d-production.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Off Topic: EDTA similar reduction in heart attack as Vitamin C, aspirin and Mg – RCT</title><link>/posts/off-topic-edta-similar-reduction-in-heart-attack-as-vitamin-c-aspirin-and-mg-rct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-edta-similar-reduction-in-heart-attack-as-vitamin-c-aspirin-and-mg-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-disodium-edta-chelation-regimen-on-cardiovascular-events-in-patients-with-previous-myocardial-infarction---the-tact-randomized-trial">Effect of Disodium EDTA Chelation Regimen on Cardiovascular Events in Patients With Previous Myocardial Infarction - The TACT Randomized Trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>JAMA. 2013;309(12):1241-1250. doi:10.1001/jama.2013.2107.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gervasio A. Lamas, MD; Christine Goertz, DC, PhD; Robin Boineau, MD, MA; Daniel B. Mark, MD, MPH; Theodore Rozema, MD; Richard L. Nahin, PhD, MPH; Lauren Lindblad, MS; Eldrin F. Lewis, MD, MPH; Jeanne Drisko, MD; Kerry L. Lee, PhD; for the TACT Investigators&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chelation therapy with disodium EDTA has been used for more than 50 years to treat atherosclerosis without proof of efficacy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s and Vitamins D, B, C, E, as well as Omega-3, metals, etc.</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-and-vitamins-d-b-c-e-as-well-as-omega-3-metals-etc.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-and-vitamins-d-b-c-e-as-well-as-omega-3-metals-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Importance and management of micronutrient deficiencies in patients with Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara Rita Cardoso1 Cristiane Cominetti2 Silvia Maria Franciscato Cozzolino1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Sao Paulo (USP), Sao Paulo, Brazil; 2Faculty of Nutrition, Federal University of Goias, Goias, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Barbara Rita Cardoso; Av Prof Lineu Prestes, 580 - Bloco &amp;lsquo;4 - CEP: 05508-900 – Sao Paulo - SP - Brazil Tel +55 3 09&amp;rsquo; 3625, +55 8 353 8223 Email &lt;a href="mailto:barbaracardoso@usp.br">barbaracardoso@usp.br&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>8 days of vitamin C reduced distress, but 8 days of Vitamin D was not long enough</title><link>/posts/8-days-of-vitamin-c-reduced-distress-but-8-days-of-vitamin-d-was-not-long-enough.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/8-days-of-vitamin-c-reduced-distress-but-8-days-of-vitamin-d-was-not-long-enough.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-vitamin-c-and-vitamin-d-on-mood-and-distress-in-acutely-hospitalized-patients">Effects of vitamin C and vitamin D on mood and distress in acutely hospitalized patients&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>(The FASEB Journal. 2013;27:225.2); Meeting Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yifan Wang1, Xing Jian Liu1, Line Robitaille1, Shaun Eintracht2, Elizabeth MacNamara2 and L John Hoffer1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Faculty of Medicine, McGill University, Montreal, QC, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Diagnostic Medicine, Jewish General Hospital, Montreal, QC, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypovitaminosis C and D are highly prevalent in acute-care hospitals, but their clinical implications have not been investigated. Because deficiencies of these vitamins can adversely affect mood, we conducted a double-blind randomized clinical trial to determine the effect of vitamin C (500 mg twice daily) or D (5000 IU daily) supplementation on psychological status, as assessed using two different validated instruments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin C is important for the common cold and much else</title><link>/posts/vitamin-c-is-important-for-the-common-cold-and-much-else.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-c-is-important-for-the-common-cold-and-much-else.html</guid><description>&lt;p>A doctor got me interested in re-looking at vitamin C in Jan 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In his practice he increases all patients to 80 ng of vitamin D and makes sure that they have a high level of Magnesium and Vitamin C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He found that some people need as much as 12 grams per day to get the right levels in their blood&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Similarity noticed of the delay in acceptance of Vitamin C and Vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Healthy bones need Ca, Silicon, Vitamins B, C, D, and K</title><link>/posts/healthy-bones-need-ca-silicon-vitamins-b-c-d-and-k.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/healthy-bones-need-ca-silicon-vitamins-b-c-d-and-k.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Update on nutrients involved in maintaining healthy bone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinol Nutr. 2012 Dec 27. pii: S1575-0922(12)00294-X. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.endonu.2012.09.006.">doi: 10.1016/j.endonu.2012.09.006.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Article in English, Spanish]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rondanelli M, Opizzi A, Perna S, Faliva MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Applied Health Sciences, Section of Human Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Medicine, University of Pavia, Endocrinology and Nutrition Unit, Azienda di Servizi alla Persona di Pavia, Pavia, Italy. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:mariangela.rondanelli@unipv.it">mariangela.rondanelli@unipv.it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis is a leading cause of morbidity and mortality in the elderly and influences quality of life, as well as life expectancy. Currently, there is a growing interest among the medical scientists in search of specific nutrients and/or bioactive compounds of natural origin for the prevention of disease and maintenance of bone health. Although calcium and vitamin D have been the primary focus of nutritional prevention of osteoporosis, a recent research has clarified the importance of several additional nutrients and food constituents.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>