<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bone on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/bone.html</link><description>Recent content in Bone on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/bone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weak bones (Osteopenia) in 93 percent of women in Pakistan attending University and wearing Islamic clothes</title><link>/posts/weak-bones-osteopenia-in-93-percent-of-women-in-pakistan-attending-university-an-islamic-clothes.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/weak-bones-osteopenia-in-93-percent-of-women-in-pakistan-attending-university-an-islamic-clothes.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bone mineral density somewhat better with 3750 IU vs 600 IU Vitamin D (1 year, with Calcium) – RCT</title><link>/posts/bone-mineral-density-somewhat-better-with-3750-iu-vs-600-iu-vitamin-d-1-year-with-calcium-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-mineral-density-somewhat-better-with-3750-iu-vs-600-iu-vitamin-d-1-year-with-calcium-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ankylosing Spondylitis – should all patients be tested for low vitamin D – not just yet</title><link>/posts/ankylosing-spondylitis-should-all-patients-be-tested-for-low-vitamin-d-not-just-yet.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ankylosing-spondylitis-should-all-patients-be-tested-for-low-vitamin-d-not-just-yet.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Teenagers having sticky, painful knees (Osteochondrosis Dissecans) virtually always have low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/teenagers-having-sticky-painful-knees-osteochondrosis-dissecans-virtually-always-have-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/teenagers-having-sticky-painful-knees-osteochondrosis-dissecans-virtually-always-have-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="painful-sticky-knee-in-1-in-10000-teenagers-2x-more-for-blacks--feb-2014">Painful, sticky knee in 1 in 10,000 teenagers, 2X more for blacks – Feb 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The demographics and epidemiology of osteochondritis dissecans of the knee in children and adolescents.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am J Sports Med. 2014 Feb;42(2):320-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/0363546513510390.">doi: 10.1177/0363546513510390.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Nov 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kessler JI1, Nikizad H, Shea KG, Jacobs JC Jr, Bebchuk JD, Weiss JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Jeffrey I. Kessler, Kaiser Permanente Southern California, 4760 Sunset Boulevard, Los Angeles, CA 90027. &lt;a href="mailto:Jeffrey.I.Kessler@kp.org">Jeffrey.I.Kessler@kp.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteochondritis dissecans (OCD) is a disorder of subchondral bone and articular cartilage whose incidence in children is not clearly known.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone diseases related to many Vitamin D diseases</title><link>/posts/bone-diseases-related-to-many-vitamin-d-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-diseases-related-to-many-vitamin-d-diseases.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Knee osteoarthritis strongly associated with low Boron – 2015</title><link>/posts/knee-osteoarthritis-strongly-associated-with-low-boron-2015.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/knee-osteoarthritis-strongly-associated-with-low-boron-2015.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Degenerative Diseases of the Spine are related to low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/degenerative-diseases-of-the-spine-are-related-to-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/degenerative-diseases-of-the-spine-are-related-to-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Low bone mineral density of male children is associated with low BMD of parents</title><link>/posts/low-bone-mineral-density-of-male-children-is-associated-with-low-bmd-of-parents.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-bone-mineral-density-of-male-children-is-associated-with-low-bmd-of-parents.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Osteosarcopenic obesity (obese with low bone and muscle mass) twice as likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/osteosarcopenic-obesity-obese-with-low-bone-and-muscle-mass-twice-as-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/osteosarcopenic-obesity-obese-with-low-bone-and-muscle-mass-twice-as-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="osteosarcopenic-obesity-the-role-of-bone-muscle-and-fat-on-health">Osteosarcopenic obesity: the role of bone, muscle, and fat on health.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2014 Sep;5(3):183-92. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s13539-014-0146-x.">doi: 10.1007/s13539-014-0146-x.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Apr 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ormsbee MJ1, Prado CM, Ilich JZ, Purcell S, Siervo M, Folsom A, Panton L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Nutrition, Food and Exercise Sciences, The Florida State University, 120 Convocation Way, Tallahassee, FL, 32306-1493, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:mormsbee@fsu.edu">mormsbee@fsu.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteopenia/osteoporosis, sarcopenia, and obesity are commonly observed in the process of aging, and recent evidence suggests a potential interconnection of these syndromes with common pathophysiology. &lt;strong>The term osteosarcopenic obesity has been coined to describe the concurrent appearance of obesity in individuals with low bone and muscle mass&lt;/strong> . Although our understanding of osteosarcopenic obesity&amp;rsquo;s etiology, prevalence, and consequences is extremely limited, it is reasonable to infer its negative impact in a population that is aging in an obesogenic environment. It is likely that these individuals will present with poorer clinical outcomes caused by the cascade of metabolic abnormalities associated with these changes in body composition. Clinical outcomes include but are not limited to increased risk of fractures, impaired functional status (including activities of daily living), physical disability, insulin resistance, increased risk of infections, increased length of hospital stay, and reduced survival. These health outcomes are likely to be worse when compared to individuals with obesity, sarcopenia, or osteopenia/osteoporosis alone. Interventions that utilize resistance training exercise in conjunction with increased protein intake appear to be promising in their ability to counteract osteosarcopenic obesity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone fractures healed much better if more than 20ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/bone-fractures-healed-much-better-if-more-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-fractures-healed-much-better-if-more-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-and-adult-fracture-healing">Vitamin D status and adult fracture healing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Orthopaedics and Trauma. online 23 Sept 2016, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jcot.2016.09.003">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jcot.2016.09.003&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E.A. Gorter, , P. Krijnen, I.B. Schipper&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: The effect of vitamin D on maintaining bone health is well researched and its role in the various metabolic stages of fracture healing has become evident, the clinical effects of a vitamin D deficiency in human fracture healing are less well described. Considering today&amp;rsquo;s high prevalence of vitamin D deficiency, the aim of this present study was to investigate the effect of vitamin D status on human adult fracture healing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leg bone (tibia) grew thicker with 4,000 IU of vitamin D and Calcium – RCT</title><link>/posts/leg-bone-tibia-grew-thicker-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/leg-bone-tibia-grew-thicker-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="three-doses-of-vitamin-d-bone-mineral-density-and-geometry-in-older-women-during-modest-weight-control-in-a-1-year-randomized-controlled-trial">Three doses of vitamin D, bone mineral density, and geometry in older women during modest weight control in a 1-year randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2016 Aug 17. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>After 1 year of daily Vitamin D and Calcium (1.2 grams)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>| | | |
| &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; |
| Dose | Thickness | Vitamin D level |
| 600 IU | -2% (loss) | 27 nanograms |
| 2000 IU | &amp;gt; 1% (gain) | 36 nanograms |
| 4000 IU | &amp;gt; 2% (gain) | 42 nanograms |&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone loss not stopped by monthly 48,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/bone-loss-not-stopped-by-monthly-48000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-loss-not-stopped-by-monthly-48000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-for-12-months-in-older-people-prevents-bone-loss-and-suppresses-parathyroid-hormone-levels">Vitamin D supplementation for 12 months in older people prevents bone loss and suppresses parathyroid hormone levels&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bone Abstracts (2016) 5 P221b | DOI:10.1530/boneabs.5.P221b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>43rd Annual European Calcified Tissue Society Congress, Rome, Italy, May 2016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Terry J Aspray1, Roger M Francis1, Elaine McColl2, Thomas Chadwick2, Elaine Stamp2, Ann Prentice3 &amp;amp; Inez Schoenmakers3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Institute of Cellular Medicine, Newcastle University, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Institute of Health and Society, Newcastle University, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Drugs that may harm bone (vitamin D needed)</title><link>/posts/drugs-that-may-harm-bone-vitamin-d-needed.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/drugs-that-may-harm-bone-vitamin-d-needed.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#drugs-that-may-harm-bone-mitigating-the-risk">Drugs that may harm bone: Mitigating the risk&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#glucocorticoids">GLUCOCORTICOIDS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#table-1-drugs-that-may-harm-bone">TABLE 1: Drugs that may harm bone&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bone-mineral-density-declines-quickly">Bone mineral density declines quickly&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#oral-therapy-increases-fracture-risk">Oral therapy increases fracture risk&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#managing-the-risk-of-glucocorticoid-induced-osteoporosis">Managing the risk of glucocorticoid-induced osteoporosis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#proton-pump-inhibitors">PROTON PUMP INHIBITORS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#selective-serotonin-reuptake-inhibitors-ssri">SELECTIVE SEROTONIN REUPTAKE INHIBITORS (SSRI)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#antiepileptic-drugs">ANTIEPILEPTIC DRUGS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#aromatase-inhibitors">AROMATASE INHIBITORS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">REFERENCES&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="drugs-that-may-harm-bone-mitigating-the-risk">Drugs that may harm bone: Mitigating the risk&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>CCJM 2016 Apr;83(4):281-288. 10.3949/ccjm.83a.15066&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FAYE N. HANT, DO, MSCR; Associate Professor of Medicine, Division of Rheumatology and Immunology, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, SC,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hospital found that Vitamin D saves money by improving bone fracture healing</title><link>/posts/hospital-found-that-vitamin-d-saves-money-by-improving-bone-fracture-healing.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hospital-found-that-vitamin-d-saves-money-by-improving-bone-fracture-healing.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>4X fewer stress fractures in college athletes if more than 40 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/4x-fewer-stress-fractures-in-college-athletes-if-more-than-40-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4x-fewer-stress-fractures-in-college-athletes-if-more-than-40-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I told author that his great study was on VitaminDWiki&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author wanted the page removed from VitaminDWiki&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Study is still on the web at &lt;a href="http://www.bsatsmc.org/downloads">http://www.bsatsmc.org/downloads&lt;/a> as of April 3, 2016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Millward- Vitamin D Levels in the College Athlete, Can Screening and Treatment Prevent Stress Fractures?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone implants aided by Vitamin D in 80 percent of studies, conclusion – more studies needed</title><link>/posts/bone-implants-aided-by-vitamin-d-in-80-percent-of-studies-conclusion-more-studies-needed.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-implants-aided-by-vitamin-d-in-80-percent-of-studies-conclusion-more-studies-needed.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="efficacy-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation-on-osseointegration-of-implants">Efficacy of Vitamin D3 Supplementation on Osseointegration of Implants.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Implant Dent. 2016 Feb 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Javed F1, Malmstrom H, Kellesarian SV, Al-Kheraif AA, Vohra F, Romanos GE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim was to systematically review the efficacy of vitamin D3 (VD3) supplementation on the osseointegration of implants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The addressed focused question was &amp;ldquo;does VD3 supplementation affect osseointegration around implants?&amp;rdquo; Indexed databases were searched from 1969 up to and including March 2015 using various key words including: &amp;ldquo;Bone to implant contact&amp;rdquo;; &amp;ldquo;implant&amp;rdquo;; &amp;ldquo;vitamin D&amp;rdquo;; and &amp;ldquo;osseointegration.&amp;rdquo; Letters to the editor, case reports/case series, reviews, and articles published in languages other than English were excluded. The pattern of the present systematic review was customized to primarily summarize the pertinent data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Childhood Fractures – consensus report on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/childhood-fractures-consensus-report-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/childhood-fractures-consensus-report-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-etiology-and-significance-of-fractures-in-infants-and-young-children-a-critical-multidisciplinary-review">The etiology and significance of fractures in infants and young children: a critical multidisciplinary review&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatric Radiology, pp 1-10, First online: 17 February 2016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sabah Servaes , Stephen D. Brown, Arabinda K. Choudhary, Cindy W. Christian, Stephen L. Done, Laura L. Hayes, Michael A. Levine, Joëlle A. Moreno, Vincent J. Palusci and 2 more&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This paper addresses significant misconceptions regarding the etiology of fractures in infants and young children in cases of suspected child abuse. This &lt;strong>consensus statement&lt;/strong> , supported by the Child Abuse Committee and endorsed by the Board of Directors of the Society for Pediatric Radiology, synthesizes the relevant scientific data distinguishing clinical, radiologic and laboratory findings of metabolic disease from findings in abusive injury. This paper discusses medically established epidemiology and etiologies of childhood fractures in infants and young children. The authors also &lt;strong>review the body of evidence on the role of vitamin D in bone health and the relationship between vitamin D and fractures&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bones not helped much by vitamin D (low dose or short term) National Osteoporosis Foundation</title><link>/posts/bones-not-helped-much-by-vitamin-d-low-dose-or-short-term-national-osteoporosis-foundation.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bones-not-helped-much-by-vitamin-d-low-dose-or-short-term-national-osteoporosis-foundation.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-national-osteoporosis-foundations-position-statement-on-peak-bone-mass-development-and-lifestyle-factors-a-systematic-review-and-implementation-recommendations">The National Osteoporosis Foundation&amp;rsquo;s position statement on peak bone mass development and lifestyle factors: a systematic review and implementation recommendations.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2016 Feb 8. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weaver CM1, Gordon CM2,3, Janz KF4, Kalkwarf HJ5, Lappe JM6, Lewis R7, O&amp;rsquo;Karma M8, Wallace TC9,10,11, Zemel BS12,13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lifestyle choices influence 20-40 % of adult peak bone mass. Therefore, optimization of lifestyle factors known to influence peak bone mass and strength is an important strategy aimed at reducing risk of osteoporosis or low bone mass later in life. The National Osteoporosis Foundation has issued this scientific statement to provide evidence-based guidance and a national implementation strategy for the purpose of helping individuals achieve maximal peak bone mass early in life. In this scientific statement, we (1) report the results of an evidence-based review of the literature since 2000 on factors that influence achieving the full genetic potential for skeletal mass; (2) recommend lifestyle choices that promote maximal bone health throughout the lifespan; (3) outline a research agenda to address current gaps; and (4) identify implementation strategies. We conducted a systematic review of the role of individual nutrients, food patterns, special issues, contraceptives, and physical activity on bone mass and strength development in youth. An evidence grading system was applied to describe the strength of available evidence on these individual modifiable lifestyle factors that may (or may not) influence the development of peak bone mass (Table 1). A summary of the grades for each of these factors is given below. We describe the underpinning biology of these relationships as well as other factors for which a systematic review approach was not possible. Articles published since 2000, all of which followed the report by Heaney et al. &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup> published in that year, were considered for this scientific statement. This current review is a systematic update of the previous review conducted by the National Osteoporosis Foundation &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. Lifestyle Factor Grade Macronutrients  Fat D  Protein C Micronutrients  Calcium A  Vitamin D B  Micronutrients other than calcium and vitamin D D Food Patterns  Dairy B  Fiber C  Fruits and vegetables C  Detriment of cola and caffeinated beverages C Infant Nutrition  Duration of breastfeeding D  Breastfeeding versus formula feeding D  Enriched formula feeding D Adolescent Special Issues  Detriment of oral contraceptives D  Detriment of DMPA injections B  Detriment of alcohol D  Detriment of smoking C Physical Activity and Exercise  Effect on bone mass and density A  Effect on bone structural outcomes B Considering the evidence-based literature review, we recommend lifestyle choices that promote maximal bone health from childhood through young to late adolescence and outline a research agenda to address current gaps in knowledge. The best evidence (grade A) is available for positive effects of calcium intake and physical activity, especially during the late childhood and peripubertal years-a critical period for bone accretion. Good evidence is also available for a role of vitamin D and dairy consumption and a detriment of DMPA injections. However, more rigorous trial data on many other lifestyle choices are needed and this need is outlined in our research agenda. Implementation strategies for lifestyle modifications to promote development of peak bone mass and strength within one&amp;rsquo;s genetic potential require a multisectored (i.e., family, schools, healthcare systems) approach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More calcium in bones in those teenage girls getting 2,000 IUs daily – RCT</title><link>/posts/more-calcium-in-bones-in-those-teenage-girls-getting-2000-ius-daily-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-calcium-in-bones-in-those-teenage-girls-getting-2000-ius-daily-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="persistent-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-musculoskeletal-parameters-in-adolescents-one-year-after-trial-completion">Persistent Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation on Musculoskeletal Parameters in Adolescents One Year after Trial Completion&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Bone and Mineral Research, &lt;a href="10.1002/jbmr.2802">10.1002/jbmr.2802&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nisrine Ghazal MD1,3, Laila Al-Shaar MS, MPH1,5,6, Joyce Maalouf MS1,2, Mona Nabulsi MD, MSc1,4, Asma Arabi MD, MSc1,3, Mahmoud Choucair MD1,3, Hani Tamim PhD1, Ziad Mahfoud PhD7 andGhada El-Hajj Fuleihan MD, MPH1,2,3,5,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1American University of Beirut Medical Center&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Calcium Metabolism and Osteoporosis Program&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stronger bones if get UVB (vitamin D) when young – in storks as well</title><link>/posts/stronger-bones-if-get-uvb-vitamin-d-when-young-in-storks-as-well.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stronger-bones-if-get-uvb-vitamin-d-when-young-in-storks-as-well.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-influence-of-ultraviolet-b-radiation-on-the-growth-of-marabou-stork-leptoptilos-crumeniferus-nestlings-in-relation-to-plasma-calcium-phosphorus-and-vitamin-d3-concentrations">THE INFLUENCE OF ULTRAVIOLET-B RADIATION ON THE GROWTH OF MARABOU STORK (LEPTOPTILOS CRUMENIFERUS) NESTLINGS IN RELATION TO PLASMA CALCIUM, PHOSPHORUS, AND VITAMIN D3 CONCENTRATIONS.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Zoo Wildl Med. 2015 Dec;46(4):682-690.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schaftenaar W, van Leeuwen JP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to prevent metabolic bone disease in growing captive-bred marabou storks (Leptoptilos crumeniferus), three hatchlings were exposed twice a day for 30 min each time to ultraviolet-B (UVB) radiation. During their first 35 days of life, body weights were monitored weekly, and blood was collected to determine total calcium, phosphorus, 25(OH)cholecalciferol, and 1.25(OH)2 cholecalciferol plasma levels. Data were compared with those obtained from two marabou stork nestlings that were raised before, without being exposed to UVB. These two birds developed metabolic bone disease, while the &lt;strong>UVB-exposed birds developed into healthy adult animals&lt;/strong> . Plasma chemistry data obtained in this study demonstrate that nestling marabou storks produce vitamin D3 under the influence of UVB radiation. The absence of clinical metabolic bone disease in the nestlings that received UVB compared to the nestlings that were raised with the same diet without UVB radiation and that developed MBD demonstrates the importance of UVB radiation for normal development in this species.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metatarsal Stress Fracture 5X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/metatarsal-stress-fracture-5x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metatarsal-stress-fracture-5x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="evaluating-the-risk-of-a-fifth-metatarsal-stress-fracture-by-measuring-the-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels">Evaluating the Risk of a Fifth Metatarsal Stress Fracture by Measuring the Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Foot &amp;amp; Ankle International November 23, 2015 1071100715617042&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yu Shimasaki, MSc1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Masashi Nagao, MD, PhD2⇑&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Takayuki Miyamori, MPthy3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yukihiro Aoba, MSc1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Norifumi Fukushi, MSc4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yoshitomo Saita, MD, PhD5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hiroshi Ikeda, MD, PhD5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sung-Gon Kim, MD, PhD2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Masahiko Nozawa, MD, PhD2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kazuo Kaneko, MD, PhD5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Masafumi Yoshimura, PhD1,6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Health and Sports Science, Juntendo University, Chiba, Japan&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Better bones again associated with higher vitamin K intake</title><link>/posts/better-bones-again-associated-with-higher-vitamin-k-intake.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/better-bones-again-associated-with-higher-vitamin-k-intake.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Professor who concluded that vitamin D (800 IU) does not help bones got 324,000 dollar prize</title><link>/posts/professor-who-concluded-that-vitamin-d-800-iu-does-not-help-bones-got-324000-dollar-prize.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/professor-who-concluded-that-vitamin-d-800-iu-does-not-help-bones-got-324000-dollar-prize.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="liley-medal-for-game-changing-vitamin-d-studyhttpwwwhrcgovtnznews-and-medianewsliley-medal-game-changing-vitamin-d-study">&lt;a href="http://www.hrc.govt.nz/news-and-media/news/liley-medal-game-changing-vitamin-d-study">Liley Medal for &amp;lsquo;game-changing&amp;rsquo; vitamin D study&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;University of Auckland Distinguished Professor &lt;strong>Ian Reid&lt;/strong> was tonight presented with the Health Research Council of New Zealand’s (HRC) Liley Medal at the 2015 Research Honours Dinner for his outstanding contribution to health and medical sciences in advancing treatment of the bone disorder osteoporosis.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;quot; Data from 23 trials involving more than 4000 patients showed &lt;strong>no evidence that bone density significally improved&lt;/strong> after taking vitamin D supplements.&amp;quot;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone health best with 40 nanograms of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/bone-health-best-with-40-nanograms-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-health-best-with-40-nanograms-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.science20.com/news_articles/is_there_evidence_for_the_vitamin_d_supplementation_fad-158758">Is There Evidence For The Vitamin D Supplementation Fad?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Report on this study&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, Calcium and protein very important to bone health</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-calcium-and-protein-very-important-to-bone-health.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-calcium-and-protein-very-important-to-bone-health.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Life-course approach to nutrition&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int DOI 10.1007/s00198-015-3288-6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P. J. Mitchell1,2 • C. Cooper3,4 • B. Dawson-Hughes • C. M. Gordon • R. Rizzoli, &lt;a href="mailto:cc@mrc.soton.ac.uk">cc@mrc.soton.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Synthesis Medical NZ Ltd, Auckland, New Zealand&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Notre Dame Australia, Sydney, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NIHR Musculoskeletal Biomedical Research Unit, Nuffield Dept of Orthopaedics, Rheumatology and Musculoskeletal Sciences, U. of Oxford, Oxford, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MRC Lifecourse Epidemiology Unit, University of Southampton, Southampton General Hospital, Southampton, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jean Mayer USDA Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging, Tufts University, Boston, MA, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Feeding increased risk of low bone density by 24 percent</title><link>/posts/breast-feeding-increased-risk-of-low-bone-density-by-24-percent.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-feeding-increased-risk-of-low-bone-density-by-24-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="breast-feeding-is-associated-with-postmenopausal-bone-loss-findings-from-the-korea-national-health-and-nutrition-examination-survey">Breast Feeding Is Associated with Postmenopausal Bone Loss: Findings from the Korea National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Korean J Fam Med. 2015 Sep;36(5):216-20. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4082/kjfm.2015.36.5.216.">doi: 10.4082/kjfm.2015.36.5.216.&lt;/a> Epub 2015 Sep 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim HJ1, Kwon H2, Oh SW2, Lee CM2, Joh HK3, Kim Y1, Um YJ1, Ahn SH1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Family Medicine, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Family Medicine, Healthcare System Gangnam Center, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Health Service Center, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2,000 IU vitamin D recommended for pediatric rheumatology</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d-recommended-for-pediatric-rheumatology.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d-recommended-for-pediatric-rheumatology.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Stress fractures – 83 percent had less than 40 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/stress-fractures-83-percent-had-less-than-40-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stress-fractures-83-percent-had-less-than-40-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-of-vitamin-d-with-stress-fractures-a-retrospective-cohort-study">Association of Vitamin D With Stress Fractures: A Retrospective Cohort Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J of Foot and Ankle Surgery, DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1053/j.jfas.2015.08.002">http://dx.doi.org/10.1053/j.jfas.2015.08.002&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jason R. Miller, DPM, FACFAS, Karl W. Dunn, DPM, AACFAS &lt;a href="mailto:dr.karldunn@gmail.com">dr.karldunn@gmail.com&lt;/a> , Louis J. Ciliberti Jr., DPM, AACFAS, Rikhil D. Patel, DPM, Brock A. Swanson, DPM&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is an essential, fat-soluble nutrient that is a key modulator of bone health. Despite the gaining popularity throughout published medical studies, no consensus has been reached regarding a serum vitamin D level that will guarantee adequate skeletal health in a patient with an increased functional demand. The purpose of the present investigation was to examine the serum concentrations of vitamin D in patients with confirmed stress fractures. A total of 124 patients were included in our retrospective cohort study. Of the 124 patients, 53 had vitamin D levels measured within 3 months of diagnosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fracture mechanics of human bone, and the importance of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/fracture-mechanics-of-human-bone-and-the-importance-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fracture-mechanics-of-human-bone-and-the-importance-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-fracture-mechanics-of-human-bone-influence-of-disease-and-treatment">The fracture mechanics of human bone: influence of disease and treatment.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Bonekey Rep. 2015 Sep 2;4:743.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zimmermann EA 1, Busse B 1, Ritchie RO 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Osteology and Biomechanics, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf , Hamburg, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Materials Sciences Division, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory , Berkeley, CA, USA ; Department of Materials Science &amp;amp; Engineering, University of California , Berkeley, CA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aging and bone diseases are associated with increased fracture risk. It is therefore pertinent to seek an understanding of the origins of such disease-related deterioration in bone&amp;rsquo;s mechanical properties. The mechanical integrity of bone derives from its hierarchical structure, which in healthy tissue is able to resist complex physiological loading patterns and tolerate damage. Indeed, the mechanisms through which bone derives its mechanical properties make fracture mechanics an ideal framework to study bone&amp;rsquo;s mechanical resistance, where crack-growth resistance curves give a measure of the intrinsic resistance to the initiation of cracks and the extrinsic resistance to the growth of cracks. Recent research on healthy cortical bone has demonstrated how this hierarchical structure can develop intrinsic toughness at the collagen fibril scale mainly through sliding and sacrificial bonding mechanisms that promote plasticity. Furthermore, the bone-matrix structure develops extrinsic toughness at much larger micrometer length-scales, where the structural features are large enough to resist crack growth through crack-tip shielding mechanisms. Although healthy bone tissue can generally resist physiological loading environments, certain conditions such as aging and disease can significantly increase fracture risk. In simple terms, the reduced mechanical integrity originates from alterations to the hierarchical structure. Here, we review how human cortical bone resists fracture in healthy bone and how changes to the bone structure due to aging, osteoporosis, &lt;strong>vitamin D deficiency&lt;/strong> and Paget&amp;rsquo;s disease can affect the mechanical integrity of bone tissue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>800 IU Vitamin D proven again to not be enough to stop bone loss</title><link>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-proven-again-to-not-be-enough-to-stop-bone-loss.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-proven-again-to-not-be-enough-to-stop-bone-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-may-not-benefit-postmenopausal-bone-healthhttpwwwreuterscomarticle20150803us-health-menopause-bones-iduskcn0q81tv20150803feedtyperssfeednamehealthnews-reuters">&lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/08/03/us-health-menopause-bones-idUSKCN0Q81TV20150803?feedType=RSS&amp;amp;feedName=healthNews">Vitamin D may not benefit postmenopausal bone health&lt;/a> Reuters&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-osteoporosis-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Osteoporosis and vitamin D">Overview Osteoporosis and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/osteoporosis-treatment-vitamin-d-is-the-most-cost-effective" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Osteoporosis treatment – Vitamin D is the most cost-effective – April 2019">Osteoporosis treatment – Vitamin D is the most cost-effective – April 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Spinal non fusion 3.5 X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/spinal-non-fusion-35-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-non-fusion-35-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-levels-and-one-year-fusion-outcomes-in-elective-spine-surgery-a-prospective-observational-study">Vitamin D Levels and One-Year Fusion Outcomes in Elective Spine Surgery: A Prospective Observational Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2015 Jul 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ravindra VM1, Godzik J, Dailey AT, Schmidt MH, Bisson EF, Hood RS, Cutler A, Ray WZ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Neurosurgery, Clinical Neurosciences Center, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Neurosurgery, Barrow Neurological Institute, Phoenix, Arizona&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3University of Florida School of Medicine, Gainesville, Florida 4Department of Neurosurgery, Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, Missouri.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinal muscular atrophy (rare disease) might be helped with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/spinal-muscular-atrophy-rare-disease-might-be-helped-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-muscular-atrophy-rare-disease-might-be-helped-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D has been proven many times to fight &lt;a href="/posts/bone-health">bone&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="/posts/muscles-and-vitamin-d-many-studies">muscle&lt;/a> problems&lt;br>
Vitamin D might fight many aspects of Spinal Muscular Atrophy&lt;br>
Maintence dosing typically does not show any benefit for 2-8 months&lt;br>
Starting with a &lt;a href="/posts/overview-loading-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Loading of vitamin D">Vitamin D loading dose&lt;/a> often shows benefits in weeks&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="bone-and-spinal-muscular-atrophy">Bone and spinal muscular atrophy.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bone. 2015 Jun 5. pii: S8756-3282(15)00220-3. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bone.2015.05.039.">doi: 10.1016/j.bone.2015.05.039.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vai S1, Bianchi ML2, Moroni I3, Mastella C4, Broggi F2, Morandi L5, Arnoldi MT6, Bussolino C6, Baranello G6.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Slipped upper femoral epiphysis (hip pain in teen) associated with vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/slipped-upper-femoral-epiphysis-hip-pain-in-teen-associated-with-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/slipped-upper-femoral-epiphysis-hip-pain-in-teen-associated-with-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-seasonality-of-slipped-upper-femoral-epiphysis---meta-analysis-a-possible-association-with-vitamin-d">The seasonality of slipped upper femoral epiphysis - meta-analysis: a possible association with vitamin D.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#slipped-capital-femoral-epiphysis-does-not-appear-to-be-subclinical-rickets-in-obese-children---june-2015">Slipped capital femoral epiphysis does not appear to be subclinical Rickets in obese children - June 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="the-seasonality-of-slipped-upper-femoral-epiphysis---meta-analysis-a-possible-association-with-vitamin-d">The seasonality of slipped upper femoral epiphysis - meta-analysis: a possible association with vitamin D.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Hip Int. 2015 May 29:0. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5301/hipint.5000203.">doi: 10.5301/hipint.5000203.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Farrier AJ 1, Ihediwa U, Khan S, Kumar A, Gulati V, Uzoigwe CE, Choudhury MZ.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone strength (more accurate than BMD) is inversely associated with vitamin D level</title><link>/posts/bone-strength-more-accurate-than-bmd-is-inversely-associated-with-vitamin-d-level.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-strength-more-accurate-than-bmd-is-inversely-associated-with-vitamin-d-level.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-association-of-vitamin-d-with-femoral-neck-strength-an-additional-evidence-of-vitamin-d-on-bone-health">The Association of Vitamin D with Femoral Neck Strength: an Additional Evidence of Vitamin D on Bone Health&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2014-4320">doi: 10.1210/jc.2014-4320&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hyeonmok Kim, Seung Hun Lee, JinJu Kim, Kyeong-Hye Lim, Seong Hee Ahn, Beom-Jun Kim, Jung-Min Koh&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Asan Medical Center, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, 138-736, Seoul, Korea&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/hypothesis-increased-bone-mineral-density-needs-protein-ca-mg-vitamin-d-and-k">Hypothesis: increased bone mineral density needs protein, Ca, Mg, Vitamin D and K&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If bone matrix is broken down, adding more bone only increases bone density, not bone strength&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sickle Cell children need more than 7,000 IU of vitamin D daily</title><link>/posts/sickle-cell-children-need-more-than-7000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sickle-cell-children-need-more-than-7000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="sickle-cell-also-helped-by-omega-3---nov-2012">Sickle cell also helped by Omega-3 - Nov 2012&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/sickle-cell-helped-by-omega-3.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Results: Omega-3 treatment reduced the median&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>rate of clinical vaso-occlusive events (0 compared with 1.0 per year, P , 0.0001),&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>severe anemia (3.2% compared with 16.4%; P , 0.05),&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>blood transfusion (4.5% compared with 16.4%; P , 0.05),&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>white blood cell count (14.4 6 3.3 compared with 15.6 6 4.0 3103 /mL; P , 0.05), and the&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Long bone fracture – prediction by low vitamin D is better than low BMD</title><link>/posts/long-bone-fracture-prediction-by-low-vitamin-d-is-better-than-low-bmd.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/long-bone-fracture-prediction-by-low-vitamin-d-is-better-than-low-bmd.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-below-25-ngml-is-a-risk-factor-for-long-bone-fracture-comparable-to-bone-mineral-density-in-japanese-postmenopausal-women">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D below 25 ng/mL is a risk factor for long bone fracture comparable to bone mineral density in Japanese postmenopausal women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Metab. 2014 Sep;32(5):514-23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00774-013-0520-3.">doi: 10.1007/s00774-013-0520-3.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tanaka S1, Kuroda T, Yamazaki Y, Shiraki Y, Yoshimura N, Shiraki M.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:500px">
&lt;p>Long bone fracture prediction for women – age 64&lt;/p>
&lt;p>41% had osteoporosis, 50% had &amp;lt; 20 ng of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2.2 X if &amp;lt; 25 ng of vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Foot and Ankle Fracture Healing – vitamin D appears promising for everyone– review</title><link>/posts/foot-and-ankle-fracture-healing-vitamin-d-appears-promising-for-everyone-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/foot-and-ankle-fracture-healing-vitamin-d-appears-promising-for-everyone-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-in-foot-and-ankle-fracture-healing-a-literature-review-and-research-design">Vitamin D in Foot and Ankle Fracture Healing: A Literature Review and Research Design.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Foot Ankle Spec. 2015 May 11. pii: 1938640015585958. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bernhard A1, Matuk J2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a generic name for a group of essential vitamins, or secosteroids, important in calcium homeostasis and bone metabolism. Specifically, efficacy of vitamin D with regard to bone healing is in question. A literature review was performed, finding mostly large studies involving vitamin D effects on prevention of fractures and randomized animal model studies consisting of controlled fractures with vitamin D interventions. The prevention articles generally focus on at-risk populations, including menopausal women and osteoporotic patients, and also most often include calcium in the treatment group. Few studies look at vitamin D specifically. The animal model studies often focus more on vitamin D supplementation; however the results are still largely inconclusive. While recent case reports &lt;strong>appear promising&lt;/strong> , the ambiguity of results on the topic of fracture healing suggests a need for more, higher level research. A novel study design is proposed to help determine the efficacy on vitamin D in fracture healing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stronger bones after 3 generations of tap water (more Ca and Mg) vs bottled water</title><link>/posts/stronger-bones-after-3-generations-of-tap-water-more-ca-and-mg-vs-bottled-water.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stronger-bones-after-3-generations-of-tap-water-more-ca-and-mg-vs-bottled-water.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="multi-generational-drinking-of-bottled-low-mineral-water-impairs-bone-quality-in-female-rats">Multi-generational drinking of bottled low mineral water impairs bone quality in female rats.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2015 Mar 24;10(3):e0121995. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0121995.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0121995.&lt;/a> eCollection 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Qiu Z1, Tan Y1, Zeng H1, Wang L1, Wang D1, Luo J1, Zhang L1, Huang Y1, Chen JA2, Shu W1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of reproductions and hormone changes, females are more sensitive to bone mineral loss during their lifetime. Bottled water has become more popular in recent years, and a large number of products are low mineral water. However, research on the effects of drinking bottled low mineral water on bone health is sparse.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone strength increased when sow and piglets had enough Vitamin D and Phosphorus</title><link>/posts/bone-strength-increased-when-sow-and-piglets-had-enough-vitamin-d-and-phosphorus.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-strength-increased-when-sow-and-piglets-had-enough-vitamin-d-and-phosphorus.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="neonatal-pig-femur-integrity-responses-to-dietary-vitamin-d-and-p-depend-on-maternal-dietary-vitamin-d">Neonatal Pig Femur Integrity Responses to Dietary Vitamin D and P Depend on Maternal Dietary Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>L Amundson1 and T Crenshaw1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Dept Anim Sci Univ of Wisconsin Madison Wisconsin United States&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/bone-strength.jpg" alt="image" width="650">
&lt;p>Kyphosis, an idiopathic disease, occurs in swine and humans. We induced kyphosis by altering maternal dietary vitamin D (D) and pig dietary D, Ca and P. The objective was to characterize bone traits and gene expression in the kyphosis model and assess maternal carryover effects. Traits from mechanical tests to characterize femur integrity are reported herein. Sows were fed diets with 0, 325 or 1750 IU D/kg (n = 6, 8, or 9/diet). At weaning (23 ± 2 d) pigs were fed diets with 0 (-D) or 280 (+D) IU D/kg, each with 95% (95P) or 120% (120P) of the P requirement. Pigs were killed at birth (n = 23), weaning (n = 22), and at the end of nursery (n = 185) for bone and tissue analysis. Excised femurs were subjected to a 4-point bending test to determine bending moment (BM), stress, strain, and modulus of elasticity (ME) at the yield point of load deformation curves. Mass moment of inertia (MOI) was derived from CT scans. ME encompasses of BM, stress, strain and MOI and is assumed to be a constant property of a material. No differences in ME were detected at birth. At weaning ME increased in pigs produced by sows fed 1750 (P &amp;lt; 0.05). At the end of nursery ME depended on maternal diets (interaction, P &amp;lt; 0.05). ME increased in pigs fed +D95P if produced by sows fed 0 or 325 but decreased if produced by sows fed 1750. As previously reported, DXA whole body bone mineral density also indicated maternal carryover effects, but the pattern differed among diets. Therefore whole body bone and femur integrity traits differ, but provide unique characterization of the model. As previously reported, the kyphosis model was further characterized by molecular analysis of bone and D homeostatic cell signaling mechanisms. All traits contribute to the characterization of the kyphosis model but a specific mechanism by which the deformity is induced has yet to be determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D during pregnancy associated with four health problems in children</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-associated-with-four-health-problems-in-children.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-associated-with-four-health-problems-in-children.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-in-fetal-development-findings-from-a-birth-cohort-study">Vitamin D in fetal development: findings from a birth cohort study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatrics. 2015 Jan;135(1):e167-73. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2014-1860.">doi: 10.1542/peds.2014-1860.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Dec 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hart PH1, Lucas RM2, Walsh JP3, Zosky GR4, Whitehouse AJ5, Zhu K3, Allen KL6, Kusel MM5, Anderson D5, Mountain JA5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Telethon Kids Institute, &lt;a href="mailto:Prue.Hart@telethonkids.org.au">Prue.Hart@telethonkids.org.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Telethon Kids Institute, College of Medicine, Biology and Environment, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Endocrinology and Diabetes, Sir Charles Gairdner Hospital, Nedlands, Australia; and School of Medicine and Pharmacology, and.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Sickle Cell and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-sickle-cell-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-sickle-cell-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Several Sickle Cell trials have found that a loading dose of vitamin D followed by a good sized maintenance dose greatly reduces the number of days of SC pain&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The size of the loading and maintence doses should vary by weight and health.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>One study used a loading dose 100,000 IU weekly for 6 weeks - ignoring weight&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>One study used a loading dose of 5,234 IU/kg for 4 days&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinal fusion improved by vitamin D (no amounts stated in abstract)</title><link>/posts/spinal-fusion-improved-by-vitamin-d-no-amounts-stated-in-abstract.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-fusion-improved-by-vitamin-d-no-amounts-stated-in-abstract.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-relationship-between-serum-vitamin-d-levels-and-spinal-fusion-success-a-quantitative-analysis">The Relationship between Serum Vitamin D Levels and Spinal Fusion Success: A Quantitative Analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2015 Jan 23. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Metzger MF1, Kanim LE, Zhao L, Robinson ST, Delamarter RB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Study Design. An in vivo dosing study of vitamin D in a rat posterolateral spinal fusion model with autogenous bone grafting. Rats randomized to four levels of Vitamin D adjusted rat chow, longitudinal serum validation, surgeons/observers blinded to dietary conditions, and rats followed prospectively for fusion endpoint.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stress fractures in basic training associated with 2.5 ng less vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/stress-fractures-in-basic-training-associated-with-25-ng-less-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stress-fractures-in-basic-training-associated-with-25-ng-less-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-stress-fractures-in-military-personnel-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels and Stress Fractures in Military Personnel: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Sports Med. 2014 Nov 4. pii: 0363546514555971. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dao D 1, Sodhi S 1, Tabasinejad R 2, Peterson D 3, Ayeni OR 3, Bhandari M 4, Farrokhyar F 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2School of Kinesiology and Health Science, York University, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Child Bone health – (incorrect) recommendations by US Pediatric and Bone Health groups</title><link>/posts/child-bone-health-incorrect-recommendations-by-us-pediatric-and-bone-health-groups.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/child-bone-health-incorrect-recommendations-by-us-pediatric-and-bone-health-groups.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>People with old burns improved muscle strength with 2200 IU average vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/people-with-old-burns-improved-muscle-strength-with-2200-iu-average-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-old-burns-improved-muscle-strength-with-2200-iu-average-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin K-2 – bone biomarkers indicate at least 600 ug of MK-4 are needed daily</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k-2-bone-biomarkers-indicate-at-least-600-ug-of-mk-4-are-needed-daily.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k-2-bone-biomarkers-indicate-at-least-600-ug-of-mk-4-are-needed-daily.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-dose-menaquinone-4-improves-γ-carboxylation-of-osteocalcin-in-young-males-a-non-placebo-controlled-doseresponse-study">Low-dose menaquinone-4 improves γ-carboxylation of osteocalcin in young males: a non-placebo-controlled dose–response study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrition Journal 2014, 13:85 doi:10.1186/1475-2891-13-85&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eriko Nakamura, Mami Aoki, Fumiko Watanabe and Ayako Kamimura &lt;a href="mailto:ayako.kamimura@kyowa-kirin.co.jp">ayako.kamimura@kyowa-kirin.co.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Healthcare Products Development Center, KYOWA HAKKO BIO CO., LTD, 2 Miyukigaoka, Tsukuba, Ibaraki 305-0841, Japan&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:>60%">
&lt;p>Increased daily doses of MK-4 each week for 13 Japanese males – age 25&lt;/p>
&lt;p>0 ug/day, 300 ug/day, 600 ug/day, 900, ug/day. 1500 ug/day&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Found that 600 ug was enough to show improved bone biomarker&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin K2 (as MK-7) is needed for bone quality – Review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k2-as-mk-7-is-needed-for-bone-quality-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k2-as-mk-7-is-needed-for-bone-quality-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-k2-and-bone-quality">Vitamin K2 and Bone Quality&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Toshiro Sato &lt;a href="mailto:oshiro.sato@j-oil.com">oshiro.sato@j-oil.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fine Chemical Laboratory, Nakashinden, Fukuroi-city, Shizuoka, Japan&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vitamin K acts as a cofactor for the endoplasmic enzyme y-glutamyl carboxylase, during post-translational conversion of glutamic acid residues to y-carboxyglutamic acid (Gla) in specific proteins. These proteins are referred to as vitamin K-dependent proteins, and include several blood coagulation factors and anti-coagulation factors, which are synthesized in the liver; Osteocalcin(OC), a bone-specific protein synthesized by osteoblasts; and Matrix Gla Protein (MGP), which is synthesized in several organs. Recently, considerable attention has been directed towards these vitamin K-dependent Gla proteins; their role in bone metabolism; and their inhibitory effect on artery calcification. The current average intake of vitamin K from a normal diet in healthy adults is greater than that required for normal blood coagulation, but is insufficient for extra hepatic tissue requirements &lt;sup>[1,2]&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: increased bone mineral density needs protein, Ca, Mg, Vitamin D and K</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-increased-bone-mineral-density-needs-protein-ca-mg-vitamin-d-and-k.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-increased-bone-mineral-density-needs-protein-ca-mg-vitamin-d-and-k.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-paradox-of-osteoporosis-irreversibilityhttpblogscreightoneduheaney20140725the-paradox-of-osteoporosis-irreversibility-2comment-34702-dr-heaney-july-2014">&lt;a href="http://blogs.creighton.edu/heaney/2014/07/25/the-paradox-of-osteoporosis-irreversibility-2/#comment-34702">The Paradox of Osteoporosis Irreversibility&lt;/a> Dr. Heaney July 2014&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>He makes a good case for protein being needed to increase Bone Mineral Density (BMD) and has the following chart&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/bmd-vs-protein.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Question posted by VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is there any evidence that bone structure (spongy latticework ) is rebuilt, rather than just BMD increased with increased protein, Calcium and Vitamin D?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also - Magnesium and Vitamin K2 are vital for building bones&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="a-calcium-collagen-chelate-dietary-supplement-attenuates-bone-loss-in-postmenopausal-women-with-osteopenia-a-randomized-controlled-trial---2014">A Calcium-Collagen Chelate Dietary Supplement Attenuates Bone Loss in Postmenopausal Women with Osteopenia: A Randomized Controlled Trial - 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Med Food. 2014 Oct&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sickle cell Vitamin D deficiency corrected with 160 K IU loading dose</title><link>/posts/sickle-cell-vitamin-d-deficiency-corrected-with-160-k-iu-loading-dose.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sickle-cell-vitamin-d-deficiency-corrected-with-160-k-iu-loading-dose.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-its-correction-in-children-with-sickle-cell-anaemia">Vitamin D deficiency and its correction in children with sickle cell anaemia.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Hematol. 2014 Jul 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wykes C1, Arasaretnam A, O&amp;rsquo;Driscoll S, Farnham L, Moniz C, Rees DC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Paediatric Haematology, King&amp;rsquo;s College Hospital, King&amp;rsquo;s College London, Denmark Hill, London, SE5 9RS, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is common in sickle cell anaemia (SCA, HbSS), although its significance and optimal means of correction are unknown. We conducted an audit to assess the clinical significance of 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25-OHD) deficiency in children with SCA and to evaluate two methods of vitamin D supplementation. We audited 25-OHD levels in 81 children with SCA and looked for statistical associations with biochemical, haematological and clinical parameters. In a separate group of regularly transfused children with SCA, we compared changes in 25-OHD blood concentrations following treatment with either high-dose intramuscular ergocalciferol (n = 15) or 4 days of high-dose oral cholecalciferol (n = 64). Ninety-one percent of children with SCA had 25-OHD levels &amp;lt;20 μg/L. The 25-OHD levels were negatively correlated with increasing age (P &amp;lt; 0.001) but showed no significant relationship to laboratory measurements, transcranial Doppler velocities or hospital attendance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone density does not decrease with lower vitamin D levels in blacks as it does in whites</title><link>/posts/bone-density-does-not-decrease-with-lower-vitamin-d-levels-in-blacks-as-it-does-in-whites.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-density-does-not-decrease-with-lower-vitamin-d-levels-in-blacks-as-it-does-in-whites.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-does-not-influence-bone-density-in-africans-abstract-p168">Vitamin D Status does not influence Bone Density in Africans Abstract P168:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Circulation. 2014; 129: AP168&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Caroline K Thoreson; Michelle Y O&amp;rsquo;Connor; Madia Ricks; Stephanie T Chung; James C Reynolds; Anne E Sumner&lt;/p>
&lt;p>National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without regard to race, the Institute of Medicine states that to protect bone health vitamin D, measured as 25(OH)D, should be &amp;gt;20 ng/mL while levels of 12-19 ng/mL are inadequate and levels of &amp;lt;12 ng/mL are deficient. However, even when 25(OH)D levels are low, bone mineral density (BMD) is not compromised in African-Americans. The relationship of 25(OH)D levels to BMD in Africans is unknown. Therefore 78 African immigrants to the United States (77% male, median age 35y, age range 22-63y (95% CI: 36, 40)) had 25(OH)D levels and dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) scans. Distribution of 25(OH)D levels by quartile was determined (Fig. 1). The distribution of whole body BMD across quartiles of 25(OH)D was assessed (Fig. 2). Median 25(0H)D levels was 21 ng/mL (95% CI: 20, 23) with 47% having 25(OH)D&amp;lt;20 ng/mL and 8% having 25(OH)D &amp;lt;12 ng/mL. BMD did not change across quartiles of 25(OH)D (Fig. 2). Spearman correlation between BMD and 25(OH)D was r =0.1, P=0.5. As there was no relationship between vitamin D levels and BMD, low 25(OH)D levels are not a predictor of low bone density in Africans.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased Bone strength during military training – with just 800 IU of vitamin D and Calcium – RCT</title><link>/posts/increased-bone-strength-during-military-training-with-just-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-bone-strength-during-military-training-with-just-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-calcium-and-vitamin-d-fortified-food-product-improves-bone-adaptation-during-military-training">A calcium and vitamin D fortified food product improves bone adaptation during military training&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The FASEB Journal, vol. 28 no. 1 Supplement 634.3 April 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Erin Gaffney-Stomberg 2, Laura Lutz 2, Julie Hughes 2, Nancy Murphy 2, Louis Marchitelli 2, Sonya Cable1, Andrew Young2 and James McClung2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Initital Military Training Center of Excellence Fort Eustis VA United States&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 US Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine Natick MA United States&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implanting titanium in mice helped by vitamin D: wonder about human teeth, hips etc.</title><link>/posts/implanting-titanium-in-mice-helped-by-vitamin-d-wonder-about-human-teeth-hips-etc.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/implanting-titanium-in-mice-helped-by-vitamin-d-wonder-about-human-teeth-hips-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-enhances-the-fixation-of-titanium-implants-in-chronic-kidney-disease-mice">Vitamin d supplementation enhances the fixation of titanium implants in chronic kidney disease mice.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2014 Apr 21;9(4):e95689. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0095689.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0095689.&lt;/a> eCollection 2014.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liu W1, Zhang S1, Zhao D1, Zou H1, Sun N1, Liang X1, Dard M2, Lanske B3, Yuan Q1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D (Vit D) deficiency is a common condition in chronic kidney disease (CKD) patients that negatively affects bone regeneration and fracture healing. Previous study has shown that timely healing of titanium implants is impaired in CKD. This study aimed to investigate the effect of Vit D supplementation on implant osseointegration in CKD mice. Uremia was induced by 5/6 nephrectomy in C57BL mice. Eight weeks after the second renal surgery, animals were given 1,25(OH)2D3 three times a week intraperitoneally for four weeks. Experimental titanium implants were inserted into the distal end of femurs two weeks later. Serum measurements confirmed decreased 1,25(OH)2D levels in CKD mice, which could be successfully corrected by Vit D injections. Moreover, the hyperparathyroidism observed in CKD mice was also corrected. X-ray examination and histological sections showed successful osseointegration in these mice. Histomorphometrical analysis revealed that the bone-implant contact (BIC) ratio and bone volume (BV/TV) around the implant were significantly increased in the Vit D-supplementation group. In addition, resistance of the implant, as measured by a push-in method, was significantly improved compared to that in the vehicle group. These results demonstrate that Vit D supplementation is an effective approach to improve the fixation of titanium implants in CKD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Military and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/military-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/military-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#overview">Overview&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-in-the-military-its-time-to-act---oct2021">Vitamin D Deficiency in the Military: It’s Time to Act! - Oct 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#86-of-us-military-no-longer-have-enough-vitamin-d-30-ng--dec2020">86% of US military no longer have enough Vitamin D (30 ng) – Dec 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#soldiers-vitamin-d-levels-dropped-by-half-over-18-years--march2014">Soldiers&amp;rsquo; vitamin D levels dropped by half over 18 years – March 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#chart-vitamin-d-levels-of-everyone-dropped-by-half-over-18years">Chart: Vitamin D levels of everyone dropped by half over 18 years&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#need-for-routine-vitamin-d-screening-in-military-personnel---letter-to-editor2016">Need for Routine Vitamin D Screening in Military Personnel - letter to Editor 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#related-items-on-theweb">Related items on the web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h4>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is essential for soldiers, to enhance physical and mental performance, and to combat stress and fatigue&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ankle fractures associated with low vitamin D, smoking etc.</title><link>/posts/ankle-fractures-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-smoking-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ankle-fractures-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-smoking-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-foot-and-ankle-injuries">Prevalence of Vitamin D Deficiency in Patients With Foot and Ankle Injuries&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ankle.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Foot &amp;amp; Ankle International January 2014 vol. 35 no. 1 8-13&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jeremy T. Smith, MD1, Kareem Halim, AB1, David A. Palms, AB1, Kanu Okike, MD, MPH2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eric M. Bluman, MD, PhD1, Christopher P. Chiodo, MD1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Brigham Foot and Ankle Center at the Faulkner, Jamaica Plain, MA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Orthopaedics, Shock Trauma Center, Baltimore, MD, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and microRNAs in bone</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-micrornas-in-bone.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-micrornas-in-bone.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Crit Rev Eukaryot Gene Expr. 2013;23(3):195-214.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lisse TS1, Adams JS, Hewison M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MicroRNAs (miRNAs) are short noncoding RNAs that orchestrate complex posttranscriptional regulatory networks essential to the regulation of gene expression. Through complementarity with messenger RNA (mRNA) sequences, miRNAs act primarily to silence gene expression through either degradation or inhibited translation of target transcripts. In this way, miRNAs can act to fine-tune the transcriptional regulation of gene expression, but they may also play distinct roles in the proliferation, differentiation, and function of specific cell types. miRNA regulatory networks may be particularly important for signaling molecules such as vitamin D that exert pleiotropic effects on tissues throughout the body.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip problem in boys (PERTHES' DISEASE) associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hip-problem-in-boys-perthes-disease-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-problem-in-boys-perthes-disease-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-effects-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-on-the-natural-progression-of-perthes-disease">THE EFFECTS OF VITAMIN D DEFICIENCY ON THE NATURAL PROGRESSION OF PERTHES&amp;rsquo; DISEASE&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>S Al-Naser, J Judd and N M P Clarke; University Hospital Southampton, Southampton, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Femoral head deformity can be a devastating outcome in a small percentage of patients with Perthes&amp;rsquo; disease. Deformities usually start during the fragmentation stage. In this study, we aimed to determine the effects of Vitamin D deficiency on the natural history of Perthes&amp;rsquo; disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New approaches to bones, genes, and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/new-approaches-to-bones-genes-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/new-approaches-to-bones-genes-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="regulation-of-gene-expression-by-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3-in-bone-cells-exploiting-new-approaches-and-defining-new-mechanisms">Regulation of gene expression by 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 in bone cells: exploiting new approaches and defining new mechanisms&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BoneKEy Reports, (2014) 3, Article number: 482 (2014) doi:10.1038/bonekey.2013.216 Jan 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Wesley Pike,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seong Min Lee&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;amp; Mark B Meyer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The biological actions of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3) serve both to orchestrate calcium and phosphorus homeostasis in higher vertebrates and to regulate a diverse set of cellular functions unrelated to control of mineral metabolism. With regard to bone, mesenchymal lineage cells, including both early and late osteoblasts as well as osteocytes represent classic targets of the vitamin D hormone. Accordingly, much of the early information regarding our current understanding of the mechanism of action of 1,25(OH)2D3, of which gene regulation is central, derives from a broad array of studies in these cell types. Indeed, a gene that provided both the earliest and perhaps the most extensive information regarding this and additional mechanisms was that of osteoblast-specific osteocalcin. Subsequent work has provided much additional detail as to how 1,25(OH)2D3, through the vitamin D receptor (VDR), mediates the modulation of many bone cell genes. In recent years, however, a series of technical advances involving the coupling of chromatin immunoprecipitation (ChIP) to unbiased methodologies that involve next-generation DNA sequencing techniques (ChIP-seq) have opened new avenues in the study of gene regulation. In this review, we summarize early work and then focus on more recent studies that have used ChIP-seq analysis and other approaches to provide insight into not only the regulation of specific genes such as the VDR, TNFSF11 (RANKL), LRP5, CBS and CYP24a1, but overarching genome-wide principles of gene regulation as well. The results of these studies highlight the value of these new approaches and the increased insight that can be gained.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone density correlates better with free D (calculated) rather than measured vitamin D</title><link>/posts/bone-density-correlates-better-with-free-d-calculated-rather-than-measured-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-density-correlates-better-with-free-d-calculated-rather-than-measured-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-free-and-bio-available-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-correlate-better-with-bone-density-than-serum-total-25-hydroxyvitamin-d">Serum free and bio-available 25-hydroxyvitamin D correlate better with bone density than serum total 25-hydroxyvitamin D.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 2014 Jan 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martin S. Johnsen 1, Guri Grimnes 1,2, Yngve Figenschau 3, Peter A. Torjesen 4, Bjørg Almås 5 &amp;amp; Rolf Jorde 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Tromsø Endocrine Research Group, Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tromsø&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Division of Internal Medicine, University Hospital of North Norway, Tromsø&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Institute of Medical Biochemistry, University of Tromsø and Department of Laboratory Medicine, University Hospital of North Norway, Tromsø&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Bone Disease – Review 2012</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-bone-disease-review-2012.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-bone-disease-review-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;p>BioMed Research International. Volume 2013 (2013), Article ID 396541, 6 pages, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2013/396541">http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2013/396541&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. Christodoulou, T. Goula, A. Ververidis, and G. Drosos&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, School of Medicine, Democritus University of Thrace, University General Hospital of Alexandroupolis, Dragana, 68100 Alexandroupolis, Greece&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 6 July 2012; Accepted 29 August 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is important for normal development and maintenance of the skeleton. Hypovitaminosis D adversely affects calcium metabolism, osteoblastic activity, matrix ossification, bone remodeling and bone density. It is well known that Vit. D deficiency in the developing skeleton is related to rickets, while in adults is related to osteomalacia. The causes of rickets include conditions that lead to hypocalcemia and/or hypophosphatemia, either isolated or secondary to vitamin D deficiency. In osteomalacia, Vit. D deficiency leads to impairment of the mineralisation phase of bone remodeling and thus an increasing amount of the skeleton being replaced by unmineralized osteoid. The relationship between Vit. D and bone mineral density and osteoporosis are still controversial while new evidence suggests that Vit. D may play a role in other bone conditions such as osteoarthritis and stress fractures. In order to maintain a “good bone health” guidelines concerning the recommended dietary intakes should be followed and screening for Vit. D deficiency in individuals at risk for deficiency is required, followed by the appropriate action.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bones grow better with high level of magnesium: rat study</title><link>/posts/bones-grow-better-with-high-level-of-magnesium-rat-study.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bones-grow-better-with-high-level-of-magnesium-rat-study.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-effects-of-magnesium-supplementation-in-diets-with-different-calcium-levels-on-the-bone-status-and-bone-metabolism-in-growing-female-rats">The effects of magnesium supplementation in diets with different calcium levels on the bone status and bone metabolism in growing female rats.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Biol Trace Elem Res. 2013 Dec;155(3):431-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s12011-013-9798-1.">doi: 10.1007/s12011-013-9798-1.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bae YJ, Kim MH. &lt;a href="mailto:mhkim1129@kangwon.ac.kr">mhkim1129@kangwon.ac.kr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Department of Food and Nutritional Sciences, Hanbuk University, Dongducheon, 483-120, South Korea&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Department of Food and Nutrition, Kangwon National University, Samcheok, 245-749, South Korea&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Previous studies have revealed that magnesium (Mg) plays a significant role in bone health; however, few studies have investigated the effects of Mg supplementation in diets with different calcium (Ca) levels on the bone status and bone metabolism in a growing stage. In this present study, we tested the effects of Mg supplementation on bone status in growing female rats, relative to Ca intake levels. A total of 40 Sprague-Dawley female rats aged 6 weeks were divided into the following four groups and fed for 12 weeks as indicated:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D for older people (VDOP) trial, with 48,000 IU per month – RCT started Fall 2012</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-for-older-people-vdop-trial-with-48000-iu-per-month-rct-started-fall-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-for-older-people-vdop-trial-with-48000-iu-per-month-rct-started-fall-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-older-people-vdop-study-protocol-for-a-randomised-controlled-intervention-trial-with-monthly-oral-dosing-with-12000-iu-24000-iu-or-48000-iu-of-vitamin-d3">Vitamin D supplementation in older people (VDOP): Study protocol for a randomised controlled intervention trial with monthly oral dosing with 12,000 IU, 24,000 IU or 48,000 IU of vitamin D3&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Inez Schoenmakers,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roger M Francis,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elaine McColl,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thomas Chadwick,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gail R Goldberg,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christine Harle,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alison Yarnall,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jennifer Wilkinson,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jennie Parker,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ann Prentice,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>… show all 11&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The randomised, double blind intervention trial ‘Optimising Vitamin D Status in Older People’ (VDOP) will test the effect of three oral dosages of vitamin D given for one year on bone mineral density (BMD) and biochemical markers of vitamin D metabolism, bone turnover and safety in older people. VDOP is funded by Arthritis Research UK, supported through Newcastle University and MRC Human Nutrition Research and sponsored by the Newcastle upon Tyne Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust.a&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased Vitamin K2 reduces the problems of excess Calcium</title><link>/posts/increased-vitamin-k2-reduces-the-problems-of-excess-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-vitamin-k2-reduces-the-problems-of-excess-calcium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Acute Multiple Sclerosis relapse associated with low bone mineral density (low vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/acute-multiple-sclerosis-relapse-associated-with-low-bone-mineral-density-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/acute-multiple-sclerosis-relapse-associated-with-low-bone-mineral-density-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="patients-with-an-acute-multiple-sclerosis-relapse-a-high-risk-group-for-osteopenia-and-osteoporosis">PATIENTS WITH AN ACUTE MULTIPLE SCLEROSIS RELAPSE: A HIGH RISK GROUP FOR OSTEOPENIA AND OSTEOPOROSIS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2013;84:e2 doi:10.1136/jnnp-2013-306573.194&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Association of British Neurologists (ABN) joint meeting with the Royal College of Physicians (RCP), London, 23–24 October 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olwen Murphy⇓, Michael S Zandi, Nitzan Lindenberg, Elaine Murphy, Jeremy Chataway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>National Hospital for Neurology and Neurosurgery, University College London Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, London.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective To evaluate the bone health of a cohort of patients with an acute Multiple Sclerosis (MS) relapse and to develop an algorithm for the management of bone health in this patient group.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin K and bone health – need more research</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k-and-bone-health-need-more-research.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k-and-bone-health-need-more-research.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-k-and-bone-health">Vitamin K and bone health&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Densitometry&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maryam S. Hamidi1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olga Gajic-Veljanoski1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Angela M. Cheung1, 2, &lt;a href="mailto:angela.m.cheung@gmail.com">angela.m.cheung@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Osteoporosis and Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Programs at University Health Network, Toronto, ON, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Medicine at University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin K has been purported to play an important role in bone health. It is required for the gamma-carboxylation of osteocalcin (the most abundant noncollagenous protein in bone), making osteocalcin functional.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Both Vitamin D and Calcium are needed to reduce bone loss – RCT</title><link>/posts/both-vitamin-d-and-calcium-are-needed-to-reduce-bone-loss-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/both-vitamin-d-and-calcium-are-needed-to-reduce-bone-loss-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-postmenopausal-women">Calcium and Vitamin D Supplementation in Postmenopausal Women&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism September 24, 2013 jc.2013-2121&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John F. Aloia, Ruban Dhaliwal, Albert Shieh, Mageda Mikhail, Shahidul Islam and James K. Yeh&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Winthrop University Hospital, Bone Mineral Research Center, Mineola, New York 11501&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address all correspondence and requests for reprints to: John F. Aloia, MD, Winthrop University Hospital, 222 Station Plaza North, Suite 510, Mineola, New York 11501. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:jaloia@winthrop.org">jaloia@winthrop.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Large seasonal variation in vitamin D levels associated with poor bone health</title><link>/posts/large-seasonal-variation-in-vitamin-d-levels-associated-with-poor-bone-health.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/large-seasonal-variation-in-vitamin-d-levels-associated-with-poor-bone-health.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="greater-seasonal-cycling-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-is-associated-with-increased-parathyroid-hormone-and-bone-resorption">Greater seasonal cycling of 25-hydroxyvitamin D is associated with increased parathyroid hormone and bone resorption.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2013 Aug 28. DOI: 10.1007/s00198-013-2493-4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Darling AL, Hart KH, Gibbs MA, Gossiel F, Kantermann T, Horton K, Johnsen S, Berry JL, Skene DJ, Eastell R, Vieth R, Lanham-New SA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutritional Sciences, School of Biosciences and Medicine, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Surrey, Guildford, Surrey, GU2 7XH, UK, &lt;a href="mailto:a.darling@surrey.ac.uk">a.darling@surrey.ac.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/seasonal-d-and-pth.pdf">Download the PDF from Sci-Hub via VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Working other than dayshift reduces vitamin D levels and Bone Mineral Density and increases bone pain</title><link>/posts/working-other-than-dayshift-reduces-vitamin-d-levels-and-bone-mineral-density-an-eases-bone-pain.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/working-other-than-dayshift-reduces-vitamin-d-levels-and-bone-mineral-density-an-eases-bone-pain.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="other-than-daytime-working-is-associated-with-lower-bone-mineral-density">Other than Daytime Working Is Associated with Lower Bone Mineral Density:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Korea National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2009.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calcif Tissue Int. 2013 Aug 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim BK, Choi YJ, Chung YS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Ajou University School of Medicine, San 5 Wonchon-dong, Yeongtong-gu, Suwon, 443-721, South Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Occupation affects bone mineral density (BMD); however, only few studies have been published. This study evaluated the effect of working time during a day on BMD. The cross-sectional study involved 18- to 50-year-old people who reported their working time and were measured for BMD using dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry in the Fourth Korea National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2009. The time period of work was divided into &amp;ldquo;daytime&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;other than daytime.&amp;rdquo; The other-than-daytime group included evening time, nighttime, regular shift time, and irregular shift time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D associated with 5.5X increased risk of low bone mineral density</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-55x-increased-risk-of-low-bone-mineral-density.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-55x-increased-risk-of-low-bone-mineral-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="relationships-between-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-quantitative-ultrasound-bone-mineral-density-in-0-6-year-old-children">Relationships between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and quantitative ultrasound bone mineral density in 0-6 year old children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bone. 2013 Mar;53(1):306-10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bone.2012.12.012.">doi: 10.1016/j.bone.2012.12.012.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Dec 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yu X, Zhang J, Yan C, Shen X.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MOE-Shanghai Key Lab of Children&amp;rsquo;s Environmental Health, XinHua Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200092, China. &lt;a href="mailto:shahd1230@yahoo.com.cn">shahd1230@yahoo.com.cn&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and quantitative ultrasound bone mineral density in young children remains unclear. In addition, consensus has not been reached with regard to the concentration of 25(OH)D to define vitamin D deficiency for infants and children. In the present study, 203 children 0-6 years old were recruited in Shanghai, China. The concentrations of serum 25(OH)D, weight, length, and quantitative ultrasound bone mineral density (BMD) of left mid-tibia were determined. Low BMD was defined as &amp;lt;20th percentile of given age and sex. Low 25(OH)D was defined as 25(OH)D&amp;lt;20 ng/ml. The results showed that median serum 25(OH)D level was 19.0 ng/ml, and 58.6% had a serum 25(OH)D below 20 ng/ml. After adjusting for potential confounders, a linear relationship between serum 25(OH)D and BMD was observed. Serum 25(OH)D was positively associated with BMD (ß=323.3, 95% CI=201.0-445.7, p&amp;lt;0.001), and &lt;strong>low 25(OH)D (&amp;lt;20 ng/ml) had a high risk for low BMD (OR=5.5, 95% CI=2.5-12)&lt;/strong> . In addition, there is a nonlinear relationship between 25(OH)D and low BMD, and a threshold for 25(OH)D of 20 ng/ml existed for low BMD. The prevalence of low BMD was 47.1% in the group of 25(OH)D&amp;lt;20 ng/ml, much higher than 16.7% in the group of 25(OH)D ≥ 20 ng/ml (p&amp;lt;0.05). The results suggested that quantitative ultrasound BMD could be an indicator for vitamin D status in young children, and also provided further evidence to define vitamin D deficiency for infants and children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bones can activate vitamin D</title><link>/posts/bones-can-activate-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bones-can-activate-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-activities-and-metabolic-bone-disease">Vitamin D activities and metabolic bone disease&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clinica Chimica Acta. Available online 30 July 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jackson W. Ryan, Paul H. Anderson, Andrew G. Turner, Howard A. Morris &lt;a href="mailto:Howard.Morris@health.sa.gov.au">Howard.Morris@health.sa.gov.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Pharmacy and Medical Sciences, University of South Australia, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chemical Pathology Directorate and Hanson Institute, SA Pathology, Adelaide South Australia 5000, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Bone mineral status depends on plasma calcium and phosphate homeostasis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D regulates bone remodelling via endocrine and intracrine activities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>7 X more likely to get hip fracture if have highest level of vitamin A</title><link>/posts/7-x-more-likely-to-get-hip-fracture-if-have-highest-level-of-vitamin-a.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7-x-more-likely-to-get-hip-fracture-if-have-highest-level-of-vitamin-a.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-retinol-levels-and-the-risk-of-fracture">Serum retinol levels and the risk of fracture.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med. 2003 Jan 23;348(4):287-94.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michaëlsson K, Lithell H, Vessby B, Melhus H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Surgical Sciences, Section of Orthopedics, University Hospital, Uppsala, Sweden. &lt;a href="mailto:karl.michaelsson@surgsci.uu.se">karl.michaelsson@surgsci.uu.se&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Although studies in animals and epidemiologic studies have indicated that a high vitamin A intake is associated with increased bone fragility, no biologic marker of vitamin A status has thus far been used to assess the risk of fractures in humans.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beyond the bone: conference summary</title><link>/posts/beyond-the-bone-conference-summary.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/beyond-the-bone-conference-summary.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-beyond-bone">Vitamin D: beyond bone&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>ANNALS OF THE NEW YORK ACADEMY OF SCIENCES&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sylvia Christakos,1 Martin Hewison,2 David G. Gardner,3 Carol L. Wagner,4 Igor N. Sergeev,5 Erica Rutten,6 Anastassios G. Pittas,7 Ricardo Boland,8 Luigi Ferrucci,9 and Daniel D. Bikle10&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, UMDNJ-New Jersey Medical School, Newark, New Jersey. 2Department of Orthopedic Surgery, The David Geffen School of Medicine at the University of California, Los Angeles, California.3Diabetes Center and Department of Medicine, University of California, San Francisco, California.4Division of Neonatology, Department of Pediatrics, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina. 5Department of Health and Nutritional Sciences, South Dakota State University, Brookings, South Dakota. 6Ciro, Center of Expertise for Chronic Organ Failure, Horn, the Netherlands. 7Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes and Metabolism, Tufts Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts. 8Departamento de Biologla, Bioqulmica, y Farmacia, Universidad Nacional del Sur, Bahia Blanca, Argentina. 9Longitudinal Studies Section, National Institute on Aging, National Institutes of Health, Baltimore, Maryland. 10Departments of Medicine and Dermatology, University of California San Francisco, and VA Medical Center, San Francisco, California&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>22 percent more bone cracking found with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/22-percent-more-bone-cracking-found-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/22-percent-more-bone-cracking-found-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-induces-early-signs-of-aging-in-human-bone-increasing-the-risk-of-fracture">Vitamin D Deficiency Induces Early Signs of Aging in Human Bone, Increasing the Risk of Fracture&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Sci Transl Med 10 July 2013: Vol. 5, Issue 193, p. 193ra88&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Björn Busse 1,2, &lt;a href="mailto:b.busse@uke.uni-hamburg.de">b.busse@uke.uni-hamburg.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hrishikesh A. Bale 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elizabeth A. Zimmermann 1,2,3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brian Panganiban 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Holly D. Barth 2,3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alessandra Carriero 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eik Vettorazzi 4,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Josef Zustin 5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael Hahn 1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joel W. Ager III 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Klaus Püschel 6,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael Amling 1 and&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High-altitude associated with higher vitamin D and better bones (sheep in this case)</title><link>/posts/high-altitude-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-and-better-bones-sheep-in-this-case.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-altitude-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-and-better-bones-sheep-in-this-case.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="influence-of-high-altitude-grazing-on-bone-metabolism-of-growing-sheep">Influence of high-altitude grazing on bone metabolism of growing sheep.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr (Berl). 2013 Feb;97(1):58-66. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Oct 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liesegang A, Hüttenmoser D, Risteli J, Leiber F, Kreuzer M, Wanner M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Animal Nutrition, University of Zurich, Winterthurerstr. 260, Zurich, Switzerland. &lt;a href="mailto:aliese@vetphys.uzh.ch">aliese@vetphys.uzh.ch&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this study was to identify the effect of high alpine grazing, associated with varying pasture grass qualities and more pronounced exercise on typically steep slopes, on bone metabolism by improving bone density and enhancing bone turnover in growing sheep. Twenty-four 5-month-old sheep were randomly assigned to two groups. One group was kept at high altitude (HA; 2000-2200 m a.s.l.) for 3 months, and the other group (C; control) remained in the lowlands (400 m a.s.l.). Both groups were kept in grazing pastures with access to good-quality swards. Before the start of the experiment, blood samples were taken, the sheep were weighed, and the left metatarsus of each animal was analysed by quantitative computer tomography. After 1 month, blood samples were taken and body weight was measured, followed by biweekly sampling. Finally, the animals were slaughtered, and the bones were collected for analysis of various bone parameters. Body weight development did not differ between the groups. Concentrations of 25-OH-Vitamin D, carboxy-terminal telopeptide of type I collagen and activities of bone-specific alkaline phosphatase were always higher in the HA group than in the C group, except on the last two sampling dates. Bone mineral content and density increased in both groups during the experiment, but more intensively in the HA group. In addition, the cortical thickness of the HA group increased. The present study demonstrates an increase in bone turnover and mineral content of the bones of the growing sheep grazing in high alpine pastures. The factors associated with HA grazing, therefore, clearly seem to improve bone composition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20 percent fewer male hip fractures if more Magnesium in the water</title><link>/posts/20-percent-fewer-male-hip-fractures-if-more-magnesium-in-the-water.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/20-percent-fewer-male-hip-fractures-if-more-magnesium-in-the-water.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="nationwide-data-on-municipal-drinking-water-and-hip-fracture">Nationwide data on municipal drinking water and hip fracture:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Could calcium and magnesium be protective? A NOREPOS study&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone, Available online 2 July 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cecilie Dahl a, b, &lt;a href="mailto:Cecilie.Dahl@fhi.no">Cecilie.Dahl@fhi.no&lt;/a>, Anne Johanne Søgaard a, Grethe S. Tel b, Trond Peder Flaten c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dag Hongve d, Tone Kristin Omsland b, e, Kristin Holvik b, Haakon E. Meyer a, e, Geir Aamodt a&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Division of Epidemiology, Norwegian Institute of Public Health, Oslo, Norway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Public Health and Primary Health Care, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Not vitamin D deficient if have normal PTH and BMD</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-not-vitamin-d-deficient-if-have-normal-pth-and-bmd.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-not-vitamin-d-deficient-if-have-normal-pth-and-bmd.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="calcium-homeostasis-and-clinical-or-subclinical-vitamin-d-deficiency---can-a-hypothesis-of-intestinal-calcistat-explain-it-all">Calcium homeostasis, and clinical or subclinical vitamin D deficiency ‰%- Can a hypothesis of &amp;ldquo;intestinal calcistat&amp;rdquo; explain it all?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Med Hypotheses. 2013 May 13. pii: S0306-9877(13)00205-3. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mehy.2013.04.035.">doi: 10.1016/j.mehy.2013.04.035.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Garg MK, Mahalle N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology, Command Hospital (Southern Command), Pune 411040, Maharashtra, India. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:mkgargs@gmail.com">mkgargs@gmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main physiological function of vitamin D is maintenance of calcium homeostasis by its effect on calcium absorption, and bone health in association with parathyroid gland. Vitamin D deficiency (VDD) is defined as serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25OHD) levels &amp;lt;20ng/ml. Vitamin D insufficiency is called when serum 25OHD levels are between 20-29ng/ml, though existence of this entity has been questioned. Do all subjects with VDD have clinical disease according to this definition? Analysis of published studies suggests that calcium absorption in inversely correlated with serum 25OHD levels and calcium intake. We hypothesize that there exist an intestinal calcistat, which controls the calcium absorption independent of PTH levels. It consists of calcium sensing receptor (CaSR) on intestinal brush border, which senses calcium in intestinal cells and vitamin D system in intestinal cells. CaSR dampens the generation of active vitamin D metabolite in intestinal cells and decrease active transcellular calcium transport. It also facilitates passive paracellular diffusion of calcium in intestine. This local adaptation adjusts the fractional calcium absorption according the body requirement. Failure of local adaptation due to decreased calcium intake, decreased supply of 25OHD, mutation in CaSR or vitamin D system decreases systemic calcium levels and systemic adaptations comes into the play. Systemic adaptations consist of rise in PTH and increase in active vitamin D metabolites. These adaptations lead to bone resorption and maintenance of calcium homeostasis. Not all subjects with varying levels of VDD manifest with secondary hyperparathyroidism and decreased in bone mineral density. We suggest that rise in PTH is first indicator of VDD is rise in PTH along with decrease in BMD depending on duration of VDD. Hence, subjects with any degree of VDD with normal PTH and BMD should not be labeled as vitamin D deficient. These subjects can be called subclinical VDD, and further studies are required to assess beneficial effect of vitamin D supplementation in this subset of population. This hypothesis further highlights pitfalls in treatment of hypoparathyroidism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Soy isoflavones synergistically aid vitamin D in building bones</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-soy-isoflavones-synergistically-aid-vitamin-d-in-building-bones.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-soy-isoflavones-synergistically-aid-vitamin-d-in-building-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-interactions-with-soy-isoflavones-on-bone-after-menopause-a-review">Vitamin D interactions with soy isoflavones on bone after menopause: a review.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Park CY, Weaver CM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutrition Science, Purdue University, 700 W State St, West Lafayette, IN 47907, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:cypark@purdue.edu">cypark@purdue.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>There might also be BAD Soy= with Glysophate&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/gmo-soybeans-have-high-levels-of-glyphosate">GMO soybeans have high levels of glyphosate – June 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/20-x-more-parkinsons-and-100x-more-autism-with-gmo-soy-in-china">20 X more Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s and 100X more Autism with GMO soy in China&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/huge-increases-in-health-problems-risk-factors-include-vitamin-d-antibiotics-and-roundup">Huge increases in health problems – risk factors include Vitamin D, Antibiotics, and Roundup&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnesium may be more important to kids’ bone health than calcium</title><link>/posts/magnesium-may-be-more-important-to-kids-bone-health-than-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/magnesium-may-be-more-important-to-kids-bone-health-than-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#highlight-dietary-magnesium-intake-but-not-calcium-intake-was-significantly-associated-with-both-total-body-bone-mineral-content-and-density">Highlight: dietary magnesium intake, but not calcium intake, was significantly associated with both total body bone mineral content and density&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#27153-magnesium-but-not-calcium-intake">2715.3 Magnesium, but Not Calcium Intake&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#press-release">Press Release&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="highlight-dietary-magnesium-intake-but-not-calcium-intake-was-significantly-associated-with-both-total-body-bone-mineral-content-and-density">Highlight: dietary magnesium intake, but not calcium intake, was significantly associated with both total body bone mineral content and density&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="27153-magnesium-but-not-calcium-intake">2715.3 Magnesium, but Not Calcium Intake&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Is Significantly Association with Bone Mineral Status in 4 to 8 Year Old Children&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Summary of Vitamin D portion of Bone and Mineral Research Meeting</title><link>/posts/summary-of-vitamin-d-portion-of-bone-and-mineral-research-meeting.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/summary-of-vitamin-d-portion-of-bone-and-mineral-research-meeting.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="meeting-report-from-the-34th-annual-meeting-of-the-american-society-for-bone-and-mineral-research">Meeting report from the 34th Annual Meeting of the American Society for Bone and Mineral Research,&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Minneapolis, MN, USA, 12–15 October 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Report on recent vitamin D research (ASBMR 2012)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IBMS BoneKEy, (2013), 10, Article number: 329; doi:10.1038/bonekey.2013.63; Published online, 10 April 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roger Bouillon&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#meeting-report-from-the-34th-annual-meeting-of-the-american-society-for-bone-and-mineral-research">Meeting report from the 34th Annual Meeting of the American Society for Bone and Mineral Research,&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-and-bone">1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D and bone&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2425-dihydroxyvitamin-d">24,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-the-intestine">Vitamin D and the intestine&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#extra-renal-cyp27b1-expression-and-production-of-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d">Extra renal cyp27b1 expression and production of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#fgf23-and-production-of-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d">FGF23 and production of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#skin-synthesis-of-vitamin-d">Skin synthesis of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-worldwide">Vitamin D status worldwide&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-and-vitamin-d-status">Vitamin D supplementation and vitamin D status&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#intermittent-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-vitamin-d-status">Intermittent high-dose vitamin D supplementation and vitamin D status&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pregnancy-and-second-generation-effects">Pregnancy and second-generation effects&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-muscle-and-falls">Vitamin D supplementation: muscle and falls&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-the-metabolic-syndrome">Vitamin D and the metabolic syndrome&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#assay-methodology-for-vitamin-d-metabolites">Assay methodology for vitamin D metabolites&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references-numbers-are-approximate">References (numbers are approximate)&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ion-line-index-to-abstracts">IOn-line index to abstracts&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-and-bone">1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D and bone&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is well known for its effects on promoting bone mineralization as the primary characteristic of rickets, and osteomalacia refers to decreased mineralization of the bone matrix. However, the direct effects of the vitamin D endocrine system on bone cells need further clarification. Earlier studies revealed that overexpression of VDR in osteoblasts (driven by osteocalcin promoter) increased bone mass and strength.1 Deletion of VDR in osteocytes (using a dmp1 cre system) did not influence bone mass or other parameters of bone metabolism.2 Deletion of VDR in osteoblasts using an osteocalcin cre system, however, increased (&amp;gt;20%) bone mass (total and trabecular femoral bone, mainly by increase in the number of trabeculae) as reported by Anderson et al.3 and by S Kato (presented at the 2012 Endocrine Society Meeting as summarized in Bouillon4). However, the mechanisms involved are not clear, as preliminary data suggested increase bone formation (as reported by Anderson et al.3) and decreased bone resorption in the Japanese osteoblast-selective VDR mice. These observations imply that VDR activation can have beneficial effects (prevent rickets and osteomalacia) but can also impair bone formation or mineralization in case of exposure to very high serum concentrations of 1,25(OH)2D.2, 5 Such negative effects of vitamin D on mineral deposition were also observed by studying the gene expression profile after exposure to 1,25(OH)2D (Pike’s group, as reported in the previous BoneKey Report4) and now in a series of in vitro experiments using osteoblasts from different regions (calvaria and femur). Exposure to 1,25(OH)2D could inhibit mineral deposition in early-stage calvaria-derived osteoblasts, whereas it enhanced mineral deposition in more mature cortical-bone-derived osteoblasts, at least in the presence of high extracellular calcium concentration.6 The direct effects of the vitamin D endocrine system on bone cells were also explored by analyzing mice with transgenic overexpression of cyp27b1 in osteoblasts using an osteocalcin promoter region. At 20 weeks of age, such mice displayed a 10% increase in bone volume as well in the lumbar vertebrae as in the femoral metaphysis.7 This beneficial effect was due to increased bone formation with unaltered bone resorption, indicating a direct bone anabolic effect of locally produced 1,25(OH)2D in osteoblasts. All these new observations indicate that the vitamin D endocrine system has a yin/yang effect on bone: in most circumstances it enhances mineral deposition but in the presence of low calcium supply the vitamin D endocrine system tries to maintain serum calcium homeostasis at the expense of bone (increased resorption and decreased mineralization).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin K-2 (180 ug MK-7) helped both bone density and strength – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k-2-180-ug-mk-7-helped-both-bone-density-and-strength-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k-2-180-ug-mk-7-helped-both-bone-density-and-strength-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="three-year-low-dose-menaquinone-7-supplementation-helps-decrease-bone-loss-in-healthy-postmenopausal-women">Three-year low-dose menaquinone-7 supplementation helps decrease bone loss in healthy postmenopausal women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis International March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. H. J. Knapen, N. E. Drummen, E. Smit, C. Vermeer, E. Theuwissen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have investigated whether low-dose vitamin K2 supplements (menaquinone-7, MK-7) could beneficially affect bone health. Next to an improved vitamin K status, MK-7 supplementation significantly decreased the age-related decline in bone mineral density and bone strength. Low-dose MK-7 supplements may therefore help postmenopausal women prevent bone loss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip bone loss stopped with 1000 IU of vitamin D, while 400 IU similar to placebo – RCT</title><link>/posts/hip-bone-loss-stopped-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-while-400-iu-similar-to-placebo-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-bone-loss-stopped-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-while-400-iu-similar-to-placebo-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hip-bone-loss-is-attenuated-with-1000-iu-but-not-400-iu-daily-vitamin-d3-a-1-year-double-blind-rct-in-postmenopausal-women">Hip bone loss is attenuated with 1000 IU but not 400 IU daily vitamin D3: a 1 year double-blind RCT in postmenopausal women&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Bone and Mineral Research, Vol. 28 Issue 4, DOI: 10.1002/jbmr.1959&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Helen M Macdonald1,‖, &lt;a href="mailto:h.macdonald@abdn.ac.uk">h.macdonald@abdn.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adrian D Wood1,‖,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lorna S Aucott1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alison J Black3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William D Fraser4,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alexandra Mavroeidi2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David M Reid1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karen R Secombes1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William G Simpson5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frank Thies1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Aberdeen, Foresterhill, Aberdeen&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lumbar spinal stenosis pain strongly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/lumbar-spinal-stenosis-pain-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lumbar-spinal-stenosis-pain-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-lumbar-spinal-stenosis-and-its-relationship-with-pain">Prevalence of vitamin d deficiency in patients with lumbar spinal stenosis and its relationship with pain.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pain Physician. 2013 Mar;16(2):165-76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim TH, Lee BH, Lee HM, Lee SH, Park JO, Kim HS, Kim SW, Moon SH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spine Center, Hallym University Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Anyang, Korea; Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Patients with lumbar spinal stenosis (LSS) are at a great risk of a fall and fracture, which vitamin D protects against. Vitamin D deficiency is expected to be highly prevalent in LSS patient, and pain is thought to have a profound effect on vitamin D status by limiting activity and sunlight exposure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low levels of vitamin D prior to spine surgery</title><link>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-prior-to-spine-surgery.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-prior-to-spine-surgery.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="preoperative-vitamin-d-status-of-adults-undergoing-surgical-spinal-fusion">Preoperative Vitamin D Status of Adults Undergoing Surgical Spinal Fusion&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Spine: 15 March 2013 - Volume 38 - Issue 6 - p 507–515&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stoker, Geoffrey E. BS; Buchowski, Jacob M. MD, MS; Bridwell, Keith H. MD; Lenke, Lawrence G. MD; Riew, K. Daniel MD; Zebala, Lukas P. MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Study Design. Retrospective investigation of cross-sectional data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective. To define the prevalence and determinants of preoperative vitamin D deficiency among adults undergoing spinal fusion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>88 percent of Intestinal failures had both low vitamin D and low bone density</title><link>/posts/88-percent-of-intestinal-failures-had-both-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/88-percent-of-intestinal-failures-had-both-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="high-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-osteoporosis-in-out-patients-with-intestinal-failure">High prevalence of vitamin D deficiency and osteoporosis in out-patients with intestinal failure.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clin Nutr. 2013 Feb 21. pii: S0261-5614(13)00051-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnu.2013.02.005">doi: 10.1016/j.clnu.2013.02.005&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ellegård L, Kurlberg G, Bosaeus I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Nutrition, Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Göteborg, Sweden. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:lasse.ellegard@nutrition.gu.se">lasse.ellegard@nutrition.gu.se&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: In intestinal failure, specific nutrient deficiencies especially for fat-soluble vitamins can be expected in addition to energy-protein malnutrition. We report serum levels of fat soluble vitamins, and bone density in out-patients with intestinal failure (IF).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D injections of a total of 1,800,000 IU reduced shinbone tenderness</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-injections-of-a-total-of-1800000-iu-reduced-shinbone-tenderness.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-injections-of-a-total-of-1800000-iu-reduced-shinbone-tenderness.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="tibial-tenderness-identifies-secondary-hyperparathyroidism-responding-to-high-dose-vitamin-d-in-pakistani-women">Tibial Tenderness Identifies Secondary Hyperparathyroidism Responding to High Dose Vitamin D in Pakistani Women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2013 Feb 20:1-20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ali B, Butt A, Fatima A, McDonnell ME, Masud F.; Department of Medicine, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To assess the utility of &lt;strong>anterior tibial tenderness&lt;/strong> (ATT) measured by visual analogue score (VAS) as a clinical diagnostic tool for vitamin D deficiency in a high-risk population of Pakistani women&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: ATT using a VAS was assessed in 75 premenopausal women, ages 17-56 (mean 41.3) with generalized aches and pains and calcium of less than 11.0mg/dl (normal: 8-11) at a tertiary care center in Lahore, Pakistan. This was followed by administration of &lt;strong>1.8 million units of vitamin D3&lt;/strong> in divided doses. ATT, vitamin D and parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels were checked before and after the injections. Correlation between ATT, vitamin D and PTH as well as change in ATT, vitamin D and (PTH) following supplementation was determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hungry bone syndrome post hyperparathyoidism – review</title><link>/posts/hungry-bone-syndrome-post-hyperparathyoidism-review.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hungry-bone-syndrome-post-hyperparathyoidism-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="therapy-of-endocrine-disease-hungry-bone-syndrome-still-a-challenge-in-the-post-operative-management-of-primary-hyperparathyroidism-a-systematic-review-of-the-literature">THERAPY OF ENDOCRINE DISEASE: Hungry bone syndrome: still a challenge in the post-operative management of primary hyperparathyroidism: a systematic review of the literature&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Eur J Endocrinol March 1, 2013 168 R45-R53&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J E Witteveen1, &lt;a href="mailto:j.e.witteveen@lumc.nl">j.e.witteveen@lumc.nl&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S van Thiel1,2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J A Romijn1,3 and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N A T Hamdy1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Endocrinology and Metabolic Diseases, Leiden University Medical Center, Leiden, The Netherlands&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Internal Medicine, Amphia Medical Center, Breda, The Netherlands and&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ankylosing spondylitis and low vitamin D – many studies</title><link>/posts/ankylosing-spondylitis-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ankylosing-spondylitis-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ankylosing-spondylitis--patients-should-increase-vitamin-d-levels---meta-analysis-nov-2022">Ankylosing Spondylitis patients should increase Vitamin D levels - meta-analysis Nov 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ankylosing-spondylitis-is-still-associated-with-low-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-sept-2022">Ankylosing Spondylitis is still associated with low Vitamin D - meta-analysis Sept 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#considering-testing-all-as-patients-for-low-vitamin-d----jan-2017">Considering testing all AS patients for low Vitamin D - Jan 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#patients-with-ankylosing-spondylitis-continue-to-have-low-vitamin-d---march-2021">Patients with Ankylosing Spondylitis continue to have low Vitamin D - March 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#males-with-ankylosing-spondylitis-having-10ng-of-vitamin-d-had-a-22-x-higher-risk-of-dying---may-2020">Males with Ankylosing Spondylitis having &amp;lt;10ng of vitamin D had a 2.2 X higher risk of dying - May 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#as-related-to-low-vitamin-d---sept-2018">AS related to low Vitamin D - Sept 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#higher-vitamin-d-associated-with-less-risk-of-as---span-stylecolorf00review--meta-analysisspan-sept-2014">Higher Vitamin D associated with less risk of AS - &lt;span style="color:#F00;">review &amp;amp; meta-analysis&lt;/span> Sept 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sponsdyloarthritis-is-21-x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficiency---nov-2017">Sponsdyloarthritis is 2.1 X more likely if Vitamin D Deficiency - Nov 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#decreased-plasma-vitamin-d-levels-in-patients-with-undifferentiated-spondyloarthritis-and-ankylosing-spondylitis---2013">Decreased plasma vitamin d levels in patients with undifferentiated spondyloarthritis and ankylosing spondylitis - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#systematic-review-of-association-between-vitamin-d-levels-and-susceptibility-and-disease-activity-of-ankylosing-spondylitis---2014">Systematic review of association between vitamin D levels and susceptibility and disease activity of ankylosing spondylitis - 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#4-out-of-7-studies-found-as-associated-with-low-vitamin-d---july-2014">4 out of 7 studies found AS associated with low vitamin D - July 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="ankylosing-spondylitis--patients-should-increase-vitamin-d-levels---meta-analysis-nov-2022">Ankylosing Spondylitis patients should increase Vitamin D levels - meta-analysis Nov 2022&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Ankylosing spondylitis disease activity and serum vitamin D levels: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone changes during and after pregnancy</title><link>/posts/bone-changes-during-and-after-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-changes-during-and-after-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="changes-in-bone-mineral-density-and-body-composition-during-pregnancy-and-postpartum-a-controlled-cohort-study">Changes in bone mineral density and body composition during pregnancy and postpartum. A controlled cohort study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Apr;23(4):1213-23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-011-1654-6.">doi: 10.1007/s00198-011-1654-6.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 May 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Møller UK, Við Streym S, Mosekilde L, Rejnmark L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Internal Medicine, MEA, Aarhus Sygehus, Aarhus University Hospital, Tage Hansens Gade 2, DK-8000, Aarhus C, Denmark. &lt;a href="mailto:kristine.moller@ki.au.dk">kristine.moller@ki.au.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a controlled cohort study, bone mineral density (BMD) was measured in 153 women pre-pregnancy; during pregnancy; and 0.5, 4, 9, and 19 months postpartum. Seventy-five age-matched controls, without pregnancy plans, were followed in parallel. Pregnancy and breastfeeding cause a reversible bone loss, which, initially, is most pronounced at trabecular sites but also involves cortical sites during prolonged breastfeeding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone health not correlated with Vitamin D level in multiple sclerosis – review</title><link>/posts/bone-health-not-correlated-with-vitamin-d-level-in-multiple-sclerosis-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-health-not-correlated-with-vitamin-d-level-in-multiple-sclerosis-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-health-in-multiple-sclerosis">Bone health in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Dec;22(12):2935-49. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-011-1644-8.">doi: 10.1007/s00198-011-1644-8.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 May 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gibson JC, Summers GD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Level 2, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Royal Derby Hospital, Uttoxeter Road, Derby, DE22 3NE, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:jeremy.gibson@nhs.net">jeremy.gibson@nhs.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People who are disabled with multiple sclerosis (MS) may be at increased risk of osteoporosis. This review discusses issues relevant to bone health in MS and makes practical recommendations regarding prevention and screening for osteoporosis and fracture risk in MS. A search of the literature up until 5 April 2011 was performed using key search terms, and articles pertinent to bone health in MS were analysed. Bone mineral density (BMD) is reduced at the lumbar spine, hip and total body in MS, with the degree of reduction being greatest at the hip. A strong relationship exists between the disability level, measured by the Expanded Disability Status Score, and BMD at the lumbar spine and femoral neck, particularly the latter. The rate of loss of BMD also correlates with the level of disability. Pulsed corticosteroids for acute episodes of MS, even with a high cumulative steroid dose, do not significantly affect BMD, but an effect on fracture risk is yet to be elucidated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D monotherapy for just 3 months did not improve bone turnover</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-monotherapy-for-just-3-months-did-not-improve-bone-turnover.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-monotherapy-for-just-3-months-did-not-improve-bone-turnover.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="bone-turnover-is-not-influenced-by-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-pubertal-healthy-black-and-white-children">Bone turnover is not influenced by serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D in pubertal healthy black and white children.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Bone. 2012 Oct;51(4):795-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bone.2012.06.014.">doi: 10.1016/j.bone.2012.06.014.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jun 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hill KM, Laing EM, Hausman DB, Acton A, Martin BR, McCabe GP, Weaver CM, Lewis RD, Peacock M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indiana University School of Medicine, Department of Medicine, Division of Endocrinology, 541 N. Clinical Drive, Indianapolis, IN 46202-5111, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25 (OH) D]&lt;/span> is common in healthy children particularly in blacks. However, serum 25 (OH) D concentrations for optimal bone turnover in children is unknown and few data exist that describe effects of increasing serum 25 (OH) D on bone turnover markers during puberty. The purpose of this study was to determine the relationships between serum 25 (OH) D and changes in serum 25 (OH) D and bone turnover in white and black pubertal adolescents. Bone turnover markers were measured in 318 healthy boys and girls from Georgia (34°N) and Indiana (40°N) who participated in a study of oral vitamin D(3) supplementation (0 to 4000 IU/d). Serum 25 (OH) D, osteocalcin, bone alkaline phosphatase, and urine N-telopeptide cross-links were measured at baseline and 12 weeks. Relationships among baseline 25 (OH) D and bone biomarkers, and between changes over 12 weeks were determined and tested for effects of race, sex, latitude, and baseline 25 (OH) D. Median 25 (OH) D was 27.6 ng/mL (n=318, range 10.1-46.0 ng/mL) at baseline and &lt;strong>34.5 ng/mL (n=302, range 9.7-95.1 ng/mL)&lt;/strong> at 12 weeks. Neither baseline nor change in 25 (OH) D over 12 weeks was associated with bone turnover. The lack of association was not affected by race, sex, latitude, or baseline serum 25 (OH) D. Serum 25 (OH) D in the range of 10-46 ng/mL appears to be sufficient for normal bone turnover in healthy black and white pubertal adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3D images of bone plus position statements on Osteo and vitamin D – 2012</title><link>/posts/3d-images-of-bone-plus-position-statements-on-osteo-and-vitamin-d-2012.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3d-images-of-bone-plus-position-statements-on-osteo-and-vitamin-d-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The following is a fraction of &lt;strong>The fragile beauty of bone architecture&lt;/strong> published in Medicographia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Louis-Georges STE-MARIE,MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Natalie DION PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre Hospitalier de l’Université de Montréal&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Université de Montréal – Montréal, CANADA&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The full issue of Medicographia, which includes the article: CONTROVERSIAL QUESTION, Is systematic supplementation with calcium/vitamin D necessary to treat postmenopausal osteoporosis? Is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/3d-bone.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h2 id="figure-2-structural-impairment-in-bone-disease">Figure 2. Structural impairment in bone disease.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Undecalcified bone biopsies (3D microcomputed tomography or 2D microscopic histology &lt;span>[Goldner’s stain]&lt;/span>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone fracture healing not a function of vitamin D level</title><link>/posts/bone-fracture-healing-not-a-function-of-vitamin-d-level.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-fracture-healing-not-a-function-of-vitamin-d-level.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-concentration-in-patients-with-normal-and-impaired-bone-union">Vitamin D concentration in patients with normal and impaired bone union.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pol Orthop Traumatol. 2013 Jan 2;78:1-3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boszczyk AM, Zakrzewski P, Pomianowski S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Musculoskeletal Trauma Surgery and Orthopaedics CMKP, Otwock, Poland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: The aim of the study was to compare vitamin D concentration in patients treated due to delayed bone union and non-union (pseudoarthrosis) and patients with normal fracture healing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Material/Methods: A retrospective case-control study was conducted. We enrolled 35 patients with inexplicable (standard and correct surgery, closed fracture, no comorbid metabolic diseases) fracture healing impairment, and 35 patients assigned by age and measurement season. Vitamin D (as 25OHD) concentration was measured in all patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D different relationship between whites and blacks for bone and plaque</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-different-relationship-between-whites-and-blacks-for-bone-and-plaque.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-different-relationship-between-whites-and-blacks-for-bone-and-plaque.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-race-and-genetics-on-vitamin-d-metabolism-bone-and-vascular-health">Effect of race and genetics on vitamin D metabolism, bone and vascular health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Nephrol. 2012 Jun 12;8(8):459-66. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneph.2012.112.">doi: 10.1038/nrneph.2012.112.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Freedman BI, Register TC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Section on Nephrology, Wake Forest School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, NC 27157-1053, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:bfreedma@wakehealth.edu">bfreedma@wakehealth.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pathophysiology of chronic kidney disease-mineral and bone disorder accounts for an inverse relationship between bone mineralization and vascular calcification in progressive nephropathy. Inverse associations between bone mineral density (BMD) and calcified atherosclerotic plaque are also observed in individuals of European and African ancestry without nephropathy, suggesting a mechanistic link between these processes that is independent of kidney disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Healthy bones need Ca, Silicon, Vitamins B, C, D, and K</title><link>/posts/healthy-bones-need-ca-silicon-vitamins-b-c-d-and-k.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/healthy-bones-need-ca-silicon-vitamins-b-c-d-and-k.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Update on nutrients involved in maintaining healthy bone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinol Nutr. 2012 Dec 27. pii: S1575-0922(12)00294-X. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.endonu.2012.09.006.">doi: 10.1016/j.endonu.2012.09.006.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Article in English, Spanish]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rondanelli M, Opizzi A, Perna S, Faliva MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Applied Health Sciences, Section of Human Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Medicine, University of Pavia, Endocrinology and Nutrition Unit, Azienda di Servizi alla Persona di Pavia, Pavia, Italy. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:mariangela.rondanelli@unipv.it">mariangela.rondanelli@unipv.it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis is a leading cause of morbidity and mortality in the elderly and influences quality of life, as well as life expectancy. Currently, there is a growing interest among the medical scientists in search of specific nutrients and/or bioactive compounds of natural origin for the prevention of disease and maintenance of bone health. Although calcium and vitamin D have been the primary focus of nutritional prevention of osteoporosis, a recent research has clarified the importance of several additional nutrients and food constituents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More than Calcium and Vitamin D can improve bones</title><link>/posts/more-than-calcium-and-vitamin-d-can-improve-bones.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-calcium-and-vitamin-d-can-improve-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Skeletal effects of nutrients and nutraceuticals, beyond calcium and vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Nov 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nieves JW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology, Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University, 722 West 168th Street, New York, NY, 10032, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:nievesj@helenhayeshosp.org">nievesj@helenhayeshosp.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a need to understand the role of nutrition, beyond calcium and vitamin D, in the treatment and prevention of osteoporosis in adults. Results regarding soy compounds on bone density and bone turnover are inconclusive perhaps due to differences in dose and composition or in study population characteristics. The skeletal benefit of black cohosh and red clover are unknown. Dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA) use may benefit elderly individuals with low serum dehydroepiandrosterone-sulfate levels, but even in this group, there are inconsistent benefits to bone density (BMD). Higher fruit and vegetable intakes may relate to higher BMD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Strong bones need both physical activity and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/strong-bones-need-both-physical-activity-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/strong-bones-need-both-physical-activity-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-status-and-physical-activity-interact-to-improve-bone-mass-in-adolescents">Vitamin D status and physical activity interact to improve bone mass in adolescents.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="the-helena-study">The HELENA Study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Aug;23(8):2227-37. Epub 2012 Jan 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Valtueña J, Gracia-Marco L, Vicente-Rodríguez G, González-Gross M, Huybrechts I, Rey-López JP, Mouratidou T, Sioen I, Mesana MI, Martínez AE, Widhalm K, Moreno LA; HELENA Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Collaborators (230)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Health and Human Performance, Faculty of Physical Activity and Sport Sciences-INEF, Technical University of Madrid, C/ Martín Fierro 7, Madrid, Spain. &lt;a href="mailto:jara.valtuena@upm.es">jara.valtuena@upm.es&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3, not D2 helps childhood bone development</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-not-d2-helps-childhood-bone-development.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-not-d2-helps-childhood-bone-development.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-levels-are-positively-related-to-subsequent-cortical-bone-development-in-childhood">25-Hydroxyvitamin-D3 levels are positively related to subsequent cortical bone development in childhood:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="findings-from-a-large-prospective-cohort-study">findings from a large prospective cohort study.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Aug;23(8):2117-28. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-011-1813-9.">doi: 10.1007/s00198-011-1813-9.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Nov 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sayers A, Fraser WD, Lawlor DA, Tobias JH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Musculoskeletal Research Unit, School of Clinical Sciences, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:adrian.sayers@bristol.ac.uk">adrian.sayers@bristol.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In exploring relationships between vitamin D status in childhood and cortical bone, little relationship was observed with plasma concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin-D(2) &lt;span>[25(OH)D(2)]&lt;/span>, whereas 25-hydroxyvitamin-D(3) &lt;span>[25(OH)D(3)]&lt;/span> was positively related to cortical bone mineral content (BMC(C)) and cortical thickness, suggesting D(3) exerts a beneficial effect on cortical bone development in contrast to D(2).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sickle cell and low vitamin D – 3 presentations</title><link>/posts/sickle-cell-and-low-vitamin-d-3-presentations.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sickle-cell-and-low-vitamin-d-3-presentations.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>All presented at 2012 American Society of Hematology December 8-11, 2012 Atlanta, GA&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-zinc-deficiency-associated-with-increased-pain-episodes-in-children-with-sickle-cell-disease-poster-abstract-3237">Vitamin D and Zinc Deficiency Associated with Increased Pain Episodes in Children with Sickle Cell Disease: poster, Abstract 3237&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#relationship-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-bone-fragility-in-sickle-cell-disease">Relationship Between vitamin D Deficiency and Bone Fragility in Sickle Cell Disease:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-deficiency-cd40l-and-vegf-in-a-young-population-with-sickle-cell-disease-abstract-4768">Vitamin Deficiency, CD40L and VEGF in a Young Population with Sickle Cell Disease, Abstract 4768&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-zinc-deficiency-associated-with-increased-pain-episodes-in-children-with-sickle-cell-disease-poster-abstract-3237">Vitamin D and Zinc Deficiency Associated with Increased Pain Episodes in Children with Sickle Cell Disease: poster, Abstract 3237&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Abi Vijenthira, BHSc*,1, Christine G Chretien, BSCN*,2, Sydney Harris-Janz, RD*,2 and Robert J Klaassen, MD2&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Relevance of Vitamin D in Bone and Muscle Health of Cancer Patients</title><link>/posts/relevance-of-vitamin-d-in-bone-and-muscle-health-of-cancer-patients.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/relevance-of-vitamin-d-in-bone-and-muscle-health-of-cancer-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.58-64 (7)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author: Heike Bischoff-Ferrari&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer patients with advanced disease frequently feel weak and fatigued, and have an increased risk of fracture. At the same time several reports describe the high prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in these patients. This review will summarize the impact of vitamin D deficiency on muscle weakness and fracture risk. While larger clinical trials of vitamin D supplementation are lacking in cancer patients, the evidence from clinical trials among older adults of the general population support a significant benefit of vitamin D on muscle strength, and fall and fracture reduction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone - Health</title><link>/posts/bone-health.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-health.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#calcium-and-bone-health-supplements-review---including-vit-d-vit-k-mg-and-boron">Calcium and Bone Health Supplements Review - Including Vit D, Vit K, Mg and Boron&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="calcium-and-bone-health-supplements-review---including-vit-d-vit-k-mg-and-boron">Calcium and Bone Health Supplements Review - Including Vit D, Vit K, Mg and Boron&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.consumerlab.com/reviews/bone-supplements-calcium-with-vitamin-d-k-magnesium/calcium/?j=3004340&amp;amp;sfmc_sub=4618332&amp;amp;l=529_HTML&amp;amp;u=31627246&amp;amp;mid=7276525&amp;amp;jb=14001&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=exacttarget&amp;amp;utm_campaign=newsletter&amp;amp;utm_term=&amp;amp;utm_content=vit_d_omega_member_de_send">ConsumerLab&lt;/a> May 2022&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/bone-supplements-cl.jpg" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;p>You can access if you elect to take a one week free trial&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/excellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlab" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Excellent reviews of supplements at ConsumerLab">Excellent reviews of supplements at ConsumerLab&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Previous Review: &lt;a href="/posts/supplement-reviews-by-consumerlab-vitamin-d-magnesium-vitamin-k-calcium-boron" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Supplement reviews by ConsumerLab – Vitamin D, Magnesium, Vitamin K, Calcium , Boron – Nov 2019">Supplement reviews by ConsumerLab – Vitamin D, Magnesium, Vitamin K, Calcium , Boron – Nov 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vertebral fracture 3X more likely with aortic calcification – Vitamins D3 and K2</title><link>/posts/vertebral-fracture-3x-more-likely-with-aortic-calcification-vitamins-d3-and-k2.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vertebral-fracture-3x-more-likely-with-aortic-calcification-vitamins-d3-and-k2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="aortic-calcification-and-bone-metabolism">Aortic Calcification and Bone Metabolism:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="the-relationship-between-aortic-calcification-bmd-vertebral-fracture-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-osteocalcin">The Relationship between Aortic Calcification, BMD, Vertebral Fracture, 25-Hydroxyvitamin D, and Osteocalcin.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Calcif Tissue Int. 2012 Sep 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim KJ, Kim KM, Park KH, Choi HS, Rhee Y, Lee YH, Cha BS, Kim MJ, Oh SM, Brown JK, Lim SK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Department of Internal Medicine, Yonsei University College of Medicine, 134 Shinchon-dong, Seodaemun-gu, Seoul, 120-752, South Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study was to investigate the relationship between aortic calcification (AC) and low bone mineral density (BMD), 25(OH)D, C-terminal telopeptide (CTx), and osteocalcin levels in Asian women. We also tried to find the association between AC and the risk of vertebral fracture. We included 769 patients in this study. All patients underwent QCT. Aortic calcium score (ACS) was quantified by the Agatston scoring method. Spinal fracture was defined by lumbar spine radiography.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increasing bone mineral density increases breast cancer by at least 2X</title><link>/posts/increasing-bone-mineral-density-increases-breast-cancer-by-at-least-2x.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increasing-bone-mineral-density-increases-breast-cancer-by-at-least-2x.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="osteoporosis-myth-the-dangers-of-high-bone-mineral-densityhttpwwwgreenmedinfocomblogosteoporosis-myth-dangers-high-bone-mineral-densityutm_sourcewwwgreenmedinfocomutm_campaignb739c633e3-greenmedinfoutm_mediumemail-green-med-info">&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/osteoporosis-myth-dangers-high-bone-mineral-density?utm_source=www.GreenMedInfo.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=b739c633e3-Greenmedinfo&amp;amp;utm_medium=email">Osteoporosis Myth: The Dangers of High Bone Mineral Density&lt;/a> Green Med Info&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="the-following-was-clipped-from-the-above-item">The following was clipped from the above item&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of the most important facts about bone mineral density, conspicuously absent from discussion, is that having higher-than-normal bone density in middle-aged and older women actually &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">INCREASES their risk of breast cancer by 200-300%&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> , and this is according to research published in some of the world&amp;rsquo;s most well-respected and authoritative journals, e.g. Lancet, JAMA, NCI. (see citations below).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Forearm fracture 3.5X more often in black children with low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/forearm-fracture-35x-more-often-in-black-children-with-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/forearm-fracture-35x-more-often-in-black-children-with-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="bone-mineral-density-and-vitamin-d-status-among-african-american-children-with-forearm-fractures">Bone mineral density and vitamin d status among african american children with forearm fractures.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatrics. 2012 Sep;130(3):e553-60. Epub 2012 Aug 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ryan LM, Teach SJ, Singer SA, Wood R, Freishtat R, Wright JL, McCarter R, Tosi L, Chamberlain JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Children&amp;rsquo;s National Medical Center, Division of Emergency Medicine, 111 Michigan Ave NW, Washington, DC 20010. &lt;a href="mailto:lryan@childrensnational.org">lryan@childrensnational.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine whether African American children with forearm fractures have decreased bone mineral density and an increased prevalence of vitamin D deficiency (serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level ?20 ng/mL) compared with fracture-free control patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Major depression associated with low vitamin D and low bone density</title><link>/posts/major-depression-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/major-depression-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="do-premenopausal-women-with-major-depression-have-low-bone-mineral-density-a-36-month-prospective-study">Do Premenopausal Women with Major Depression Have Low Bone Mineral Density? A 36-Month Prospective Study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(7):e40894. Epub 2012 Jul 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cizza G &lt;a href="mailto:cizzag@intra.niddk.nih.gov">cizzag@intra.niddk.nih.gov&lt;/a>, Mistry S, Nguyen VT, Eskandari F, Martinez P, Torvik S, Reynolds JC, Gold PW, Sinai N, Csako G; for the POWER Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Section on Neuroendocrinology of Obesity, National Institutes of Diabetes and Digestive Kidney Diseases (NIDDK), National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland, United States of America.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone health markers generally not improved by 550 IU of vitamin D after birth</title><link>/posts/bone-health-markers-generally-not-improved-by-550-iu-of-vitamin-d-after-birth.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-health-markers-generally-not-improved-by-550-iu-of-vitamin-d-after-birth.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="impact-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-markers-of-bone-mineral-metabolism-in-term-infants">Impact of vitamin D supplementation on markers of bone mineral metabolism in term infants.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Bone. 2012 Jul 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Czech-Kowalska J, Pludowski P, Dobrzanska A, Kryskiewicz E, Karczmarewicz E, Gruszfeld D, Pleskaczynska A, Golkowska M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neonatology and Neonatal Intensive Care, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Health Institute, 04-730 Warsaw, Al. Dzieci Polskich 20, Poland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) may influence bone turnover. We compared the dynamics of bone markers in 30 infants on vitamin D supplementation (?550IU/d) with different degrees of hypovitaminosis D (25OHD &amp;lt;11ng/ml - deficiency vs. ?11&amp;lt;20ng/ml - insufficiency). Baseline and follow-up (after 10 weeks), 25OHD, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)(2)D), alkaline phosphatase (ALP), PTH, osteocalcin (OC), N-terminal propeptide of type I procollagen (PINP), C-terminal telopeptide of type I collagen (CTX), amino-terminal propeptide of C-type natriuretic peptide (NT-proCNP) were measured. None of the newborns had craniotabes, hypocalcaemia or hyperparathyroidism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fractures reduced 30 percent with 800 IU of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-pooled-analysis-of-vitamin-d-dose-requirements-for-fracture-prevention">A pooled analysis of vitamin D dose requirements for fracture prevention.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med. 2012 Jul 5;367(1):40-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Willett WC, Orav EJ, Lips P, Meunier PJ, Lyons RA, Flicker L, Wark J, Jackson RD, Cauley JA, Meyer HE, Pfeifer M, Sanders KM, Stähelin HB, Theiler R, Dawson-Hughes B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center on Aging and Mobility, University of Zurich and Waid City Hospital, Zurich, Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The results of meta-analyses examining the relationship between vitamin D supplementation and fracture reduction have been inconsistent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Female Athlete health problems may be due to lack of vitamin D and Iron</title><link>/posts/female-athlete-health-problems-may-be-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d-and-iron.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/female-athlete-health-problems-may-be-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d-and-iron.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>