<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Overview for Doctors on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/overview-for-doctors.html</link><description>Recent content in Overview for Doctors on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/overview-for-doctors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency in adolescents – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-in-adolescents-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-in-adolescents-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-adolescents">Vitamin D deficiency in adolescents.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Indian J Endocrinol Metab. 2014 Nov;18(Suppl 1):S9-S16. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4103/2230-8210.145043.">doi: 10.4103/2230-8210.145043.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soliman AT1, De Sanctis V2, Elalaily R3, Bedair S4, Kassem I5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Pediatrics, University of Alexandria, Alexandria, Egypt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Pediatric and Adolescent Outpatients Clinic, Quisisana Hospital, Ferrara, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Primary Health Care, AbuNakhla Hospital, Doha, Qatar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4Department of Radiology, AlKhor Hospital, Hamad Medical Center, Doha, Qatar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>5Department of Faciomaxillay Surgery, University of Alexandria, Alexandria, Egypt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The prevalence of severe vitamin D deficiency (VDD) in adolescents is variable but considerably high in many countries, especially in Middle-east and Southeast Asia. Different factors attribute to this deficiency including lack of sunlight exposure due to cultural dress codes and veiling or due to pigmented skin, and less time spent outdoors, because of hot weather, and lower vitamin D intake. A potent adaptation process significantly modifies the clinical presentation and therefore clinical presentations may be subtle and go unnoticed, thus making true prevalence studies difficult. Adolescents with severe VDD may present with vague manifestations including pain in weight-bearing joints, back, thighs and/or calves, difficulty in walking and/or climbing stairs, or running and muscle cramps. Adaptation includes increased parathormone (PTH) and deceased insulin-like growth factor-I (IGF-I) secretion. PTH enhances the tubular reabsorption of Ca and stimulates the kidneys to produce 1, 25-(OH) 2D3 that increases intestinal calcium absorption and dissolves the mineralized collagen matrix in bone, causing osteopenia and osteoporosis to provide enough Ca to prevent hypocalcaemia. Decreased insulin like growth factor-I (IGF-I) delays bone growth to economize calcium consumption. Radiological changes are not uncommon and include osteoporosis/osteopenia affecting long bones as well as vertebrae and ribs, bone cysts, decalcification of the metaphysis of the long bones and pseudo fractures. In severe cases pathological fractures and deformities may occur. Vitamin D treatment of adolescents with VDD differs considerably in different studies and proved to be effective in treating all clinical, biochemical, and radiological manifestations. Different treatment regiments for VDD have been discussed and presented in this mini-review for practical use. Adequate vitamin D replacement after treating VDD, improving calcium intake (milk and dairy products), encouraging adequate exposure to the sun and possible enrichment of the stable food with vitamin D in areas with high prevalence of VDD are important measures to prevent the harmful consequences of VDD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Continuing Medical Education (CME) for Vitamin D includes genes and questions</title><link>/posts/continuing-medical-education-cme-for-vitamin-d-includes-genes-and-questions.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/continuing-medical-education-cme-for-vitamin-d-includes-genes-and-questions.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-ds-role-in-health--deterministic-or-indeterminate---2014">Vitamin D’s Role in Health — Deterministic or Indeterminate? - 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#10-multiple-choice-questions">10 multiple choice questions&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#1-vitamin-d-is-considered-to-be-which-of-the-following">1. Vitamin D is considered to be which of the following?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2-which-of-the-following-genetic-mutations-can-result-in-normal-levels-of">2. Which of the following genetic mutations can result in normal levels of&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#3-vitamin-d-testing-specifically-is-recommended-for-which-of-the-following-groups">3. Vitamin D testing specifically is recommended for which of the following groups?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#4-which-of-the-following-is-the-active-form-of-vitamin-d-in-the-body">4. Which of the following is the active form of vitamin D in the body?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#5-beyond-bone-health-vitamin-d-seems-to-help-maintain-health-in-which-of-the-following-ways">5. Beyond bone health, vitamin D seems to help maintain health in which of the following ways?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#6-which-of-the-following-foods-has-the-highest-content-of-vitamin-d-per-serving">6. Which of the following foods has the highest content of vitamin D per serving?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#7-the-sun-is-too-low-during-the-winter-months-to-produce-any-vitamin-d">7. The sun is too low during the winter months to produce any vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#8-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-bone-health-because-it-does-which-of-the-following">8. Vitamin D is associated with bone health because it does which of the following?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#9-the-institute-of-medicine-identifies-vitamin-d-deficiency">9. The Institute of Medicine identifies vitamin D deficiency&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#10-each-serving-of-foods-fortified-with-vitamin-d-contain-approximately-which-of-the-following-amounts">10. Each serving of foods fortified with vitamin D contain approximately which of the following amounts?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-ds-role-in-health--deterministic-or-indeterminate---2014">Vitamin D’s Role in Health — Deterministic or Indeterminate? - 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.todaysdietitian.com/newarchives/070114p48.shtml">URL&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency – Physicians Assistants Continued Medical Education</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-physicians-assistants-continued-medical-education.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-physicians-assistants-continued-medical-education.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Health outcomes of vitamin D. Parts I (VDR) and II – 2014</title><link>/posts/health-outcomes-of-vitamin-d-parts-i-vdr-and-ii-2014.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/health-outcomes-of-vitamin-d-parts-i-vdr-and-ii-2014.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="health-outcomes-of-vitamin-d-part-i-characteristics-and-classic-role">Health outcomes of vitamin D. Part I. characteristics and classic role&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Rocz Panstw Zakl Hig. 2014;65(3):179-84.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wranicz J1, Szostak-Węgierek D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Julia Wranicz, Chair of Dietetics, Department of Nutritional Physiology, Faculty of Human Nutrition and Consumer Sciences, Warsaw University of Life Sciences – SGGW, Nowoursynowska street 159c, 02-776 Warsaw, Poland&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="table-1-cells-tissues-and-organs-with-the-vitamin-d3-receptor-vdr">Table 1. Cells, tissues and organs with the vitamin D3 receptor (VDR)&lt;/h4>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Adipose tissue&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Skin tissue&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Placenta&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Osseous tissue&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Hair follicle&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Uterus&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Cartilaginous tissue&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Kidney&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Ovary&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Smooth muscles&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Fetal liver&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Testicle&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Cardiac muscle&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Lungs&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Epididymis&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Fetal muscle tissue&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Brain&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Parotid gland&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Adrenal gland&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Parathyroid gland&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Retina&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Cancer cells&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Pituitary gland&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Bone marrow&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Stomach&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Thymus gland&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Pancreatic beta-cells&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Small intestine&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Thyroid gland&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Osteoblasts&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Large intestine&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Mammary gland&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Lymphocytes B and T&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a compound responsible for maintaining mineral homeostasis. It protects against calcium and phosphate deficiency through the effects on the intestine, kidney, parathyroid gland and bone. All mechanisms that help maintain mineral homeostasis of the body are regulated by the vitamin D hormonal form - calcitriol. Synthesis of vitamin D starts in the skin as a non-enzymatic process, which begins during exposure to sunlight, when the absorption of ultraviolet B (UVB) radiation results in convertion of 7-dehydrocholesterol, a metabolite of cholesterol that is stored in the skin, to precholecalciferol (previtamin-D₃) that is immediately converted into cholecalciferol (vitamin D₃). After the skin synthesis cholecalciferol is transported to the liver where it undergoes hydroxylation, what results in formation of calcidiol (25(OH)D₃). The second metabolic process takes place in the kidney, where calcidiol undergoes hydroxylation at the C-1 position to the hormonal, the most active metabolite - 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (calcitriol).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Survey of Vitamin D Practice in Primary Care (costly)</title><link>/posts/survey-of-vitamin-d-practice-in-primary-care-costly.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/survey-of-vitamin-d-practice-in-primary-care-costly.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="emerging-practice-concerning-vitamin-d-in-primary-care">Emerging Practice Concerning Vitamin D in Primary Care.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://qhr.sagepub.com/content/early/2014/10/07/1049732314554100.long%20">Qual Health Res. 2014 Oct 7. &lt;/a>pii: 1049732314554100. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span> &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">$30&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epling JW1, Mader EM2, Roseamelia CA2, Morley CP2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The establishment of practice patterns concerning the diagnosis and management of hypovitaminosis D seems to be heterogeneous among primary care physicians.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We conducted a qualitative study to explore the emerging practices among primary care providers regarding screening and treatment for hypovitaminosis D, as well as factors that influence practice patterns.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uptodate – Medical professional information – on Vitamin D, etc.</title><link>/posts/uptodate-medical-professional-information-on-vitamin-d-etc.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uptodate-medical-professional-information-on-vitamin-d-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>UpToDate® is an evidence-based, physician-authored clinical decision support resource which clinicians trust to make the right point-of-care decisions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>More than 5,700 world-renowned physician authors, editors and peer reviewers use a rigorous editorial process to synthesize the most recent medical information into trusted, evidence-based recommendations that are proven to improve patient care and quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>More than 850,000 clinicians in 164 countries and almost 90% of academic medical centers in the United States rely on UpToDate to provide the best care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Quantifying the vitamin D economy in the body - Heaney</title><link>/posts/quantifying-the-vitamin-d-economy-in-the-body-heaney.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/quantifying-the-vitamin-d-economy-in-the-body-heaney.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;p>Quantifying the vitamin D economy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrition Reviews VR Vol. 73(1):51–67, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/nutrit/nuu004">doi: 10.1093/nutrit/nuu004&lt;/a> Special Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robert P. Heaney and Laura A.G. Armas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R.P. Heaney is with Creighton University, Omaha, Nebraska, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:rpheaney@creighton.edu">rpheaney@creighton.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>L.A.G. Armas is with the Department of Medicine, Creighton University, Omaha, Nebraska, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/quantifying-the-vitamin-d-economy.pdf">Download the PDF with all figures from VitaminDWiki.&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The following is virtually all of the text, most of the equations, and a few of the figures&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Special issue on Vitamin D in Frontiers in Physiology – Summer 2014</title><link>/posts/special-issue-on-vitamin-d-in-frontiers-in-physiology-summer-2014.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/special-issue-on-vitamin-d-in-frontiers-in-physiology-summer-2014.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="references-many-of-which-are-in-vitamindwiki-followed-by-editorial">References (many of which are in VitaminDWiki), followed by Editorial&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bendik, I., Friedel, A., Roos, F.F., Weber, P., and Eggersdorfer, M. (2014).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>in VitaminDWiki &lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-is-critical-and-essential-but-only-1-in-10-people-have-more-than-30-ng">Vitamin D is critical and essential, but only 1 in 10 people have more than 30 ng – July 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Vitamin D: a critical and essential micronutrient for human health. Front Physiol 5,	248.	doi:10.3389/fphys.2014.00248.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Campbell, M.J. (2014). &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Vitamin D and the RNA transcriptome: more than mRNA regulation. Front Physiol 5, 181. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2014.00181.">doi: 10.3389/fphys.2014.00181.&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding vitamin D deficiency - Editorial in Age and Ageing</title><link>/posts/understanding-vitamin-d-deficiency-editorial-in-age-and-ageing.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/understanding-vitamin-d-deficiency-editorial-in-age-and-ageing.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Opinder Sahota*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Healthcare of Older People, QMC, Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust, Nottingham NG7 2UH, UK Tel: (+44) 1159249924; Fax (+44) 1159709947;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Email: &lt;a href="mailto:opinder.sahota@nuh.nhs.uk">opinder.sahota@nuh.nhs.uk&lt;/a> *To whom correspondence should be addressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Age and Ageing Advance Access published July 28, 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© The Author 2014. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the British Geriatrics Society. This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution Non-CommercialLicense (&lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)&lt;/a>, which permits non-commercial re-use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the originalwork is properly cited.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes and Vitamin D - Malacards</title><link>/posts/genes-and-vitamin-d-malacards.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-and-vitamin-d-malacards.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="malacards---vitamin-dhttpwwwmalacardsorgsearchresults22vitamin20d22-describes-each-disease-and-shows-genes-identified-with-it-and-the-top-20-disease-related-to-those-genes">&lt;a href="http://www.malacards.org/search/results/%22vitamin%20d%22">Malacards - Vitamin D&lt;/a> Describes each disease and shows genes identified with it and the top 20 disease related to those genes&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="multiple-sclerosis-ms-maladyhttpwwwmalacardsorgcardmultiple_sclerosissearch22vitamind22-malacards-has-the-following-graphic">&lt;a href="http://www.malacards.org/card/multiple_sclerosis?search=%22vitamin+d%22">Multiple Sclerosis (MS) malady&lt;/a> Malacards has the following graphic&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Top 20 diseases related by genes to MS ( many of which are associated with low vitamin D)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ms-top-20-gene-related-diseases.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="rickets-maladyhttpwwwmalacardsorgcardricketssearch22vitamind22-malacards---has-the-following-chart">&lt;a href="http://www.malacards.org/card/rickets?search=%22vitamin+d%22">Rickets malady&lt;/a> Malacards - has the following chart&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Top 20 diseases related to Rickets by genes (many of which are associated with low vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A doctor becomes aware of vitamin D deficiency in Brazil, a sunny country</title><link>/posts/a-doctor-becomes-aware-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-brazil-a-sunny-country.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-doctor-becomes-aware-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-brazil-a-sunny-country.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="shed-some-sunlight-on-vitamin-d-deficiency">Shed some (sun)light on vitamin D deficiency&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Revista Brasileira de Hematologia e Hemoterapia, Print version ISSN 1516-8484&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rev. Bras. Hematol. Hemoter. vol.36 no.3 São José do Rio Preto May/June 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adriana Seber *, Hospital Samaritano, São Paulo, SP, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We do not read an article that can make us change practice very often.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Vitamin D deficiency in children and adolescents submitted to hematopoietic stem cell transplantation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>by Campos DJ from the Curitiba Pediatric Transplantation group&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nurses continuing education – Vitamin D Overview</title><link>/posts/nurses-continuing-education-vitamin-d-overview.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nurses-continuing-education-vitamin-d-overview.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-overviewhttpnursece4lesscomcoursedescriptionaspxtestnumbern039r20">&lt;a href="http://nursece4less.com/CourseDescription.aspx?testNumber=N039R%20">Vitamin D Overview&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Nursece4less&lt;/strong> Course author: Dana Bartlett, RN, MA, MSN&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Contact Hours: 3.0 , Price: $6.00 (had been $8.97)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price includes all materials and certificate of completion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Target audience:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Advanced Practice Registered Nurses, Registered Nurses,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Licensed Practical Nurses, and Medical Assistants&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Difficulty level: Intermediate, Format: Homestudy, This course expires on: 4/30/2017&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="course-description">Course Description&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nursing knowledge of the physiological functions of vitamin D and the systemic effects of vitamin D deficiency will help them educate patients on the prevention and treatment of vitamin D deficiency. Patients treated for vitamin D deficiency should be aware of the signs of acute and chronic vitamin D intoxication. This course will help nurses identify signs and symptoms of vitamin D deficiency and its treatment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D update – 40-60 ng ideal, 50K biweekly maintenance</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-update-40-60-ng-ideal-50k-biweekly-maintenance.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-update-40-60-ng-ideal-50k-biweekly-maintenance.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-update-2013-from-rickets-prophylaxis-to-general-preventive-healthcare">Vitamin D: Update 2013 From rickets prophylaxis to general preventive healthcare&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#from-sunshine-vitamin-to-sunshine-hormone">From Sunshine Vitamin to Sunshine Hormone&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-barometer-of-vitamin-d-health-25-hydroxyvitamin-d">The Barometer of Vitamin D Health: 25-hydroxyvitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#health-risk-vitamin-d-deficiency">Health Risk: Vitamin D Deficiency&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bone-muscle-metabolism-and-dental-health-risk-of-fractures-falling-and-caries">Bone, Muscle Metabolism, and Dental Health: Risk of Fractures, Falling and Caries&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ecological-association-studies">Ecological Association Studies&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#gene-expression-link-between-vitamin-d-and-prevention">Gene Expression: Link Between Vitamin D and Prevention&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cardiovascular-system-hypertension-and-cardiac-insufficiency">Cardiovascular System: Hypertension and Cardiac Insufficiency&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#diabetology">Diabetology&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#type-1-diabetes">Type 1 diabetes.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#type-2-diabetes-and-metabolic-syndrome">Type 2 diabetes and metabolic syndrome.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#respiratory-tract-diseases-rti">Respiratory tract diseases (RTI)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#atopic-dermatitis-psoriasis-other-dermatides">Atopic dermatitis, psoriasis other dermatides.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#autoimmune-disease-rheumatoid-arthritis-ibd-and-multiple-sclerosis">Autoimmune disease: rheumatoid arthritis, IBD and multiple sclerosis.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#degenerative-brain-disease-and-traumatic-injury">Degenerative Brain Disease and Traumatic Injury&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cancers">Cancers&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#medical-drugs-and-vitamin-d">Medical Drugs and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#treatment-strategies">Treatment Strategies&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#concluding-remarks">Concluding Remarks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references-in-pdf">References in PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-update-2013-from-rickets-prophylaxis-to-general-preventive-healthcare">Vitamin D: Update 2013 From rickets prophylaxis to general preventive healthcare&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dermato-Endocrinology 5:3, e2; September-December 2013; © 2013 Landes Bioscience&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Great Vitamin D webinar for doctors - Plotnikoff</title><link>/posts/great-vitamin-d-webinar-for-doctors-plotnikoff.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/great-vitamin-d-webinar-for-doctors-plotnikoff.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="update---new-webinar-vitamin-d-webinar---plotnikoff---feb-29-2016postsvitamin-d-webinar-plotnikoff">Update - new webinar &lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-webinar-plotnikoff">Vitamin D Webinar - Plotnikoff - Feb 29 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h3 id="the-shocking-truth-about-vitamin-d-status">The Shocking Truth About Vitamin D Status&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Some notes of excellent 90 minute Vitamin D webinar for doctors with CME credit&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Webinar by Dr. Greg Plotnikoff, &lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-webinars-by-diasorin-2013-2014">Vitamin D Webinars by DiaSorin 2013-2014&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a Nature Deficient Disorder&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Safe sunning, no burning&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rickets making a comeback – Plotnikoff asked viewer to guess which year&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>IoM in 2010 lowered 30ng ==&amp;gt; 20 ng, but tripled recommend amount for elderly&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>372 types of vitamin D prescriptions in France, 200,000 IU was the most popular</title><link>/posts/372-types-of-vitamin-d-prescriptions-in-france-200000-iu-was-the-most-popular.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/372-types-of-vitamin-d-prescriptions-in-france-200000-iu-was-the-most-popular.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-a-healthy-middle-aged-population-actual-practices-based-on-data-from-a-french-comprehensive-regional-health-care-database">Vitamin D supplementation in a healthy, middle-aged population: actual practices based on data from a French comprehensive regional health-care database&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Clinical Nutrition , (2 October 2013) | doi:10.1038/ejcn.2013.182&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P Caillet, J C Souberbielle, S B Jaglal, A Reymondier, E Van Ganse, R Chapurlat and A M Schott&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND/OBJECTIVES: The debate surrounding recommendations for vitamin D supplementation in middle-aged patients (that is, 20–60 years of age) with low serum concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) is growing. Our aim was to describe practices regarding vitamin D supplementation in this age group, which are basically unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Grassroots Health participants Vitamin D vs age, intake, and resulting level</title><link>/posts/grassroots-health-participants-vitamin-d-vs-age-intake-and-resulting-level.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/grassroots-health-participants-vitamin-d-vs-age-intake-and-resulting-level.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="grassroots-health-d-action-projecthttpwwwgrassrootshealthnetindexphpdaction">&lt;a href="http://www.grassrootshealth.net/index.php/daction">Grassroots Health D-Action Project&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="note-the-d-action-participants-pay-a-lot-to-keep-their-vitamin-d-levels-40-50-ng">Note: the D-action participants pay a lot to keep their vitamin D levels 40-50 ng&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>They are tested 4X per year (@ $70/test), so they pay about&lt;span style="color:#F00;">$300/year.&lt;/span> ($ test + $ vitamin d)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note: Henry Lahore, admin of VitaminDWiki, pays&lt;a href="/posts/47" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 266">$47&lt;/a> for a test once every 18 months, for a total annual cost of $47*2/3 + $17(vitamin D) = &lt;span style="color:#F00;">$50/year&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30 to 50 ng of vitamin D is optimal – Central Europe consensus</title><link>/posts/30-to-50-ng-of-vitamin-d-is-optimal-central-europe-consensus.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/30-to-50-ng-of-vitamin-d-is-optimal-central-europe-consensus.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Short url =&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="http://is.gd/PolandVitD">http://is.gd/PolandVitD&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half of elderly care physicians in the Netherlands do not follow vitamin D guidelines – 2013</title><link>/posts/half-of-elderly-care-physicians-in-the-netherlands-do-not-follow-vitamin-d-guidelines-2013.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-of-elderly-care-physicians-in-the-netherlands-do-not-follow-vitamin-d-guidelines-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="spanvitamin-d-supplementation-in-the-elderly-guidelines-and-practicespan">&lt;span>[Vitamin D supplementation in the elderly: guidelines and practice]&lt;/span>.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[Article in Dutch]&lt;/span> Ned Tijdschr Geneeskd. 2013;157(33):A5779.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chel VG, Elders PJ, Tuijp ML, van den Berg HH, van Drongelen KI, Siedenburg RC, Ooms ME, Lips PT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Verpleeg-, behandel- en huntingtoncentrum Topaz Overduin, Katwijk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: In 2008, the Health Council of the Netherlands published an advice on vitamin D supplementation for the elderly. Nevertheless, suspicion arose at the Ministry of Health, Welfare and Sport and the Netherlands Nutrition Centre that vitamin D supplementation in the elderly is still insufficient. We aimed to determine the extent to which general practitioners and elderly care physicians actually followed the advice of the Health Council.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D survey of general practitioners in New Zealand</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-survey-of-general-practitioners-in-new-zealand.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-survey-of-general-practitioners-in-new-zealand.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-and-deficiency-new-zealand-general-practitioners-perceptions-of-risk-factors-and-clinical-management">Vitamin D insufficiency and deficiency: New Zealand general practitioners&amp;rsquo; perceptions of risk factors and clinical management.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>N Z Med J. 2013 Jun 14;126(1376):49-60.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reeder AI, Jopson JA, Gray AR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Preventive and Social Medicine, Dunedin School of Medicine, PO Box 913, Dunedin, New Zealand. &lt;a href="mailto:tony.reeder@otago.ac.nz">tony.reeder@otago.ac.nz&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIMS: To report perceptions regarding vitamin D sources; risk factors, prevention and management of vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency; supplement prescribing practices; patients&amp;rsquo; enquiries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: A NSW survey instrument was adapted and pre-tested for NZ conditions. Royal NZ College of General Practitioners online weekly newsletter recipients were provided an electronic survey link. The Medical Council emailed an invitation and online survey link to non-respondents. Hard copy questionnaires were posted to remaining non-respondents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview of vitamin D issues: IoM, Endocrine Society etc.</title><link>/posts/overview-of-vitamin-d-issues-iom-endocrine-society-etc.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-of-vitamin-d-issues-iom-endocrine-society-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Value and limitations of assessing vitamin D nutritional status and advised levels of vitamin D supplementations&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eur J Endocrinol July 11, 2013 EJE-13-0435&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elisabetta Romagnoli, Jessica Pepe, Sara Piemonte, Cristiana Cipriani, Salvatore Minisola &lt;a href="mailto:salvatore.minisola@fastwebnet.it">salvatore.minisola@fastwebnet.it&lt;/a> ; &lt;a href="mailto:salvatore.minisola@uniroma1.it">salvatore.minisola@uniroma1.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine and Medical Disciplines, University of Rome &amp;ldquo;Sapienza&amp;rdquo;, Rome, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#abstract">Abstract&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#figure-1">Figure 1&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#figure-2">Figure 2&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#measurement-of-25ohd">Measurement of 25(OH)D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-binding-protein">Vitamin D binding protein&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-vitamin-d-and-the-search-for-a-threshold">The vitamin D and the search for a threshold&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-vitamin-d-and-the-supplementation-general-considerations">The vitamin D and the supplementation: general considerations&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-vitamin-d-and-the-supplementation-the-discussion">The vitamin D and the supplementation: the discussion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#achieving-and-maintaining-vitamin-d-sufficiency">Achieving and maintaining vitamin D sufficiency&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-which-type">Vitamin D supplementation: which type?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-intramuscular-or-oral-route-of-administration">Vitamin D supplementation: intramuscular or oral route of administration?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-and-the-safety">Vitamin D supplementation and the safety&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-and-real-world">Vitamin D supplementation and real world&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#conclusions-and-perspectives">Conclusions and perspectives&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references-are-in-pdf">References are in PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The growing attention to the role of vitamin D in skeletal and extra-skeletal diseases over the last decade, induced an increased demand for Vitamin D determination as well as a dramatic rise of sales of vitamin D supplement. However, several critical points in this field remain to be clarified. We lack a clear consensus about the definition of vitamin D deficiency, insufficiency and sufficiency. The identification of different thresholds defining vitamin D status have relevant implications in clinical practice. In fact, the worldwide prevalence of low vitamin D status is highly varying according to the level of 25(OH)D utilized to define sufficiency. Therefore, the assessment of 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels may have a critical role, but a number of different technical problems associated with its determination may interfere in interpreting the results. The hydrophobic nature of the vitamin D and the tight binding to its carrier (vitamin D binding protein, DBP), the different forms circulating in blood and the issue of standardisation are among the most important factors influencing the measurement of this metabolite. Another controversial point relies on the conflicting guidance on prevention and treatment of vitamin D deficiency endorsed by different medical and scientific communities. In particular, uncertainty exists about how to replete vitamin D stores, how to maintain normal 25(OH)D levels after repletion, which form of vitamin D is preferable for supplementation, which route of administration and dosing regimens are advisable. Finally, concerns have been raised regarding vitamin D toxicity and its adverse effects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Vitamin D - Journal of Family Practice</title><link>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-journal-of-family-practice.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-journal-of-family-practice.html</guid><description>&lt;h3>
&lt;p>Vitamin D: When it helps, when it harms&lt;/h3>&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="Deck">
&lt;p>&lt;b>Evidence supports its use for protecting bone health and preventing falls in the elderly, but little else.&lt;br />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For postmenopausal women, daily supplementation at doses ≤400 IU can actually be harmful.&lt;/b>&lt;br />&lt;em>&lt;span style="color:#0000cd;">&lt;strong>(Nope: VitaminDWiki)&lt;/strong>&lt;/span>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;p>&lt;br />&lt;span class="AuthorGrp">&lt;b>&lt;span>Doug &lt;/span>&lt;span>Campos-Outcalt, &lt;/span>MD, MPA&lt;/b>&lt;/span>&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="AuthorGrp">
&lt;p>&lt;i>&lt;span class="AuthorGrp">Department of Family, Community and Preventive Medicine, University of Arizona College of Medicine, Phoenix&lt;br />&lt;a href="mailto:dougco@email.arizona.edu" target="_blank">&lt;a href="mailto:dougco@email.arizona.edu">dougco@email.arizona.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/span>&lt;/i>&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="Body">
&lt;p>Vitamin D is the new wonder cure and preventive for all kinds of ailments and chronic diseases. Or so it would seem from the popular press and Internet.&lt;sup>&lt;a href="http://www.jfponline.com/Pages.asp?AID=11506#bib1">&lt;font color="#FF0000">1&lt;/font>&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Extraskeletal effects and manifestations of Vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/extraskeletal-effects-and-manifestations-of-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/extraskeletal-effects-and-manifestations-of-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Indian Journal of Endocrinology and Metabolism / Jul-Aug 2013 / Vol 17 | Issue 4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R. Kasi Visweswaran &lt;a href="mailto:rkasivis@yahoo.com">rkasivis@yahoo.com&lt;/a> , H. Lekha&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nephrology, Ananthapuri Hospitals and Research Institute, NH Bypass, Chackai, Trivandrum, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The actions of vitamin D are not confined to bone. Vitamin D receptors are present in nearly all the nuclei and its actions are manifold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Populations deficient in vitamin D are at higher risk of developing autoimmune diseases, diabetes, cancer, infections, allergies and other chronic illnesses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UK Nursing Times Review of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/uk-nursing-times-review-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uk-nursing-times-review-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1>
&lt;p>Health claims about vitamin D examined&lt;/h1>&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="byline">
&lt;p>&lt;span class="date">24 June, 2013 &lt;/span>&lt;a href="http://www.nursingtimes.net/home/behind-the-headlines/health-claims-about-vitamin-d-examined/5060171.article?blocktitle=Behind-the-Headlines&amp;amp;amp;contentID=4530">http://www.nursingtimes.net/home/behind-the-headlines/health-claims-about-vitamin-d-examined/5060171.article?blocktitle=Behind-the-Headlines&amp;amp;amp;contentID=4530&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="standfirst">
&lt;p>
&lt;p>Rarely a month goes by without the papers reporting at least one health news story related to vitamin D.&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>
&lt;p>In recent weeks the media has reported that vitamin D can help relieve the symptoms of asthma and lower blood pressure.&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;p>There have been long-standing claims that vitamin D brings a wide range of benefits, from preventing cancer risk to improving mental health, or even reducing your risk of getting multiple sclerosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fewer than 1 in 4 of nutrition students actually consumed RDA of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/fewer-than-1-in-4-of-nutrition-students-actually-consumed-rda-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fewer-than-1-in-4-of-nutrition-students-actually-consumed-rda-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="do-dutch-nutrition-and-dietetics-students-meet-nutritional-requirements-during-education">Do Dutch nutrition and dietetics students meet nutritional requirements during education?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2013 May 10:1-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van der Kruk JJ, Jager-Wittenaar H, Nieweg RM, van der Schans CP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hanze University of Applied Sciences, Professorship in Health Care and Nursing, Eyssoniusplein 18, 9714 CE Groningen, The Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: To compare the dietary intakes of Dutch nutrition and dietetics students with the Dutch RDA and the Dutch National Food Consumption Survey (DNFCS), and to assess whether dietary intake changes during education.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Defining normal level of vitamin D (need 4000-5000 IU) - Heaney Spring 2013</title><link>/posts/defining-normal-level-of-vitamin-d-need-4000-5000-iu-heaney-spring-2013.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/defining-normal-level-of-vitamin-d-need-4000-5000-iu-heaney-spring-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#part-one-defining-normal--lessons-from-our-ancestors">PART ONE: Defining normal – lessons from our ancestors&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#lessons-from-our-ancestors">Lessons from our ancestors&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#part-two-defining-normal--thermostats-feedback-and-adaptation">PART TWO: Defining normal – thermostats, feedback and adaptation&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-relationship-between-pth-and-vitamin-d">The relationship between PTH and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#postscript">Postscript.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#part-three-yet-another-way-of-determining-a-nutrient-requirement---analogy-to-iron">Part Three yet another way of determining a nutrient requirement - analogy to Iron&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#part-four-defining-normal--origins-and-resiliency">PART FOUR: Defining normal – origins and resiliency&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="part-one-defining-normal--lessons-from-our-ancestors">PART ONE: Defining normal – lessons from our ancestors&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Posted on April 1, 2013 by Robert P. Heaney&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D – Continuing Medical Education – 2013</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-continuing-medical-education-2013.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-continuing-medical-education-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-in-clinical-practice">Vitamin D in clinical practice&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.cmej.org.za/index.php/cmej/article/view/2682/2763%20">Continuing Medical Education, Vol 31, No 2 (2013)&lt;/a> South Africa&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A E Zemlin &lt;a href="mailto:azemlin@sun.ac.za">azemlin@sun.ac.za&lt;/a>, MB ChB, MMed (Chem Path), FC Path (SA) Chem&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Senior Specialist/Senior Lecturer, Department of Chemical Pathology, Stellenbosch University and National Health Laboratory Service, Tygerberg Hospital and Green Point Laboratories&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Meyer, MB ChB, MMed (Chem Path), Senior Specialist/Senior Lecturer, Department of Chemical Pathology, Stellenbosch University and National Health Laboratory Service, Tygerberg Hospital and Green Point Laboratories&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Major review of Vitamin D – Holick</title><link>/posts/major-review-of-vitamin-d-holick.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/major-review-of-vitamin-d-holick.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-roles-of-vitamin-d-in-skeletal-muscle-form-function-and-metabolism">The Roles of Vitamin D in Skeletal Muscle: Form, Function, and Metabolism&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocrine Reviews February 1, 2013 vol. 34 no. 1 33-83&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christian M. Girgis, Roderick J. Clifton-Bligh, Mark W. Hamrick, Michael F. Holick, and Jenny E. Gunton&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Garvan Institute of Medical Research (C.M.G., J.E.G.) and St. Vincent&amp;rsquo;s Clinical School (J.E.G.), University of New South Wales, Sydney, New South Wales 2010, Australia; Faculty of Medicine (C.M.G., R.J.C.-B., J.E.G.), University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales 2052, Australia; The Kolling Institute of Medical Research (R.J.C.-B.) and Royal North Shore Hospital (R.J.C.-B.), Sydney, New South Wales 2065, Australia; Georgia Health Sciences University (M.W.H.), Augusta, Georgia 30912; Boston University Medical Center (M.F.H.), Boston, Massachusetts 02118; and Department of Endocrinology and Diabetes (J.E.G.), Westmead Hospital, Sydney, New South Wales 2145, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>80 ng vitamin D doctor - interview Jan 2013 - admin only</title><link>/posts/80-ng-vitamin-d-doctor-interview-jan-2013-admin-only.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/80-ng-vitamin-d-doctor-interview-jan-2013-admin-only.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>This page is currently hidden on VitaminDWiki = only admins can see it&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a rough draft. There will be extensive re-writing, deleting, re-arranging&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Recently retired Family Practice physician in Jan 2013 telephone interview by Henry Lahore of VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He started a family practice which expanded to having 8,000 patients, most of whom now have vitamin D level 80 ng ± 10 ng.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/grassrootshealth" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 3614">Grassrootshealth&lt;/a> provided him with the target of 80 ng of vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Vitamin D papers - 2012</title><link>/posts/top-vitamin-d-papers-2012.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/top-vitamin-d-papers-2012.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Periodontal Disease – continuing education</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-periodontal-disease-continuing-education.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-periodontal-disease-continuing-education.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-review-of-vitamin-d-as-it-relates-to-periodontal-disease">A Review of Vitamin D as It Relates to Periodontal Disease&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Suellan Go Yao, DMD; Clinical Instructor, Columbia University College of Dental Medicine, Department of Periodontics, New York, New York; Private Practice; New York, New York&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>James Burke Fine, DMD; Associate Dean for Postdoctoral Education, Professor of Clinical Dentistry and Postdoctoral Director of the Division of Periodontics, Attending Dental Surgeon, Presbyterian Hospital Dental Service; New York, New York; Private Practice limited to Periodontics; Hoboken, New Jersey; faculty practice, Columbia University&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>With just 200 IU vitamin D in intravenous feeds, deficiency results</title><link>/posts/with-just-200-iu-vitamin-d-in-intravenous-feeds-deficiency-results.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/with-just-200-iu-vitamin-d-in-intravenous-feeds-deficiency-results.html</guid><description>&lt;p>!!Recommendations for Changes in Commercially Available Parenteral Multivitamin and Multi–Trace Element Products
&lt;strong>A.S.P.E.N. Position Paper&lt;/strong>
Nutr Clin Pract August 2012 vol. 27 no. 4 440-491
Vincent W. Vanek, MD, FACS, FASPEN (Chair)1
Peggy Borum, PhD, FASPEN2
Alan Buchman, MD, MSPH, FACP, FACG, FACN, AGAF3
Theresa A. Fessler, MS, RD, CNSC4
Lyn Howard, MB, FRCP5
Khursheed Jeejeebhoy, MBBS, PhD, FRCPC6
Marty Kochevar, MS, RPh, BCNSP7
Alan Shenkin, MB, ChB, PhD, FRCP, FRCPath8
Christina J. Valentine, MD, MS, RD9
&lt;strong>Novel Nutrient Task Force, Parenteral Multi-Vitamin and Multi–Trace Element Working Group&lt;/strong>
American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition (A.S.P.E.N.) Board of Directors
1 St. Elizabeth Health Center, Youngstown, Ohio
2 University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida
3 Northwestern University School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois
4 University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia
5 Albany Medical College, Albany, New York
6 Polyclinic, Toronto, Ontario
7 A.S.P.E.N., Silver Spring, Maryland
8 Royal Liverpool University Hospital, Liverpool, England
9 University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, Ohio
Vincent W. Vanek, St. Elizabeth Health Center, 1044 Belmont Ave, PO Box 1790, Youngstown, OH 44501-1790; e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:vince_vanek@hmis.org">vince_vanek@hmis.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Australia and NZ very conservative position statement on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/australia-and-nz-very-conservative-position-statement-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/australia-and-nz-very-conservative-position-statement-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>