<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Youth on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/youth.html</link><description>Recent content in Youth on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/youth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Psychiatric disorders 4X more likely in teens if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/psychiatric-disorders-4x-more-likely-in-teens-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/psychiatric-disorders-4x-more-likely-in-teens-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="low-levels-of-vitamin-d-linked-to-teen-delusions-hallucinationshttpwwwfoxnewscomhealth20111102low-levels-vitamin-d-linked-to-teen-delusions-hallucinations-foxnews">&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/health/2011/11/02/low-levels-vitamin-d-linked-to-teen-delusions-hallucinations/">Low Levels of Vitamin D Linked to Teen Delusions, Hallucinations&lt;/a> FoxNews&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A group of researchers led by Dr. Barbara L. Gracious, a psychiatrist at Nationwide Children’s Hospital in Columbus, Ohio, presented data at that meeting showing that adolescents who were vitamin D deficient showed a fourfold (400 percent) increased rate of psychotic symptoms, compared to other adolescents with normal vitamin D levels who sought psychiatric treatment at the University of Rochester, in New York.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese teens needed 4000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/obese-teens-needed-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-teens-needed-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="press-release-from-university-of-missourihttpmunewsmissouriedunews-releases20111101-obese-adolescents-benefit-from-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplements-nov-2011">&lt;a href="http://munews.missouri.edu/news-releases/2011/1101-obese-adolescents-benefit-from-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplements/">Press Release from University of Missouri&lt;/a> Nov 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="the-press-release-has-the-hyperlinks">The Press Release has the hyperlinks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Catherine Peterson, nutrition researcher at MU, found that a daily dose of 4,000 IUs of vitamin D3 is both safe and effective at improving vitamin D status in obese adolescents.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="obese-adolescents-benefit-from-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplements">Obese Adolescents Benefit from High-Dose Vitamin D Supplements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="high-doses-safely-combat-nutritional-deficiencies-mu-researchers-find">High doses safely combat nutritional deficiencies, MU researchers find&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>COLUMBIA, Mo. –Vitamin D deficiency is common in Americans, and especially in overweight and obese adolescents, according to the National Institutes of Health. University of Missouri researchers have found that providing obese adolescents with a high daily dose of vitamin D3 is safe and effective in improving their vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>97 percent of Native American children have less than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/97-percent-of-native-american-children-have-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/97-percent-of-native-american-children-have-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-is-associated-with-diabetes-risk-in-native-american-children">Vitamin D Insufficiency Is Associated With Diabetes Risk in Native American Children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2011 Oct 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nsiah-Kumi PA, Erickson JM, Beals JL, Ogle EA, Whiting M, Brushbreaker C, Borgeson CD, Qui F, Yu F, Larsen JL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha, NE, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aims/Hypothesis. Vitamin D insufficiency has not been well studied in Native American (NA) children, who are at risk for obesity and diabetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The authors examined vitamin D insufficiency and its association with body mass index (BMI) and insulin resistance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children have PTH problems when vitamin D is less than 15 ng</title><link>/posts/children-have-pth-problems-when-vitamin-d-is-less-than-15-ng.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-have-pth-problems-when-vitamin-d-is-less-than-15-ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Children surviving blood cancer and vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/children-surviving-blood-cancer-and-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-surviving-blood-cancer-and-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Teenage knee injury 4X increase in last decade in Philadelphia</title><link>/posts/teenage-knee-injury-4x-increase-in-last-decade-in-philadelphia.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/teenage-knee-injury-4x-increase-in-last-decade-in-philadelphia.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="knee-injuries-on-the-rise-in-child-and-adolescent-athleteshttpmedicalxpresscomnews2011-10-knee-injuries-child-adolescent-athleteshtml">&lt;a href="http://medicalxpress.com/news/2011-10-knee-injuries-child-adolescent-athletes.html">Knee injuries on the rise in child and adolescent athletes&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clipped from Medical Express&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="knee-injuries-in-children-and-adolescents-has-there-been-an-increase-in-acl-and-meniscus-tears-in-recent-years">&amp;ldquo;Knee Injuries In Children and Adolescents: Has There Been An Increase In ACL and Meniscus Tears In Recent Years?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Academy of Pediatrics Oct 16, 2011 presentation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Researchers at the Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Philadelphia noted a more than 400 percent increase in these injuries at their institution over the last decade&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="suspect-slower-muscle-reaction-time-due-to-low-vitamin-d-levels">Suspect slower muscle reaction time due to low vitamin D levels&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d">Overview Sports and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer in children 6X more likely if very low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cancer-in-children-6x-more-likely-if-very-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-in-children-6x-more-likely-if-very-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-paediatric-patients-with-cancer">Vitamin D status in paediatric patients with cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2011 Oct;57(4):594-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/pbc.22963.">doi: 10.1002/pbc.22963.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Feb 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sinha A, Avery P, Turner S, Bailey S, Cheetham T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Paediatric Endocrinology, Great North Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Children with malignant disease are at increased risk of bone disorders and cardiovascular disease. Vitamin D status may influence this risk and so we assessed vitamin D levels in children with malignant disease undergoing active treatment or surveillance post-therapy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children with low vitamin D were 4.8X more likely to get asthma</title><link>/posts/children-with-low-vitamin-d-were-48x-more-likely-to-get-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-with-low-vitamin-d-were-48x-more-likely-to-get-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="note-many-asthmatics-were-also-low-on-span-stylecolorf00magnesiumspan">Note: many asthmatics were also low on &lt;span style="color:#F00;">Magnesium&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-strong-predictor-of-asthma-in-children">Vitamin D Deficiency as a Strong Predictor of Asthma in Children.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int Arch Allergy Immunol. 2011 Oct 6;157(2):168-175.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bener A, Ehlayel MS, Tulic MK, Hamid Q.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medical Statistics and Epidemiology, Hamad Medical Corporation, Department of Public Health, Weill Cornell Medical College, Doha, Qatar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Epidemiological studies suggest a link between vitamin D deficiency in early life and development of asthma in later life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark Skinned youths and vitamin D in Southern Canada - Dissertation 2011</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-youths-and-vitamin-d-in-southern-canada-dissertation-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-youths-and-vitamin-d-in-southern-canada-dissertation-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-metabolites-in-young-adults-of-diverse-ancestry-living-in-the-greater-toronto-area">Vitamin D Metabolites in Young Adults of Diverse Ancestry Living in the Greater Toronto Area&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>By Agnes Gozdzik&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A thesis submitted in conformity with the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Anthropology University of Toronto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© Copyright by Agnes Gozdzik 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor00fpdf-is-attached-at-the-bottom-of-this-pagespan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D plays a critical role in bone metabolism and many cellular and immunological processes, and low vitamin D levels have been associated with several chronic and infectious diseases. Previous studies have reported that many otherwise healthy adults of European ancestry living in Canada have low vitamin D concentrations during the wintertime. However, individuals of non-European ancestry are at a higher risk of having low vitamin D levels. This thesis examined vitamin D status in a sample of young adults of diverse ancestry living in the Greater Toronto Area. In my research I found that:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>80 percent of teens in Europe had less than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/80-percent-of-teens-in-europe-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/80-percent-of-teens-in-europe-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D insufficiency in UK youths – 37X more likely if dark skin</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-uk-youths-37x-more-likely-if-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-uk-youths-37x-more-likely-if-dark-skin.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Caucasian youths low on vitamin D were more likely to have hypertension</title><link>/posts/caucasian-youths-low-on-vitamin-d-were-more-likely-to-have-hypertension.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/caucasian-youths-low-on-vitamin-d-were-more-likely-to-have-hypertension.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-25ohd3-levels-are-associated-with-total-adiposity-metabolic-syndrome-and-hypertension-in-caucasian-children-and-adolescents">Low 25(OH)D3 levels are associated with total adiposity, metabolic syndrome, and hypertension in Caucasian children and adolescents.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eur J Endocrinol. 2011 Jul 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pacifico L, Anania C, Osborn JF, Ferraro F, Bonci E, Olivero E, Chiesa C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>L Pacifico, PEDIATRICS, SAPIENZA UNIVERSITY OF ROME, ROME, 00161, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: Evidence of the association between vitamin D and cardiovascular (CV) risk factors in the young is limited. We therefore assessed the relationships between circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 &lt;span>[25(OH)D3]&lt;/span> and metabolic syndrome (MetS), its components, and early atherosclerotic changes in 452 (304 overweight/obese, 148 healthy, normal weight) Caucasian children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300 IU vitamin D daily raised child levels to 20 ng from 8 ng</title><link>/posts/300-iu-vitamin-d-daily-raised-child-levels-to-20-ng-from-8-ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300-iu-vitamin-d-daily-raised-child-levels-to-20-ng-from-8-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="randomized-trial-of-fortified-milk-and-supplements-to-raise-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-schoolchildren-in-mongolia">Randomized trial of fortified milk and supplements to raise 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations in schoolchildren in Mongolia.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jun 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rich-Edwards JW, Ganmaa D, Kleinman K, Sumberzul N, Holick MF, Lkhagvasuren T, Dulguun B, Burke A, Frazier AL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Connors Center for Women&amp;rsquo;s Health and Gender Biology, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA and Nutrition, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, MA; Channing Laboratory, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skinned teens use media much more</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-teens-use-media-much-more.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-teens-use-media-much-more.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="clipped-from-good-website-kids-of-color-consume-a-lot-more-media-than-white-kidshttpwwwgoodispostkids-of-color-consume-a-lot-more-media-than-white-kids-june-2011">Clipped from Good website: &lt;a href="http://www.good.is/post/kids-of-color-consume-a-lot-more-media-than-white-kids/">Kids of Color Consume a Lot More Media Than White Kids&lt;/a> June 2011&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A &lt;a href="http://www.northwestern.edu/newscenter/stories/2011/06/media-usa-youth-wartella.html">new study&lt;/a> at Northwestern University found a huge difference between the amount of media white and nonwhite kids consume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Minority children ages 8 to 18 consume an average of 13 hours of media content a day—about 4-and-a-half hours more than their white counterparts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In the last ten years, this number has doubled for black children and quadrupled for Hispanics&lt;/strong> .&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sun exposure protects children from asthma</title><link>/posts/sun-exposure-protects-children-from-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sun-exposure-protects-children-from-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sunny-hours-and-variations-in-the-prevalence-of-asthma-in-schoolchildren-according-to-the-international-study-of-asthma-and-allergies-isaac-phase-iii-in-spain">Sunny hours and variations in the prevalence of asthma in schoolchildren according to the International Study of Asthma and Allergies (ISAAC) Phase III in Spain.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int J Biometeorol. 2011 May;55(3):423-34. Epub 2010 Aug 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arnedo-Pena A, García-Marcos L, Fernández-Espinar JF, Bercedo-Sanz A, Aguinaga-Ontoso I, González-Díaz C, Carvajal-Urueña I, Busquet-Monge R, Suárez-Varela MM, de Andoin NG, Batlles-Garrido J, Blanco-Quirós A, Varela AL, García-Hernández G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiology Division, Centre of Public Health, C/ L&amp;rsquo;Olivera 5, 2-C, 12005, Castellón, Spain, &lt;a href="mailto:arnedo_alb@gva.es">arnedo_alb@gva.es&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Allergy - Overview</title><link>/posts/allergy-overview.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/allergy-overview.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="might-peanut-allergy-be-associated-with-low-vitamin-d--asked-perplexity-ai-july-2024">Might peanut allergy be associated with low vitamin D? asked Perplexity AI July 2024&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There is evidence suggesting a potential association between peanut allergy and low vitamin D levels. Several studies have explored this relationship, indicating that vitamin D deficiency might play a role in the development of food allergies, including peanut allergy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Evidence Supporting the Association&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Australian Study&lt;/strong> :&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>An Australian study found that infants with low vitamin D levels were more likely to have egg or peanut allergies and multiple allergies compared to those with normal vitamin D levels. This suggests that vitamin D might have a protective role against the development of food allergies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hardly any children had enough vitamin D before bone surgery</title><link>/posts/hardly-any-children-had-enough-vitamin-d-before-bone-surgery.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hardly-any-children-had-enough-vitamin-d-before-bone-surgery.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Black obese children had low vitamin D and more fat under skin than whites</title><link>/posts/black-obese-children-had-low-vitamin-d-and-more-fat-under-skin-than-whites.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-obese-children-had-low-vitamin-d-and-more-fat-under-skin-than-whites.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-adiposity-and-lipids-in-black-american-and-caucasian-children">Vitamin D Status, Adiposity, and Lipids in Black American and Caucasian Children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Mar 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rajakumar K, de Las Heras J, Chen TC, Lee S, Holick MF, Arslanian SA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics (K.R.), Division of General Academic Pediatrics, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Department of Pediatrics (J.d.l.H., S.L., S.A.A.), Division of Weight Management and Wellness, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Division of Pediatric Endocrinology, Metabolism, and Diabetes Mellitus (S.A.A.), University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Department of Pediatrics and Endocrinology and Diabetes Research Group (J.d.l.H.), Cruces Hospital, 48903 Barakaldo, Vizcaya, Spain; and Department of Medicine (T.C.C., M.F.H.), Boston University School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts 02118.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Alert – one in three pre-teens in Tehran had less than 5 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/red-alert-one-in-three-pre-teens-in-tehran-had-less-than-5-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/red-alert-one-in-three-pre-teens-in-tehran-had-less-than-5-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-school-age-children-in-tehran-2008-a-red-alert">High prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in school-age children in Tehran, 2008: a red alert.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Feb 28:1-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neyestani TR, Hajifaraji M, Omidvar N, Eshraghian MR, Shariatzadeh N, Kalayi A, Gharavi A, Khalaji N, Haidari H, Zowghi T, Nikooyeh B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Laboratory of Nutrition Research, National Research Institute, Faculty of Nutritional Science and Food Technology, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, PO Box 19395-4741, Tehran, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To assess the vitamin D status of 9-12-year-old primary-school children in Tehran during autumn and winter 2007-2008.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AAP Issues Guidelines on Limiting Sun Exposure in Children</title><link>/posts/aap-issues-guidelines-on-limiting-sun-exposure-in-children.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/aap-issues-guidelines-on-limiting-sun-exposure-in-children.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Laurie Barclay, MD February 28, 2011 — The American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) has issued guidelines on limiting sun exposure in children and supporting legislation to prohibit salon tanning by minors, according to a policy statement entitled &amp;ldquo;Ultraviolet Radiation: A Hazard to Children and Adolescents.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new recommendations and an accompanying technical document are reported online February 28 and published in the March issue of Pediatrics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Ultraviolet radiation (UVR) causes the 3 major forms of skin cancer: basal cell carcinoma; squamous cell carcinoma; and cutaneous malignant melanoma,&amp;rdquo; write Sophie J. Balk, MD, former chairperson, AAP Committee on Environmental Health, and colleagues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children with Cancer were 6X more likely to have less than 10ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/children-with-cancer-were-6x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-10ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-with-cancer-were-6x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-10ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-paediatric-patients-with-cancer">Vitamin D status in paediatric patients with cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Research Article&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Akash Sinha MBBS1,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Peter Avery PhD2,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Steve Turner BSc3,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Simon Bailey PhD4,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tim Cheetham MD1,5, &lt;a href="mailto:tim.cheetham@nuth.nhs.uk">tim.cheetham@nuth.nhs.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Article first published online: 3 FEB 2011; DOI: 10.1002/pbc.22963&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Paediatric Endocrinology, Great North Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Mathematics and Statistics, Newcastle University, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Great North Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>200 to 2000 IU vitamin D daily did not improve child bone density – BMJ</title><link>/posts/200-to-2000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-did-not-improve-child-bone-density-bmj.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/200-to-2000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-did-not-improve-child-bone-density-bmj.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-bone-density-in-healthy-children-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Effects of vitamin D supplementation on bone density in healthy children: systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>BMJ 2011; 2011; 342:c7254 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.c7254">doi: 10.1136/bmj.c7254&lt;/a> (Published 25 January 2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tania Winzenberg, senior research fellow in general practice1, &lt;a href="mailto:tania.winzenberg@utas.edu.au">tania.winzenberg@utas.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sandi Powell, endocrinologist2,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kelly Anne Shaw, honorary associate and postdoctoral fellow13,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Graeme Jones, head of musculoskeletal unit1&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Author Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>1Menzies Research Institute, University of Tasmania, Private Bag 23, Hobart, TAS 7000, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Royal Hobart Hospital, Liverpool St Hobart, Tasmania&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>South African white children 48 ng vitamin D – black 37 ng</title><link>/posts/south-african-white-children-48-ng-vitamin-d-black-37-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/south-african-white-children-48-ng-vitamin-d-black-37-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="factors-influencing-the-vitamin-d-status-of-10-year-old-urban-south-african-children">Factors influencing the vitamin D status of 10-year-old urban South African children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Feb;14(2):334-339. Epub 2010 Aug 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Poopedi MA, Norris SA, Pettifor JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MRC Mineral Metabolism Research Unit &amp;amp; Birth to Twenty Research Programme, Faculty of Health Sciences, Department of Paediatrics and Child Health, Chris Hani Baragwanath Hospital, The University of the Witwatersrand, PO Bertsham, 2013 Johannesburg, South Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Assessment of vitamin D status in a cohort of healthy 10-year-old urban children and the factors that influence vitamin D status in these children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>744 IU vitamin D needed by Northern white teens to prevent Rickets</title><link>/posts/744-iu-vitamin-d-needed-by-northern-white-teens-to-prevent-rickets.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/744-iu-vitamin-d-needed-by-northern-white-teens-to-prevent-rickets.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="estimation-of-the-dietary-requirement-for-vitamin-d-in-healthy-adolescent-white-girls">Estimation of the dietary requirement for vitamin D in healthy adolescent white girls.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jan 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cashman KD, Fitzgerald AP, Viljakainen HT, Jakobsen J, Michaelsen KF, Lamberg-Allardt C, Mølgaard C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Food and Nutritional Sciences and Departments of Medicine and Epidemiology and Public Health, and Statistics, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Knowledge gaps have contributed to considerable variation (between 0 and 15 ?g/d) between international dietary recommendations for vitamin D in adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding a little vitamin D for 3 months did not help bones of healthy children</title><link>/posts/adding-a-little-vitamin-d-for-3-months-did-not-help-bones-of-healthy-children.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adding-a-little-vitamin-d-for-3-months-did-not-help-bones-of-healthy-children.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-bone-density-in-healthy-children-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Effects of vitamin D supplementation on bone density in healthy children: systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tania Winzenberg, senior research fellow in general practice1,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sandi Powell, endocrinologist2,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kelly Anne Shaw, honorary associate and postdoctoral fellow13,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Graeme Jones, head of musculoskeletal unit1&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Author Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>1.Menzies Research Institute, University of Tasmania, Private Bag 23, Hobart, TAS 7000, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2.Royal Hobart Hospital, Liverpool St Hobart, Tasmania&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3.ASLaRC Aged Services Unit, Southern Cross University, Coffs Harbour, Queensland Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poorer teen cognition due to lower vitamin D or race</title><link>/posts/poorer-teen-cognition-due-to-lower-vitamin-d-or-race.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poorer-teen-cognition-due-to-lower-vitamin-d-or-race.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Why vitamin D is not a problem for some youth</title><link>/posts/why-vitamin-d-is-not-a-problem-for-some-youth.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-vitamin-d-is-not-a-problem-for-some-youth.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="youthful-skin-produces-4x-as-much-vitamin-d-per-minute-in-the-sun-as-elderly-skin">Youthful skin produces 4X as much vitamin D per minute in the sun as elderly skin&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="youth-rarely-have-diseases-that-actually-consume-vitamin-d-such-as">Youth rarely have diseases that actually consume vitamin D, such as:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpostsms-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-691msa-diabetescategoriesdiabetes-obesitycategoriesobesity-colon-cancerhttpswwwvitamindwikicomtiki-browse_categoriesphpparentid41sort_modecreated_desc-bariatric-surgery-kidney-failurehttpswwwvitamindwikicomtiki-browse_categoriesphpparentid15sort_modecreated_desc-liver-failurehttpswwwvitamindwikicomtiki-browse_categoriesphpparentid14sort_modecreated_desc-">&lt;a href="/posts/ms" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 691">MS&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="/categories/diabetes">diabetes&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="/categories/obesity">obesity&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=41&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">colon cancer&lt;/a>, bariatric surgery, &lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=15&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">kidney failure&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=14&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">liver failure&lt;/a>, &amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpostsclick-here-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-information-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-889click-here-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-informationa">&lt;a href="/posts/click-here-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-information" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 889">CLICK HERE for vitamin D deficiency information&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="youth-tend-to-be-outdoors-more---example-summer-vacation-from-school">Youth tend to be outdoors more - example: summer vacation from school&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="exceptions---probably-need-vitamin-d-if">Exceptions - probably need vitamin D if:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>sensitive skin,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increase in some childhood cancers with latitude</title><link>/posts/increase-in-some-childhood-cancers-with-latitude.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increase-in-some-childhood-cancers-with-latitude.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="childhood-cancer-incidence-in-relation-to-sunlight-exposure">Childhood cancer incidence in relation to sunlight exposure.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Br J Cancer. 2010 Nov 23. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Musselman JR, Spector LG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatrics, Department of Epidemiology and Clinical Research, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:There is increasing interest in the possible association between cancer incidence and vitamin D through its role as a regulator of cell growth and differentiation. Epidemiological studies in adults and one paediatric study suggest an inverse association between sunlight exposure and cancer incidence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Youthful heart attacks associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/youthful-heart-attacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/youthful-heart-attacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="markers-of-bone-metabolism-in-premature-myocardial-infarction--40-years-of-age">Markers of Bone Metabolism in premature myocardial infarction (? 40 years of age).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Bone. 2010 Nov 12&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goliasch G, Blessberger H, Azar D, Heinze G, Wojta J, Bieglmayer C, Wagner O, Schillinger M, Huber K, Maurer G, Haas M, Wiesbauer F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardiology, Vienna General Hospital/Medical University of Vienna and 6Wilhelminen Hospital Vienna.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Acute myocardial infarction (AMI) at young age is a rare disease with a poor prognosis. Bone metabolism parameters such as 1,25 (OH)(2) vitamin D(3), 25 (OH) vitamin D(3) and osteocalcin have been recently implicated in the development of coronary heart disease (CHD). We evaluated the role of these serum markers in a study population of very young AMI survivors (? 40 years).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU raised black teens vitamin D level to 34 ng and they lost fat</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-raised-black-teens-vitamin-d-level-to-34-ng-and-they-lost-fat.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-raised-black-teens-vitamin-d-level-to-34-ng-and-they-lost-fat.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-16-week-randomized-clinical-trial-of-2000-international-units-daily-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-black-youth-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-adiposity-and-arterial-stiffness">A 16-week randomized clinical trial of 2000 international units daily vitamin D3 supplementation in black youth: 25-hydroxyvitamin D, adiposity, and arterial stiffness.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2010 Oct;95(10):4584-91. Epub 2010 Jul 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dong Y, Stallmann-Jorgensen IS, Pollock NK, Harris RA, Keeton D, Huang Y, Li K, Bassali R, Guo DH, Thomas J, Pierce GL, White J, Holick MF, Zhu H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Georgia Prevention Institute, Department of Pediatrics, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta, Georgia 30912, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:ydong@mail.mcg.edu">ydong@mail.mcg.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>