<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Orient on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/orient.html</link><description>Recent content in Orient on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/orient/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chinese have very low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chinese-have-very-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chinese-have-very-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="updatea-hrefpostsvitamin-d-levels-are-correlated-with-6-environmental-variables-in-china-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-vitamin-d-levels-are-correlated-with-6-environmental-variables-in-china--july-2022vitamin-d-levels-are-correlated-with-6-environmental-variables-in-china--july-2022a">Update: &lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-levels-are-correlated-with-6-environmental-variables-in-china" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Vitamin D levels are correlated with 6 environmental variables in China – July 2022">Vitamin D levels are correlated with 6 environmental variables in China – July 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/map.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;h4 id="a-glimpse-of-vitamin-d-status-in-mainland-china">A glimpse of vitamin D status in Mainland China&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/journal/08999007">Nutrition&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/journal/08999007/29/7">Volume 29, Issues 7–8&lt;/a>, July–August 2013, Pages 953–957&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S089990071300052X#">Weiguo Zhang&lt;/a>, M.D., Ph.D.{ANAME()}bcor1|&lt;img src="http://cdn.els-cdn.com/sd/entities/REcor.gif" alt="image">{ANAME}&lt;sup>, &lt;/sup>,weiguo.zhang@dsm.com&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S089990071300052X#">Elisabeth Stoecklin&lt;/a>, M.D.,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S089990071300052X#">Manfred Eggersdorfer&lt;/a>, Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>DSM Nutritional Products, Human Nutrition and Health, Beijing, China and Kaiseraugst, Switzerland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Japanese women 20X more likely to be vitamin D deficient than men, etc. – Many 2013</title><link>/posts/japanese-women-20x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-men-etc-many-2013.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/japanese-women-20x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-men-etc-many-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="profiles-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-and-deficiency-in-japanese-men-and-women-association-with-biological-environmental-and-nutritional-factors-and-coexisting-disorders-the-road-study">Profiles of vitamin D insufficiency and deficiency in Japanese men and women: association with biological, environmental, and nutritional factors and coexisting disorders: the ROAD study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2013 May 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yoshimura N, Muraki S, Oka H, Morita M, Yamada H, Tanaka S, Kawaguchi H, Nakamura K, Akune T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Joint Disease Research, 22nd Century Medical and Research Center, Graduate School of Medicine, The University of Tokyo, 7-3-1 Hongo, Bunkyo-ku, Tokyo, 113-8655, Japan, &lt;a href="mailto:YOSHIMURAN-ORT@h.u-tokyo.ac.jp">YOSHIMURAN-ORT@h.u-tokyo.ac.jp&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Japanese recommendations without RDA: Vitamin D about 200 IU, Vitamin K about 60 ug</title><link>/posts/japanese-recommendations-without-rda-vitamin-d-about-200-iu-vitamin-k-about-60-ug.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/japanese-recommendations-without-rda-vitamin-d-about-200-iu-vitamin-k-about-60-ug.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dietary-reference-intakes-for-japanese-2010-fat-soluble-vitamins">Dietary Reference Intakes for Japanese 2010: Fat-Soluble Vitamins&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>/Nutr Sci Vitaminol, 59, S57-S66, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kiyoshi Tanaka1, Junji TfeRAO2, Yoshihiro Shidoji3, Hiroshi Tamai4, Eri Imai5 and Toshio Okano6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Food and Nutrition, Kyoto Women&amp;rsquo;s University, Kyoto 605-8501, Japan &lt;a href="mailto:tanakak@kyoto-wu.ac.jp">tanakak@kyoto-wu.ac.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Food Science, Institute of Health Biosciences, The University of Tokushima Graduate School, Tokushima 770-8503, Japan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Nutrition and Health Science, Graduate School of Human Health Science, University of Nagasaki, Nagasaki 851-2195, Japan 4Department of Pediatrics, Osaka Medical College, Osaka 569-8686, Japan 5 Section of the Dietary Reference Intakes, Department of Nutritional Epidemiology, National Institute of Health and Nutrition, Tokyo 162-8636, Japan 6Department of Hygienic Sciences, Kobe Pharmaceutical University, Kobe, 658-8558, Japan&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D in Japanese women: 91 percent have less than 30 ng– 2012</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-in-japanese-women-91-percent-have-less-than-30-ng-2012.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-in-japanese-women-91-percent-have-less-than-30-ng-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="mutual-interaction-between-vitamin-d-and-lifestyle-related-diseases-in-women">Mutual Interaction Between Vitamin D and Lifestyle-Related Diseases in Women&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of UOEH; Vol. 34 (2012) No. 4 p. 323-329 &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.7888/juoeh.34.323">http://dx.doi.org/10.7888/juoeh.34.323&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hiroko MORI1), Yosuke OKADA1), Yoshiya TANAKA1)&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>First Department of Internal Medicine, School of Medicine, University of Occupational and Environmental Health, Japan&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency increases the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus, cardiovascular, hypertension, cancer, infectious and autoimmune diseases, as well as the risk of fractures. The major causes of vitamin D deficiency are lack of adequate vitamin D from dietary sources and avoidance of sensible sun exposure, amongst many others. Particularly, in women, vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency are common medical problems with insidious health consequences. The control of Vitamin D is important for many women to continue working longer in good health.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets in Chinese</title><link>/posts/rickets-in-chinese.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-in-chinese.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostsclick-here-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-4044click-herea-for-the-main-web-page-for-this-article">&lt;a href="/posts/click-here" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 4044">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for the main web page for this article&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>which has the PDF, image, and text in English&lt;/p>
&lt;p>第14卷第10期2012年10月&lt;/p>
&lt;p>中国当代儿科杂志&lt;/p>
&lt;p>论著•临床研究&lt;/p>
&lt;p>血清25-羟维生素D在佝偻病诊断中的应用价值&lt;/p>
&lt;p>王晓燕1 金春华1吴建新2刘卓2 李梅1李娜1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(1.首都儿科研究所附属儿童医院保健科，北京 100020 ; 2.首都儿科研究所生化研究室，北京 100020)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[摘要]&lt;/span>目的探讨血清25-羟维生素D&lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>在维生素D缺乏性佝偻病早期诊断中的意义。方法检测对照组(73例）、可疑组(45例）和佝偻病组（65例）的血清25( OH) D、钙、磷、碱性磷酸酶浓度，并通过ROC曲线对血清25( OH) D的诊断价值进行评价。结果对照组、可疑组和佝偻病组的血清25 ( OH) D水平分别为112 ± 37、83 ±30和72 ±31 nmol/L，后两者均显著低于对照组（F=26. 174， P &amp;lt; 0. 01)，可疑组与佝偻病组差异无统计学意义（8&amp;gt;0.05 )。可疑组和佝偻病组的维生素D缺乏率均显著高于对照组（；!2 = 33.346， 8 &amp;lt;0. 01 )。血清25(OH) D的ROC曲线下面积为0. 760(95% C/:0.692 ~0. 820，P &amp;lt;0. 01)，最佳临界点为90.7 nmol/L时，灵敏度为68.49%，特异度为72. 73%;可疑组和佝偻病组的血钙、磷、碱性磷酸酶浓度与对照组比较差异均无统计学意义（8 &amp;gt;0.05)。结论血清25(OH) D水平在可疑及确诊佝偻病的患儿中显著降低，可以反映维生素D的营养状况，适用于佝偻病的早期筛查。 &lt;span>[中国当代儿科杂志,2012,14(10) :767 - 770]&lt;/span>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beijing extremely vitamin D deficient even in the fall: 10 ng</title><link>/posts/beijing-extremely-vitamin-d-deficient-even-in-the-fall-10-ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/beijing-extremely-vitamin-d-deficient-even-in-the-fall-10-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-mainland-china">Vitamin D status in Mainland China&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrition April 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weiguo Zhang, M.D., Ph.D. &lt;a href="mailto:weiguo.zhang@dsm.com">weiguo.zhang@dsm.com&lt;/a> , Elisabeth Stoecklin, M.D., Manfred Eggersdorfer, Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DSM Nutritional Products, Human Nutrition and Health, Beijing, China and Kaiseraugst, Switzerland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 12 November 2012; accepted 11 January 2013. published online 16 April 2013. Corrected Proof&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an essential dietary micronutrient, vitamin D plays a pivotal role in promoting calcium absorption in the intestine and maintaining a healthy skeletal system throughout life. Beyond bone health, an emerging volume of scientific studies shows that vitamin D also may provide cardiovascular, metabolic, and immunologic benefits and reduce mortality. To our knowledge, in mainland China no national surveys have been conducted to date to depict the overall vitamin D status in the population. Therefore, the purpose of this contribution was to provide the best possible evaluation of vitamin D deficiency/insufficiency in China by reviewing publications that measured plasma/serum 25-hydroxyvitamin-D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels in various age groups and in different areas of China from &lt;strong>January 2000 to June 2012.&lt;/strong> From these investigations conducted throughout the country and from newborns to adults to the elderly, it has been found that &lt;strong>vitamin D deficiency/insufficiency is prevalent in the Chinese population in almost all age groups and areas if individuals are not taking vitamin D–fortified products/supplements or are lacking sufficient sunshine exposure&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D DRI for children lowered to 200 IU in Korea</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-dri-for-children-lowered-to-200-iu-in-korea.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-dri-for-children-lowered-to-200-iu-in-korea.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="adequate-vitamin-d-status-and-adiposity-contribute-to-bone-health-in-peripubertal-nonobese-children">Adequate vitamin D status and adiposity contribute to bone health in peripubertal nonobese children.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Metab. 2013 Jan 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee YA, Kim JY, Kang MJ, Chung SJ, Shin CH, Yang SW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Pediatrics, Seoul National University College of Medicine, 101 Daehak-ro, Jongno-gu, Seoul, 110-769, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dietary reference intake (DRI) of vitamin D for Korean children was &lt;strong>reduced from 400 IU/day in 2005 to 200 IU/day in 2010.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7 genes associated with low vitamin D levels in China – 2012, 2013</title><link>/posts/gc-cyp2r1-and-dhcr7-genes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels-in-china-2012-2013.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gc-cyp2r1-and-dhcr7-genes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels-in-china-2012-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolorf00two-articles-from-china-on-this-page-have-the-same-conclusionspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Two articles from China on this page have the same conclusion&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="the-gc-cyp2r1-and-dhcr7-genes-are-associated-with-vitamin-d-levels-in-northeastern-han-chinese-children">The GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7 genes are associated with vitamin D levels in northeastern Han Chinese children.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Swiss Med Wkly. &lt;strong>2012 July&lt;/strong> 16;142:w13636. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4414/smw.2012.13636.">doi: 10.4414/smw.2012.13636.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhang Y, Wang X, Liu Y, Qu H, Qu S, Wang W, Ren L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, Heilongjiang Province, PR China. &lt;a href="mailto:zhangyuling0000@yahoo.com.cn">zhangyuling0000@yahoo.com.cn&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is associated with risk in several diseases. Vitamin D status has high heritability, yet the genetic epidemiology of vitamin D or its metabolites has not been well studied. Our objective was to identify the relationship among three vitamin D-related genes (GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7/NADSYN1) and the levels of 25(OH)D in northeastern Han Chinese children. A total of 506 northeastern Han Chinese children were enrolled in this study. Linear regression was used to examine the impact of 12 SNPs on 25(OH)D concentrations after adjustment for age, gender, BMI and regular usage of vitamin D, and Bonferroni&amp;rsquo;s method was adopted for multiple corrections. The two SNPs in GC (rs222020, rs2298849), four SNPs in CYP2R1 (rs10741657, rs10766197, rs12794714 and rs1562902) and two SNPs in DHCR7/NADSYN1 (rs3829251, rs12785878) were significantly associated with plasma 25(OH)D concentrations under both additive and recessive models (P &amp;lt;0.05). The genotypes of the CYP2R1 rs2060793 polymorphism showed positive association with serum 25(OH)D status under all of the three genetic models even after correction for multiple comparison. This population-based study was the first to confirm the strong effects of the GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7/NADSYN1 loci on circulating 25(OH)D concentrations in northeastern Han Chinese children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Comparison of Vitamin D supplementation guidelines for children – China 400 IU 2012</title><link>/posts/comparison-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-guidelines-for-children-china-400-iu-2012.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/comparison-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-guidelines-for-children-china-400-iu-2012.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Women around the world want whiter skin</title><link>/posts/women-around-the-world-want-whiter-skin.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-around-the-world-want-whiter-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="many-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic-postsmany-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic-aug-2012">&lt;a href="/posts/many-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic">Many reasons why vitamin D deficiency has become epidemic &lt;/a> Aug 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Want whiter skin - especially women&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://innerreflectionstranscribed.wordpress.com/2007/04/25/fair-skin-desirable/">Here&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=K8PCYtg1SocC&amp;amp;pg=PT81&amp;amp;lpg=PT81&amp;amp;dq=desirability+of+white+skin&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=CI7w34zn6X&amp;amp;sig=2ma4FM-zouS59Afbz4tggXdxUNI&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ei=eaTaTbniI4HGsAOz0dGFDA&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;oi=book_result&amp;amp;ct=result&amp;amp;resnum=5&amp;amp;ved=0CDQQ6AEwBA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=desirability%20of%20white%20skin&amp;amp;f=false">Here (Helen of Troy)&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.abcdlady.com/2005-07/art6.php">Being Fair-Skinned in Today&amp;rsquo;s World&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/suntan-popularity-is-fading" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 304">Suntan: Popularity is fading&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/perhaps-not-burn-from-the-sun-if-have-enough-vitamin-d">Perhaps not burn from the sun if have enough vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/09/23/thai-vulva-bleaching-product.html">Thai vulva-bleaching product&lt;/a> Sept 2012&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In many countries across south-east Asia, fairer skin has long been equated with higher class as it suggests a life not spent toiling in rice paddies under the sun. The Thai language is peppered with cultural expressions that denigrate dark skin, such as the insult dam mhuen e-ga – &amp;ldquo;black like a crow&amp;rdquo;. These days, rice farmers wear long sleeves, trousers, wide-brimmed hats and gloves&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One third of lung disease patients in China had less than 4ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/one-third-of-lung-disease-patients-in-china-had-less-than-4ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/one-third-of-lung-disease-patients-in-china-had-less-than-4ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="lung-cancer-and-benign-lung-diseases-in-patients-with-serious-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-eastern-china">Lung cancer and benign lung diseases in patients with serious vitamin D deficiency in eastern China.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology, 2012 ASCO Annual Meeting Proceedings (Post-Meeting Edition).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol 30, No 15_suppl (May 20 Supplement), 2012: e12010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2012 American Society of Clinical Oncology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rong Li, Jing Wu, Liwen Xiong and Baohui Han&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Pulmonary Medicine of Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai, China; The Biochemical Laboratory of Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai, China; Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai, China&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtually all Chinese teens at 30 degree N have less than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/virtually-all-chinese-teens-at-30-degree-n-have-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/virtually-all-chinese-teens-at-30-degree-n-have-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Japanese men eating small fish were 32 percent less likely to get diabetes</title><link>/posts/japanese-men-eating-small-fish-were-32-percent-less-likely-to-get-diabetes.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/japanese-men-eating-small-fish-were-32-percent-less-likely-to-get-diabetes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="fish-intake-and-type-2-diabetes-in-japanese-men-and-women-the-japan-public-health-centerbased-prospective-study123">Fish intake and type 2 diabetes in Japanese men and women: the Japan Public Health Center–based Prospective Study1,2,3&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr September 2011 vol. 94 no. 3 884-891&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Akiko Nanri, Tetsuya Mizoue, Mitsuhiko Noda, Yoshihiko Takahashi, Yumi Matsushita, Kalpana Poudel-Tandukar, Masayuki Kato, Shino Oba, Manami Inoue,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shoichiro Tsugane, and for the Japan Public Health Center–based Prospective Study Group&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1From the Department of Epidemiology and Prevention, International Clinical Research Center, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan (AN, TM, YM, and KP-T); the Department of Diabetes and Metabolic Medicine, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan (MN and YT); the Japan Foundation for the Promotion of International Medical Research Cooperation, Tokyo, Japan (MK); the Department of Health Promotion, National Institute of Public Health, Wako, Japan (SO); and the Epidemiology and Prevention Division, Research Center for Cancer Prevention and Screening, National Cancer Center, Tokyo, Japan (MI and ST).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low levels of vitamin D in Japanese office workers</title><link>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-in-japanese-office-workers.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-in-japanese-office-workers.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-and-season-specific-correlates-in-japanese-adults">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentrations and Season-Specific Correlates in Japanese Adults.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Epidemiol. 2011 Jul 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nanri A, Foo LH, Nakamura K, Hori A, Poudel-Tandukar K, Matsushita Y, Mizoue T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Prevention, International Clinical Research Center, National Center for Global Health and Medicine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Several lines of evidence indicate an important role for vitamin D in the prevention of a range of diseases. Blood vitamin D levels show clear seasonal variation; however, data on the determinants of vitamin D status for each season are limited. We investigated the association between lifestyle and serum vitamin D concentration by season in Japanese workers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – China air conditioning disease is the result of less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-china-air-conditioning-disease-is-the-result-of-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-china-air-conditioning-disease-is-the-result-of-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hypothesis-people-living-in-sunny-climates-who-can-afford-air-conditioning-get-less-vitamin-d">Hypothesis: People living in sunny climates who can afford air conditioning get less vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/air-conditioning-probably-has-decreased-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 81">Air Conditioning probably has decreased vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/depression-in-uae-peaks-in-the-summer-probably-due-to-sun-avoidance">Depression in UAE peaks in the summer – probably due to sun avoidance – Feb 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="air-conditioning-diseasehttpwwwmyhealthbeijingcomillnesse2809cair-conditioning-diseasee2809d">&lt;a href="http://www.myhealthbeijing.com/illness/%E2%80%9Cair-conditioning-disease%E2%80%9D/">“Air Conditioning Disease”?&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>By Dr. Richard Saint Cyr, on August 15th, 2010&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boy, was this summer a scorcher. Even as I write this, hundreds of people in Russia are still dying from heat stroke and the peat-fire pollution. Here in China, with the temperatures raging a couple weeks ago, most newspapers were filled with health advice stories. Discussing how to avoid heat stroke, of course? Uh, not really — many talked about that &lt;span style="color:#900;">uniquely Chinese malady, “air conditioning disease“.&lt;/span>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>