<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Orient on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/orient.html</link><description>Recent content in Orient on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/orient/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Japanese men eating small fish were 32 percent less likely to get diabetes</title><link>/posts/japanese-men-eating-small-fish-were-32-percent-less-likely-to-get-diabetes.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/japanese-men-eating-small-fish-were-32-percent-less-likely-to-get-diabetes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="fish-intake-and-type-2-diabetes-in-japanese-men-and-women-the-japan-public-health-centerbased-prospective-study123">Fish intake and type 2 diabetes in Japanese men and women: the Japan Public Health Center–based Prospective Study1,2,3&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr September 2011 vol. 94 no. 3 884-891&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Akiko Nanri, Tetsuya Mizoue, Mitsuhiko Noda, Yoshihiko Takahashi, Yumi Matsushita, Kalpana Poudel-Tandukar, Masayuki Kato, Shino Oba, Manami Inoue,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shoichiro Tsugane, and for the Japan Public Health Center–based Prospective Study Group&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1From the Department of Epidemiology and Prevention, International Clinical Research Center, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan (AN, TM, YM, and KP-T); the Department of Diabetes and Metabolic Medicine, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan (MN and YT); the Japan Foundation for the Promotion of International Medical Research Cooperation, Tokyo, Japan (MK); the Department of Health Promotion, National Institute of Public Health, Wako, Japan (SO); and the Epidemiology and Prevention Division, Research Center for Cancer Prevention and Screening, National Cancer Center, Tokyo, Japan (MI and ST).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low levels of vitamin D in Japanese office workers</title><link>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-in-japanese-office-workers.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-in-japanese-office-workers.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-and-season-specific-correlates-in-japanese-adults">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentrations and Season-Specific Correlates in Japanese Adults.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Epidemiol. 2011 Jul 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nanri A, Foo LH, Nakamura K, Hori A, Poudel-Tandukar K, Matsushita Y, Mizoue T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Prevention, International Clinical Research Center, National Center for Global Health and Medicine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Several lines of evidence indicate an important role for vitamin D in the prevention of a range of diseases. Blood vitamin D levels show clear seasonal variation; however, data on the determinants of vitamin D status for each season are limited. We investigated the association between lifestyle and serum vitamin D concentration by season in Japanese workers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – China air conditioning disease is the result of less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-china-air-conditioning-disease-is-the-result-of-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-china-air-conditioning-disease-is-the-result-of-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hypothesis-people-living-in-sunny-climates-who-can-afford-air-conditioning-get-less-vitamin-d">Hypothesis: People living in sunny climates who can afford air conditioning get less vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/air-conditioning-probably-has-decreased-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 81">Air Conditioning probably has decreased vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/depression-in-uae-peaks-in-the-summer-probably-due-to-sun-avoidance">Depression in UAE peaks in the summer – probably due to sun avoidance – Feb 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="air-conditioning-diseasehttpwwwmyhealthbeijingcomillnesse2809cair-conditioning-diseasee2809d">&lt;a href="http://www.myhealthbeijing.com/illness/%E2%80%9Cair-conditioning-disease%E2%80%9D/">“Air Conditioning Disease”?&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>By Dr. Richard Saint Cyr, on August 15th, 2010&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boy, was this summer a scorcher. Even as I write this, hundreds of people in Russia are still dying from heat stroke and the peat-fire pollution. Here in China, with the temperatures raging a couple weeks ago, most newspapers were filled with health advice stories. Discussing how to avoid heat stroke, of course? Uh, not really — many talked about that &lt;span style="color:#900;">uniquely Chinese malady, “air conditioning disease“.&lt;/span>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>