<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Depression on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/depression.html</link><description>Recent content in Depression on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/depression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mood disorders 11X worse for older adults with low vitamin D – 2006</title><link>/posts/mood-disorders-11x-worse-for-older-adults-with-low-vitamin-d-2006.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mood-disorders-11x-worse-for-older-adults-with-low-vitamin-d-2006.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-low-mood-and-worse-cognitive-performance-in-older-adults">Vitamin D Deficiency Is Associated With Low Mood and Worse Cognitive Performance in Older Adults&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>American Journal of Geriatric Psychiatry: December 2006 - Volume 14 - Issue 12 - pp 1032-1040&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wilkins, Consuelo H. M.D.; Sheline, Yvette I. M.D.; Roe, Catherine M. Ph.D.; Birge, Stanley J. M.D.; Morris, John C. M.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency is common in older adults and has been implicated in psychiatric and neurologic disorders. This study examined the relationship among vitamin D status, cognitive performance, mood, and physical performance in older adults.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Psychiatric disorders 4X more likely in teens if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/psychiatric-disorders-4x-more-likely-in-teens-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/psychiatric-disorders-4x-more-likely-in-teens-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="low-levels-of-vitamin-d-linked-to-teen-delusions-hallucinationshttpwwwfoxnewscomhealth20111102low-levels-vitamin-d-linked-to-teen-delusions-hallucinations-foxnews">&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/health/2011/11/02/low-levels-vitamin-d-linked-to-teen-delusions-hallucinations/">Low Levels of Vitamin D Linked to Teen Delusions, Hallucinations&lt;/a> FoxNews&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A group of researchers led by Dr. Barbara L. Gracious, a psychiatrist at Nationwide Children’s Hospital in Columbus, Ohio, presented data at that meeting showing that adolescents who were vitamin D deficient showed a fourfold (400 percent) increased rate of psychotic symptoms, compared to other adolescents with normal vitamin D levels who sought psychiatric treatment at the University of Rochester, in New York.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Depression 40 percent more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/depression-40-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/depression-40-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="depression-is-associated-with-low-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-among-jordanian-adults-results-from-a-national-population-survey">Depression is associated with low levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D among Jordanian adults: results from a national population survey.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2012 Jun;262(4):321-7. (online first - Oct 2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jaddou HY, Batieha AM, Khader YS, Kanaan SH, El-Khateeb MS, Ajlouni KM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Community Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Irbid, Jordan, &lt;a href="mailto:jaddou@just.edu.jo">jaddou@just.edu.jo&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and elevated serum parathyroid hormone (PTH) have been associated with depression in clinical settings, this link in community-dwelling individuals is inconclusive. The present study aimed at examining the association between serum 25(OH)D and PTH levels and the presence of depression in a national population-based household sample of 4,002 Jordanian participants aged ?25 years. The DASS21 depression scale was used to screen for depression, and serum concentrations of 25(OH)D and PTH were measured by radioimmunoassay. Multiple logistic regression models were used to explore the association between serum 25(OH)D and PTH levels and depression. The unadjusted odds ratio (OR) decreased linearly with increasing quartiles of serum 25(OH)D (P (trend) = 0.00). The OR for having depression was significantly higher among individuals in the first and second quartiles (OR = 1.4, 1.23, respectively) than among those in the fourth quartile (P values = 0.00 and 0.03, respectively). This relationship remained significant after adjusting for age, sex, marital status, education, BMI, serum creatinine, number of chronic diseases (OR = 1.39 and 1.21 and P values = 0.00 and 0.05, respectively) and after further adjustment for exercise, altitude, and smoking (OR = 1.48 and 1.24, respectively, and P values = 0.00 and 0.03, respectively). No significant association was found between serum PTH levels and depression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>36 percent less depression when have high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/36-percent-less-depression-when-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/36-percent-less-depression-when-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-are-associated-with-depression-in-an-adult-norwegian-population">Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels are associated with depression in an adult Norwegian population.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Kjærgaard M, Joakimsen R, Jorde R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Psychiatry Res. 2011 Jul 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Observational and intervention studies have suggested an association between low levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and depressive symptoms in several subgroups of disease and age. This study tests the hypothesis in a general population. Our data are based on 10,086 persons who participated in the sixth Tromsø study carried out in 2007-2008. Depressive symptoms were evaluated using Hopkins Symptoms Check List 10 (SCL-10) based on answers from a questionnaire.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Serotonin related to season, light and perhaps latitude and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/serotonin-related-to-season-light-and-perhaps-latitude-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/serotonin-related-to-season-light-and-perhaps-latitude-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-on-the-web">See on the web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clips-from-wikipedia-sadhttpenwikipediaorgwikiseasonal_affective_disorder">Clips from &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seasonal_affective_disorder">WikiPedia SAD&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#possible-contributions-of-skin-pigmentation-and-vitamin-d-in-a-polyfactorial-model-of-seasonal-affective-disorder---2014">Possible contributions of skin pigmentation and vitamin D in a polyfactorial model of seasonal affective disorder - 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#light-therapy-as-a-treatment-for-epilepsy---2011">Light therapy as a treatment for epilepsy. - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effect-of-sunlight-exposure-on-cognitive-function-among-depressed-and-non-depressed-participants-a-regards-cross-sectional-study--2009">Effect of sunlight exposure on cognitive function among depressed and non-depressed participants: a REGARDS cross-sectional study.- 2009&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#seasonal-variation-in-human-brain-serotonin-transporter-binding--2008">Seasonal variation in human brain serotonin transporter binding.- 2008&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-on-the-web">See on the web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindcouncil.org/health-conditions/mental-health-and-learning-disorders/depression/">VitaminDCouncil&lt;/a> new and working as of June 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis non-severe depression and diabetes related by low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-non-severe-depression-and-diabetes-related-by-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-non-severe-depression-and-diabetes-related-by-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="depression-and-type-2-diabetes-mellitus-a-call-to-explore-the-common-cause-hypothesis">Depression and Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: A Call to Explore the Common Cause Hypothesis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Briana Mezuk, PhD, Department of Epidemiology and Community Health, Virginia Commonwealth University School of Medicine, Richmond, VA (&lt;a href="mailto:bmezuk@vcu.edu">bmezuk@vcu.edu&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Archives of Internal Medicine	Vol. 171 No. 11, June 13, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Short item with just the first 150 words of the full text)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read the recent article by Pan and colleagues1 with great interest. Their findings using the Short-Form 36 Health Status Survey suggest that even mood disturbances that do not require clinical intervention are predictive of diabetes. This interpretation, combined with the counterintuitive finding that nonsevere depression was similarly, and potentially more strongly, associated with diabetes risk than severe depression reported in another recent article,2 begs the question(s):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SAD rate 10X higher in cloudy Seattle than sunny Florida</title><link>/posts/sad-rate-10x-higher-in-cloudy-seattle-than-sunny-florida.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sad-rate-10x-higher-in-cloudy-seattle-than-sunny-florida.html</guid><description>&lt;p>from&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.king5.com/news/local/Winter-blues-are-the-real-deal-say-Seattle-doctors-119639824.html">http://www.king5.com/news/local/Winter-blues-are-the-real-deal-say-Seattle-doctors-119639824.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Depression in UAE peaks in the summer – probably due to sun avoidance</title><link>/posts/depression-in-uae-peaks-in-the-summer-probably-due-to-sun-avoidance.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/depression-in-uae-peaks-in-the-summer-probably-due-to-sun-avoidance.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sunshine-sadness-and-seasonality-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-depressive-symptoms-in-the-united-arab-emirates-uae">Sunshine, Sadness and Seasonality: 25-Hydroxyvitamin D, and Depressive Symptoms in the United Arab Emirates (UAE)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Authors: Thomas, Justin; Anouti, Fatme A.l.; Hasani, Sara Al; Abdel-Wareth, Laila; Haq, Afrozul&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The International Journal of Mental Health Promotion, Volume 13, Number 1, February 2011 , pp. 23-26(4)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Publisher: The Clifford Beers Foundation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several studies have described the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in Gulf Arab populations and focused on the physical health consequences of VTD deficiency. No work to date on this population has explored the psychological consequences of VTD deficiency or the issue of seasonal variations in deficiency and symptom severity. The aim of this study was to assess seasonal variation in depressive symptoms and 25-Hydroxyvitamin D levels, exploring the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and mood in female university students in the United Arab Emirates. A cross-sectional study design was used to assess seasonal variation in mood, and a correlational analysis to assess the relationship between vitamin D levels and depressive symptoms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less than 20 ng vitamin D increases depression by 80 percent</title><link>/posts/less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d-increases-depression-by-80-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d-increases-depression-by-80-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-vitamin-d-concentrations-are-related-to-depression-in-young-adult-us-population-the-third-national-health-and-nutrition-examination-survey">Serum vitamin D concentrations are related to depression in young adult US population: the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int Arch Med. 2010; 3: 29. PMCID: PMC2996356&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vijay Ganji,corresponding author1 Cristiana Milone,1 Mildred M Cody,1 Frances McCarty,2 and Yong T Wang3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Nutrition, School of Health Professions, College of Health and Human Sciences, Georgia State University, 140 Decatur Street, Atlanta, GA 30302, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Institute of Public Health, College of Health and Human Sciences, Georgia State University, 140 Decatur Street, Atlanta, GA 30302, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Earthquake and Vitamin D - several studies</title><link>/posts/earthquake-and-vitamin-d-several-studies.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/earthquake-and-vitamin-d-several-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-nutritional-status-of-reproductive-women-at-one-year-after-the-disaster-of-earthquake-in-wenchuan">(The nutritional status of reproductive women at one year after the disaster of Earthquake in Wenchuan)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-articles-on-vitamin-d-and-stress-at-vitamindwiki">Some articles on Vitamin D and stress at VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#study-by-same-chinese-authors-found-92-of-children-under-5-in-earthquake-area-were-vitamin-d-insufficient">Study by same Chinese authors found 92% of children under 5 in earthquake area were vitamin D insufficient&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#200000-iu-of-vitamin-d-monthly-did-not-help-after-earthquake---rct-dec-2014">200,000 IU of Vitamin D monthly did not help after earthquake - RCT Dec 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-nutritional-status-of-reproductive-women-at-one-year-after-the-disaster-of-earthquake-in-wenchuan">(The nutritional status of reproductive women at one year after the disaster of Earthquake in Wenchuan)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Zhonghua Yu Fang Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2010 Aug;44(8):686-90.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Young almost 2X more likely to be depressed if vitamin D less than 20ng</title><link>/posts/young-almost-2x-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-vitamin-d-less-than-20ng.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/young-almost-2x-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-vitamin-d-less-than-20ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-vitamin-d-concentrations-are-related-to-depression-in-young-adult-us-population-the-third-national-health-and-nutrition-examination-survey">Serum vitamin D concentrations are related to depression in young adult US population: the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Vijay Ganji Cristiana Milone , Mildred M Cody Frances McCarthy and Yong T Wang&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International Archives of Medicine 2010, 3:29doi:10.1186/1755-7682-3-29&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 	11 November 2010, Abstract (provisional)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D receptors have been mapped throughout the brain suggesting a role for vitamin D in psychosomatic disorders. Results from previous epidemiological studies on relation between vitamin D status and depression are equivocal. Also, limited information is available relating vitamin D status with depression in young adult US population.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>