<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Depression on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/depression/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Depression on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/depression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SSRI Drugs Can Cause Chronic Fatigue Syndrome - Mercola</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ssri-drugs-can-cause-chronic-fatigue-syndrome-mercola/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ssri-drugs-can-cause-chronic-fatigue-syndrome-mercola/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;ssri-drugs-can-cause-chronic-fatigue-syndrome&#34;&gt;SSRI Drugs Can Cause Chronic Fatigue Syndrome&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2024/04/19/selective-serotonin-reuptake-inhibitors.aspx?ui=d738e3df52a8a14aea9298fe6ec5bc113ed0d6d7922f31861727d54a43cbe29d&amp;amp;sd=20121119&amp;amp;cid_source=dnl&amp;amp;cid_medium=email&amp;amp;cid_content=art1ReadMore&amp;amp;cid=20240419_HL2&amp;amp;foDate=false&amp;amp;mid=DM1559692&amp;amp;rid=2099719523&#34;&gt;Mercola April 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STORY AT-A-GLANCE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SSRIs, which increase serotonin levels, have been linked to chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS). A study showed that administering  &lt;strong&gt;Prozac (fluoxetine)&lt;/strong&gt;  to mice at high dosages induced symptoms of CFS, suggesting a link between excessive serotonin levels and the condition&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Symptom reversal was achieved with the serotonin inhibitor fenclonine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other serotonin inhibitors include Benadryl, the H2 blocker Pepcid (famotidine), aspirin, progesterone and GABA&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Adolescent Anxiety and suicide rates - GBD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/international-adolescent-anxiety-and-suicide-rates-gbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/international-adolescent-anxiety-and-suicide-rates-gbd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;thirty-year-trends-of-anxiety-disorders-among-adolescents-based-on-the-2019-global-burden-of-disease-study&#34;&gt;Thirty-year trends of anxiety disorders among adolescents based on the 2019 Global Burden of Disease Study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Xiaohan Liu, Fan Yang, Ning Huang, Shan Zhang and Jing Guo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background Anxiety disorders are the most common psychiatric problems, affecting approximately 1 in 12 children and 1 in 4 adolescents. Understanding the incidence, burden and correlated risks of anxiety disorders among children and adolescents can help identify areas of success, stagnation and emerging threats, thereby facilitating effective improvement strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elderly with low vitamin D were depressed, anxious, or stressed (Saudi Arabia)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/elderly-with-low-vitamin-d-were-depressed-anxious-or-stressed-saudi-arabia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/elderly-with-low-vitamin-d-were-depressed-anxious-or-stressed-saudi-arabia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-concealed-hazard-vitamin-d-deficiency-awareness-and-its-impact-on-psychological-wellness-among-elderly&#34;&gt;The Concealed Hazard: Vitamin D Deficiency, Awareness, and Its Impact on Psychological Wellness among Elderly&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Noha Ahmed Mohameda, Sameer Hamdy Hafeza,b*, Ahmad A. Alshehric, Abdalla MohamedAhmed Osman Abdallab, Hoda Khalifa Abdelhady e,f, Hanan Saad Abdullah Alwadeib, Abdelelah Abdelgadir Ahmedd, Elsadig Eltaher Hamed Abdulrahmand, Nahla Elradhi Abdulrahmanb, Nahid Khalil Elfakib, Sadeq Abdo Alwesabid , Mohammed Ateeg Abdelrahman Ahmedb&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Depression, Anxiety, or Stress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;250&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency and its consequences is expected to increase with ageing. Consequently, this study aimed to explore the prevalence of the hidden danger posed by vitamin D deficiency among the elderly, awareness and its impact on psychological well-being. A cross-sectional study design was employed in Najran City, using a convenient sample of 100 elderly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More depression if less vitamin D getting to cells (poor VDR)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-depression-if-less-vitamin-d-getting-to-cells-poor-vdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-depression-if-less-vitamin-d-getting-to-cells-poor-vdr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;interaction-between-fokl-polymorphism-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-the-symptoms-of-mental-disorders-in-adults-a-population-based-study&#34;&gt;Interaction between Fokl polymorphism and vitamin D deficiency in the symptoms of mental disorders in adults: a population-based study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sci Rep. 2024 Mar 22;14(1):6925. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-57558-1.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-57558-1.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thaís da Silva Sabião 1, Luiz Antônio Alves de Menezes-Júnior 2, Aline Priscila Batista 3, Samara Silva de Moura 2, Adriana Lúcia Meireles 4, Mariana Carvalho de Menezes 4, George Luiz Lins Machado-Coelho 5, Júlia Cristina Cardoso Carraro 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Caption: The variable in green and with the “►” symbol was the exposure variable; in blue and with the letter “I” was the response variables; variables in blue are the antecedents of the outcome variable; and those in red are antecedents of the outcome and exposure variables;the variable in gray is a collider and indicates a closed or blocked path.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depression with low vitamin D increased risk of CVD and Cancer deaths</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-with-low-vitamin-d-increased-risk-of-cvd-and-cancer-deaths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-with-low-vitamin-d-increased-risk-of-cvd-and-cancer-deaths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;–-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;association-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-with-all-cause-and-cause-specific-mortality-among-individuals-with-depression-a-cohort-study&#34;&gt;Association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin d concentrations with all-cause and cause-specific mortality among individuals with depression: A cohort study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Journal of Affective Disorders &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jad.2024.02.018&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jad.2024.02.018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yafei Mao a b, Xinyuan Li a, Yanming Li a, Shumin Zhu a, Xu Han b, Rui Zhao b, Yulan Geng a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Limited evidence exists on the relationship between vitamin D status and mortality in depressed patients.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Methods&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study investigates serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span&gt;[25(OH)D]&lt;/span&gt; concentrations in 8417 adults with depression among the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES, 2005–2018). Mortality outcomes were assessed through National Death Index records up to December 31, 2019. Cox proportional risk models estimated risk ratios (HR) and 95 % confidence intervals (CI) for all-cause, cardiovascular disease (CVD), and cancer mortality. Restricted cubic spline analyses explored the nonlinear association of serum 25(OH)D levels with mortality, using the likelihood ratio test for nonlinearity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central Nervous System protection by Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-nervous-system-protection-by-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-nervous-system-protection-by-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;molecular-regulation-of-the-cns-by-vitamin-d&#34;&gt;Molecular Regulation of the CNS by Vitamin D&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Physiol Res 2023 Dec 17;72(S4):S339-S356.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;L Máčová 1, R Kancheva, M Bičíková&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;Factors that are up-regulated are marked in green&lt;/span&gt;%%%  &lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;factors that are down-regulated are in red&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D is a lipid-soluble vitamin that can be found in some foods. It is also produced endogenously (in the presence of ultraviolet light), transported through the blood to the targets organs and this is the reason to consider vitamin D as a hormone. It is known that vitamin D has genomic and non-genomic effects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low Vitamin D is associated with risk of Depression 5X, Stress 4.8 X, and Anxiety 3.9 X (Saudi Arabia college students)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/low-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-risk-of-depression-5x-stress-48-x-and-anxiety-3-ollege-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/low-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-risk-of-depression-5x-stress-48-x-and-anxiety-3-ollege-students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;impact-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-on-mental-health-in-university-students-a-cross-sectional-study&#34;&gt;Impact of Vitamin D Deficiency on Mental Health in University Students: A Cross-Sectional Study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Healthcare (Basel) . 2023 Jul 23;11(14):2097. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare11142097.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/healthcare11142097.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mansour Almuqbil 1, Moneer E Almadani 2, Salem Ahmad Albraiki 3, Ali Musharraf Alamri 3, Ahmed Alshehri 4, Adel Alghamdi 5, Sultan Alshehri 6, Syed Mohammed Basheeruddin Asdaq 7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Students pursuing a university education are vulnerable to psychological burdens such as depression, anxiety, and stress. The frequency of vitamin D deficiency, on the other hand, is extensively recognized worldwide, and vitamin D regulates various neurological pathways in the brain that control psychological function. Therefore, the goal of this cross-sectional study was to determine the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and psychological burden among university students in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. During March-May 2021 in Riyadh, a cross-sectional comparative study survey was delivered to university students. The DASS-21 scale was used to determine the severity of the psychological burden. Both univariate and binomial regression analyses were conducted to analyze the level of significance and influence of several factors on the development of psychological burden. The data were analyzed with SPSS-IBM, and a p value of &amp;lt;0.05 was considered significant. Of the 480 students recruited for the study, 287 (59.79%) had a vitamin D deficiency. Significantly (p = 0.048), a high proportion of the vitamin D-deficient students attained a low or moderate GPA compared to the control cohort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depression would be cost-effectively decreased in teens by Vitamin D (Iran)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-would-be-cost-effectively-decreased-in-teens-by-vitamin-d-iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-would-be-cost-effectively-decreased-in-teens-by-vitamin-d-iran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;is-vitamin-d-supplementation-program-in-iranian-schools-effective-in-reducing-adolescent-depressive-symptoms-cost-effectiveness-study&#34;&gt;Is vitamin D supplementation program in Iranian schools effective in reducing adolescent depressive symptoms? Cost effectiveness study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BMC Public Health . 2023 Jul 20;23(1):1393. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-023-16244-z.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1186/s12889-023-16244-z.&lt;/a&gt; PDF behind paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seyed Vahid Jasemi 1, Zhale Zandieh 2, Narges Zandieh 1, Mohsen Rezaei Hemami 3, Ali Darvishi 4 5, Zahra Abdollahi 6, Ramin Heshmat 7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Purpose: We aimed to assess the cost-effectiveness of the vitamin D supplementation program in Iranian adolescents reducing adolescent depressive Symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global burden of brain disorders surpasses cardiovascular disease and cancer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/global-burden-of-brain-disorders-surpasses-cardiovascular-disease-and-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/global-burden-of-brain-disorders-surpasses-cardiovascular-disease-and-cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;from-mdedgehttpswwwmdedgecomneurologyarticle264086neurologyglobal-burden-brain-disorders-surpasses-cardiovascular-diseaseecdwnl_eve_230715_mdedge&#34;&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdedge.com/neurology/article/264086/neurology/global-burden-brain-disorders-surpasses-cardiovascular-disease?ecd=WNL_EVE_230715_mdedge&#34;&gt;MDEdge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brain disorders, including mental illness, neurologic conditions, and stroke, account for more than 15% of all health loss worldwide – more than either cardiovascular disease or cancer – at huge cost to health care systems and society, an analysis of data from the most recent Global Burden of Disease (GBD) study shows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“The burden of brain conditions will increase as populations continue to grow and age,” said study presenter Shayla Smith, MPH, an epidemiologist at the Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation, the University of Washington, Seattle, in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depression in seniors greatly reduced by Vitamin D (e.g. 50,000 IU) – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-in-seniors-greatly-reduced-by-vitamin-d-eg-50000-iu-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-in-seniors-greatly-reduced-by-vitamin-d-eg-50000-iu-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-supplementation-for-depression-in-older-adults-a-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials&#34;&gt;Vitamin D supplementation for depression in older adults: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front Nutr. 2023 Jun 21;10:1169436. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2023.1169436&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3389/fnut.2023.1169436&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yoonjung Park 1 2, Young-Mi Ah 3, Yun Mi Yu 1 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 2 trials giving enough vitamin D to be meaningful&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: In older adults, depression is associated with several other clinical problems such as cognitive impairment and low quality of life. Several studies have evaluated the relationship between vitamin D and depression in older adults; however, the results have been controversial thus far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depressed infants have very low Vitamin D (7.5 ng)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/depressed-infants-have-very-low-vitamin-d-75-ng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/depressed-infants-have-very-low-vitamin-d-75-ng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;serum-vitamin-d-status-in-full-term-neonates-with-severe-perinatal-depression&#34;&gt;Serum Vitamin D status in full-term neonates with severe perinatal depression&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J Neonatal Perinatal Med . 2023;16(2):257-264. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3233/NPM-230020&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3233/NPM-230020&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind a $27 paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;P Batra 1, P Singh 1, R S Ahmed 2, D Harit 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Severe perinatal depression is a significant cause of mortality and morbidity in neonates. Vitamin D levels were observed to be low in mothers and their neonates with hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy in some studies, owing to its neuroprotective properties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infants getting an additional 800 IU of vitamin D for 2 years had 60% fewer psychiatric symptoms at age 7 – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/infants-getting-an-additional-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-2-years-had-60-percent-few-ms-at-age-7-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/infants-getting-an-additional-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-2-years-had-60-percent-few-ms-at-age-7-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;~~#00F:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reduced: Autism, ADHD, Depression. etc&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finland was supplementing milk with Vitamin D during the study, so both groups got more D&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefit if it had increased vitamin D dose with increased body weight&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Infant body weight triples in 24 months - so probably need 3600 IU at 24 months&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefit if it had adjusted vitamin D dose with BMI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Obese needs &amp;gt;2X more vitamin D&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefits if supplementation had started before birth&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefits with non-daily supplementation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study found a 79% reduction in problems if 1200 IU  when mothers had Vitamin D levels &amp;lt;30 ng&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preemies need even more vitamin D – no comment in study about preemies~~&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-the-first-2-years-of-life-on-psychiatric-symptoms-at-ages-6-to-8-years-a-randomized-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;Effect of Vitamin D3 Supplementation in the First 2 Years of Life on Psychiatric Symptoms at Ages 6 to 8 Years: A Randomized Clinical Trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JAMA Netw Open. 2023 May 1;6(5):e2314319. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.14319.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.14319.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17% of US currently depressed (Vitamin D etc. can reduce it)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/17-percent-of-us-currently-depressed-vitamin-d-etc-can-reduce-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/17-percent-of-us-currently-depressed-vitamin-d-etc-can-reduce-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;Vitamin D is the lowest-cost depression treatment: only pennies a day %%%Single 50,000 IU capsule bi-weekly or weekly &lt;a href=&#34;https://vitamindwiki.com/tiki-index.php?page_id=11241&#34;&gt;(RCT)&lt;/a&gt;%%% Start with 50,000 IU daily for the first week to get results in 1 week, %%% &lt;del&gt;hs&lt;/span&gt;hs&lt;/del&gt; otherwise must wait for 2 months to notice reduced depression%%%        &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/can-get-50000-iu-vitamin-d-anywhere-on-the-globe&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Can get 50,000 IU Vitamin D anywhere on the globe&#34;&gt;Can get 50,000 IU Vitamin D anywhere on the globe&lt;/a&gt;%%%Both Omega-3 and Magnesium also reduce depression ~~&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depression in Icelandic men 2.5 X more likely if vitamin D deficient</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-in-icelandic-men-25-x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-in-icelandic-men-25-x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficient/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;depression-and-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-older-adults-living-at-northern-latitudes--ages-reykjavik-study&#34;&gt;Depression and serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D in older adults living at northern latitudes – AGES-Reykjavik Study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Journal of Nutritional Science (2015), vol. 4, e37, page 1 of 8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cindy M. Imai. Thorhallur I. Halldorsson, Gudny Eiriksdottir, Mary F. Cotch, Laufey Steingrimsdottir, Inga Thorsdottir, Lenore J. Launer, Tamara Harris, Vilmundur Gudnason and Ingibjorg Gunnarsdottir&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unit for Nutrition Research, Landspitali – The National University Hospital of Iceland and Faculty of Food Science and Nutrition, School of Health Sciences, University of Iceland, Eiriksgata 29, 101 Reykjavik, Iceland&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-partum depression and low Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-partum-depression-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-partum-depression-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;only-vitamin-d-was-found-to-treat-post-partum-depression---meta-analysis-april-2023&#34;&gt;Only Vitamin D was found to treat post-partum depression - Meta-analysis April 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dietary interventions for perinatal depression and anxiety: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Am J Clin Nutr. 2023 Apr 3;S0002-9165(23)46315-0. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajcnut.2023.03.025&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.ajcnut.2023.03.025&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zoe Tsai 1, Nirmay Shah 2, Umair Tahir 2, Neda Mortaji 3, Sawayra Owais 4, Maude Perreault 5, Ryan J Van Lieshout 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Dietary interventions are a widely available intervention for depression and anxiety among pregnant and/or postpartum (i.e., perinatal) persons but their effectiveness is not well known.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depression is especially reduced by large intermittent doses of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-is-especially-reduced-by-large-intermittent-doses-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-is-especially-reduced-by-large-intermittent-doses-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;efficacy-and-acceptability-of-vitamin-d-supplements-for-depressed-patients-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials&#34;&gt;Efficacy and acceptability of vitamin D supplements for depressed patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrition 2023 Jan 7;108:111968. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nut.2022.111968&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2022.111968&lt;/a&gt; PDFis behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maytinee Srifuengfung 1, Somporn Srifuengfung 2, Chalermsri Pummangura 2, Keerati Pattanaseri 1, Awirut Oon-Arom 3, Manit Srisurapanont 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objectives: This systematic review and meta-analysis synthesized the evidence from randomized controlled trials comparing vitamin D and placebo in reducing depressive symptoms and contributing to all-cause dropout rates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depression: Low vitamin D in the strongest of 11 risk factors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-low-vitamin-d-in-the-strongest-of-11-risk-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/depression-low-vitamin-d-in-the-strongest-of-11-risk-factors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-four-horsemen-of-the-apocalypse-cancer-depression-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-obesity-an-observational-study&#34;&gt;The Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse: Cancer, Depression, Vitamin D Deficiency, and Obesity: An Observational Study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Disease Markers Volume 2023 | Article ID 9652491 | &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1155/2023/9652491&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1155/2023/9652491&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Savas Tuna 1, Mehmet Akif Aydin 2, Muhammet Fatih Aydin 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Note: They did not measure Omega-3  %%% Serum Magnesium is a poor indicator of free Magnesium&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objective: Studies aiming at illuminating the complex relationships between cancer, obesity, 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25-OHD) deficiency, and body fat percentage are ongoing. The objective of this study was to investigate the relationships between 25-OHD deficiency, visceral fat tissue, and the Beck Depression Inventory (BDI) in cancer patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
