<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Depression on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/depression.html</link><description>Recent content in Depression on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/depression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The new happy pill, vitamin D – Prevention</title><link>/posts/the-new-happy-pill-vitamin-d-prevention.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-new-happy-pill-vitamin-d-prevention.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-new-happy-pill">The New Happy Pill&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="a-natural-way-to-make-you-shine">A natural way to make you shine&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>By Jessica Chia, Prevention Magazine&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/happy-pill.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Vitamin D could be your ticket to a brighter mood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sunshine vitamin isn’t just for bone health—maintaining healthy levels of the vitamin can combat depressive symptoms, according to a cluster of preliminary research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A weekly dose of 50,000 IU of vitamin D lifted the moods of a group of 46 vitamin D-deficient women with type 2 diabetes. On average, the women alleviated their depressive symptoms from moderately- to mildly-depressed, according to a presentation at the American Diabetes Association’s (ADA) 73rd Scientific Session in Chicago. This mimics the results of another study that was presented at the Endocrine Society 94th Annual Meeting in 2012, in which clinically depressed women began taking vitamin D supplements in addition to their usual antidepressant medications. Once their blood levels of the fat-soluble vitamin were brought up to a healthy level, these women reported fewer depressive symptoms. In one case, a woman’s depressive symptom classification fell from “severely depressed” to “minimally depressed.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>99 percent of psychiatric population had less than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/99-percent-of-psychiatric-population-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/99-percent-of-psychiatric-population-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fewest Google searches for Mental Health when there is lots of vitamin D from the sun</title><link>/posts/fewest-google-searches-for-mental-health-when-there-is-lots-of-vitamin-d-from-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fewest-google-searches-for-mental-health-when-there-is-lots-of-vitamin-d-from-the-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="seasonality-in-seeking-mental-health-information-on-google">Seasonality in Seeking Mental Health Information on Google&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>American Journal of Preventive Medicine. Volume 44, Issue 5 , Pages 520-525, May 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John W. Ayers, PhD, MA. Benjamin M. Althouse, ScM , Jon-Patrick Allem, MA , J. Niels Rosenquist, MD, PhD , Daniel E. Ford, MD, MPH&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background” Population mental health surveillance is an important challenge limited by resource constraints, long time lags in data collection, and stigma. One promising approach to bridge similar gaps elsewhere has been the use of passively generated digital data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D and depression - Study and meta-analysis,</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-depression-study-and-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-depression-study-and-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-association-between-low-vitamin-d-and-depressive-disorders">The association between low vitamin D and depressive disorders&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#8-less-likely-to-be-depressed-for-10ng-higher-level-of-vitamin-d---meta-analysis">8% less likely to be depressed for 10ng higher level of vitamin D - Meta-analysis&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="the-association-between-low-vitamin-d-and-depressive-disorders">The association between low vitamin D and depressive disorders&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Molecular Psychiatry , (9 April 2013) | doi:10.1038/mp.2013.36&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Y Milaneschi, W Hoogendijk, P Lips, A C Heijboer, R Schoevers, A M van Hemert, A T F Beekman, J H Smit and B W J H Penninx&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Every school shooter had used antidepression drugs, but how many were low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/every-school-shooter-had-used-antidepression-drugs-but-how-many-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/every-school-shooter-had-used-antidepression-drugs-but-how-many-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary">Summary&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-evidence-ssri-antidepressants-cause-mass-shootings---sept-2024">The Evidence SSRI Antidepressants Cause Mass Shootings - Sept 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#87-of-mass-shooters-who-survived-had-mental-illnesses-many-associated-with-low-vitamin-d---dec-2023">87% of mass shooters who survived had mental illnesses, many associated with low Vitamin D - Dec 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#note-a-hrefpostsmagnesium-deficiency-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-947magnesium-deficiencya-is-also-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-poor-mental-health">Note: &lt;a href="/posts/magnesium-deficiency" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 947">Magnesium deficiency&lt;/a> is also associated with low vitamin D and poor mental health&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact&lt;/strong> People who are depressed are often low on vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact&lt;/strong> People who are depressed take antidepression drugs&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X more likely to be depressed if low vitamin D (cohort studies) - Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/2x-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-low-vitamin-d-cohort-studies-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-low-vitamin-d-cohort-studies-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-depression-in-adults-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D deficiency and depression in adults: systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The British Journal of Psychiatry (2013) 202: 100-107&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rebecca E. S. Anglin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zainab Samaan,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen D. Walter and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah D. McDonald&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rebecca E. S. Anglin, MD, PhD, FRCPC, Department of Psychiatry and Behavioural Neurosciences and Medicine, McMaster University; Zainab Samaan, MRCPsych, PhD, Department of Psychiatry and Behavioural Neurosciences, McMaster University; Stephen D. Walter, PhD, Department of Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, McMaster University; Sarah D. McDonald, MD, MSc, Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine, Departments of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Diagnostic Imaging and Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D intake associated with depressive symptoms in senior women</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-intake-associated-with-depressive-symptoms-in-senior-women.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-intake-associated-with-depressive-symptoms-in-senior-women.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-intake-from-foods-and-supplements-and-depressive-symptoms-in-a-diverse-population-of-older-women1234">Vitamin D intake from foods and supplements and depressive symptoms in a diverse population of older women1,2,3,4&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 October; 94(4): 1104–1112.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2011 August 24. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3945/ajcn.111.017384">doi: 10.3945/ajcn.111.017384&lt;/a>; PMCID: PMC3173027&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elizabeth R. Bertone-Johnson,corresponding author Sally I. Powers, Leslie Spangler, Robert L. Brunner, Yvonne L. Michael, Joseph C. Larson, Amy E. Millen, Maria N. Bueche, Elena Salmoirago-Blotcher, Simin Liu, Sylvia Wassertheil-Smoller, Judith K. Ockene, Ira Ockene, and JoAnn E. Manson&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mental health problems cut in half when have adequate level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mental-health-problems-cut-in-half-when-have-adequate-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mental-health-problems-cut-in-half-when-have-adequate-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-common-mental-disorders-in-mid-life-cross-sectional-and-prospective-findings">Vitamin D and common mental disorders in mid-life: cross-sectional and prospective findings&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clinical Nutrition, Jan 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jane Maddock, Diane J. Berry, Marie-Claude Geoffroy, Chris Power, Elina Hyppönen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MRC Centre of Epidemiology for Child Health/Centre for Paediatric Epidemiology and Biostatistics, UCL Institute of Child Health, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between vitamin D and common mental disorders (CMDs) remains unclear. We aimed to determine if behaviours affecting vitamin D concentrations differ between individuals with or without CMDs and evaluate, cross-sectionally and prospectively, the extent to which the association between 25(OH)D and CMDs are explained by these behaviours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First and 2nd generation migrants 2X more likely to have psychotic disorders</title><link>/posts/first-and-2nd-generation-migrants-2x-more-likely-to-have-psychotic-disorders.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/first-and-2nd-generation-migrants-2x-more-likely-to-have-psychotic-disorders.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="ethnic-minority-position-and-risk-for-psychotic-disorders">Ethnic minority position and risk for psychotic disorders&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Current Opinion in Psychiatry:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Veling, Wim&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose of review: This article reviews the recent literature about migration, ethnic minority position and the risk of psychotic disorders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent findings: A meta-analysis found that both first and second-generation migrants have on average a two-fold increase in risk for psychotic disorders. In the Netherlands, the risk was most elevated for individuals who migrated in early childhood. Several studies investigated diagnostic ethnic bias and reported greater likelihood of schizophrenia diagnosis in ethnic minority patients at the cost of diagnosis of affective psychotic disorders. Neighbourhood ethnic density was related to prevalence of psychotic experiences in ethnic minority populations in the UK. Perceived discrimination was associated with severity of psychotic and depressive symptoms in ethnic minority patients. Both weak and strong ethnic identification, as well as experiences of social adversity, were related to risk for psychosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Suicide 2X more likely with low vitamin D (in military)</title><link>/posts/suicide-2x-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d-in-military.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/suicide-2x-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d-in-military.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="low-vitamin-d-status-and-suicide">Low Vitamin D Status and Suicide:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A Case-Control Study of Active Duty Military Service Members&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plos One Jan 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John C. Umhau &lt;a href="mailto:umhau@jhu.edu">umhau@jhu.edu&lt;/a>, David T. George, Robert P. Heaney, Michael D. Lewis, Robert J. Ursano, Markus Heilig, Joseph R. Hibbeln equal contributor, Melanie L. Schwandt equal contributor,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: Considering that epidemiological studies show that suicide rates in many countries are highest in the spring when vitamin D status is lowest, and that low vitamin D status can affect brain function, we sought to evaluate if a low level of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> could be a predisposing factor for suicide.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Psychiatric disorders in a few elderly associated with insufficient vitamin D</title><link>/posts/psychiatric-disorders-in-a-few-elderly-associated-with-insufficient-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/psychiatric-disorders-in-a-few-elderly-associated-with-insufficient-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-a-contributor-to-psychiatric-disorders-in-elderly">Hypovitaminosis d: a contributor to psychiatric disorders in elderly?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Can Geriatr J. 2012 Sep;15(3):80-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5770/cgj.15.39.">doi: 10.5770/cgj.15.39.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Sep 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ford J, Hategan A, Bourgeois JA &lt;a href="mailto:james.bourgeois@ucsf.edu">james.bourgeois@ucsf.edu&lt;/a>, Tisi DK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioural Neurosciences, Michael G. DeGroote School of Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypovitaminosis D is unrecognized and remarkably common in geriatric patients, with various clinical manifestations. The purpose of this study was to prospectively assess the vitamin D (VD) status in newly admitted psychogeriatric patients, and to study the correlation of VD status with indicators of calcium metabolism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antidepressants might increase infertility and pregnancy problems</title><link>/posts/antidepressants-might-increase-infertility-and-pregnancy-problems.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/antidepressants-might-increase-infertility-and-pregnancy-problems.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Depression book talks about vitamin D</title><link>/posts/depression-book-talks-about-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/depression-book-talks-about-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Some Mental Illness could be treated or prevented with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-some-mental-illness-could-be-treated-or-prevented-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-some-mental-illness-could-be-treated-or-prevented-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#started-reading-anatomy-of-an-epidemic-magic-bullets-psychiatric-drugs-and-the-astonishing-rise-of-mental-illness-in-america-httpwwwamazoncomanatomy-epidemic-bullets-psychiatric-astonishingdp0307452425refsr_1_1sbooksieutf8qid1351721770sr1-1keywordsepidemic">Started reading &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Anatomy-Epidemic-Bullets-Psychiatric-Astonishing/dp/0307452425/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1351721770&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=epidemic">Anatomy of an Epidemic: Magic Bullets, Psychiatric Drugs, and the Astonishing Rise of Mental Illness in America &lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#i-observe-that">I observe that&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#it-will-be-interesting-how-many-a-hrefpostsother-factors-to-point-to-health-problems-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-597other-factors-to-point-to-health-problems-associated-with-low-vitamin-da-such-as">It will be interesting how many &lt;a href="/posts/other-factors-to-point-to-health-problems-associated-with-low-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 597">other factors to point to health problems associated with low vitamin D&lt;/a> such as:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-levels-of-psychiatric-out-patients-did-not-vary-much-with-season">Vitamin D levels of psychiatric out-patients did not vary much with season&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-is-it-ready-for-psychiatric-prime-time">Vitamin D: Is It Ready for Psychiatric Prime Time?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-does-it-play-a-role-in-psychiatry">Vitamin D: Does it play a role in psychiatry?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#seasonal-distribution-of-psychiatric-births-in-england">Seasonal Distribution of Psychiatric Births in England&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#why-are-mental-illness-patients-extremely-low-on-vitamin-d">Why are Mental Illness patients extremely low on vitamin D?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-among-psychiatric-inpatients">Vitamin D Deficiency Among Psychiatric Inpatients&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-of-psychiatric-inpatients-in-new-zealands-waikato-region">Vitamin D status of psychiatric inpatients in New Zealand’s Waikato region&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#feasibility-of-screening-for-and-treating-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-forensic-psychiatric-inpatients">Feasibility of screening for and treating vitamin D deficiency in forensic psychiatric inpatients.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-among-psychiatric-inpatients-1">Vitamin d deficiency among psychiatric inpatients.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-association-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-and-d2-with-behavioural-problems-in-childhood">The association of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 and D2 with behavioural problems in childhood.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-and-psychotic-features-in-mentally-ill-adolescents-a-cross-sectional-study">Vitamin D deficiency and psychotic features in mentally ill adolescents: A cross-sectional study.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-of-psychiatric-inpatients-in-new-zealands-waikato-region-1">Vitamin D status of psychiatric inpatients in New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s Waikato region.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-and-depression-causal-relationship-or-artifact">Vitamin D deficiency and depression: Causal relationship or artifact?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-a-potential-role-in-reducing-suicide-risk">Vitamin D: a potential role in reducing suicide risk?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-cognitive-and-emotional-functioning-in-young-adults--a-randomised-controlled-trial">Effects of vitamin D supplementation on cognitive and emotional functioning in young adults&amp;ndash;a randomised controlled trial.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#d-for-depression-any-role-for-vitamin-d-food-for-thought-ii">&amp;lsquo;D&amp;rsquo; for depression: any role for vitamin D? &amp;lsquo;Food for Thought&amp;rsquo; II.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-depression">Vitamin D and depression.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#5700-iu-of-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-decrease-depression">5700 IU of vitamin D not enough to decrease depression&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#children-and-adolescents-with-severe-mental-illness-need-vitamin-d-supplementation-regardless-of-disease-or-treatment">Children and adolescents with severe mental illness need vitamin D supplementation regardless of disease or treatment.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#spanthe-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-neuropsychiatric-conditionsspan">&lt;span>[The effect of vitamin D on neuropsychiatric conditions]&lt;/span>.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#37-of-psychiatric-inpatients-had-vitamin-d-levels--25-ng">37% of Psychiatric Inpatients had vitamin D levels &amp;lt; 25 ng&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mental-disorders-wikipediahttpenwikipediaorgwikilist_of_mental_disorders_as_defined_by_the_dsm_and_icd">&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_mental_disorders_as_defined_by_the_DSM_and_ICD">Mental Disorders wikipedia&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="started-reading-anatomy-of-an-epidemic-magic-bullets-psychiatric-drugs-and-the-astonishing-rise-of-mental-illness-in-america-httpwwwamazoncomanatomy-epidemic-bullets-psychiatric-astonishingdp0307452425refsr_1_1sbooksieutf8qid1351721770sr1-1keywordsepidemic">Started reading &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Anatomy-Epidemic-Bullets-Psychiatric-Astonishing/dp/0307452425/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1351721770&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=epidemic">Anatomy of an Epidemic: Magic Bullets, Psychiatric Drugs, and the Astonishing Rise of Mental Illness in America &lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="i-observe-that">I observe that&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>People with mental illness often have diseases associated with low vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Much less depression if higher than 43 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/much-less-depression-if-higher-than-43-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/much-less-depression-if-higher-than-43-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Association between season of birth and suicide – perhaps vitamin D</title><link>/posts/association-between-season-of-birth-and-suicide-perhaps-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/association-between-season-of-birth-and-suicide-perhaps-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="associations-between-season-of-birth-and-suicide-a-brief-review">Associations between season of birth and suicide: a brief review.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Neuropsychopharmacol Hung. 2012 Sep;14(3):177-87.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antonsen JH, Gonda X, Dome P, Rihmer Z.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NAF-garden family practice, Brugata 6, 2380 Brumunddal, Norway. &lt;a href="mailto:kendermagos@yahoo.com">kendermagos@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suicide is a complex behaviour contributing to a significant number of unnecessary deaths worldwide. Accordingly, the quest for suicide risk factors is one of the most intensively developing issues of psychiatric research. In the last few decades a number of interesting results have been published about associations between season of birth (SOB) and several physiological and pathological aspects of human life, while, in regard to neuroscience, several investigations confirmed that SOB is associated with the risk of several major neuropsychiatric disorders and suicide as well. Research concerning the possible causative factors behind these associations were also performed suggesting that&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>400 IU vitamin D was not enough to stop depression</title><link>/posts/400-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-stop-depression.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/400-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-stop-depression.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="see-vitamin-d-supplementation-does-not-reduce-depression-risk-in-older-womenhttppsychiatryjwatchorgcgicontentfull20128301maxtoshowhits10hits5resultformatandorexacttitleandtitleabstractvitamindandorexacttitleabsphraseandorexactfulltextandsearchid1usestrictdatesyesresourcetypehwcitct">See &lt;a href="http://psychiatry.jwatch.org/cgi/content/full/2012/830/1?maxtoshow=&amp;amp;HITS=10&amp;amp;hits=5&amp;amp;RESULTFORMAT=&amp;amp;andorexacttitle=and&amp;amp;titleabstract=vitamin+d&amp;amp;andorexacttitleabs=phrase&amp;amp;andorexactfulltext=and&amp;amp;searchid=1&amp;amp;usestrictdates=yes&amp;amp;resourcetype=HWCIT&amp;amp;ct">Vitamin D Supplementation Does Not Reduce Depression Risk in Older Women&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Although the vitamin D dose might have been too small, the authors note that when added to intake from food, it achieved the daily dose recommended by the Institute of Medicine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Depression 50 percent more likely if low vitamin D in early pregnancy</title><link>/posts/depression-50-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-in-early-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/depression-50-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-in-early-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-early-pregnancy-vitamin-d-status-is-associated-with-maternal-depressive-symptoms-in-the-amsterdam-born-children-and-their-development-cohort">Maternal Early-Pregnancy Vitamin D Status Is Associated With Maternal Depressive Symptoms in the Amsterdam Born Children and Their Development Cohort&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Psychosomatic Medicine August 9, 2012 PSY.0b013e3182639fdb Joke Brandenbarg, MSc, Tanja G.M. Vrijkotte, PhD, Geertje Goedhart, PhD and Manon van Eijsden, PhD &lt;a href="mailto:mveijsden@ggd.amsterdam.nl">mveijsden@ggd.amsterdam.nl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Department of Epidemiology, Documentation, and Health Promotion (J.B., M.v.E.), Public Health Service; Department of Health Sciences (M.v.E.), VU University; and Department of Public Health (T.G.M.V.), Academic Medical Center, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam; and Institute for Risk Assessment Sciences (G.G.), University of Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Major depression associated with low vitamin D and low bone density</title><link>/posts/major-depression-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/major-depression-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="do-premenopausal-women-with-major-depression-have-low-bone-mineral-density-a-36-month-prospective-study">Do Premenopausal Women with Major Depression Have Low Bone Mineral Density? A 36-Month Prospective Study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(7):e40894. Epub 2012 Jul 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cizza G &lt;a href="mailto:cizzag@intra.niddk.nih.gov">cizzag@intra.niddk.nih.gov&lt;/a>, Mistry S, Nguyen VT, Eskandari F, Martinez P, Torvik S, Reynolds JC, Gold PW, Sinai N, Csako G; for the POWER Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Section on Neuroendocrinology of Obesity, National Institutes of Diabetes and Digestive Kidney Diseases (NIDDK), National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland, United States of America.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pregnant blacks 50 pcnt more likely to be depressed if 3 ng less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pregnant-blacks-50-pcnt-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-3-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnant-blacks-50-pcnt-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-3-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Depression not reduced with 5700 IU vitamin D average in 6 months</title><link>/posts/depression-not-reduced-with-5700-iu-vitamin-d-average-in-6-months.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/depression-not-reduced-with-5700-iu-vitamin-d-average-in-6-months.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Psychosis in dark skinned people 3.5 X higher if low level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/psychosis-in-dark-skinned-people-35-x-higher-if-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/psychosis-in-dark-skinned-people-35-x-higher-if-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-psychotic-features-in-mentally-ill-adolescents-a-cross-sectional-study">Vitamin D deficiency and psychotic features in mentally ill adolescents: A cross-sectional study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Barbara L Gracious, Teresa L Finucane, Meriel Freidman-Campbell, Susan Messing and Melissa M Parkhurst&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Psychiatry 2012, 12:38 doi:10.1186/1471-244X-12-38; Published: 9 May 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency is a re-emerging epidemic, especially in minority populations. Vitamin D is crucial not only for bone health but for proper brain development and functioning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low levels of vitamin D are associated with depression, seasonal affective disorder, and &lt;strong>schizophrenia&lt;/strong> in adults but little is known about vitamin D and mental health in the pediatric population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High levels of vitamin D associated with somewhat less depression – Mayo</title><link>/posts/high-levels-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-somewhat-less-depression-mayo.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-levels-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-somewhat-less-depression-mayo.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Teens no longer depressed after vitamin D raised to 36 ng</title><link>/posts/teens-no-longer-depressed-after-vitamin-d-raised-to-36-ng.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/teens-no-longer-depressed-after-vitamin-d-raised-to-36-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="depressed-adolescents-in-a-case-series-were-low-in-vitamin-d-and-depression-was-ameliorated-by-vitamin-d-supplementation">Depressed adolescents in a case-series were low in vitamin D and depression was ameliorated by vitamin D supplementation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Paediatrica Vol. 101 Issue 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Göran Högberg 1,2, &lt;a href="mailto:gor.hogberg@gmail.com">gor.hogberg@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sven A. Gustafsson 3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tore Hällström 4,5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tove Gustafsson 6,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Björn Klawitter 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maria Petersson 6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Women’s and Children’s Health, Child and Adolescent Psychiatric Unit, Astrid Lindgren Children?s Hospital, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Stockholm Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Stockholm, BUP Huddinge Stockholm,Sweden&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mood disorders 11X worse for older adults with low vitamin D – 2006</title><link>/posts/mood-disorders-11x-worse-for-older-adults-with-low-vitamin-d-2006.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mood-disorders-11x-worse-for-older-adults-with-low-vitamin-d-2006.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-low-mood-and-worse-cognitive-performance-in-older-adults">Vitamin D Deficiency Is Associated With Low Mood and Worse Cognitive Performance in Older Adults&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>American Journal of Geriatric Psychiatry: December 2006 - Volume 14 - Issue 12 - pp 1032-1040&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wilkins, Consuelo H. M.D.; Sheline, Yvette I. M.D.; Roe, Catherine M. Ph.D.; Birge, Stanley J. M.D.; Morris, John C. M.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency is common in older adults and has been implicated in psychiatric and neurologic disorders. This study examined the relationship among vitamin D status, cognitive performance, mood, and physical performance in older adults.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Psychiatric disorders 4X more likely in teens if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/psychiatric-disorders-4x-more-likely-in-teens-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/psychiatric-disorders-4x-more-likely-in-teens-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="low-levels-of-vitamin-d-linked-to-teen-delusions-hallucinationshttpwwwfoxnewscomhealth20111102low-levels-vitamin-d-linked-to-teen-delusions-hallucinations-foxnews">&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/health/2011/11/02/low-levels-vitamin-d-linked-to-teen-delusions-hallucinations/">Low Levels of Vitamin D Linked to Teen Delusions, Hallucinations&lt;/a> FoxNews&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A group of researchers led by Dr. Barbara L. Gracious, a psychiatrist at Nationwide Children’s Hospital in Columbus, Ohio, presented data at that meeting showing that adolescents who were vitamin D deficient showed a fourfold (400 percent) increased rate of psychotic symptoms, compared to other adolescents with normal vitamin D levels who sought psychiatric treatment at the University of Rochester, in New York.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Depression 40 percent more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/depression-40-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/depression-40-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="depression-is-associated-with-low-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-among-jordanian-adults-results-from-a-national-population-survey">Depression is associated with low levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D among Jordanian adults: results from a national population survey.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2012 Jun;262(4):321-7. (online first - Oct 2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jaddou HY, Batieha AM, Khader YS, Kanaan SH, El-Khateeb MS, Ajlouni KM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Community Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Irbid, Jordan, &lt;a href="mailto:jaddou@just.edu.jo">jaddou@just.edu.jo&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and elevated serum parathyroid hormone (PTH) have been associated with depression in clinical settings, this link in community-dwelling individuals is inconclusive. The present study aimed at examining the association between serum 25(OH)D and PTH levels and the presence of depression in a national population-based household sample of 4,002 Jordanian participants aged ?25 years. The DASS21 depression scale was used to screen for depression, and serum concentrations of 25(OH)D and PTH were measured by radioimmunoassay. Multiple logistic regression models were used to explore the association between serum 25(OH)D and PTH levels and depression. The unadjusted odds ratio (OR) decreased linearly with increasing quartiles of serum 25(OH)D (P (trend) = 0.00). The OR for having depression was significantly higher among individuals in the first and second quartiles (OR = 1.4, 1.23, respectively) than among those in the fourth quartile (P values = 0.00 and 0.03, respectively). This relationship remained significant after adjusting for age, sex, marital status, education, BMI, serum creatinine, number of chronic diseases (OR = 1.39 and 1.21 and P values = 0.00 and 0.05, respectively) and after further adjustment for exercise, altitude, and smoking (OR = 1.48 and 1.24, respectively, and P values = 0.00 and 0.03, respectively). No significant association was found between serum PTH levels and depression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>36 percent less depression when have high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/36-percent-less-depression-when-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/36-percent-less-depression-when-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-are-associated-with-depression-in-an-adult-norwegian-population">Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels are associated with depression in an adult Norwegian population.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Kjærgaard M, Joakimsen R, Jorde R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Psychiatry Res. 2011 Jul 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Observational and intervention studies have suggested an association between low levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and depressive symptoms in several subgroups of disease and age. This study tests the hypothesis in a general population. Our data are based on 10,086 persons who participated in the sixth Tromsø study carried out in 2007-2008. Depressive symptoms were evaluated using Hopkins Symptoms Check List 10 (SCL-10) based on answers from a questionnaire.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Serotonin related to season, light and perhaps latitude and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/serotonin-related-to-season-light-and-perhaps-latitude-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/serotonin-related-to-season-light-and-perhaps-latitude-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-on-the-web">See on the web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clips-from-wikipedia-sadhttpenwikipediaorgwikiseasonal_affective_disorder">Clips from &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seasonal_affective_disorder">WikiPedia SAD&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#possible-contributions-of-skin-pigmentation-and-vitamin-d-in-a-polyfactorial-model-of-seasonal-affective-disorder---2014">Possible contributions of skin pigmentation and vitamin D in a polyfactorial model of seasonal affective disorder - 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#light-therapy-as-a-treatment-for-epilepsy---2011">Light therapy as a treatment for epilepsy. - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effect-of-sunlight-exposure-on-cognitive-function-among-depressed-and-non-depressed-participants-a-regards-cross-sectional-study--2009">Effect of sunlight exposure on cognitive function among depressed and non-depressed participants: a REGARDS cross-sectional study.- 2009&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#seasonal-variation-in-human-brain-serotonin-transporter-binding--2008">Seasonal variation in human brain serotonin transporter binding.- 2008&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-on-the-web">See on the web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindcouncil.org/health-conditions/mental-health-and-learning-disorders/depression/">VitaminDCouncil&lt;/a> new and working as of June 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis non-severe depression and diabetes related by low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-non-severe-depression-and-diabetes-related-by-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-non-severe-depression-and-diabetes-related-by-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="depression-and-type-2-diabetes-mellitus-a-call-to-explore-the-common-cause-hypothesis">Depression and Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: A Call to Explore the Common Cause Hypothesis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Briana Mezuk, PhD, Department of Epidemiology and Community Health, Virginia Commonwealth University School of Medicine, Richmond, VA (&lt;a href="mailto:bmezuk@vcu.edu">bmezuk@vcu.edu&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Archives of Internal Medicine	Vol. 171 No. 11, June 13, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Short item with just the first 150 words of the full text)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read the recent article by Pan and colleagues1 with great interest. Their findings using the Short-Form 36 Health Status Survey suggest that even mood disturbances that do not require clinical intervention are predictive of diabetes. This interpretation, combined with the counterintuitive finding that nonsevere depression was similarly, and potentially more strongly, associated with diabetes risk than severe depression reported in another recent article,2 begs the question(s):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SAD rate 10X higher in cloudy Seattle than sunny Florida</title><link>/posts/sad-rate-10x-higher-in-cloudy-seattle-than-sunny-florida.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sad-rate-10x-higher-in-cloudy-seattle-than-sunny-florida.html</guid><description>&lt;p>from&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.king5.com/news/local/Winter-blues-are-the-real-deal-say-Seattle-doctors-119639824.html">http://www.king5.com/news/local/Winter-blues-are-the-real-deal-say-Seattle-doctors-119639824.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Depression in UAE peaks in the summer – probably due to sun avoidance</title><link>/posts/depression-in-uae-peaks-in-the-summer-probably-due-to-sun-avoidance.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/depression-in-uae-peaks-in-the-summer-probably-due-to-sun-avoidance.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sunshine-sadness-and-seasonality-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-depressive-symptoms-in-the-united-arab-emirates-uae">Sunshine, Sadness and Seasonality: 25-Hydroxyvitamin D, and Depressive Symptoms in the United Arab Emirates (UAE)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Authors: Thomas, Justin; Anouti, Fatme A.l.; Hasani, Sara Al; Abdel-Wareth, Laila; Haq, Afrozul&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The International Journal of Mental Health Promotion, Volume 13, Number 1, February 2011 , pp. 23-26(4)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Publisher: The Clifford Beers Foundation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several studies have described the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in Gulf Arab populations and focused on the physical health consequences of VTD deficiency. No work to date on this population has explored the psychological consequences of VTD deficiency or the issue of seasonal variations in deficiency and symptom severity. The aim of this study was to assess seasonal variation in depressive symptoms and 25-Hydroxyvitamin D levels, exploring the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and mood in female university students in the United Arab Emirates. A cross-sectional study design was used to assess seasonal variation in mood, and a correlational analysis to assess the relationship between vitamin D levels and depressive symptoms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less than 20 ng vitamin D increases depression by 80 percent</title><link>/posts/less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d-increases-depression-by-80-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d-increases-depression-by-80-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-vitamin-d-concentrations-are-related-to-depression-in-young-adult-us-population-the-third-national-health-and-nutrition-examination-survey">Serum vitamin D concentrations are related to depression in young adult US population: the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int Arch Med. 2010; 3: 29. PMCID: PMC2996356&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vijay Ganji,corresponding author1 Cristiana Milone,1 Mildred M Cody,1 Frances McCarty,2 and Yong T Wang3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Nutrition, School of Health Professions, College of Health and Human Sciences, Georgia State University, 140 Decatur Street, Atlanta, GA 30302, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Institute of Public Health, College of Health and Human Sciences, Georgia State University, 140 Decatur Street, Atlanta, GA 30302, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Earthquake and Vitamin D - several studies</title><link>/posts/earthquake-and-vitamin-d-several-studies.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/earthquake-and-vitamin-d-several-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-nutritional-status-of-reproductive-women-at-one-year-after-the-disaster-of-earthquake-in-wenchuan">(The nutritional status of reproductive women at one year after the disaster of Earthquake in Wenchuan)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-articles-on-vitamin-d-and-stress-at-vitamindwiki">Some articles on Vitamin D and stress at VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#study-by-same-chinese-authors-found-92-of-children-under-5-in-earthquake-area-were-vitamin-d-insufficient">Study by same Chinese authors found 92% of children under 5 in earthquake area were vitamin D insufficient&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#200000-iu-of-vitamin-d-monthly-did-not-help-after-earthquake---rct-dec-2014">200,000 IU of Vitamin D monthly did not help after earthquake - RCT Dec 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-nutritional-status-of-reproductive-women-at-one-year-after-the-disaster-of-earthquake-in-wenchuan">(The nutritional status of reproductive women at one year after the disaster of Earthquake in Wenchuan)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Zhonghua Yu Fang Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2010 Aug;44(8):686-90.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Young almost 2X more likely to be depressed if vitamin D less than 20ng</title><link>/posts/young-almost-2x-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-vitamin-d-less-than-20ng.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/young-almost-2x-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-vitamin-d-less-than-20ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-vitamin-d-concentrations-are-related-to-depression-in-young-adult-us-population-the-third-national-health-and-nutrition-examination-survey">Serum vitamin D concentrations are related to depression in young adult US population: the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Vijay Ganji Cristiana Milone , Mildred M Cody Frances McCarthy and Yong T Wang&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International Archives of Medicine 2010, 3:29doi:10.1186/1755-7682-3-29&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 	11 November 2010, Abstract (provisional)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D receptors have been mapped throughout the brain suggesting a role for vitamin D in psychosomatic disorders. Results from previous epidemiological studies on relation between vitamin D status and depression are equivocal. Also, limited information is available relating vitamin D status with depression in young adult US population.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>