<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Skin on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/skin.html</link><description>Recent content in Skin on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/skin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Warts removed by vitamin D injection - many studies</title><link>/posts/warts-removed-by-vitamin-d-injection-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/warts-removed-by-vitamin-d-injection-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-injection-cleared-80-of-palmoplantar-warts-adding-co2-laser-cured-90--may-2023">Vitamin D injection cleared 80% of palmoplantar warts (adding CO2 laser cured 90%) – May 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-injection-cured-a-variety-of-warts-on-skin---2017-a">Vitamin D injection cured a variety of warts on skin - 2017 A&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-injection-cured-a-variety-of-warts-on-skin---2017-b">Vitamin D injection cured a variety of warts on skin - 2017 B&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#warts-eliminated-in-80-percent-of-those-getting-vitamin-d-injection--aug-2015">Warts eliminated in 80 percent of those getting vitamin D injection – Aug 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#67-of-warts-cleared-by-vitamin-d-injections---jan-2020">67% of warts cleared by Vitamin D injections - Jan 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#intralesional-vitamin-d3-treats-of-cutaneous-warts--2021">Intralesional Vitamin D3 treats of Cutaneous Warts- 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#wart-removal-85-by-duck-tape-60-by-cyrotherapy---but-later-study-disagreed---2002">Wart removal: 85% by Duck Tape, 60% by Cyrotherapy - but later study disagreed - 2002&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-injection-cleared-80-of-palmoplantar-warts-adding-co2-laser-cured-90--may-2023">Vitamin D injection cleared 80% of palmoplantar warts (adding CO2 laser cured 90%) – May 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Comparative Study Among CO2 Laser, Intralesional Vitamin D3, and Combined Intralesional Vitamin D3 and CO2 Laser in Treatment of Palmoplantar Warts&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Phototherapy and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/phototherapy-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/phototherapy-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Clin Dermatol. 2016 Sep-Oct;34(5):548-55. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clindermatol.2016.05.004.">doi: 10.1016/j.clindermatol.2016.05.004.&lt;/a> Epub 2016 May 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Juzeniene A1, Grigalavicius M2, Juraleviciute M2, Grant WB3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Montebello, N-0310 Oslo, Norway. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:Asta.juzeniene@rr-research.no">Asta.juzeniene@rr-research.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Montebello, N-0310 Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, San Francisco, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/pdt.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>The skin is the site for the photosynthesis of vitamin D and is a target tissue for the active metabolite of vitamin D. An increasing body of evidence indicates that vitamin D produced during phototherapy may be responsible for the positive effects observed during treatment of some skin diseases. Topical or oral application of vitamin D derivatives are used alone or with phototherapy. This paper reviews what is known about the use of phototherapy to enhance vitamin D levels, the use of vitamin D analogues with phototherapy, the efficacy of combination therapies, and controversies regarding some of the outcomes. Vitamin D can play a beneficial role in treating psoriasis, even though the exact role of vitamin D in the pathogenesis and severity of psoriasis remains unclear. The role of vitamin D in vitiligo, atopic dermatitis, polymorphic light eruption, and mycosis fungoides must be further investigated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eczema (Atopic Dermatitis) treated by 1600 IU of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/eczema-atopic-dermatitis-treated-by-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/eczema-atopic-dermatitis-treated-by-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Malignant melanoma may be reduced by skin-activated vitamin D</title><link>/posts/malignant-melanoma-may-be-reduced-by-skin-activated-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/malignant-melanoma-may-be-reduced-by-skin-activated-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Current knowledge on the active form of Vitamin D synthesized in the skin and its effects on malignant melanoma&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neoplasma, doi:10.4149/neo_2017_101, Received April 18, 2016 / Accepted August 27, 2016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b. bolerazska &lt;a href="mailto:beata@moly.sk">beata@moly.sk&lt;/a>, m. rabajdova, i. spakova, m. marekova&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medical and Clinical Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, P. J. Safarik University in Kosice, Kosice, Slovakia&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">&lt;/nav>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:750px">
&lt;p>Vitamin D can be activated in many places in the body&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study incorrectly states that activatation only occurs in the skin and Kidneys&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitiligo is associated with low vitamin D (nothing about treatment) – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitiligo-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-nothing-about-treatment-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitiligo-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-nothing-about-treatment-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-are-associated-with-vitiligo-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Low 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels are Associated with Vitiligo: a Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Photodermatol Photoimmunol Photomed. 2016 Mar 23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/phpp.12241.">doi: 10.1111/phpp.12241.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upala S1,2, Sanguankeo A1,2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Internal Medicine, Bassett Medical Center and Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, Cooperstown, N.Y, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Preventive and Social Medicine, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is associated with a number of autoimmune diseases. We completed a meta-analysis of observational studies to establish whether there was a relationship between hypovitaminosis D and the autoimmune skin disease vitiligo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin physiology, pathology and vitamin D - review</title><link>/posts/skin-physiology-pathology-and-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-physiology-pathology-and-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sunscreen cream (Photocil) which allows Vitamin D to be produced (not US)</title><link>/posts/sunscreen-cream-photocil-which-allows-vitamin-d-to-be-produced-not-us.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunscreen-cream-photocil-which-allows-vitamin-d-to-be-produced-not-us.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Company did not respond to email nor phone Nov 2015&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Appears to be out of business&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="topical-cream-delivers-nb-uvb-from-sunlight-for-the-treatment-of-vitiligo">Topical cream delivers NB-UVB from sunlight for the treatment of vitiligo.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2014 Dec;15(18):2623-7. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1517/14656566.2014.978287.">doi: 10.1517/14656566.2014.978287.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Nov 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wang X1, McCoy J, Lotti T, Goren A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Applied Biology , 17780 Fitch, Suite 192, Irvine, CA 92614 , USA &lt;a href="mailto:johnm@appliedbiology.com">johnm@appliedbiology.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet-B (UVB) phototherapy for the treatment of vitiligo is an effective first-line choice. However, the cost of multiple doctor visits and the lengthy treatment regimen has resulted in low compliance, limiting access to this safe and effective mode of treatment. Topical Photocil represents an innovative solution to this problem. The drug selectively filters solar radiation to deliver narrow-band UVB to vitiligo lesions. Here, we discuss how this novel topical cream could provide a convenient alternative to artificial light phototherapy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and the skin: Focus on a complex relationship</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-skin-focus-on-a-complex-relationship.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-skin-focus-on-a-complex-relationship.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Stretch marks (after pregnancy) prevented and treated by Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/stretch-marks-after-pregnancy-prevented-and-treated-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stretch-marks-after-pregnancy-prevented-and-treated-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-is-one-of-many-ways-to-reduce-stretch-marks--treatment-and-prevention">Vitamin D is one of many ways to reduce stretch marks – treatment and prevention&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.stretchmarkcreamcenter.com/">http://www.stretchmarkcreamcenter.com/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>weight gain, pregnancy, growth spurts, and even genetics&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In women and men&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ingredients include Vitamin E, grapefruit seed extract, &lt;strong>vitamin D3&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://storify.com/jordan5vel299/pregnancy-the-best-stretch-mark-cream-when-pregnan">Pregnancy :: The Best Stretch Mark Cream When Pregnant Includes Safe But Effective Ingredients&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Vitamin E, &lt;strong>Vitamin D&lt;/strong> , Aloe Vera, Shea Butter, Squalene Oil, etc&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/how-60-ng-of-vitamin-d-enabled-pregnancy-a-personal-story" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: How 60 ng of vitamin D enabled pregnancy - a personal story">How 60 ng of vitamin D enabled pregnancy - a personal story&lt;/a> on VitaminDWiki&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Stretch marks PREVENTED in one woman with lots of vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic Dermatitis risk is 55 percent higher if low vitamin D – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-risk-is-55-percent-higher-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-risk-is-55-percent-higher-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-association-between-serum-vitamin-d-and-atopic-dermatitis">A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Association between Serum Vitamin D and Atopic Dermatitis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Siriraj Med J, Volume 67, Number 5, September-October 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pichanee Chaweekulrat, M.D.&lt;em>, Chaiyawat Suppasilp, M.D.&lt;/em>, Bhoom Suktitipat, M.D., Ph.D. *, &lt;a href="mailto:bhoom.suk@mahidol.aath">bhoom.suk@mahidol.aath&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Department of Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok 10700,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Integrative Computational BioScience Center (ICBS), Mahidol University, Salaya, Phuttamonthon, Nakhon Pathom 73170, Thailand.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Objective: The relationship between vitamin D and atopic dermatitis remains controversial. Here, we systematically reviewed and meta-analyzed the association between serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D concentration (25(OH) D) and atopic dermatitis (AD), AD severity, and the benefits of oral vitamin D supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Caesarean section increases risk of Eczema (Atopic dermatitis) by 1.8 X</title><link>/posts/off-topic-caesarean-section-increases-risk-of-eczema-atopic-dermatitis-by-18-x.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-caesarean-section-increases-risk-of-eczema-atopic-dermatitis-by-18-x.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="atopic-dermatitis-is-associated-with-caesarean-sections-in-korean-adolescents-but-asthma-is-not">Atopic dermatitis is associated with Caesarean sections in Korean adolescents but asthma is not.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Paediatr. 2015 Sep 12. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/apa.13212.">doi: 10.1111/apa.13212.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yu M1, Han K2, Kim DH3, Nam GE3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Studies on the associations between mode of delivery and allergic diseases have produced different results and research has rarely been conducted in Asian countries such as South Korea. This study assessed the relationship between mode of delivery and atopic dermatitis and asthma in Korean adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis - Atopic Dermatitis protected by Omega-3</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-atopic-dermatitis-protected-by-omega-3.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-atopic-dermatitis-protected-by-omega-3.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="do-long-chain-omega-3-fatty-acids-protect-from-atopic-dermatitis">Do long-chain omega-3 fatty acids protect from atopic dermatitis?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal der Deutschen Dermatologischen Gesellschaft. Volume 13, Issue 9, pages 879–885, September 2015,DOI: 10.1111/ddg.12780&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Imke Reese1,* andThomas Werfel2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summary&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Long-chain polyunsaturated fatty acids are essential for human nutrition. The number of double bonds determines whether a given fatty acid is termed two, three, or x times unsaturated. Depending on the distance of the first double bond from the fatty acid&amp;rsquo;s methyl group, one distinguishes omega-3 fatty acids from omega-6 fatty acids.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Warts eliminated by vitamin D injections</title><link>/posts/warts-eliminated-by-vitamin-d-injections.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/warts-eliminated-by-vitamin-d-injections.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#40-of-warts-removed-by-300000-iu-vitamin-d-injection---rct-march-2019">40% of Warts removed by 300,000 IU Vitamin D injection - RCT March 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d3-600000-iu-injection-eliminated-periungual-warts-finger-or-toe-nails--may-2019">Vitamin D3 600,000 IU injection eliminated periungual warts (finger or toe nails)- May 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#warts-removed-by-60000-iu-vitamin-d-injection---2015">Warts removed by 60,000 IU Vitamin D injection - 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#successful-treatment-of-anogenital-wart-with-a-topical-vitamin-d3-derivative-in-an-infant--2010">Successful Treatment of Anogenital Wart with a Topical Vitamin D(3) Derivative in an Infant.- 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="40-of-warts-removed-by-300000-iu-vitamin-d-injection---rct-march-2019">40% of Warts removed by 300,000 IU Vitamin D injection - RCT March 2019&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Effectiveness of intralesional vitamin D3 injection in the treatment of common warts: single-blinded placebo-controlled study.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic Eczema might be helped by Vitamin D – Review</title><link>/posts/atopic-eczema-might-be-helped-by-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-eczema-might-be-helped-by-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-the-development-of-atopic-eczema">Vitamin D and the Development of Atopic Eczema&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J. Clin. Med. 2015, 4(5), 1036-1050; doi:10.3390/jcm4051036&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Debra J. Palmer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Paediatrics and Child Health, The University of Western Australia, PO Box D184, Princess Margaret Hospital, Perth WA 6001, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>(This article belongs to the Special Issue Epidemiology and Treatment of Atopic Eczema)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A “vitamin D hypothesis” has been proposed to explain the increased prevalence of eczema in regions with higher latitude. This review focuses on the current available evidence with regard to the possible effect of vitamin D on the development of atopic eczema. Observational studies have indicated a link between vitamin D status and eczema outcomes, including lower serum vitamin D levels associated with increased incidence and severity of eczema symptoms. Vitamin D is known to have a regulatory influence on both the immune system and skin barrier function, both critical in the pathogenesis of eczema. However heterogeneous results have been found in studies to date investigating the effect of vitamin D status during pregnancy and infancy on the prevention of eczema outcomes. Well-designed, adequately powered, randomised controlled trials are needed. The study design of any new intervention trials should measure vitamin D levels at multiple time points during the intervention, ultraviolet (UV) radiation exposure via the use of individual UV dosimeters, and investigate the role of individual genetic polymorphisms. In conclusion, the current available evidence does not allow firm conclusions to be made on whether vitamin D status affects the development of atopic eczema.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunscreens - 80 percent are ineffective or possibly harmful</title><link>/posts/sunscreens-80-percent-are-ineffective-or-possibly-harmful.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunscreens-80-percent-are-ineffective-or-possibly-harmful.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="80-of-sunscreens-are-useless-or-harmful-says-ewghttpwwwmnncomhealthfitness-well-beingblogs80-of-sunscreens-are-useless-or-harmful-says-ewg-mother-nature-network">&lt;a href="http://www.mnn.com/health/fitness-well-being/blogs/80-of-sunscreens-are-useless-or-harmful-says-ewg">80% of sunscreens are useless or harmful, says EWG&lt;/a> Mother Nature Network&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="environmental-working-group-2015-guide-to-sunscreenshttpwwwewgorg2015sunscreen">&lt;a href="http://www.ewg.org/2015sunscreen/">Environmental Working Group 2015 Guide to Sunscreens&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="217-sunscreens-which-were-okhttpwwwewgorg2015sunscreenbest-sunscreensbest-beach-sport-sunscreens">&lt;a href="http://www.ewg.org/2015sunscreen/best-sunscreens/best-beach-sport-sunscreens/">217 Sunscreens which were OK&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/ways-to-block-uva-but-not-the-uvb-which-makes-vitamin-d">Ways to block UVA but not the UVB which makes vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/sunscreen-in-a-pill-with-low-spf">Sunscreen in a pill (with low SPF) &lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/melanoma-huge-increase-perhaps-due-to-use-of-sunscreen-or-lower-vitamin-d">Melanoma huge increase - perhaps due to use of sunscreen or lower vitamin D - Aug 2014&lt;/a> - free book&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/uv-spectra-of-the-sun-and-sunscreens" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: UV spectra of the sun and sunscreens">UV spectra of the sun and sunscreens&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Itchy skin (pruritus) due to kidney disease was treated with topical vitamin D</title><link>/posts/itchy-skin-pruritus-due-to-kidney-disease-was-treated-with-topical-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/itchy-skin-pruritus-due-to-kidney-disease-was-treated-with-topical-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-topical-vitamin-d-on-chronic-kidney-disease-associated-pruritus-an-open-label-pilot-study">Effect of topical vitamin D on chronic kidney disease-associated pruritus: An open-label pilot study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Japanese Dermatological Association, Article first published online: 28 APR 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1111/1346-8138.12895&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kyung Eun Jung1, Yu Ri Woo1, Joong Sun Lee1, Jong Ho Shin2, Jin Uk Jeong2, Dae Won Koo1 andKi Tae Bang2,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Dermatology, School of Medicine, Eulji University Hospital, Daejeon, Korea&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Internal Medicine (Nephrology), School of Medicine, Eulji University Hospital, Daejeon, Korea&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic Dermatitis (Eczema) in Mongolian children reduced with 1,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-eczema-in-mongolian-children-reduced-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-eczema-in-mongolian-children-reduced-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="randomized-trial-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-for-winter-related-atopic-dermatitis-in-children">Randomized trial of vitamin D supplementation for winter-related atopic dermatitis in children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2014 Oct;134(4):831-835.e1. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaci.2014.08.002.">doi: 10.1016/j.jaci.2014.08.002.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Camargo CA Jr1, Ganmaa D2, Sidbury R3, Erdenedelger Kh4, Radnaakhand N5, Khandsuren B4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, and Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, Mass. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:ccamargo@partners.org">ccamargo@partners.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, and Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, Mass; Health Sciences University of Mongolia, Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Seattle Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Seattle, Wash.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin damaged by sun helped by vitamin D supplementation - pilot study</title><link>/posts/skin-damaged-by-sun-helped-by-vitamin-d-supplementation-pilot-study.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-damaged-by-sun-helped-by-vitamin-d-supplementation-pilot-study.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pilot-study-on-the-bioactivity-of-vitamin-d-in-the-skin-after-oral-supplementation">Pilot Study on the Bioactivity of Vitamin D in the Skin after Oral Supplementation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Prevention Research 14-0280 Published OnlineFirst April 2, 2015; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1158/1940-6207.">doi: 10.1158/1940-6207.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clara Curiel-Lewandrowski1,*, Jean Y. Tang2, Janine G. Einspahr3, Yira Bermudez4, Chiu-Hsieh Hsu5, Melika Rezaee6, Alex Hao Lee6, Joseph Tangrea7, Howard L. Parnes8, David S. Alberts9, and H-H S Chow4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Dermatology, The University of Arizona Cancer Center&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Dermatology, Stanford School of Medicine, Stanford University&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Medicine, The University of Arizona Cancer Center&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rare skin diseases (autoimmune bullous ) strongly associated with low vitamin D and is increasing</title><link>/posts/rare-skin-diseases-autoimmune-bullous-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-is-increasing.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rare-skin-diseases-autoimmune-bullous-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-is-increasing.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-skeletal-health-in-autoimmune-bullous-skin-diseases-a-case-control-study">Vitamin D and skeletal health in autoimmune bullous skin diseases: a case control study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-skeletal-health-in-autoimmune-bullous-skin-diseases-a-case-control-study">Vitamin D and skeletal health in autoimmune bullous skin diseases: a case control study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Orphanet Journal of Rare Diseases 2015, 10:8 doi:10.1186/s13023-015-0230-0&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Angelo Valerio Marzano1, Valentina Trevisan1, Elisa Cairoli23, Cristina Eller-Vainicher3, Valentina Morelli23, Anna Spada23, Carlo Crosti1 and Iacopo Chiodini 3 Iacopo Chiodini &lt;a href="mailto:iacopo.chiodini@unimi.it">iacopo.chiodini@unimi.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background The presence of hypovitaminosis D in patients with autoimmune bullous skin diseases, such as pemphigus vulgaris (PV) and bullous pemphigoid (BP), is debated. In a previous study we found an increased prevalence of vertebral fractures (VFx) and hypovitaminosis D in PV and BP patients. The present study extends the sample size of the previous one, for investigating the 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHVitD) levels in relation with the skeletal health and disease intensity in these patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>92 percent of Burn patients had low vitamin D, 600 IU did not help</title><link>/posts/92-percent-of-burn-patients-had-low-vitamin-d-600-iu-did-not-help.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/92-percent-of-burn-patients-had-low-vitamin-d-600-iu-did-not-help.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-cholecalciferol-recommended-daily-allowances-on-vitamin-d-status-and-fibroblast-growth-factor-23-an-observational-study-in-acute-burn-patients">Effect of cholecalciferol recommended daily allowances on vitamin D status and fibroblast growth factor-23: an observational study in acute burn patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Burns. 2014 Aug;40(5):865-70. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.burns.2013.11.015.">doi: 10.1016/j.burns.2013.11.015.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Jan 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rousseau AF1, Damas P2, Ledoux D2, Cavalier E3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Burn Centre and General Intensive Care Department, University of Liège, University Hospital, Sart-Tilman, Liège, Belgium. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:afrousseau@chu.ulg.ac.be">afrousseau@chu.ulg.ac.be&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Burn Centre and General Intensive Care Department, University of Liège, University Hospital, Sart-Tilman, Liège, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Clinical Chemistry Department, University of Liège, University Hospital, Sart-Tilman, Liège, Belgium.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Evidence indicating that vitamin D deals with microorganisms in atopic dermatitis</title><link>/posts/evidence-indicating-that-vitamin-d-deals-with-microorganisms-in-atopic-dermatitis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/evidence-indicating-that-vitamin-d-deals-with-microorganisms-in-atopic-dermatitis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="microorganism-induced-exacerbations-in-atopic-dermatitis-a-possible-preventive-role-for-vitamin-d">Microorganism-induced exacerbations in atopic dermatitis: A possible preventive role for vitamin D?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Allergy Asthma Proc. 2015 Jan;36(1):19-25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Benetti C1, Piacentini GL, Capristo C, Boner AL, Peroni DG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Life and Reproduction Sciences, Pediatric Division, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Atopic dermatitis (AD) is a common skin disease characterized by a complex pathogenesis not completely understood despite numerous studies to date. The clinical patterns result from interactions between genetic disorders determining abnormalities in the epidermis differentiation complex, modification of the cutaneous barrier, and dysfunction of immune responses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Burns, ulcers, and wounds healed by Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/burns-ulcers-and-wounds-healed-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/burns-ulcers-and-wounds-healed-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note: Vitamin D lotions/oils applied &lt;a href="/posts/topical-vitamin-d">topically&lt;/a> will probably better than oral Vitamin D. Perhaps 100X higher concentration on burn if applied topically&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#asked-ai-are-burns-less-severe-if-the-person-has-higher-level-of-vitamin-d">Asked AI: Are burns less severe if the person has higher level of vitamin d?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burn-with-low-vitamin-d-1-day-longer-infection-3x-more-likely-when-leave-hospital---feb-2024">Burn with low Vitamin D: 1 day longer, infection 3X more likely when leave hospital - Feb 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burn-length-of-stay-in-hospital-vs-vitamin-d-level---18-vs-12-days---dec-2023">Burn length of stay in hospital vs. Vitamin D level - 18 vs 12 days - Dec 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#more-intense-burns-associated-with-lower-vitamin-d-might-low-d-cause-more-burn-sept2020">More intense burns associated with lower Vitamin D (might low D cause more burn)– Sept 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#potential-ways-vitamin-d-can-help-burns---april2019">Potential ways Vitamin D can help burns - April 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burn-centers-typically-still-do-not-test-vitamin-d-levels--survey--march2019">Burn Centers typically still do not test vitamin D levels- survey – March 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burns-with-higher-vitamin-d-have-fewer-problems---feb2019">Burns with higher vitamin D have fewer problems - Feb 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#nearly-all-burn-patients-have-low-vitamin-d-levels---may2018">Nearly all burn patients have low Vitamin D levels - May 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#50-fracture-admissions-occurred-within-7-years-of-burn-admission---sept2017">50% fracture admissions occurred within 7 years of burn admission - Sept 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burns-with-low-vitamin-d-associated-with-more-days-in-icu-and-hospital--jan2017">Burns with low vitamin D associated with more days in ICU and hospital – Jan 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bone-fractures-after-a-burn---none-if-vitamin-d-6-if-no-vitamin-d--rct-may2015">Bone fractures after a burn - none if vitamin D, 6 if no vitamin D – RCT May 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-after-a-high-dose-of-cholecalciferol-in-healthy-and-burnsubjects">Vitamin D status after a high dose of cholecalciferol in healthy and burn subjects&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#quarterly-vitamin-d-injections-200000-iu-helped-muscles-in-burn-patients---march2015">Quarterly Vitamin D injections (200,000 IU) helped muscles in burn patients - March 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#both-vitamins-d3-and-d2-100-iukg-provided-some-help-to-critically-ill-pediatric-burn-patients---june2015">Both vitamins D3 and D2 (100 IU/kg) provided some help to Critically Ill Pediatric Burn Patients - June 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#97-of-pediatric-burn-patients-had-low-vitamin-d---feb2016">97% of pediatric burn patients had low vitamin D - Feb 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pain-6-months-after-thermal-burn-and-skin-autography-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-low-omega-3---march2018">Pain 6 months after thermal burn and skin autography associated with low vitamin D and low Omega-3 - March 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burned-in-factory-explosion-8x-less-likely-to-get-infected-if-treated-with-magnesium-and-vitamins-such-as-b12---rct-nov2018">Burned in factory explosion: 8X less likely to get infected if treated with Magnesium and Vitamins such as B12 - RCT Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-may-improve-wound-healing-in-burns-patients--nov2017">Vitamin D may improve wound healing in burns patients – Nov 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#diabetic-foot-ulcers-helped-by-50000-iu-weekly--rct-june2016">Diabetic foot ulcers helped by 50,000 IU weekly – RCT June 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-role-of-the-vitamin-d-receptor-in-the-epidermal-stem-cell-response-to-wounding---aug-2024">The Role of the Vitamin D Receptor in the Epidermal Stem Cell Response to Wounding - Aug 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#diabetic-foot-ulcers-healed-2x-faster-with-6400-iu-daily---rct-june2021">Diabetic foot ulcers healed 2X faster with 6,400 IU daily - RCT June 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-vitamin-d-deficiency-epidemic-pulsating-wound-jan2018">The Vitamin D Deficiency Epidemic (pulsating wound) Jan 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-for-healing-wounds--nov2014">Vitamin D for Healing Wounds – Nov 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="asked-ai-are-burns-less-severe-if-the-person-has-higher-level-of-vitamin-d">Asked AI: Are burns less severe if the person has higher level of vitamin d?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The study mentioned in 1 found that 88.9% of burn patients had a vitamin D deficiency and that wound healing time (WHT) across all three burn types was a common factor associated with vitamin D levels. Particularly, electrical burn patients with vitamin D deficiency showed prolonged wound healing over a post-burn period of 2 months.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Every person having Verneuil's disease (skin) was vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/every-person-having-verneuils-disease-skin-was-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/every-person-having-verneuils-disease-skin-was-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Raised veins on my left hand are no longer raised</title><link>/posts/raised-veins-on-my-left-hand-are-no-longer-raised.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/raised-veins-on-my-left-hand-are-no-longer-raised.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Many other anti-cancer photoproducts generated on the skin in addition to vitamin D</title><link>/posts/many-other-anti-cancer-photoproducts-generated-on-the-skin-in-addition-to-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-other-anti-cancer-photoproducts-generated-on-the-skin-in-addition-to-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="cytochromes-p450-and-skin-cancer-role-of-local-endocrine-pathways">Cytochromes p450 and skin cancer: role of local endocrine pathways.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Anticancer Agents Med Chem. 2014 Jan;14(1):77-96.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Slominski AT, Zmijewski MA, Semak I, Zbytek B, Pisarchik A, Li W, Zjawiony J, Tuckey RC1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skin is the largest body organ forming a metabolically active barrier between external and internal environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The metabolic barrier is composed of cytochromes P450 (CYPs) that regulate its homeostasis through activation or inactivation of biologically relevant molecules. In this review we focus our attention on local steroidogenic and secosteroidogenic systems in relation to skin cancer, e.g., prevention, attenuation of tumor progression and therapy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB increases vitamin D even if poor kidney by changing CYP27B1 genes in skin</title><link>/posts/uvb-increases-vitamin-d-even-if-poor-kidney-by-changing-cyp27b1-genes-in-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-increases-vitamin-d-even-if-poor-kidney-by-changing-cyp27b1-genes-in-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-narrow-band-ultraviolet-b-course-improves-vitamin-d-balance-and-alters-cutaneous-cyp27a1-and-cyp27b1-mrna-expression-levels-in-haemodialysis-patients-supplemented-with-oral-vitamin-d">A narrow-band ultraviolet B course improves vitamin D balance and alters cutaneous CYP27A1 and CYP27B1 mRNA expression levels in haemodialysis patients supplemented with oral vitamin D.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephron Clin Pract. 2013;124(1-2):17-22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1159/000355010.">doi: 10.1159/000355010.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Sep 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ala-Houhala MJ1, Vähävihu K, Snellman E, Hasan T, Kautiainen H, Karisola P, Dombrowski Y, Schauber J, Saha H, Reunala T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Tampere University Hospital, Tampere, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND/AIMS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) patients on dialysis are prone to vitamin D insufficiency despite oral vitamin D supplementation. Here, we studied whether narrow-band ultraviolet B (NB-UVB) exposures improve vitamin D balance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitiligo (loss of skin pigment) treated by narrowband UVB</title><link>/posts/vitiligo-loss-of-skin-pigment-treated-by-narrowband-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitiligo-loss-of-skin-pigment-treated-by-narrowband-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#correlation-of-vitamin-d-levels-with-pigmentation-in-vitiligo-patients-treated-with-nbuvb-therapy---july-2014">Correlation of Vitamin D Levels with Pigmentation in Vitiligo Patients Treated with NBUVB Therapy - July 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-2nd-article-in-july-2014">A 2nd article in July 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-50000-iu-every-2-weeks-for-8-weeks--narrowband-uvb-treated-vitiligo---rct--jan-2018">Vitamin D (50,000 IU every 2 weeks for 8 weeks) + narrowband UVB treated vitiligo - RCT Jan 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="correlation-of-vitamin-d-levels-with-pigmentation-in-vitiligo-patients-treated-with-nbuvb-therapy---july-2014">Correlation of Vitamin D Levels with Pigmentation in Vitiligo Patients Treated with NBUVB Therapy - July 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>ISRN Dermatology, Volume 2014 (2014), Article ID 493213, 6 pages, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/493213">http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/493213&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some vitamin D remains in the skin to protect skin from the sun</title><link>/posts/some-vitamin-d-remains-in-the-skin-to-protect-skin-from-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-vitamin-d-remains-in-the-skin-to-protect-skin-from-the-sun.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Topical Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/topical-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/topical-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="off-label-uses-of-topical-vitamin-d-in-dermatology-a-systematic-review---2014">Off-label uses of topical vitamin d in dermatology: a systematic review - 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Cutan Med Surg. 2014 Mar 1;18(2):91-108.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wat H, Dytoc M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:Topical vitamin D is approved by the US Food and Drug Administration for the treatment of psoriasis but is also used off-label in the treatment of a variety of cutaneous diseases despite a lack of evidence-based guidelines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective:The objective of this study was to provide evidence-based clinical guidelines for the off-label use of topical vitamin D in the treatment of dermatologic disease.Methods:A systematic literature review was conducted via the MEDLINE, Embase, and CENTRAL databases for off-label uses of topical vitamin D analogues in the treatment of dermatologic disease other than psoriasis. The data were synthesized, and evidence-based recommendations were rendered according to the highest level of evidence available.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin benefits from vitamin D – major overview</title><link>/posts/skin-benefits-from-vitamin-d-major-overview.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-benefits-from-vitamin-d-major-overview.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-the-skin-focus-on-a-complex-relationship-a-review">Vitamin D and the skin: Focus on a complex relationship: A review&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Advanced Research, Available online 8 February 2014, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jare.2014.01.011">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jare.2014.01.011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wedad Z. Mostafa, Rehab A. Hegazy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The “sunshine” vitamin is a hot topic that attracted ample attention over the past decades, specially that a considerable proportion of the worldwide population are deficient in this essential nutrient. Vitamin D was primarily acknowledged for its importance in bone formation, however; increasing evidence point to its interference with the proper function of nearly every tissue in our bodies including brain, heart, muscles, immune system and skin. Thereby its deficiency has been incriminated in a long panel of diseases including cancers, autoimmune diseases, cardiovascular and neurological disorders. Its involvement in the pathogenesis of different dermatological diseases is no exception and has been the subject of much research over the recent years. In the current review, we will throw light on this highly disputed vitamin that is creating a significant concern from a dermatological perspective. Furthermore, the consequences of its deficiency on the skin will be in focus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eczema not reduced in small study which used narrowband UVB to raise vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/eczema-not-reduced-in-small-study-which-used-narrowband-uvb-to-raise-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/eczema-not-reduced-in-small-study-which-used-narrowband-uvb-to-raise-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-patients-with-atopic-eczema-and-the-influence-of-narrow-band-ultraviolet-b-phototherapy">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in patients with atopic eczema and the influence of narrow-band ultraviolet B phototherapy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Photodermatology, Photoimmunology &amp;amp; Photomedicine. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/phpp.12117">doi: 10.1111/phpp.12117&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R F Rose MRCP*, C Williams MRCP, T Oliphant MRCP, F Browne MRCP, D Turner, V Goulden FRCP, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Narrow-band ultraviolet B phototherapy (nbUVB) is an established treatment modality for patients with severe atopic dermatitis (AD) and is known to increase serum vitamin D levels (SVD). The relationship between SVD and AD remains unclear.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dermatologists still not convienced that Vitamin D reduces atopic dermatitis – Review</title><link>/posts/dermatologists-still-not-convienced-that-vitamin-d-reduces-atopic-dermatitis-review.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dermatologists-still-not-convienced-that-vitamin-d-reduces-atopic-dermatitis-review.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Eczema 25 percent more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/eczema-25-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/eczema-25-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-vitamin-d-serum-level-is-inversely-associated-with-eczema-in-children-and-adolescents-in-germany">Low vitamin D serum level is inversely associated with eczema in children and adolescents in Germany.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Allergy. 2013 Jul;68(7):906-10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/all.12167.">doi: 10.1111/all.12167.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Jun 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heimbeck I, Wjst M, Apfelbacher CJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical Sociology, Department of Epidemiology and Preventive Medicine, University of Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Recent studies have yielded heterogeneous results regarding the relationship between vitamin D and atopic conditions. The aim of this study was to investigate the association between serum vitamin D level and the prevalence of eczema in German children and adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dermatologists view of UV radiation and the Skin</title><link>/posts/dermatologists-view-of-uv-radiation-and-the-skin.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dermatologists-view-of-uv-radiation-and-the-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="uv-radiation-and-the-skin">UV Radiation and the Skin&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2013, 14(6), 12222-12248; doi:10.3390/ijms140612222&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John D&amp;rsquo;Orazio 1,* email, Stuart Jarrett 2 email, Alexandra Amaro-Ortiz 3 email and Timothy Scott 3 email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Graduate Center for Toxicology and the Departments of Pediatrics, Biomedical and Molecular Pharmacology and Physiology, Markey Cancer Center, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA 2 Markey Cancer Center, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA 3 Graduate Center for Toxicology, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dr. Holick video on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dr-holick-video-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dr-holick-video-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="holick-video-on-youtubehttpwwwyoutubecomwatchvhigbvdcbfvkfeatureyoutube">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hiGBVDcbFVk&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be">Holick Video on YouTube&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-few-images-from-another-of-his-excellent-videos">A few images from another of his excellent videos&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="other-forms-of-vitamin-d-generated">Other forms of vitamin D generated&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-other-forms-of-vitamin-d-generated.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="c-section">C-section&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-c-section.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h2 id="iguana-with-little-vitamin-d">Iguana with little vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-iguana.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="uvb-white-skin-vs-black-skin">UVB White skin vs black skin&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/hollick-uvb-white-vs-black.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;h3 id="global-deficiency-of-vitamin-d">Global deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-global-deficiency.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="psorasis-placebo-vs-vitamin-d">Psorasis placebo vs vitamin d&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-psorasis-pacelbo-vs-vitamin-d.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="navy-indoors-8x-more-death-than-outdoors---1915">Navy indoors 8X more death than outdoors - 1915&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-navy-indoors-8x-more-death-than-outdoors---1915.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="type-1-diabetes-10x-less-at-equator">Type 1 diabetes 10X less at equator&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-type-1-diabetes-10x-less-at-equator.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="perhipheral-vascular-disease-decrease-80">Perhipheral Vascular Disease decrease 80%&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-pvd-decrease-80-.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="holick-and-his-family-take-3000-iu-vitamin-d-total-daily">Holick and his family take 3000 IU vitamin D total daily&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-3000-iu-vitamin-d-total.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="holick-recommendations-vs-age">Holick recommendations vs age&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-recommendations-vs-age.jpg" alt="image" width="400"></description></item><item><title>Expert Review by Dermatologists: get more vitamin D but avoid the sun</title><link>/posts/expert-review-by-dermatologists-get-more-vitamin-d-but-avoid-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/expert-review-by-dermatologists-get-more-vitamin-d-but-avoid-the-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-sun-exposure-to-bare-all-or-cover-up">Vitamin D and sun exposure: to bare all or cover up?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Editorial, Expert Review of Dermatology, December 2012, Vol. 7, No. 6, Pages 495-497 , DOI 10.1586/edm.12.60&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aaron Hughes*, Jeremy Hoffman and Adiele Hoffman&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Author for correspondence&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="they-do-not-want-to-say-that-they-have-been-wrong-for-50-years">They do not want to say that they have been wrong for 50 years&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Quote from the PDF&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Advice that encourages the public to increase sun exposure has the potential to undermine the work done by health agencies over the past 50 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5X more likely to have facial skin aging if vitamin D insufficient</title><link>/posts/5x-more-likely-to-have-facial-skin-aging-if-vitamin-d-insufficient.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5x-more-likely-to-have-facial-skin-aging-if-vitamin-d-insufficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="association-of-facial-skin-aging-and-vitamin-d-levels-in-middle-aged-white-women">Association of facial skin aging and vitamin D levels in middle-aged white women.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2010 Dec;21(12):2315-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10552-010-9646-y.">doi: 10.1007/s10552-010-9646-y.&lt;/a> Epub 2010 Sep 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chang AL, Fu T, Amir O, Tang JY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Stanford University School of Medicine, 450 Broadway, Pavilion C, MC 5334, Redwood City, CA 94305, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the relationship between UV-induced skin photodamage and 25(OH) vitamin D levels, we performed a cross-sectional study in 45 female subjects aged &amp;gt;40. Menopausal status, smoking status, skin cancer history, oral supplement use, and season of blood draw were recorded and serum 25(OH)D measured. A single-blinded, dermatologist evaluated standardized digital facial images for overall photodamage, erythema/telangiectasias, hyperpigmentation, number of lentigines, and wrinkling. Adjusting for age and season of blood collection, women with lower photodamage scores were associated with a 5-fold increased odds of being vitamin D insufficient (OR 5.0, 95% CI: 1.1, 23). Low scores for specific photodamage parameters including erythema/telangiectasias, hyperpigmentation, and wrinkling were also significantly associated with vitamin D insufficiency. Our results suggest an association between skin aging and 25(OH)D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Extensive burns reduce vitamin D, which increase bone loss</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-extensive-burns-reduce-vitamin-d-which-increase-bone-loss.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-extensive-burns-reduce-vitamin-d-which-increase-bone-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="does-vitamin-d-deficiency-contribute-to-post-burn-bone-loss">Does vitamin D deficiency contribute to post-burn bone loss?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://f1000research.com/articles/does-vitamin-d-deficiency-contribute-to-post-burn-bone-loss/%20">URL&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gordon L Klein &lt;a href="mailto:gordonklein@ymail.com">gordonklein@ymail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation and Shriners Burns Hospital, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, Texas 77555, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burn injury results in the acute loss of bone as well as the development of progressive vitamin D deficiency. Bone loss occurs acutely due to resorption, which is then followed by apoptosis of osteoblasts preventing repair of the bone loss. The acute resorption is due to a combination of the inflammatory response and the stress response to the burn injury. The resultant production of inflammatory cytokines and endogenous glucocorticoids initially stimulate the osteoblasts to produce RANK ligand, which stimulates marrow stem cell differentiation into osteoclasts. As the stress response persists for approximately one year post-burn the glucocorticoids produced by the body will cause osteoblast apoptosis and adynamic bone, impairing the ability of bone to recover its resorptive losses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D aids the aging skin</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-aids-the-aging-skin.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-aids-the-aging-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="unravelling-of-hidden-secrets-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-skin-aging">Unravelling of hidden secrets: the role of vitamin D in skin aging&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermato Endochronology Volume 4, Issue 3 July/August/September 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jörg Reichrath &lt;a href="mailto:Joerg.Reichrath@uks.eu">Joerg.Reichrath@uks.eu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Klinik für Dermatologie; Venerologie und Allergologie; Universitätsklinikum des Saarlandes; Homburg/Saar, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The skin is the only tissue in the human body that represents both a target tissue for biologically active vitamin D compounds including 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)2D) and has the capacity for the synthesis of 1,25(OH)2D from 7-dehydrocholesterol (7-DHC). Recent findings indicate that the vitamin D endocrine system (VDES), besides multiple other important functions, regulates aging in many tissues, including skin. This concept is strongly supported by several independent studies in genetically modified mice (including FGF23?/? and Klotho?/? mice) that are characterized by altered mineral homeostasis caused by a high vitamin D activity. These mice typically have phenotypic features of premature aging that include, besides short lifespan, retarded growth, ectopic calcification, immunological deficiency, osteoporosis, atherosclerosis, hypogonadism, skin and general organ atrophy. Notably, it has been demonstrated that these phenotypic features can be reversed by normalizing mineral homeostasis and/or vitamin D status. Interestingly, the aging phenotypes of mice suffering from hypovitaminosis D (VDR?/? and CYP27B1?/? mice) are quite similar to those suffering from hypervitaminosis D (including FGF-23?/? and Klotho?/? mice). Consequently, it has been hypothesized that thus, both hypo- and hypervitaminosis D may enhance aging.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intense UV damages cadaver skin</title><link>/posts/intense-uv-damages-cadaver-skin.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/intense-uv-damages-cadaver-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="solar-uv-radiation-reduces-the-barrier-function-of-human-skin">Solar UV radiation reduces the barrier function of human skin&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PNAS October 1, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Krysta Biniek, Kemal Levi, and Reinhold H. Dauskardt &lt;a href="mailto:dauskardt@stanford.edu">dauskardt@stanford.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA 94305&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Edited by John W. Hutchinson, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA, and approved August 31, 2012 (received for review April 25, 2012)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ubiquitous presence of solar UV radiation in human life is essential for vitamin D production but also leads to skin photoaging, damage, and malignancies. Photoaging and skin cancer have been extensively studied, but the effects of UV on the critical mechanical barrier function of the outermost layer of the epidermis, the stratum corneum (SC), are not understood. The SC is the first line of defense against environmental exposures like solar UV radiation, and its effects on UV targets within the SC and subsequent alterations in the mechanical properties and related barrier function are unclear. Alteration of the SC’s mechanical properties can lead to severe macroscopic skin damage such as chapping and cracking and associated inflammation, infection, scarring, and abnormal desquamation. Here, we show that UV exposure has dramatic effects on cell cohesion and mechanical integrity that are related to its effects on the SC’s intercellular components, including intercellular lipids and corneodesmosomes. We found that, although the keratin-controlled stiffness remained surprisingly constant with UV exposure, the intercellular strength, strain, and cohesion decreased markedly. We further show that solar UV radiation poses a double threat to skin by both increasing the biomechanical driving force for damage while simultaneously decreasing the skin’s natural ability to resist, compromising the critical barrier function of the skin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Women around the world want whiter skin</title><link>/posts/women-around-the-world-want-whiter-skin.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-around-the-world-want-whiter-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-hrefpostsmany-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1586many-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic-a-aug-2012">&lt;a href="/posts/many-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1586">Many reasons why vitamin D deficiency has become epidemic &lt;/a> Aug 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Want whiter skin - especially women&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://innerreflectionstranscribed.wordpress.com/2007/04/25/fair-skin-desirable/">Here&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=K8PCYtg1SocC&amp;amp;pg=PT81&amp;amp;lpg=PT81&amp;amp;dq=desirability+of+white+skin&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=CI7w34zn6X&amp;amp;sig=2ma4FM-zouS59Afbz4tggXdxUNI&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ei=eaTaTbniI4HGsAOz0dGFDA&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;oi=book_result&amp;amp;ct=result&amp;amp;resnum=5&amp;amp;ved=0CDQQ6AEwBA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=desirability%20of%20white%20skin&amp;amp;f=false">Here (Helen of Troy)&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.abcdlady.com/2005-07/art6.php">Being Fair-Skinned in Today&amp;rsquo;s World&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/suntan-popularity-is-fading" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 304">Suntan: Popularity is fading&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/perhaps-not-burn-from-the-sun-if-have-enough-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1669">Perhaps not burn from the sun if have enough vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/09/23/thai-vulva-bleaching-product.html">Thai vulva-bleaching product&lt;/a> Sept 2012&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In many countries across south-east Asia, fairer skin has long been equated with higher class as it suggests a life not spent toiling in rice paddies under the sun. The Thai language is peppered with cultural expressions that denigrate dark skin, such as the insult dam mhuen e-ga – &amp;ldquo;black like a crow&amp;rdquo;. These days, rice farmers wear long sleeves, trousers, wide-brimmed hats and gloves&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic dermatitis dramatically reduced in Iran with 1600 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-dramatically-reduced-in-iran-with-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-dramatically-reduced-in-iran-with-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-the-treatment-of-atopic-dermatitis-a-clinical-trial-study">Vitamin D supplementation in the treatment of atopic dermatitis: a clinical trial study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Amestejani M, Salehi BS, Vasigh M, Sobhkhiz A, Karami M, Alinia H, Kamrava SK, Shamspour J Drugs Dermatol. 2012 Mar;11(3):327-30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N, Ghalehbaghi B, Behzadi AH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Orumieh University of Medical Science, Orumieh, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of vitamin D in Atopic Dermatitis (AD) is ambiguous and clinical trials are needed to assess the role of vitamin D in the treatment of AD. The aim of this clinical trial study to evaluate the effect of vitamin D supplementation on patients with AD.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>