<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Skin on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/skin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Skin on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/skin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nails treated by Vitamins (D etc.)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nails-treated-by-vitamins-d-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nails-treated-by-vitamins-d-etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamins-for-the-management-of-nail-disease-a-literature-review&#34;&gt;Vitamins for the Management of Nail Disease: A Literature Review&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Skin Appendage Disord (2024) 10 (2): 104–122. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1159/000534972&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1159/000534972&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kaya L. Curtis; Shari R. Lipner&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Vitamins have gained popularity among physicians and patients for purported benefits to hair, skin, and nail health. Safe and efficacious therapies for nail disorders, many of which are chronic conditions, are needed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summary: We conducted a literature review of studies assessing the efficacy of oral, topical, and intralesional vitamin/vitamin derivatives for the treatment of nail disorders, including yellow nail syndrome, brittle nail syndrome, onychomycosis, habit-tic nail deformity, periungual/subungual verruca, and nail psoriasis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accutane for acne associated with birth defects, abortions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/accutane-for-acne-associated-with-birth-defects-abortions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/accutane-for-acne-associated-with-birth-defects-abortions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;surge-in-usage-of-acne-medication-linked-to-birth-defects-prompts-in-depth-analysis-of-pregnancy-outcomes&#34;&gt;Surge in Usage of Acne Medication Linked to Birth Defects Prompts In-Depth Analysis of Pregnancy Outcomes&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trialsitenews.com/a/surge-in-usage-of-acne-medication-linked-to-birth-defects-prompts-in-depth-analysis-of-pregnancy-outcomes-d5d0e877&#34;&gt;TrialSiteNews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  Reporting on:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of isotretinoin among girls and women of childbearing age and occurrence of isotretinoin-exposed pregnancies in Germany: A population-based study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January 25, 2024 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1004339&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1004339&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;This finding and the fact that at least  &lt;strong&gt;45%&lt;/strong&gt;  of exposed pregnancies (74 of 164) in our study ended in an  &lt;strong&gt;induced abortion&lt;/strong&gt; —as compared to  &lt;strong&gt;4%&lt;/strong&gt;  when all pregnancies &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-file-pdf&#34; style=&#34;margin-right: 0.3em;&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atopic Dermatitis not helped by small weekly doses of Vitamin D (8K 2y-6y.16K 12y-18y) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/atopic-dermatitis-not-helped-by-small-weekly-doses-of-vitamin-d-8k-2y-6y16k-12y-18y-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/atopic-dermatitis-not-helped-by-small-weekly-doses-of-vitamin-d-8k-2y-6y16k-12y-18y-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-weekly-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-the-severity-of-atopic-dermatitis-and-type-2-immunity-biomarkers-in-children-a-randomized-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;Effect of weekly vitamin D supplementation on the severity of atopic dermatitis and type 2 immunity biomarkers in children: A randomized controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol . 2024 Mar 14. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/jdv.19959&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1111/jdv.19959&lt;/a&gt; PDF behind paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Vitamin D (VD) deficiency is common among patients with atopic dermatitis (AD) and often associated with severity. However, randomized trials of VD supplementation in AD have had equivocal results, and there is little information regarding the effect of VD supplementation on type 2 immunity in AD patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wounds and pregnancy masks treated by topical Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wounds-and-pregnancy-masks-treated-by-topical-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wounds-and-pregnancy-masks-treated-by-topical-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-and-wound-healing-assessing-skin-barrier-function-and-implications-for-chloasma-treatment&#34;&gt;Vitamin D and wound healing: Assessing skin barrier function and implications for chloasma treatment&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Int Wound J 2024 Jan;21(1):e14541. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/iwj.14541.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1111/iwj.14541.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Qiong Chen 1, Lin Liu 2, Yi Zhang 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chloasma, which is distinguished by irregularities in the pigmentation of skin, poses substantial challenge in the field of dermatology. The regulatory influence of vitamin D on the functions of skin cells implies that it may have the capacity to effectively treat chloasma and promote wound healing. To assess the efficacy of vitamin D in chloasma treatment and its impact on the function of skin barrier during the process of wound healing. The research spanned from April 2022 to September 2023, in Shanghai, China, examined 480 individuals who had been diagnosed with chloasma. A double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial was utilized to evaluate effectiveness of topical vitamin D3 in treatment of chloasma. Concurrently, randomized control trial investigated the effects of ingested vitamin D3 supplements on the process of wound healing. Transepidermal water loss (TEWL), chloasma severity score changes, wound size reduction and skin hydration levels were critical performance indicators. Statistically, the severity scores of chloasma decreased significantly in the vitamin D treatment group at 3 and 6 months compared with the placebo (p &amp;lt; 0.05). The Vitamin D group exhibited superior wound healing outcomes, including more substantial reduction in lesion size and enhanced skin barrier function, as evidenced by increased skin hydration and decreased TEWL (p &amp;lt; 0.05). Vitamin D substantially mitigated the severity of chloasma and has beneficial effect on wound healing and integrity of the skin barrier. Based on the results obtained, vitamin D exhibited promise as a therapeutic intervention in the field of dermatology, specifically in treatment of chloasma and promotion of wound recovery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skin Helath improved by Vitamin D and 12 other supplements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/skin-helath-improved-by-vitamin-d-and-12-other-supplements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/skin-helath-improved-by-vitamin-d-and-12-other-supplements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;nutritional-supplements-for-skin-health-a-review-of-what-should-be-chosen-and-why&#34;&gt;Nutritional Supplements for Skin Health-A Review of What Should Be Chosen and Why&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Medicina (Kaunas) 2023 Dec 29;60(1):68. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina60010068.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/medicina60010068.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jacek Januszewski 1, Alicja Forma 2, Julita Zembala 3, Michał Flieger 2, Magdalena Tyczyńska 1, James Curtis Dring 1, Iga Dudek 2, Kamila Świątek 1, Jacek Baj 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;250&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Supplementation of micronutrients is considered to be crucial in the reinforcement of the skin&amp;rsquo;s barrier. In this paper, 14 nutritional compounds commonly used in food or pharmaceutic industries were analyzed in terms of influencing skin conditions. The major objective of this paper was to provide a narrative review of the available literature regarding several chosen compounds that are currently widely recommended as supplements that aim to maintain proper and healthy skin conditions. We conducted a review of the literature from PubMed, Scopus, and Web of Science until September 2023 without any other restrictions regarding the year of the publication. Ultimately, we reviewed 238 articles, including them in this review. Each of the reviewed compounds, including vitamin A, vitamin C, vitamin D, vitamin E, curcumin, chlorella, Omega-3, biotin,Ppolypodium leucotomos, Simmondsia chinesis, gamma oryzanol, olive leaf extract, spirulina, and astaxanthin, was observed to present some possible effects with promising benefits for a skin condition, i.e., photoprotective radiation. Adding them to the diet or daily routine might have a positive influence on some skin inflammatory diseases such as atopic dermatitis or psoriasis. Further, UV radiation protection facilitated by some supplements and their impact on human cells might be helpful during chemotherapy or in preventing melanoma development. Further research is needed because of the lack of clear consensus regarding the doses of the described compounds that could provide desirable effects on the skin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitiligo (spotty skin) and Vitamin D, UVB - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitiligo-spotty-skin-and-vitamin-d-uvb-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitiligo-spotty-skin-and-vitamin-d-uvb-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange8span-vitamindwiki-pages-with-vitiligo-in-the-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;8+&lt;/span&gt; VitaminDWiki pages with VITILIGO in the title&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{list max=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;VITILIGO&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; shownbitems=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xA;&#xA;{column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=title format=&amp;ldquo;objectlink&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;topical-vitamin-d-analogs-patented-help-treat-vitiligo---sep-2023&#34;&gt;Topical vitamin D analogs (patented) help treat Vitiligo - Sep 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using a Topical Formulation of Vitamin D for the Treatment of Vitiligo: A Systematic Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D benefits your skin in 7 ways</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-benefits-your-skin-in-7-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-benefits-your-skin-in-7-ways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;by-chrome-generative-ai-aug-2023&#34;&gt;By Chrome Generative AI Aug 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anti-inflammatory: Vitamin D can help treat skin conditions like acne, eczema, and psoriasis. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anti-aging: Vitamin D can help prevent skin aging by protecting against damage, reducing puffiness, and minimizing fine lines and wrinkles. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moisturizing: Vitamin D3 can improve skin hydration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Antioxidant: Vitamin D can help neutralize free radicals, especially those caused by UV radiation. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Skin repair: Vitamin D can contribute to skin repair and enhance the skin&amp;rsquo;s immune system. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D and the skin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-skin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-skin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-and-the-skin-an-immunologic-and-therapeutic-update&#34;&gt;Vitamin D and the skin: an immunologic and therapeutic update&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J Egypt Women’s Dermatol Soc 20:69-80 DOI: 10.4103/jewd.jewd_55_22&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Naglaa N. El Mongy, Rana F. Hilal&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Department of Dermatology, Kasr Al Ainy Teaching Hospital, Cairo University, Cairo, Egypt&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Correspondence to Rana F. Hilal, MD, Department of Dermatology, Kasr Al Ainy Teaching Hospital, Cairo University, Al-Saray Street, Kasr Al Ainy, El Manial, Cairo 11956, e-mail: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:rana.hilal@kasralainy.edu.eg&#34;&gt;rana.hilal@kasralainy.edu.eg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D plays a vital role in skin diseases, and vitamin D supplementation seems to warrant protection against occurrence and exacerbation of several dermatological conditions. This review covers the immunopathological and therapeutic role of vitamin D, with a comprehensive illustration in some diseases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
