<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vitamin D and Boron on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/vitamin-d-and-boron.html</link><description>Recent content in Vitamin D and Boron on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vitamin-d-and-boron/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Low cost cofactors for vitamin D</title><link>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-for-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-for-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="it-is-important-to-have-cofactors-when-taking-more-than-2000-iu-vitamin-d-average">It is IMPORTANT to have cofactors when taking more than 2000 IU vitamin D average&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/decrease-calcium-and-increase-magnesium-when-increasing-vitamin-d">Decrease Calcium and Increase Magnesium when increasing vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There is a lack of evidence of the interactions - the following are guesses based on incomplete information&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most studies are monotheraputic: e.g. supply Vitamin D, and rarely use any of the cofactors&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="update-2022-taking-most-of-my-supplements-as-pills---average-of-about-3day">Update 2022 taking most of my supplements as pills - average of about 3/day&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/herny-s-weekly-pills.jpg" alt="image" width="800">
&lt;p>Also take Magnesium Chloride as a liquid and Omega-3 as a cream&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10 mg of Boron daily increased Vitamin D and other levels</title><link>/posts/10-mg-of-boron-daily-increased-vitamin-d-and-other-levels.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10-mg-of-boron-daily-increased-vitamin-d-and-other-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="comparative-effects-of-daily-and-weekly-boron-supplementation-on-plasma-steroid-hormones-and-proinflammatory-cytokines">Comparative effects of daily and weekly boron supplementation on plasma steroid hormones and proinflammatory cytokines.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Trace Elem Med Biol. 2010 Dec 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Naghii MR, Mofid M, Asgari AR, Hedayati M, Daneshpour MS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sport Physiology Research Center, Baqiyatallah (a.s.) University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Islamic Republic of Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boron possesses widespread properties in biochemistry and nutrition. Acute supplementation with 11.6mg of boron resulted in a significant increase in plasma boron concentration. Given such a fast bioavailability, the objective was to determine whether acute (hourly or daily), and weekly supplementation could have any significant biological effects on the steroid hormones and further on some inflammatory biomarkers. Eight healthy male volunteers attended the laboratory on three occasions (days 0, 1 and 7). On the first day (day 0), a blood sample collection at 8.00A.M was followed by ingestion of placebo with the breakfast. On the next day (supplementation-day 1), similar procedure was followed by ingestion of a capsule containing &lt;strong>10mg of boron&lt;/strong> . On both occasions blood was collected every 2h for the next 6h. Subjects were requested to consume a capsule of 10mg boron every day with their breakfast, and on the day 7, the blood collection was carried out at 8.00A.M, again. Boron in plasma increased significantly following hours and weekly consumption. Six hours supplementation showed a significant decrease on sex hormone binding globulin (SHBG), high sensitive CRP (hsCRP) and TNF-? level. After one week (in samples taken at 8.00A.M, only), the mean plasma free testosterone increased and the mean plasma estradiol decreased significantly. Dihydrotestosterone, cortisol and &lt;strong>vitamin D was elevated&lt;/strong> . Also, concentrations of all three inflammatory biomarkers decreased after supplementation. Of note, despite decreased proinflammatory cytokines, based on recent clinical data, this must be the first human study report to show an increase level of free testosterone after boron consumption.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>