<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pregnancy on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/pregnancy.html</link><description>Recent content in Pregnancy on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/pregnancy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smoking while pregnant: are the problems due to low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/smoking-while-pregnant-are-the-problems-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/smoking-while-pregnant-are-the-problems-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>A UK doctor doubts that more than 400 IU is needed during pregnancy of white women</title><link>/posts/a-uk-doctor-doubts-that-more-than-400-iu-is-needed-during-pregnancy-of-white-women.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-uk-doctor-doubts-that-more-than-400-iu-is-needed-during-pregnancy-of-white-women.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="is-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-pregnancy-advisable">Is vitamin D supplementation in pregnancy advisable?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Lancet,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 381, Issue 9884, 22–28 June 2013, Pages 2143–2145&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Philip J Steer a, b, E-mail the corresponding author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Division of Cancer, Faculty of Medicine, Imperial College London, London, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Academic Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Chelsea and Westminster Hospital, London SW10 9NH, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Refers To&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Debbie A Lawlor, Andrew K Wills, Abigail Fraser, Adrian Sayers, William D Fraser, Jonathan H Tobias&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamins D and A, before and after birth</title><link>/posts/vitamins-d-and-a-before-and-after-birth.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamins-d-and-a-before-and-after-birth.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D, Vitamin A, Maternal-Perinatal Considerations: Old Concepts, New Insights, New Questions&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Journal of Pediatrics, Volume 162, Issue 3, Supplement, March 2013, Pages S26–S30&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Teresa Murguía-Peniche, MDCorresponding author contact information, E-mail the corresponding author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>National Center for Child and Adolescent Health (CeNSIA), Mexico City, Mexico&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jpeds.2012.11.050">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jpeds.2012.11.050&lt;/a>,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamins A and D are essential nutrients that play important roles in growth and development. Preterm and low birth weight infants have low levels of these nutrients and are at risk for developing detrimental health consequences associated with vitamin A and vitamin D deficiencies. Preliminary data suggest that vitamin A and D supplementation is needed to prevent deficiency. More work is needed to define optimal doses, timing, and modes of administration to ensure that an adequate supply of these vitamins is available to meet the critical needs during pregnancy and in high-risk neonates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WHO says that infants not need vitamin D until 6 months and only 200 IU after - 2013</title><link>/posts/who-says-that-infants-not-need-vitamin-d-until-6-months-and-only-200-iu-after-2013.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/who-says-that-infants-not-need-vitamin-d-until-6-months-and-only-200-iu-after-2013.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Getting pregnant in May increases chance of premature birth by 10 percent</title><link>/posts/getting-pregnant-in-may-increases-chance-of-premature-birth-by-10-percent.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/getting-pregnant-in-may-increases-chance-of-premature-birth-by-10-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>But there may be many problems with infant health if pregnancy started in June or July. See chart below&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="within-mother-analysis-of-seasonal-patterns-in-health-at-birth">Within-mother analysis of seasonal patterns in health at birth&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Janet Currie &lt;a href="mailto:jcurrie@princeton.edu">jcurrie@princeton.edu&lt;/a> and Hannes Schwandt&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A large literature describes relationships between month of birth, birth weight, and gestation. These relationships are hypothesized to reflect the causal impact of seasonal environmental factors. However, recent work casts doubt on this interpretation by showing that mothers with lower socioeconomic status are more likely to give birth in months that are associated with poorer birth outcomes. Seasonality in the numbers of conceptions in different months can also induce a mechanical correlation between preterm birth and month of birth. This paper analyzes the seasonality of health at birth using a large sample of 647,050 groups of US siblings representing &lt;strong>1,435,213 children&lt;/strong> . By following the same mother over time, we eliminate differences in fixed maternal characteristics as an explanation for seasonal differences in health at birth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pregnant women should have 4,000 IU of vitamin D – Topic review</title><link>/posts/pregnant-women-should-have-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-topic-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnant-women-should-have-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-topic-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="is-increased-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-pregnancy-for-deficient-and-non-deficient-mother-associated-with-positive-pregnancyneonatal-outcomes">Is increased vitamin D supplementation during pregnancy for deficient and non-deficient mother associated with positive pregnancy/neonatal outcomes?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span>[&amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;The following is a Critically Appraised Topic for Doctor of Nursing Practice (DNP) program at George Mason University&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;]&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Search Strategies and Results: EBSCO HOST search engine was used to search: CINAHL (7 articles), MEDLINE (17articles), and PubMed (14 articles) databases. MESH terms used in search: &amp;ldquo;vitamin D supplementation AND pregnancy AND neonatal outcomes&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Will 1600 IU vitamin D prevent gestational diabetes – no, not enough,</title><link>/posts/will-1600-iu-vitamin-d-prevent-gestational-diabetes-no-not-enough.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/will-1600-iu-vitamin-d-prevent-gestational-diabetes-no-not-enough.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dali-vitamin-d-and-lifestyle-intervention-for-gestational-diabetes-mellitus-gdm-prevention-an-european-multicentre-randomised-trial----study-protocol">DALI: Vitamin D and lifestyle intervention for gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) prevention: an European multicentre, randomised trial &amp;ndash; study protocol&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth 2013, 13:142 doi:10.1186/1471-2393-13-142&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 5 July 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Judith GM Jelsma, Mireille NM van Poppel, Sander Galjaard, Gernot Desoye, Rosa Corcoy, Roland Devlieger, Andre van Assche, Dirk Timmerman, Goele Jans, Jurgen Harreiter, Alexandra Kautzky-Willer, Peter Damm, Elisabeth R Mathiesen, Dorte M Jensen, Liselotte Andersen, Fidelma Dunne, Annunziata Lapolla, Graziano Di Cianni, Alessandra Bertolotto, Ewa Wender-Oegowska, Agnieszka Zawiejska, Kinga Blumska, David Hill, Pablo Rebollo, Frank J Snoek and David Simmons&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Global Perspective - Holick</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-global-perspective-holick.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-global-perspective-holick.html</guid><description>&lt;p>It is now generally accepted that vitamin D deficiency is a worldwide health problem that affects not only musculoskeletal health but also a wide range of acute and chronic diseases. However, there remains cynicism about the lack of randomized controlled trials to support the association studies regarding the nonskeletal health benefits of vitamin D. This review was obtained by searching English-language studies published up to April 1, 2013, in PubMed, MEDLINE, and the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (search terms: vitamin D and supplementation) and focuses on recent challenges regarding the definition of vitamin D deficiency and how to achieve optimal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations from dietary sources, supplements, and sun exposure. The effect of vitamin D on fetal programming epigenetics and gene regulation could potentially explain why vitamin D has been reported to have such wide-ranging health benefits throughout life. There is potentially a great upside to increasing the vitamin D status of children and adults worldwide for improving musculoskeletal health and reducing the risk of chronic illnesses, including some cancers, autoimmune diseases, infectious diseases, type 2 diabetes mellitus, neurocognitive disorders, and mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Single dose of 200,000 IU of vitamin D during pregnancy did not reduce wheezing 3 years later</title><link>/posts/single-dose-of-200000-iu-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-did-not-reduce-wheezing-3-years-later.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/single-dose-of-200000-iu-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-did-not-reduce-wheezing-3-years-later.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="prenatal-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-child-respiratory-health-a-randomised-controlled-trial">Prenatal Vitamin D Supplementation and Child Respiratory Health: A Randomised Controlled Trial&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(6): e66627. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0066627&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen T. Goldring, Chris J. Griffiths, Adrian R. Martineau, Stephen Robinson, Christina Yu,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sheree Poulton, Jane C. Kirkby, Janet Stocks, Richard Hooper, Seif O. Shaheen, John O. Warner, Robert J. Boyle&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Observational studies suggest high prenatal vitamin D intake may be associated with reduced childhood wheezing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We examined the effect of prenatal vitamin D on childhood wheezing in an interventional study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, DHA, Folic, Iodine benefits during pregnancy</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-dha-folic-iodine-benefits-during-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-dha-folic-iodine-benefits-during-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="benefits-of-docosahexaenoic-acid-folic-acid-vitamin-d-and-iodine-on-foetal-and-infant-brain-development-and-function-following-maternal-supplementation-during-pregnancy-and-lactation">Benefits of Docosahexaenoic Acid, Folic Acid, Vitamin D and Iodine on Foetal and Infant Brain Development and Function Following Maternal Supplementation during Pregnancy and Lactation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2012 July; 4(7): 799–840.. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/nu4070799">doi: 10.3390/nu4070799&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nancy L. Morse&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3407995&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scientific literature is increasingly reporting on dietary deficiencies in many populations of some nutrients critical for foetal and infant brain development and function.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose: To highlight the potential benefits of maternal supplementation with docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) and other important complimentary nutrients, including vitamin D, folic acid and iodine during pregnancy and/or breast feeding for foetal and/or infant brain development and/or function.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pregnancy needs 4000 IU of vitamin D: current opinion</title><link>/posts/pregnancy-needs-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-current-opinion.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnancy-needs-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-current-opinion.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-nutrition-in-pregnancy-current-opinion">Vitamin D nutrition in pregnancy: current opinion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>International Journal of Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Volume 2013:5 Pages 333 - 343; DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.2147/IJWH.S34032">http://dx.doi.org/10.2147/IJWH.S34032&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dawodu A, Akinbi H &lt;a href="mailto:adekunle.dawodu@cchmc.org">adekunle.dawodu@cchmc.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Global Health Center, 2 Neonatology and Pulmonary Biology, Cincinnati Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Medical Center, Cincinnati, OH, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is increasing interest in vitamin D nutrition during pregnancy because of widespread reports of a high prevalence of low vitamin D status in pregnant women. While vitamin D is important for calcium and phosphorus homeostasis and for bone health, it also plays important roles in many other physiologic functions in the body. Consistent with the expanded role of vitamin D, recent observational studies have demonstrated that low vitamin D status in pregnancy is associated with multiple potential adverse maternal, fetal, and infant outcomes and contributes to low vitamin D status in infants at birth. Therefore, an overview of the current understanding of vitamin D nutrition in pregnancy and a review of the results of studies to optimize vitamin D status during pregnancy and in the offspring is of public health importance and timely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Group is giving only 200 IU of Vitamin D to 70 million women and children to prevent Rickets</title><link>/posts/group-is-giving-only-200-iu-of-vitamin-d-to-70-million-women-and-children-to-prevent-rickets.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/group-is-giving-only-200-iu-of-vitamin-d-to-70-million-women-and-children-to-prevent-rickets.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-angels-we-could-reach-100-million-kids--tomorrow-if-we-had-the-fundinghttpwwwnutraingredientscomindustryvitamin-angels-we-could-reach-100-million-kids-tomorrow-if-we-had-the-funding">&lt;a href="http://www.nutraingredients.com/Industry/Vitamin-Angels-We-could-reach-100-million-kids-tomorrow-if-we-had-the-funding?">Vitamin Angels: We could reach 100 million kids tomorrow if we had the funding&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nice introduction at Nutraingredients, May 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.vitaminangels.org/%20">Vitamin Angels home page&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.vitaminangels.org/contributors">Biggest Contributors to Vitamin Angels&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cash $500,000+ Sams Club, Flintstone Vitamins, VitaminWater&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cash $100,000+ Pharmachem labs, Univera, Vitamin World, Barlean’s&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cash $50,000+ Nutragenetics, Purity Products, Vitamin Shoppe, TwinLab&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pills&lt;/strong> $5,000,000+ ProCaps Labs&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pills&lt;/strong> $1,000,000+ NBTY&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pills&lt;/strong> $250,000+ Capsugel&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-angels-have-2-programs---both-operated-thru-ngos-in-the-country">Vitamin Angels have 2 programs - both operated thru NGOs in the country&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Operation 20/20&lt;/strong> which gives &lt;strong>vitamin A&lt;/strong> twice a year&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Low maternal vitamin D increases probability of heart disease later in adult</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-low-maternal-vitamin-d-increases-probability-of-heart-disease-later-in-adult.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-low-maternal-vitamin-d-increases-probability-of-heart-disease-later-in-adult.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-early-life-and-the-potential-programming-of-cardiovascular-disease-in-adulthood">Vitamin D Deficiency in Early Life and the Potential Programming of Cardiovascular Disease in Adulthood.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Cardiovasc Transl Res. 2013 May 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gezmish O, &lt;a href="mailto:Oksan.Gezmish@med.monash.edu.au">Oksan.Gezmish@med.monash.edu.au&lt;/a>, Black MJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Anatomy and Developmental Biology, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, 3800, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is a major worldwide public health problem affecting people of all ages, from infants to the elderly. Of particular concern is the high incidence of vitamin D deficiency in women during pregnancy and lactation, leading to the exposure of the growing fetus/infant to inadequate levels of vitamin D, which is essential for normal development. Vitamin D deficiency in adulthood is linked to the etiology of hypertension and to a multitude of adverse cardiovascular outcomes. It is now well-established that the antecedents of cardiovascular disease can originate very early in life. The purpose of this review is to highlight how maternal vitamin D deficiency, and its effects in upregulating the fetal renin-angiotensin system and altering cardiomyocyte growth in the fetal heart, has the potential to program long-term vulnerability to cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>March of Dimes pays for study of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/march-of-dimes-pays-for-study-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/march-of-dimes-pays-for-study-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-maternal-and-child-health-overview-and-implications-for-dietary-requirements">Vitamin D and maternal and child health: Overview and implications for dietary requirements&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-maternal-and-child-health-overview-and-implications-for-dietary-requirements">Vitamin D and maternal and child health: Overview and implications for dietary requirements&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Birth Defects Research Part C: Embryo Today: Reviews, Volume 99, Issue 1, pages 24–44, March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Janet Y. Uriu-Adams 1, Sarah G. Obican 2, Carl L. Keen 3,clkeen@ucdavis.edu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Nutrition, University of California, Davis, Davis, California&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Columbia University, New York, New York&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bones better after pregnancy with just 200 IU of vitamin D plus 600 Calcium – RCT</title><link>/posts/bones-better-after-pregnancy-with-just-200-iu-of-vitamin-d-plus-600-calcium-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bones-better-after-pregnancy-with-just-200-iu-of-vitamin-d-plus-600-calcium-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Needed more than 1600 IU of vitamin D during pregnancy – RCT</title><link>/posts/needed-more-than-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/needed-more-than-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-requirement-in-pregnancy-to-prevent-deficiency-in-neonates-a-randomised-trial">Vitamin D requirement in pregnancy to prevent deficiency in neonates: a randomised trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Singapore Med J. 2013 May;54(5):285-288.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shakiba M, Iranmanesh MR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paediatric Department, Shahid Sadoughi Medical University, Avicenna St, Yazd, Iran. &lt;a href="mailto:shakiba@ssu.ac.ir">shakiba@ssu.ac.ir&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: The exact amount of vitamin D required for pregnant women to adequately supply the foetus during pregnancy is still unclear. This randomised trial attempted to determine the optimal dose of vitamin D necessary during pregnancy in order to attain a vitamin D level &amp;gt; 20 ng/mL in neonates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects against many types of health problems – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-effects-on-musculoskeletal-health-immunity-autoimmunity-cardiovascular-disease-cancer-fertility-pregnancy-dementia-and-mortality-a-review-of-recent-evidence">Vitamin D effects on musculoskeletal health, immunity, autoimmunity, cardiovascular disease, cancer, fertility, pregnancy, dementia and mortality-A review of recent evidence.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmun Rev. 2013 Mar 28. pii: S1568-9972(13)00040-2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.">doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pawel Pludowski a &lt;a href="mailto:p.pludowski@czd.pl">p.pludowski@czd.pl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael F. Holick b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Pilzc, d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carol L. Wagner e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce W. Hollis e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant f,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yehuda Shoenfeld g,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elisabeth Lerchbaum c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David J. Llewellyn h,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katharina Kienreich c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maya Soni h&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Biochemistry, Radioimmunology and Experimental Medicine, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Health Institute, Warsaw, Poland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Season of birth associated with Pneumonia (10 %) and Multiple Sclerosis (30 %)</title><link>/posts/season-of-birth-associated-with-pneumonia-10-percent-and-multiple-sclerosis-30-percent.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/season-of-birth-associated-with-pneumonia-10-percent-and-multiple-sclerosis-30-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#no-effect-of-season-of-birth-on-risk-of-type-1-diabetes-cancer-schizophrenia-and-ischemic-heart-disease-while-some-variations-may-be-seen-for-pneumonia-and-multiple-sclerosis">No effect of season of birth on risk of type 1 diabetes, cancer, schizophrenia and ischemic heart disease, while some variations may be seen for pneumonia and multiple sclerosis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="no-effect-of-season-of-birth-on-risk-of-type-1-diabetes-cancer-schizophrenia-and-ischemic-heart-disease-while-some-variations-may-be-seen-for-pneumonia-and-multiple-sclerosis">No effect of season of birth on risk of type 1 diabetes, cancer, schizophrenia and ischemic heart disease, while some variations may be seen for pneumonia and multiple sclerosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermato Endocrinology: Volume 5, Issue 2 April/May/June 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Susanna við Streym, Lars Rejnmark, Leif Mosekilde and Peter Vestergaard&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PCBs increased the chance of being Vitamin D deficient by 3 percent</title><link>/posts/pcbs-increased-the-chance-of-being-vitamin-d-deficient-by-3-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pcbs-increased-the-chance-of-being-vitamin-d-deficient-by-3-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="associations-between-blood-persistent-organic-pollutants-and-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-in-pregnancy">Associations between blood persistent organic pollutants and 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 in pregnancy.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Environ Int. 2013 May 4;57-58C:34-41. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2013.03.011.">doi: 10.1016/j.envint.2013.03.011.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morales E, Gascon M, Martinez D, Casas M, Ballester F, Rodríguez-Bernal CL, Ibarluzea J, Marina LS, Espada M, Goñi F, Vizcaino E, Grimalt JO, Sunyer J; on behalf of the INMA Project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Research in Environmental Epidemiology (CREAL), Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain; Hospital del Mar Medical Research Institute (IMIM), Barcelona, Catalonia,Spain; CIBER in Epidemiology and Public Health (CIBERESP), Spain. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:emorales1@creal.cat">emorales1@creal.cat&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Near the end of pregnancy 50,000 IU vitamin D weekly was great – RCT</title><link>/posts/near-the-end-of-pregnancy-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-was-great-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/near-the-end-of-pregnancy-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-was-great-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-administration-in-vitamin-d-deficient-pregnant-women-on-maternal-and-neonatal-serum-calcium-and-vitamin-d-concentrations-a-randomised-clinical-trial">Effect of vitamin D administration in vitamin D-deficient pregnant women on maternal and neonatal serum calcium and vitamin D concentrations: a randomised clinical trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2013 Apr 29:1-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hashemipour S, Lalooha F, Zahir Mirdamadi S, Ziaee A, Dabaghi Ghaleh T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Metabolic Diseases Research Center, Qazvin University of Medical Science, Qazvin, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
#### ||Measure| Control|50,000 IU weekly
&lt;p>Body length|48|49&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Head circumference|35.3|35.9&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Body weight|3.26 kg|3.42 kg&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maternal weight gain|11.7 kg|13.7 kg||&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don’t be pregnant in Scotland</title><link>/posts/dont-be-pregnant-in-scotland.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dont-be-pregnant-in-scotland.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-at-high-latitude-in-scotland">Vitamin D in pregnancy at high latitude in Scotland.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2013 Mar 14;109(5):898-905. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0007114512002255.">doi: 10.1017/S0007114512002255.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jul 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Haggarty P, Campbell DM, Knox S, Horgan GW, Hoad G, Boulton E, McNeill G, Wallace AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Lifelong Health, Rowett Institute of Nutrition and Health, University of Aberdeen, Greenburn Road, Bucksburn, Aberdeen AB21 9SB, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="lowlights-definitely-not-highlights">Lowlights (definitely not highlights)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Only 21% of pregnant women supplement with vitamin D (median = 200 IU!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many groups of pregnant women are at high risk of being vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/many-groups-of-pregnant-women-are-at-high-risk-of-being-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-groups-of-pregnant-women-are-at-high-risk-of-being-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-pregnancy---still-a-public-health-issue">Vitamin D deficiency in pregnancy - still a public health issue.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Matern Child Nutr. 2013 Jan;9(1):23-30. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/mcn.12014.">doi: 10.1111/mcn.12014.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>McAree T, Jacobs B, Manickavasagar T, Sivalokanathan S, Brennan L, Bassett P, Rainbow S, Blair M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>North West London Hospital NHS Trust, RNOH NHS Trust, Harrow, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:trixie.mcaree@nhs.net">trixie.mcaree@nhs.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objectives of this study were to quantify the prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency and deficiency in pregnancy, explore associated risk factors and discuss the public health implications. The study used retrospective analysis of randomly selected data. This is the first report on serum vitamin D levels in an unselected multi-ethnic population of pregnant women collected between April 2008 and March 2009.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dr. Holick video on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dr-holick-video-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dr-holick-video-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="holick-video-on-youtubehttpwwwyoutubecomwatchvhigbvdcbfvkfeatureyoutube">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hiGBVDcbFVk&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be">Holick Video on YouTube&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-few-images-from-another-of-his-excellent-videos">A few images from another of his excellent videos&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="other-forms-of-vitamin-d-generated">Other forms of vitamin D generated&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-other-forms-of-vitamin-d-generated.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="c-section">C-section&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-c-section.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h2 id="iguana-with-little-vitamin-d">Iguana with little vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-iguana.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="uvb-white-skin-vs-black-skin">UVB White skin vs black skin&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/hollick-uvb-white-vs-black.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;h3 id="global-deficiency-of-vitamin-d">Global deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-global-deficiency.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="psorasis-placebo-vs-vitamin-d">Psorasis placebo vs vitamin d&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-psorasis-pacelbo-vs-vitamin-d.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="navy-indoors-8x-more-death-than-outdoors---1915">Navy indoors 8X more death than outdoors - 1915&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-navy-indoors-8x-more-death-than-outdoors---1915.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="type-1-diabetes-10x-less-at-equator">Type 1 diabetes 10X less at equator&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-type-1-diabetes-10x-less-at-equator.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="perhipheral-vascular-disease-decrease-80">Perhipheral Vascular Disease decrease 80%&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-pvd-decrease-80-.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="holick-and-his-family-take-3000-iu-vitamin-d-total-daily">Holick and his family take 3000 IU vitamin D total daily&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-3000-iu-vitamin-d-total.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="holick-recommendations-vs-age">Holick recommendations vs age&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-recommendations-vs-age.jpg" alt="image" width="400"></description></item><item><title>2X more preeclampsia when vitamin D less than 30 ng, etc. - meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/2x-more-preeclampsia-when-vitamin-d-less-than-30-ng-etc-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-preeclampsia-when-vitamin-d-less-than-30-ng-etc-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#association-between-maternal-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-and-pregnancy-and-neonatal-outcomes-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-observational-studies">Association between maternal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level and pregnancy and neonatal outcomes: systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#editorial-in-same-issue-vitamin-d-sufficiency-in-pregnancy">Editorial in same issue: Vitamin D sufficiency in pregnancy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references-for-editorial">References for editorial&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-doses-of-vitamin-d-linked-with-harmful-outcomes-during-pregnancyhttpwwwmedicalnewstodaycomarticles258251php">&lt;a href="http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/258251.php">Low Doses Of Vitamin D Linked With Harmful Outcomes During Pregnancy&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="association-between-maternal-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-and-pregnancy-and-neonatal-outcomes-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-observational-studies">Association between maternal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level and pregnancy and neonatal outcomes: systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>British Medical Journal&lt;/strong> (BMJ) 2013; 346 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/http">doi: http&lt;/a>://dx.doi.org/10.1136/bmj.f1169 (Published 26 March 2013)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>35,000 IU vitamin D weekly during 3rd quarter pregnancy – RCT</title><link>/posts/35000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-during-3rd-quarter-pregnancy-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/35000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-during-3rd-quarter-pregnancy-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pharmacokinetics-of-high-dose-weekly-oral-vitamin-d3-supplementation-during-the-third-trimester-of-pregnancy-in-dhaka-bangladesh">Pharmacokinetics of High-Dose Weekly Oral Vitamin D3 Supplementation during the Third Trimester of Pregnancy in Dhaka, Bangladesh&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(3), 788-810; doi:10.3390/nu5030788&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daniel E. Roth 1,†,daniel.roth@sickkids.ca , Abdullah Al Mahmud 2 , Rubhana Raqib 2 , Evana Akhtar 2 , Robert E. Black 1 and Abdullah H. Baqui 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of International Health, The Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, 615 North Wolfe Street, Baltimore, MD 21205, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese mothers with adequate vitamin D gave birth to low D and fat infants</title><link>/posts/obese-mothers-with-adequate-vitamin-d-gave-birth-to-low-d-and-fat-infants.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-mothers-with-adequate-vitamin-d-gave-birth-to-low-d-and-fat-infants.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="maternal-obesity-and-vitamin-d-sufficiency-are-associated-with-cord-blood-vitamin-d-insufficiency">Maternal obesity and vitamin D sufficiency are associated with cord blood vitamin D insufficiency.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013 Jan;98(1):114-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2012-2882.">doi: 10.1210/jc.2012-2882.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Nov 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Josefson JL, Feinglass J, Rademaker AW, Metzger BE, Zeiss DM, Price HE, Langman CB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatric Endocrinology, Ann and Robert H. Lurie Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Chicago, Department of Pediatrics, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois 60611-2605, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:J-Josefson@northwestern.edu">J-Josefson@northwestern.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CONTEXT: An inverse relationship between total serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OH D) and increased adiposity has been established in children, adolescents, and adults. However, the relationship between neonatal adiposity and vitamin D status has not been reported. Both maternal obesity and vitamin D deficiency in pregnancy are common and are associated with adverse pregnancy outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>93% of newborns of military in Hawaii had low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/93-percent-of-newborns-of-military-in-hawaii-had-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/93-percent-of-newborns-of-military-in-hawaii-had-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-at-birth-among-military-dependants-in-hawaii">Vitamin D Deficiency at Birth Among Military Dependants in Hawai&amp;rsquo;i&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>HAWAI&amp;rsquo;I JOURNAL OF MEDICINE &amp;amp; PUBLIC HEALTH, MARCH 2013, VOL 72, NO 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eldon G. Palmer MD; Emmanuel Ramirez-Enriquez MD; Sarah M. Frioux MD; and Melissa M. Tyree MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has long been known to be essential in bone mineralization as well as calcium and phosphate regulation. An increasing body ofliterature suggests that Vitamin D is also key in many other areas to include immune function, brain development, prevention of autoimmune disease, and prevention of certain types of cancers. Studies also suggest that, with decreased sun exposure due to concern for skin cancer risk, much of the world&amp;rsquo;s population is becoming increasingly deficient in vitamin D. Our hypothesis was that vitamin D deficiency exists, and can be detected, even in sunny climates such as the state ofHawaii. To test this hypothesis, eighty-six cord blood samples were collected in the process of routine clinical testing. These samples were tested for 25-hydroxy vitamin D via liquid chromatography mass spectroscopy. Percent deficiency (&amp;lt;20ng/mL) and insufficiency (20-31.9ng/mL) were determined by statistical analysis. Forty-six percent (n=37) of cord blood samples tested were deficient in vitamin D; 47 percent (n=38) of samples had insufficient 25-OH vitamin D. &lt;strong>Only 7 percent (n=6) of samples showed vitamin D concentrations at the recommended levels.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Opening windows while pregnant cut the number of low birth weight infants by half</title><link>/posts/opening-windows-while-pregnant-cut-the-number-of-low-birth-weight-infants-by-half.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/opening-windows-while-pregnant-cut-the-number-of-low-birth-weight-infants-by-half.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="opening-windows-while-pregnant-improves-babys-healthhttpwwwnaturalnewscom039196_fresh_air_pregnancy_babys_healthhtml-natural-news">&lt;a href="http://www.naturalnews.com/039196_fresh_air_pregnancy_babys_health.html">Opening windows while pregnant improves baby&amp;rsquo;s health&lt;/a> Natural News&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The article attributes the reduction in rate of births of less than 5 pounds to reduction of indoor polutants.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Wonder how much of the reduction was due to more UVB light, and thus vitamin D.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/recurrent-pre-term-birth-and-low-vitamin-d">Recurrent pre term birth and low vitamin D – Dec 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/low-birth-weight-associated-with-vitamin-d-levels-less-than-11-ng">Low birth weight associated with vitamin D levels less than 11 ng – Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Predicted vitamin D levels during pregnancy were sort of similar to those measured</title><link>/posts/predicted-vitamin-d-levels-during-pregnancy-were-sort-of-similar-to-those-measured.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/predicted-vitamin-d-levels-during-pregnancy-were-sort-of-similar-to-those-measured.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="development-and-validation-of-a-vitamin-d-status-prediction-model-in-danish-pregnant-women-a-study-of-the-danish-national-birth-cohort">Development and Validation of a Vitamin D Status Prediction Model in Danish Pregnant Women: A Study of the Danish National Birth Cohort&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Camilla Bjorn Jensen1, Andrew L. Thorne-Lyman2, Linda Vadgard Hansen1, Marin Strom1, Nina Odgaard Nielsen3, Arieh Cohen4, Sjurdur Frodi Olsen1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Centre for Fetal Programming, Department of Epidemiology Research, Statens Serum Institut, Copenhagen, Denmark, 2 Department of Nutrition, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, Massachusetts, United States of America, 3 National Institute of Public Health, University of Southern Denmark, Copenhagen, Denmark, 4 Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Statens Serum Institut, Copenhagen, Denmark&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone changes during and after pregnancy</title><link>/posts/bone-changes-during-and-after-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-changes-during-and-after-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="changes-in-bone-mineral-density-and-body-composition-during-pregnancy-and-postpartum-a-controlled-cohort-study">Changes in bone mineral density and body composition during pregnancy and postpartum. A controlled cohort study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Apr;23(4):1213-23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-011-1654-6.">doi: 10.1007/s00198-011-1654-6.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 May 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Møller UK, Við Streym S, Mosekilde L, Rejnmark L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Internal Medicine, MEA, Aarhus Sygehus, Aarhus University Hospital, Tage Hansens Gade 2, DK-8000, Aarhus C, Denmark. &lt;a href="mailto:kristine.moller@ki.au.dk">kristine.moller@ki.au.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a controlled cohort study, bone mineral density (BMD) was measured in 153 women pre-pregnancy; during pregnancy; and 0.5, 4, 9, and 19 months postpartum. Seventy-five age-matched controls, without pregnancy plans, were followed in parallel. Pregnancy and breastfeeding cause a reversible bone loss, which, initially, is most pronounced at trabecular sites but also involves cortical sites during prolonged breastfeeding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recurrent pre term birth and low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/recurrent-pre-term-birth-and-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/recurrent-pre-term-birth-and-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-and-recurrent-preterm-birth-a-nested-case-control-study-in-high-risk-women">Vitamin D status and recurrent preterm birth: a nested case-control study in high-risk women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>BJOG. 2012 Dec;119(13):1617-23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-0528.2012.03495.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1471-0528.2012.03495.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Oct 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thorp JM, Camargo CA, McGee PL, Harper M, Klebanoff MA, Sorokin Y, Varner MW, Wapner RJ, Caritis SN, Iams JD, Carpenter MW, Peaceman AM, Mercer BM, Sciscione A, Rouse DJ, Ramin SM, Anderson GB; Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development Maternal-Fetal Medicine Units Network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis more likely if mother had less than 25 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-more-likely-if-mother-had-less-than-25-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-more-likely-if-mother-had-less-than-25-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-as-a-protective-factor-in-multiple-sclerosis">Vitamin D as a protective factor in multiple sclerosis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Salzer J, Hallmans G, Nyström M, Stenlund H, Wadell G, Sundström P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neurology. 2012 Nov 20;79(21):2140-5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182752ea8.">doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182752ea8.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pharmacology and Clinical Neuroscience, Section of Neurology, Umeå University, Umeå, Sweden. &lt;a href="mailto:jonatan.salzer@neuro.umu.se">jonatan.salzer@neuro.umu.se&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To examine the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels and the risk of multiple sclerosis (MS) in blood samples collected prospectively and during gestation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: In this nested case-control study, 2 population-based biobanks with 291,500 samples from 164,000 persons collected since 1975 in the northern half of Sweden were used. We identified prospectively collected blood samples from MS cases (n = 192, controls matched 2:1) and gestational samples from pregnant mothers where the offspring had later developed MS (n = 37, control mothers matched 5:1). 25(OH)D levels were measured using an ELISA, and the risk of MS was analyzed using matched logistic regression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X more likely to have preeclampsia if less than 20 ng of vitamin D – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/2x-more-likely-to-have-preeclampsia-if-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-likely-to-have-preeclampsia-if-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-and-adverse-pregnancy-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Maternal Vitamin D Status and Adverse Pregnancy Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2013 Jan 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wei SQ, Qi HP, Luo ZC, Fraser WD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Saint-Justine Hospital, University of Montreal, Montreal, Canada;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To estimate the associations between maternal vitamin D status and adverse pregnancy outcomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>STUDY DESIGN: We searched electronic databases of the human literature in PubMed, EMBASE and the Cochrane Library up to October, 2012 using the following keywords: &amp;lsquo;vitamin D&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;status&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;deficiency&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;insufficiency&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;pregnancy&amp;rsquo;. A systematic review and meta-analysis were conducted on observational studies that reported the association between maternal blood vitamin D levels and adverse pregnancy outcomes including preeclampsia, gestational diabetes mellitus, preterm birth or small-for-gestational age.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pregnancy complications reduced with 4000 IU of vitamin D - 2RCT</title><link>/posts/pregnancy-complications-reduced-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-2rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnancy-complications-reduced-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-2rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="health-characteristics-and-outcomes-of-two-randomized-vitamin-d-supplementation-trials-during-pregnancy-a-combined-analysis">Health Characteristics and Outcomes of Two Randomized Vitamin D Supplementation Trials during Pregnancy: A Combined Analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2013 Jan 10. pii: S0960-0760(13)00006-X. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2013.01.002.">doi: 10.1016/j.jsbmb.2013.01.002.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#900;">Wagner&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> CL, McNeil RB, Johnson DD, Hulsey TC, Ebeling M, Robinson C, Hamilton SA, &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#900;">Hollis&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> BW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Neonatology, Department of Pediatrics, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, SC; Eau Claire Cooperative Health Centers, Columbia, SC. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:wagnercl@musc.edu">wagnercl@musc.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To assess the safety and health effects of vitamin D supplementation during pregnancy. Methods and Design: Datasets from two randomized clinical trials were first analyzed separately then combined for this analysis using a common data dictionary. In the NICHD trial, women were randomized to 400, 2000, or 4000 IU vitamin D(3)/day, stratified by race. In the Thrasher Research Fund trial, participants were randomized to 2000 or 4000 IU vitamin D(3)/day. Study drugs were from the same manufacturing lot for both trials. Identical questionnaires were given for comparable sociodemographics &amp;amp; clinical characteristics. Outcome measures were: &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup> maternal and neonatal 25(OH)D achieved, and &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup> maternal comorbidities of pregnancy (COP). SAS 9.3 was used for all analyses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twins, no tan, winter, and smoking all associated with low levels of vitamin D during pregnancy</title><link>/posts/twins-no-tan-winter-and-smoking-all-associated-with-low-levels-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/twins-no-tan-winter-and-smoking-all-associated-with-low-levels-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="parity-and-tanned-white-skin-as-novel-predictors-of-vitamin-d-status-in-early-pregnancy-a-population-based-cohort-study">Parity and tanned white skin as novel predictors of vitamin D status in early pregnancy: A population-based cohort study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clinical Endocrinology, Vol. 78 Issue 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LB. Andersen 1,2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B. Abrahamsen 3,4,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C. Dalgård 5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>HB. Kyhl 6,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SS. Beck-Nielsen 2,7,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. Frost-Nielsen 6,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>JS. Jørgensen 8,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>T. Barington 3,6,9,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>HT. Christesen 1,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Hans Christian Andersen Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Odense University Hospital, Odense, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Institute of Clinical Research, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High level of maternal vitamin D and infant food allergy – controversy</title><link>/posts/high-level-of-maternal-vitamin-d-and-infant-food-allergy-controversy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-level-of-maternal-vitamin-d-and-infant-food-allergy-controversy.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="maternal-and-newborn-vitamin-d-status-and-its-impact-on-food-allergy-development-in-the-german-lina-cohort-study">Maternal and newborn vitamin D status and its impact on food allergy development in the German LINA cohort study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Allergy 2012; 68:220–228; DOI: 10.1111/all.12081.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K. Weisse 1, S. Winkler 1,2, F. Hirche 2, G. Herberth 1, D. Hinz 1, M. Bauer 1, S. Röder 3, U. Rolle-Kampczyk 4, M. von Bergen 4, S. Olek 5, U. Sack 6, T. Richter 7, U. Diez 7, M. Borte 7, G. I. Stangl 2, I. Lehmann 1,3, &lt;a href="mailto:irina.lehmann@ufz.de">irina.lehmann@ufz.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More vitamin D during pregnancy made for higher mental scores at 14 months</title><link>/posts/more-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-made-for-higher-mental-scores-at-14-months.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-made-for-higher-mental-scores-at-14-months.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-in-pregnancy-and-infant-neuropsychological-development">Circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 in pregnancy and infant neuropsychological development.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Morales E, Guxens M, Llop S, Rodríguez-Bernal CL, Tardón A, Riaño I, Ibarluzea J, Lertxundi N, Espada M, Rodriguez A, Sunyer J; INMA Project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Collaborators (96)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Research in Environmental Epidemiology (CREAL), Parc de Recerca Biomèdica de Barcelona, Dr Aiguader 88, 08003-Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain. &lt;a href="mailto:emorales1@creal.cat">emorales1@creal.cat&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate whether circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3) &lt;span>[25(OH)D(3)]&lt;/span> concentration in pregnancy is associated with neuropsychological development in infants.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D of 32 to 60 ng is needed before, during, and after pregnancy</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-of-32-to-60-ng-is-needed-before-during-and-after-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-of-32-to-60-ng-is-needed-before-during-and-after-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="implications-of-maternal-vitamin-d-deficiency-for-the-fetus-the-neonate-and-the-young-infant">Implications of maternal vitamin D deficiency for the fetus, the neonate and the young infant.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Nutr. 2012 Dec 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Principi N, Bianchini S, Baggi E, Esposito S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pediatric Clinic 1, Department of Pathophysiology and Transplantation, Università degli Studi di Milano, Fondazione IRCCS Ca&amp;rsquo; Granda Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico, Via Commenda 9, 20122, Milan, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: It has recently been demonstrated that vitamin D (VD) deficiency during pregnancy and lactation can give rise to problems in mothers and their children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gates funding Vitamin D studies during pregnancy to improve growth</title><link>/posts/gates-funding-vitamin-d-studies-during-pregnancy-to-improve-growth.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gates-funding-vitamin-d-studies-during-pregnancy-to-improve-growth.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="update---study-did-not-find-a-benefit-when-starting-at-17th-week">Update - study did not find a benefit when starting at 17th week&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30089075">Vitamin D Supplementation in Pregnancy and Lactation and Infant Growth&lt;/a> Aug 2018&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>28,000 IU/week, not start until 17th week, which is too late to be a benefit&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/ensure-a-healthy-pregnancy-and-baby-take-vitamin-d-before-conception" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Ensure a healthy pregnancy and baby - take Vitamin D before conception">Ensure a healthy pregnancy and baby - take Vitamin D before conception&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and pregnancy – looks promising, but concerned about too much – Review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-pregnancy-looks-promising-but-concerned-about-too-much-review.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-pregnancy-looks-promising-but-concerned-about-too-much-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-impact-of-vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-on-extraskeletal-health-in-children">The impact of vitamin D in pregnancy on extraskeletal health in children:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-systematic-review">a systematic review.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2012 Dec;91(12):1368-80. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/aogs.12006.">doi: 10.1111/aogs.12006.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christesen HT, Elvander C, Lamont RF, Jørgensen JS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hans Christian Andersen Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Clinical Institute, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Odense University Hospital, Odense Division of Surgery, University College, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The impact of maternal vitamin D status in pregnancy on the extraskeletal health of the offspring has become a &amp;ldquo;hot topic&amp;rdquo; with a potential for cost-beneficial prevention. The objective of this study was to systematically review the level I and II evidence. PubMed, Embase and Cochrane databases were searched using the MeSH terms &amp;ldquo;vitamin D&amp;rdquo; AND &amp;ldquo;pregnancy&amp;rdquo; until 1 January 2012. The search was limited to randomized controlled trials (evidence level I) and observational studies (evidence level II) in humans and in the English language. Papers reporting on vitamin D supplementation in combination with other supplements, or not reporting on 25OHD or outcomes of the offspring were excluded.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low birth weight associated with vitamin D levels less than 11 ng</title><link>/posts/low-birth-weight-associated-with-vitamin-d-levels-less-than-11-ng.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-birth-weight-associated-with-vitamin-d-levels-less-than-11-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-measures-of-newborn-and-placental-weight-in-a-us-multicenter-cohort-study">Maternal Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Measures of Newborn and Placental Weight in a U.S. Multicenter Cohort Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012 Nov 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gernand AD, Simhan HN, Klebanoff MA, Bodnar LM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology (A.D.G.), University of Pittsburgh Graduate School of Public Health, and Departments of Epidemiology and Obstetrics and Gynecology (L.M.B.), University of Pittsburgh Graduate School of Public Health and School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15261; Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine (H.N.S.), Magee-Womens Hospital and Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, School of Medicine, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15213; and Departments of Pediatrics and of Obstetrics and Gynecology (M.A.K.), Ohio State University College of Medicine and The Research Institute, Nationwide Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Columbus, Ohio 43210.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis 23 percent more likely if born in April vs. Oct – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-23-percent-more-likely-if-born-in-april-vs-oct-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-23-percent-more-likely-if-born-in-april-vs-oct-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-month-of-birth-effect-in-multiple-sclerosis-systematic-review-meta-analysis-and-effect-of-latitude">The month of birth effect in multiple sclerosis: systematic review, meta-analysis and effect of latitude&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry doi:10.1136/jnnp-2012-303934&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ruth Dobson1, Gavin Giovannoni1, Sreeram Ramagopalan1,2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Queen Mary University of London, Blizard Institute, Barts and the London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Wellcome Trust Centre for Human Genetics, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Clinical Neurology, John Radcliffe Hospital, Oxford, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence to: Dr Ruth Dobson, Queen Mary University of London, Blizard Institute, Newark Street, London E1 2AT; &lt;a href="mailto:ruth.dobson@qmul.ac.uk">ruth.dobson@qmul.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antidepressants might increase infertility and pregnancy problems</title><link>/posts/antidepressants-might-increase-infertility-and-pregnancy-problems.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/antidepressants-might-increase-infertility-and-pregnancy-problems.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Variety of pregnancy problems with low vitamin D – systematic review</title><link>/posts/variety-of-pregnancy-problems-with-low-vitamin-d-systematic-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/variety-of-pregnancy-problems-with-low-vitamin-d-systematic-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-impact-of-vitamin-d-on-pregnancy-a-systematic-review">The impact of vitamin D on pregnancy: a systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2012 Sep 14. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/aogs.12000.">doi: 10.1111/aogs.12000.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christesen HT, Falkenberg T, Lamont RF, Jørgensen JS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hans Christian Andersen Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Odense University Hospital, Odense, Denmark Clinical Institute, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Odense University Hospital, Odense, Denmark Division of Surgery, University College, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypovitaminosis D is common in pregnancy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dial D for danger – absurd editorial in Thorax</title><link>/posts/dial-d-for-danger-absurd-editorial-in-thorax.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dial-d-for-danger-absurd-editorial-in-thorax.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dial-d-for-danger">Dial D for danger?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Andrew Bush, Ian Pavord, Editors&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thorax 2012;67:i doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2012-202790&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of us are following the vitamin D papers with the same apprehension as we contemplate our erratic teenage sons—huge potential for future good, but how much damage may be done to the family home and the parental psyche in the meantime? In this issue of Thorax, we feature two contributions to the unfolding Vitamin D story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Basic Science for the Chest Physician, &lt;a href="http://thorax.bmj.com/content/67/11/1018.abstract?sid=54537522-3561-499c-b812-522e657dc10d%20">Pfeffer and Hawrylowicz&lt;/a> steer the non-immunologists through the complexities of the actions of 1,25(OH)D3, which is now known to be generated in far more organs than just the kidney, the nuclear Vitamin D receptor, and the end-results on the expression of genes concerned in the adaptive and immune responses (see page 1017).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autistic measure 5X more likely if low vitamin D in second trimester</title><link>/posts/autistic-measure-5x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-in-second-trimester.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/autistic-measure-5x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-in-second-trimester.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="maternal-vitamin-d-levels-and-the-autism-phenotype-among-offspring">Maternal Vitamin D Levels and the Autism Phenotype Among Offspring.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Autism Dev Disord. 2012 Oct 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whitehouse AJ, Holt BJ, Serralha M, Holt PG, Hart PH, Kusel MM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telethon Institute for Child Health Research, Centre for Child Health Research, University of Western Australia, 100 Roberts Road, Subiaco, West Perth, WA, 6008, Australia, &lt;a href="mailto:awhitehouse@ichr.uwa.edu.au">awhitehouse@ichr.uwa.edu.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We tested whether maternal vitamin D insufficiency during pregnancy is related to the autism phenotype. Serum 25(OH)-vitamin D concentrations of 929 women were measured at &lt;strong>18 weeks&amp;rsquo; pregnancy&lt;/strong> . The mothers of the three children with a clinical diagnosis of autism spectrum disorder had 25(OH)-vitamin D concentrations above the population mean.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Infants born early had low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/infants-born-early-had-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/infants-born-early-had-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Association between season of birth and suicide – perhaps vitamin D</title><link>/posts/association-between-season-of-birth-and-suicide-perhaps-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/association-between-season-of-birth-and-suicide-perhaps-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="associations-between-season-of-birth-and-suicide-a-brief-review">Associations between season of birth and suicide: a brief review.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Neuropsychopharmacol Hung. 2012 Sep;14(3):177-87.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antonsen JH, Gonda X, Dome P, Rihmer Z.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NAF-garden family practice, Brugata 6, 2380 Brumunddal, Norway. &lt;a href="mailto:kendermagos@yahoo.com">kendermagos@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suicide is a complex behaviour contributing to a significant number of unnecessary deaths worldwide. Accordingly, the quest for suicide risk factors is one of the most intensively developing issues of psychiatric research. In the last few decades a number of interesting results have been published about associations between season of birth (SOB) and several physiological and pathological aspects of human life, while, in regard to neuroscience, several investigations confirmed that SOB is associated with the risk of several major neuropsychiatric disorders and suicide as well. Research concerning the possible causative factors behind these associations were also performed suggesting that&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Small for gestational age and insulin at age 6</title><link>/posts/small-for-gestational-age-and-insulin-at-age-6.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/small-for-gestational-age-and-insulin-at-age-6.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Higher vitamin D in pregnancy resulted in 2X better infant psychomotor and mental scores</title><link>/posts/higher-vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-resulted-in-2x-better-infant-psychomotor-and-mental-scores.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/higher-vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-resulted-in-2x-better-infant-psychomotor-and-mental-scores.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-in-pregnancy-and-infant-neuropsychological-development">Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D3 in Pregnancy and Infant Neuropsychological Development&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatrics Published online September 17, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eva Morales, MD, PhD, MPHa,b,c,&lt;em>, Mònica Guxens, MD, MPH, PhDa,b,c,&lt;/em>, Sabrina Llop, MSc, PhDc,d, Clara L. Rodríguez-Bernal, DDS, MPHc,d, Adonina Tardón, MD, PhDc,e, Isolina Riaño, MD, PhDf, Jesús Ibarluzea, MSc, PhDg, Nerea Lertxundi, MSch,i, Mercedes Espada, PhDj, Agueda Rodriguez, MDk, Jordi Sunyer, MD, PhDa,b,c,l, and on behalf of the INMA Project&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Centre for Research in Environmental Epidemiology (CREAL), Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skinned pregnant women far from equator were very vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-pregnant-women-far-from-equator-were-very-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-pregnant-women-far-from-equator-were-very-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prevalence-of-low-vitamin-d-levels-in-an-urban-midwestern-obstetric-practice">Prevalence of low vitamin d levels in an urban midwestern obstetric practice.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Midwifery Womens Health. 2012 Sep;57(5):439-44. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1542-2011.2012.00167.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1542-2011.2012.00167.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Collins-Fulea C, Klima K, Wegienka GR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: This study describes the prevalence of low vitamin D levels in pregnancy in a diverse urban population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: This was a retrospective chart review of 2839 women who gave birth at a Michigan hospital between January 1, 2008 and December 31, 2009 and had at least 1 vitamin D (25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>) measurement during their pregnancies. Race/ethnic group, wearing the hijab, and season of 25(OH)D sample collection were used in the descriptive analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D pregnancy associated with both low birth weight and more weight in child later</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-pregnancy-associated-with-both-low-birth-weight-and-more-weight-in-child-later.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-pregnancy-associated-with-both-low-birth-weight-and-more-weight-in-child-later.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-in-pregnancy-is-associated-with-adiposity-in-the-offspring-findings-from-the-southampton-womens-survey">Maternal vitamin D status in pregnancy is associated with adiposity in the offspring: findings from the Southampton Women&amp;rsquo;s Survey.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2012 Jul;96(1):57-63. Epub 2012 May 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Crozier SR, Harvey NC, Inskip HM, Godfrey KM, Cooper C, Robinson SM; SWS Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical Research Council Lifecourse Epidemiology Unit, Southampton General Hospital, Southampton, United Kingdom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low vitamin D status has been linked to adiposity, but little is known of the effects of low status in pregnancy on offspring body composition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About 21 ng of vitamin D during pregnancy in Belgium</title><link>/posts/about-21-ng-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-in-belgium.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/about-21-ng-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-in-belgium.html</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="high-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-pregnant-women--a-national-cross-sectional-survey">High Prevalence of Vitamin D Deficiency in Pregnant Women: A National Cross-Sectional Survey&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 7(8): e43868. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0043868 Aug 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefanie Vandevijvere 1*, Sihame Amsalkhir 2, Herman Van Oyen 1, Rodrigo Moreno-Reyes 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Public Health and Surveillance, Scientific Institute of Public Health, Brussels, Belgium,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Nuclear Medicine, Hôpital Erasme, Université Libre de Bruxelles, Brussels, Belgium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An increasing number of studies suggest that vitamin D deficiency during pregnancy is associated with multiple adverse health outcomes in mothers, neonates and children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prevention of vitamin D deficiency in mothers and infants worldwide - a paradigm shift.</title><link>/posts/prevention-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-mothers-and-infants-worldwide-a-paradigm-shift.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prevention-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-mothers-and-infants-worldwide-a-paradigm-shift.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Paediatr Int Child Health. 2012 Feb;32(1):3-13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dawodu A, Wagner CL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Global Health Center, Cincinnati Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Medical Center and University of Cincinnati, 3333 Burnet Avenue, MLC 2048, Cincinnati, OH 45229, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:adekunle.dawodu@cchmc.org">adekunle.dawodu@cchmc.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="2016-chart-by-author-via-grassrootshealth">2016 Chart by author via GrassrootsHealth&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency in mothers and infants is a global health disorder despite recognition that it is preventable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent data support the theory that vitamin D deficiency in adults and children may increase the risk of infections and auto-immune diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D prior to and after birth</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-prior-to-and-after-birth.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-prior-to-and-after-birth.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="example">Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>50,000 IU Vitamin D every two weeks during most of pregnancy = 3,600 IU average daily&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3,600 IU is not enough Vitamin D for breast feeding without supplementing&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="color:black;background-color:#FF3;">50,000 IU of vitamin D every week shortly before birth will stock up on vitamin D (7,100 IU average)&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="color:black;background-color:#3F0;">Must continue at that same rate until finished breast feeding&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/just-mark-your-calendar-for-vitamin-d-days">Just mark your calendar for vitamin D days&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/how-often-should-i-take-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 3188">How often should I take 50000 IU of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Air pollution while pregnant reduced vitamin D level in infant</title><link>/posts/air-pollution-while-pregnant-reduced-vitamin-d-level-in-infant.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/air-pollution-while-pregnant-reduced-vitamin-d-level-in-infant.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="gestational-exposure-to-urban-air-pollution-related-to-a-decrease-in-cord-blood-vitamin-d-levels">Gestational Exposure to Urban Air Pollution Related to a Decrease in Cord Blood Vitamin D Levels&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism August 17, 2012 jc.2012-1943&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nour Baïz, Patricia Dargent-Molina, John D. Wark, Jean-Claude Souberbielle, Rémy Slama, Isabella Annesi-Maesano and the EDEN Mother-Child Cohort Study Group&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institut National de la Santé et de la Recherche Médicale (INSERM) Epidemiology of Allergic and Respiratory Diseases Department (N.B., I.A.-M.), Unité Mixte de Recherche (UMR)-S707, Paris, France; Medical School Saint-Antoine (N.B., I.A.-M.), Université Pierre et Marie Curie (UPMC), Université Paris 6 (Univ6), F-75571 Paris, France; INSERM Epidemiological Research in Perinatal Health and Women&amp;rsquo;s and Child Health (P.D.-M.), UMR-S953, Villejuif, France; University Pierre and Marie Curie (P.D.-M.), UMR-S953, F-75005 Paris, France; Department of Medicine (J.D.W.), The Royal Melbourne Hospital, The University of Melbourne, Parkville, 3050 Victoria, Australia; Laboratoire de Physiologie (J.-C.S.), Université Paris-Descartes, Hôpital Necker-Enfants-Malades, Assistance Publique Hôpitaux de Paris, Paris, France; INSERM Unité 823 (R.S.), Team “Environmental Epidemiology applied to Reproduction and Respiratory Health,” Institut Albert Bonniot, F-38706 Grenoble, France; and Université J. Fourier Grenoble (R.S.), F-38041 Grenoble, France&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pregnancy and vitamin D meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/pregnancy-and-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnancy-and-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-maternal-neonatal-and-infant-health-outcomes">Vitamin D During Pregnancy and Maternal, Neonatal and Infant Health Outcomes:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Andrew Thorne-Lyman1,*, Wafaie W. Fawzi1,2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paediatric and Perinatal Epidemiology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Special Issue: Improving maternal, newborn, and child health outcomes through better designed policies and programs that enhance the nutrition of women&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 26, Issue Supplement s1, pages 75–90, July 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has well-defined classical functions related to calcium metabolism and bone health but also has non-classical effects that may influence other aspects of health. There has been considerable recent interest in the role of vitamin D on outcomes related to pregnancy and young child health but few efforts have been made to systematically consolidate this evidence to inform the research and policy agenda for low-income countries. A systematic review was undertaken to identify intervention and observational studies of vitamin D supplementation, intake or status (25-hydroxy-vitamin D) during pregnancy on perinatal and infant health outcomes. Data from trials and observational studies isolating the effect of vitamin D supplementation and intake were extracted and study quality was evaluated. Meta-analysis was used to pool effect estimates. We identified five randomised trials with outcomes of relevance to our review. All had small sample size and dosage amount, duration and frequency varied as did the ability to correct deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium and bone disorders in pregnancy</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-bone-disorders-in-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-bone-disorders-in-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Indian J Endocrinol Metab. 2012 May-Jun; 16(3): 358–363, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4103/2230-8210.95665">doi: 10.4103/2230-8210.95665&lt;/a>, PMCID: PMC3354840&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shriraam Mahadevan, V. Kumaravel,1 and R. Bharath2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Endocrinology, Dr. E. V. Kalyani Medical Centre, Chennai, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Clinical Endocrinology, Alpha Hospital and Research Centre, Madurai, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Endocrinology, Chettinad Medical College and Research Institute, Chennai, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corresponding Author: Dr. Shriraam Mahadevan, Department of Clinical Endocrinology, Dr. E. V. Kalyani Medical Centre, 4, Radhakrishnan Salai, Mylapore, Chennai 600004, India. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:mshriraam@gmail.com">mshriraam@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>7X increase in early severe preeclampsia associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/7x-increase-in-early-severe-preeclampsia-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7x-increase-in-early-severe-preeclampsia-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="association-of-maternal-vitamin-d-and-placenta-growth-factor-with-the-diagnosis-of-early-onset-severe-preeclampsia">Association of Maternal Vitamin D and Placenta Growth Factor with the Diagnosis of Early Onset Severe Preeclampsia.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Perinatol. 2012 Aug 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robinson CJ, Wagner CL, Hollis BW, Baatz JE, Johnson DD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Division of Maternal Fetal Medicine, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective Decreased maternal 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OH-D) and placenta growth factor (PlGF) have both been associated with the diagnosis of early onset severe preeclampsia (EOSPE). This investigation aimed to define the association of these biomarkers with EOSPE.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Depression 50 percent more likely if low vitamin D in early pregnancy</title><link>/posts/depression-50-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-in-early-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/depression-50-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-in-early-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-early-pregnancy-vitamin-d-status-is-associated-with-maternal-depressive-symptoms-in-the-amsterdam-born-children-and-their-development-cohort">Maternal Early-Pregnancy Vitamin D Status Is Associated With Maternal Depressive Symptoms in the Amsterdam Born Children and Their Development Cohort&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Psychosomatic Medicine August 9, 2012 PSY.0b013e3182639fdb Joke Brandenbarg, MSc, Tanja G.M. Vrijkotte, PhD, Geertje Goedhart, PhD and Manon van Eijsden, PhD &lt;a href="mailto:mveijsden@ggd.amsterdam.nl">mveijsden@ggd.amsterdam.nl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Department of Epidemiology, Documentation, and Health Promotion (J.B., M.v.E.), Public Health Service; Department of Health Sciences (M.v.E.), VU University; and Department of Public Health (T.G.M.V.), Academic Medical Center, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam; and Institute for Risk Assessment Sciences (G.G.), University of Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>200 IU of Vitamin D does not prevent preeclampsia – RCT</title><link>/posts/200-iu-of-vitamin-d-does-not-prevent-preeclampsia-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/200-iu-of-vitamin-d-does-not-prevent-preeclampsia-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-calcium-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-metabolic-profiles-in-pregnant-women-at-risk-for-pre-eclampsia--a-randomized-placebo-controlled-trial">Effect of Calcium-vitamin D Supplementation on Metabolic Profiles in Pregnant Women at Risk for Pre-eclampsia: A Randomized Placebo-controlled Trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pakistan Journal of Biological Sciences 2012. Volume:	15, Issue:	7, pages/rec.No:	316-324&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zatollah Asemi ; Zohreh Tabassi ; Zahra Heidarzadeh ; Hassan Khorammian ; Sima-Sadat Sabihi ; Mansooreh Samimi&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Increased metabolic profiles during pregnancy are associated with an increased risk of maternal and neonatal morbidity and remain a significant medical challenge. To our knowledge, no reports are available indicating the effects of calcium-vitamin D supplementation on metabolic profiles among pregnant women at risk for pre-eclampsia. This study was designed to determine the effects of consumption calcium-vitamin D supplements on metabolic profiles among Iranian pregnant women at risk for pre-eclampsia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pregnant blacks 50 pcnt more likely to be depressed if 3 ng less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pregnant-blacks-50-pcnt-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-3-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnant-blacks-50-pcnt-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-3-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>7 percent less likely to get immune mediated disease if born in the fall</title><link>/posts/7-percent-less-likely-to-get-immune-mediated-disease-if-born-in-the-fall.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7-percent-less-likely-to-get-immune-mediated-disease-if-born-in-the-fall.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#month-of-birth-vitamin-d-and-risk-of-immune-mediated-disease-a-case-control-study">Month of birth, vitamin D and risk of immune mediated disease: a case control study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#october-births-are-12-less-likely-to-get-influenza-they-think-because-of-vaccination---feb-2024">October births are 12% less likely to get influenza (they think because of vaccination) - Feb 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="month-of-birth-vitamin-d-and-risk-of-immune-mediated-disease-a-case-control-study">Month of birth, vitamin D and risk of immune mediated disease: a case control study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Medicine 2012, 10:69 doi:10.1186/1741-7015-10-69&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giulio Disanto, George Chaplin, Julia M Morahan, Gavin Giovannoni, Elina Hypponen, George C Ebers and Sreeram V Ramagopalan&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Odds of living to 100 increase by 40 percent if had been born in the fall – 2011</title><link>/posts/odds-of-living-to-100-increase-by-40-percent-if-had-been-born-in-the-fall-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/odds-of-living-to-100-increase-by-40-percent-if-had-been-born-in-the-fall-2011.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>83 percent insufficient vitamin D during early pregnancy near equator</title><link>/posts/83-percent-insufficient-vitamin-d-during-early-pregnancy-near-equator.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/83-percent-insufficient-vitamin-d-during-early-pregnancy-near-equator.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-its-associated-factors-and-the-course-of-pregnancy-in-thai-women">Maternal vitamin D status, its associated factors and the course of pregnancy in Thai women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2012 Jun 16. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2265.2012.04470.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2265.2012.04470.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charatcharoenwitthaya N, Nanthakomon T, Somprasit C, Chanthasenanont A, Chailurkit LO, Pattaraarchachai J, Ongphiphadhanakul B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Thammasat University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CONTEXT:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are limited data on the prevalence of vitamin D inadequacy in pregnant women living in Southeast Asia, and changes in their vitamin D status during pregnancy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D increased probability of low birth weight by 60 percent – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increased-probability-of-low-birth-weight-by-60-percent-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increased-probability-of-low-birth-weight-by-60-percent-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-maternal-neonatal-and-infant-health-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D During Pregnancy and Maternal, Neonatal and Infant Health Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Andrew Thorne-Lyman1,*, Wafaie W. Fawzi1,2,3; Article first published online: 28 JUN 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2012 Blackwell Publishing Ltd&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paediatric and Perinatal Epidemiology, Volume 26, Issue Supplement s1, pages 75–90, July 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Special Issue: Improving maternal, newborn, and child health outcomes through better designed policies and programs that enhance the nutrition of women&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:>85%">
&lt;p>The only daily vitamin D data used in the meta-analysis was 1000 IU of vitamin &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">D2&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gestational diabetes 2.2X more likely below 10 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/gestational-diabetes-22x-more-likely-below-10-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gestational-diabetes-22x-more-likely-below-10-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-pregnancy-and-gestational-diabetes-mellitus">Vitamin D deficiency in pregnancy and gestational diabetes mellitus.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2012 Jun 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burris HH, Rifas-Shiman SL, Kleinman K, Litonjua AA, Huh SY, Rich-Edwards JW, Camargo CA Jr, Gillman MW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neonatology, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Boston, MA; Division of Newborn Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Boston, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We examined the association of second-trimester maternal plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) during pregnancy with gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oral contraceptive use associated with higher levels of vitamin D – thesis</title><link>/posts/oral-contraceptive-use-associated-with-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-thesis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/oral-contraceptive-use-associated-with-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-thesis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="oral-contraceptive-use-and-vitamin-d-status-among-women-ages-15-44-in-the-us-a-cross--sectional-study">Oral contraceptive use and vitamin D status among women ages 15-44 in the US: a cross- sectional study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Brinker, Kimberly Ann (2012)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Master&amp;rsquo;s Thesis (158 pages)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Committee Chair / Thesis Adviser: Sullivan, Kevin M Sharma, Andrea (CDC);&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Committee Members: Oraka, Emeka (ICF International);&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Research Fields: Health Sciences, Epidemiology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Partnering Agencies: CDC&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Program: Career Masters of Public Health (Applied Epidemiology)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose: This analysis was conducted to determine the association between oral&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No association of first trimester fetal size with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/no-association-of-first-trimester-fetal-size-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-association-of-first-trimester-fetal-size-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="lack-of-correlation-between-first-trimester-maternal-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-ultrasound-measured-crown-rump-length-and-nuchal-translucency">Lack of correlation between first trimester maternal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels and ultrasound measured crown-rump length and nuchal translucency.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2011 Dec;284(6):1585-8. Epub 2011 Aug 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fernández-Alonso AM, Fiol-Ruiz G, Chedraui P, Pérez-López FR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departamento de Obstetricia y Ginecología, Hospital Torrecárdenas, Paraje Torrecárdenas s/n, 04009 Almeria, Spain. &lt;a href="mailto:amfa257@yahoo.es">amfa257@yahoo.es&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D regulates the human genome and it is thought to influence the fetal growth and development, but its relation to early ultrasound fetal measures is still unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low birth weight 3X more likely if mother had less than 25 nanograms of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/low-birth-weight-3x-more-likely-if-mother-had-less-than-25-nanograms-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-birth-weight-3x-more-likely-if-mother-had-less-than-25-nanograms-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-small-for-gestational-age-in-black-and-white-infants">Plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D during pregnancy and small-for-gestational age in black and white infants.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Burris HH, Rifas-Shiman SL, Camargo CA Jr, Litonjua AA, Huh SY, Rich-Edwards JW, Gillman MW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ann Epidemiol. 2012 May 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neonatology, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA; Division of Newborn Medicine, Children’s Hospital Boston, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a prospective prenatal cohort study, we examined associations of second trimester and cord plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) with small-for-gestational age (SGA) and the extent to which vitamin D might explain black/white differences in SGA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is Vitamin D Supplementation Responsible for the Allergy Pandemic</title><link>/posts/is-vitamin-d-supplementation-responsible-for-the-allergy-pandemic.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-vitamin-d-supplementation-responsible-for-the-allergy-pandemic.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Matthias Wjst&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Posted: 05/22/2012; Curr Opin Allergy Clin Immunol. 2012;12(3):257-262. © 2012 Lippincott Williams &amp;amp; Wilkins&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matthias Wjst, Molecular Genetics of Lung Diseases, Comprehensive Pneumology Center (CPC), Institute of Lung Biology and Disease (iLBD), Helmholtz Zentrum München, German Research Center for Environmental Health, Ingolstädter Landstr. 1, D-85764 Neuherberg, Germany. E-mail: wjst@helmholtz-muenchen. &lt;a href="mailto:de/wjst@tum.de">de/wjst@tum.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>(Impression after a very quick read by VitaminDWiki: Author speculates that low vitamin D during pregnancy sets up an expectation in the infant body for low vitamin D environment – which is upset by getting vitamin D. This would not occur if there were enough vitamin D during pregnancy)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D in womb linked to more weight at age 6</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-womb-linked-to-more-weight-at-age-6.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-womb-linked-to-more-weight-at-age-6.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="lack-of-maternal-vitamin-d-may-predispose-baby-to-gain-excess-body-fat-in-childhood">Lack of maternal vitamin D may predispose baby to gain excess body fat in childhood&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.cbc.ca/news/health/story/2012/05/23/vitamin-d-pregnancy-childhood-fat.html%20">CBC News&lt;/a> Posted: May 23, 2012 2:39 PM ET&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">(unfortunately, the abstract does not quantize the amount of weight)&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Children of women with low blood levels of vitamin D were leaner at birth, researchers found. But by the time they reached age six, those children had more body fat than those born to women with higher vitamin D status during pregnancy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pre-term birth 3X more likely and C-section 4X if less than 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pre-term-birth-3x-more-likely-and-c-section-4x-if-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pre-term-birth-3x-more-likely-and-c-section-4x-if-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>How 60 ng of vitamin D enabled pregnancy - a personal story</title><link>/posts/how-60-ng-of-vitamin-d-enabled-pregnancy-a-personal-story.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-60-ng-of-vitamin-d-enabled-pregnancy-a-personal-story.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>80 percent of South Asian Women in UK had less than 10 ng of vitamin D in winter</title><link>/posts/80-percent-of-south-asian-women-in-uk-had-less-than-10-ng-of-vitamin-d-in-winter.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/80-percent-of-south-asian-women-in-uk-had-less-than-10-ng-of-vitamin-d-in-winter.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mothers and infants in India have very low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mothers-and-infants-in-india-have-very-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mothers-and-infants-in-india-have-very-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-status-of-low-birth-weight-infants-in-delhi-a-comparative-study">Vitamin D Status of Low Birth Weight Infants in Delhi: A Comparative Study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ramesh Agarwal, Deenanath Virmani, Munna Lal Jaipal, Shuchita Gupta, Nandita Gupta, M. Jeeva Sankar, Sunita Bhatia, Anand Agarwal, Veena Devgan, Ashok Deorari, Vinod K. Paul and Investigators of LBW Micronutrient Study Group, Departments of Pediatrics and Endocrinology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Department of Pediatrics, Kasturba Hospital and Swami Dayanand Hospital, New Delhi 110029, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Ramesh Agarwal, Newborn Health Knowledge Centre (NHKC), Department of Pediatrics, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Ansari Nagar, New Delhi 110029, India. Tel: +91-11-26589633, Fax: +91-11-26588633, E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:aranag@rediffmail.com">aranag@rediffmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Risk of Cesarean 2X higher if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/risk-of-cesarean-2x-higher-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/risk-of-cesarean-2x-higher-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Preeclampsia 3X more likely if low vitamin D at 25th week</title><link>/posts/preeclampsia-3x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-at-25th-week.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/preeclampsia-3x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-at-25th-week.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="longitudinal-vitamin-d-status-in-pregnancy-and-the-risk-of-pre-eclampsia">Longitudinal vitamin D status in pregnancy and the risk of pre-eclampsia&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>SQ Wei1, F Audibert1, N Hidiroglou2,†, K Sarafin2, P Julien3, Y Wu1, ZC Luo1, WD Fraser1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Sainte-Justine Hospital, University of Montreal, Montreal, QC&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Bureau of Nutritional Sciences, Health Canada, Ottawa, ON&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Lipid Research Center, Laval University Medical Center (CHUQ), Québec city, QC, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>† Deceased.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>SQ Wei, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, CHU Sainte-Justine, Université de Montréal, 5757 Decelles, Montreal, QC H3S 2C3, Canada. Email: &lt;a href="mailto:shu.qin.wei@umontreal.ca">shu.qin.wei@umontreal.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>BJOG: An International Journal of Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynaecology; Article first published online: 29 MAR 2012&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Abu Dhabi 2012 - Hollis</title><link>/posts/abu-dhabi-2012-hollis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/abu-dhabi-2012-hollis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="presented-at-international-symposium-on-vitamin-d-deficiency---abu-dhabi-march-2012">Presented at International Symposium on Vitamin D Deficiency - Abu Dhabi March 2012&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;1225&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prof-bruce-hollis">Prof. Bruce Hollis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Qualifications: Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Position: Director of Pediatric Sciences at the Medical University of South Carolina, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-during-pregnancy-and-its-effect-on-pregnancy-outcomes">Vitamin D Supplementation during Pregnancy and Its Effect on Pregnancy Outcomes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The function and requirement of vitamin D during pregnancy for both mother and fetus has remained a mystery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This fact was highlighted by The Cochrane Review in 1999 that reported a lack of randomized controlled trials (RCTs) with respect to vitamin D requirements during pregnancy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Folate fortification of foods</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-folate-fortification-of-foods.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-folate-fortification-of-foods.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Abu Dhabi 2012 - Grant</title><link>/posts/abu-dhabi-2012-grant.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/abu-dhabi-2012-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="presented-at-international-symposium-on-vitamin-d-deficiency---abu-dhabi-march-2012">Presented at International Symposium on Vitamin D Deficiency - Abu Dhabi March 2012&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;1182&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prof-william-b-grant">Prof. William B. Grant&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Qualifications: Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Position: Director, Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center (SUNARC), San Francisco, California, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-reducing-risk-of-cardiovascular-disease">1) The Role of Vitamin D in Reducing Risk of Cardiovascular Disease&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The aim of this presentation is to make the audience aware of the benefits of vitamin D in reducing the risk of cardiovascular diseases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Included in the talk will be an overview of the epidemiological findings regarding vitamin D and risk of cardiovascular diseases, the mechanisms whereby vitamin D might reduce the risk of cardiovascular disease, and the amount of vitamin D required to achieve optimal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Optimal Vitamin D during pregnancy - 4000 IU</title><link>/posts/optimal-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-4000-iu.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/optimal-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-4000-iu.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-its-role-during-pregnancy-in-attaining-optimal-health-of-mother-and-fetus">Vitamin D and Its Role During Pregnancy in Attaining Optimal Health of Mother and Fetus&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Carol L. &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#090;">Wagner &lt;/span>&lt;/strong> Sarah N. Taylor 1, Adekunle Dawodu 2, Donna D. Johnson 3 and Bruce W. &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Hollis &lt;/span>&lt;/strong> 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Neonatology, Department of Pediatrics, Medical University of South Carolina,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>173 Ashley Avenue, MSC 513, Charleston, SC 29425, USA; E-Mails: &lt;a href="mailto:taylorse@musc.edu">taylorse@musc.edu&lt;/a> (S.N.T.); &lt;a href="mailto:Hollisb@musc.edu">Hollisb@musc.edu&lt;/a> (B.W.H.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Global Health Center, Cincinnati Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Medical Center, Cincinnati, OH 45229, USA; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:Adekunle.Dawodu@cchmc.org">Adekunle.Dawodu@cchmc.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gestational diabetes 60 percent more likely below 20 ng of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/gestational-diabetes-60-percent-more-likely-below-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gestational-diabetes-60-percent-more-likely-below-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-gestational-diabetes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D and gestational diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#maternal-vitamin-d-status-as-a-critical-determinant-in-gestational-diabetes">Maternal vitamin d status as a critical determinant in gestational diabetes.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-gestational-diabetes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D and gestational diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Internal Medicine, online 20 February 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Y.H.M. Poel a, Corresponding author contact information, E-mail the corresponding author,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P. Hummel b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P. Lips c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>F. Stam a,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>T. van der Ploeg d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. Simseka c&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Internal Medicine, Gynaecology and Reproductive Medicine, Medical Centre Alkmaar, Alkmaar, The Netherlands&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vaginosis during pregnancy 5X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/vaginosis-during-pregnancy-5x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vaginosis-during-pregnancy-5x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="maternal-vitamin-d-folate-and-polyunsaturated-fatty-acid-status-and-bacterial-vaginosis-during-pregnancy">Maternal vitamin D, folate, and polyunsaturated fatty acid status and bacterial vaginosis during pregnancy.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Infect Dis Obstet Gynecol. 2011;2011:216217. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1155/2011/216217.">doi: 10.1155/2011/216217.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Dec 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dunlop AL, Taylor RN, Tangpricha V, Fortunato S, Menon R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Family &amp;amp; Preventive Medicine, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA 30322, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:amlang@emory.edu">amlang@emory.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To investigate associations among serum 25-hydroxy-vitamin D (25-OH-D), folate, omega-6/omega-3 fatty acid ratio and bacterial vaginosis (BV) during pregnancy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: Biospecimens and data were derived from a random sample (N = 160) of women from the Nashville Birth Cohort. We compared mean plasma nutrient concentrations for women with and without BV during pregnancy (based on Nugent score ?7) and assessed the odds of BV for those with 25-OH-D &amp;lt;12?ng/mL, folate &amp;lt;5?ug/L, and omega-6/omega-3 ratio &amp;gt;15.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cochrane Report on Vitamin D for pregnancies ignored the facts</title><link>/posts/cochrane-report-on-vitamin-d-for-pregnancies-ignored-the-facts.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cochrane-report-on-vitamin-d-for-pregnancies-ignored-the-facts.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> Taking more vitamin D usually provides more benefits&lt;/p>
&lt;p>              But this report grouped all of the studies together: 200 IU to 4,000 IU&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d3-works-better-than-vitamin-d2" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2138">Vitamin D3 works better than Vitamin D2&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>              But this report grouped all of the studies together&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> The body reacts differently to daily, monthly, and annual doses of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>              But this report grouped all of the studies together&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many pregnant women have low levels of nutrients</title><link>/posts/many-pregnant-women-have-low-levels-of-nutrients.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-pregnant-women-have-low-levels-of-nutrients.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="review-of-fortified-food-and-beverage-products-for-pregnant-and-lactating-women-and-their-impact-on-nutritional-status">Review of fortified food and beverage products for pregnant and lactating women and their impact on nutritional status.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Yang Z, Huffman SL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Global Alliance for Improved Nutrition (GAIN), Geneva, Switzerland. &lt;a href="mailto:Yang.Zhenyuid@gmail.com">Yang.Zhenyuid@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fortified beverages and supplementary foods, when given during pregnancy, have been shown to have positive effects on preventing maternal anaemia and iron deficiency. Studies show that use of micronutrient fortified supplementary foods, especially those containing milk and/or essential fatty acids during pregnancy, increase mean birthweight by around 60-73 g. A few studies have also shown that fortified supplementary foods have impacts on increasing birth length and reducing preterm delivery. Fortification levels have ranged generally from 50% to 100% of the recommended nutrient intake (RNI). &lt;strong>Iron, zinc, copper, iodine, selenium, vitamins A, D, E, C, B1, B2, B6, and B12, folic acid, niacin and pantothenic acid&lt;/strong> are important nutrients that have been included in fortified beverages and supplemental foods for pregnant and lactating women. While calcium has been shown to reduce the risk of pre-eclampsia and maternal mortality, calcium, phosphorus, potassium, magnesium and manganese can have negative impacts on organoleptic properties, so many products tested have not included these nutrients or have done so in a limited way. Fortified food supplements containing milk and essential fatty acids offer benefits to improving maternal status and pregnancy outcome. Fortified beverages containing only multiple micronutrients have been shown to reduce micronutrient deficiencies such as anaemia and iron deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of recent publications on vitamin D and pregnancy</title><link>/posts/review-of-recent-publications-on-vitamin-d-and-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-recent-publications-on-vitamin-d-and-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-current-concepts">Vitamin D in pregnancy: current concepts&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Rachel P. Urrutia and John M. Thorp&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Obstet Gynecol. 2012 Feb 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose of review: Vitamin D is part of a complex steroid hormone system long known to be involved in bone metabolism. Recently, vitamin D has been implicated in physiologic processes as diverse as vascular health, immune function, metabolism and placental function. This review summarizes the current evidence for the role of vitamin D in pregnancy and perinatal outcomes A systematic review of articles published in PubMed between May 2010 and October 2011 was undertaken using key words for vitamin D and pregnancy. Seventy-eight studies were reviewed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D in pregnancy and 2X worse language skills later</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-and-2x-worse-language-skills-later.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-and-2x-worse-language-skills-later.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="summary-18-ng-during-pregnancy-vs-28-ng-resulted-in-2x-more-language-difficulties-at-ages-510">Summary: &amp;lt;18 ng during pregnancy vs &amp;gt;28 ng resulted in 2X more language difficulties at ages 5/10&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="maternal-serum-vitamin-d-levels-during-pregnancy-and-offspring-neurocognitive-development">Maternal Serum Vitamin D Levels During Pregnancy and Offspring Neurocognitive Development&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Andrew J. O. Whitehouse, PhD, &lt;a href="mailto:awhitehouse@ichr.uwa.edu.au">awhitehouse@ichr.uwa.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara J. Holt, BSc,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael Serralha, BSc(Hons),&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patrick G. Holt, DSc,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Merci M. H. Kusel, MBBS, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prue H. Hart, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telethon Institute for Child Health Research, Centre for Child Health Research, University of Western Australia, Subiaco, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type I diabetes 2X more likely if mother had low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-i-diabetes-2x-more-likely-if-mother-had-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-i-diabetes-2x-more-likely-if-mother-had-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="maternal-serum-levels-of-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-risk-of-type-1-diabetes-in-the-offspring">Maternal serum levels of 25-hydroxy-vitamin D during pregnancy and risk of type 1 diabetes in the offspring.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Diabetes. 2012 Jan;61(1):175-8. Epub 2011 Nov 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sørensen IM, Joner G, Jenum PA, Eskild A, Torjesen PA, Stene LC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Oslo University Hospital Ullevål, Oslo, Norway. &lt;a href="mailto:i.m.sorensen@medisin.uio.no">i.m.sorensen@medisin.uio.no&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous studies indicate reduced risk of type 1 diabetes after intake of vitamin D supplements during pregnancy or early childhood. We aimed to test whether lower maternal serum concentrations of 25-hydroxy-vitamin D (25-OH D) during pregnancy were associated with an increased risk of childhood-onset type 1 diabetes. In this case-control study nested within a cohort of 29,072 women in Norway, 25-OH D levels were measured using a radioimmunoassay on samples from late pregnancy in 109 women delivering a child who developed type 1 diabetes before 15 years of age (case subjects) and from 219 control women. Dividing the levels of maternal 25-OH D into quartiles, there was a trend toward a higher risk of type 1 diabetes with lower levels of vitamin D during pregnancy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OBGYN College in UK still recommends only 400 IU during pregnancy</title><link>/posts/obgyn-college-in-uk-still-recommends-only-400-iu-during-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obgyn-college-in-uk-still-recommends-only-400-iu-during-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="rcog-statement-on-vitamin-d-supplementation-for-pregnant-womenhttpwwwrcogorgukwhat-we-docampaigning-and-opinionsstatementrcog-statement-vitamin-d-supplementation-pregnant-wome">&lt;a href="http://www.rcog.org.uk/what-we-do/campaigning-and-opinions/statement/rcog-statement-vitamin-d-supplementation-pregnant-wome">RCOG Statement on vitamin D supplementation for pregnant women&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="by-royal-college-of-obgyn-jan-2012">By Royal College of OBGYN Jan 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>– – – – – – – – –&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="note-from-admin-of-vitamindwiki">Note from Admin of VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When asked, I said that the OBGYNs would be the last to acknowledge the need for more vitamin D because that is the medical group which has the most to lose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I estimated that the world will need about 1/3 fewer OBGYN when enough vitamin D is given during pregnancy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>120000 IU vitamin D twice during pregnancy helped some</title><link>/posts/120000-iu-vitamin-d-twice-during-pregnancy-helped-some.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/120000-iu-vitamin-d-twice-during-pregnancy-helped-some.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Finland max 2000 IU vitamin D since cannot get more from food - 2011</title><link>/posts/finland-max-2000-iu-vitamin-d-since-cannot-get-more-from-food-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/finland-max-2000-iu-vitamin-d-since-cannot-get-more-from-food-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-children-with-chronic-illnesses-predisposing-and-protecting-factors">Vitamin D deficiency in children with chronic illnesses: Predisposing and protecting factors&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Author: 	Koskivirta, Panu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Contributor: 	Helsingin yliopisto, Lääketieteellinen tiedekunta, Kliininen laitos&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thesis level:&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="comment-by-vitamindwiki-finnish-span-stylecolor00fnutrition-spanboard-apparently-decided-on-2000-iu-upper-limit-because-people-cannot-get-more-vitamin-d-from-food-without-fortification-supplements-or-sunuv">Comment by VitaminDWiki: Finnish &lt;span style="color:#00F;">nutrition &lt;/span>board apparently decided on 2,000 IU upper limit because people cannot get more vitamin D from FOOD without fortification, supplements, or sun/uv&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolor00fthe-finnish-nutritional-advisory-board-states-in-their-report-that-the-recommended-dose-cannot-further-be-elevatedspan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">The Finnish nutritional advisory board states in their report that the recommended dose cannot further be elevated&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolor00for-it-would-be-even-harder-or-even-impossible-to-fulfill-it-without-usage-of-food-supplements-in-the-whole-populationspan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">or “it would be even harder or even impossible to fulfill it without usage of food supplements in the whole population”&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Abstract: 	This thesis assesses clinical differences in patients with low and high vitamin D levels. The factors analyzed included the underlying disease, body size, age, ethnic background, use of vitamin D supplements and the season when the blood sample was taken. Fifty patients with the lowest and 50 patients with the highest vitamin D concentrations were selected from a cohort of 1351 chronically ill children and adolescents who had had their vitamin D status assessed at Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wonder when the first doctor will be found liable for not providing vitamin D to a patient</title><link>/posts/wonder-when-the-first-doctor-will-be-found-liable-for-not-providing-vitamin-d-to-a-patient.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wonder-when-the-first-doctor-will-be-found-liable-for-not-providing-vitamin-d-to-a-patient.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="go-to-court-not-enough-vitamin-dsunshine-for-the-monkey">Go to court: Not enough vitamin D/sunshine for the monkey&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-birmingham-16169756%20">Stourbridge pair in court for monkey cruelty&lt;/a> BBC Dec 2011&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Monkey had many bone fractures&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Owners got four charges of cruelty under the Animal Welfare Act 2006.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;935&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Owners of some pet reptiles setup UV lamps which their animals can use as they desire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The administrator of this wiki site has setup UV lamp for himself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several friends who have cats have also purchased UV lamps - which their cats enjoy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Recommendations during Pregnancy, Lactation and Early Infancy</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-recommendations-during-pregnancy-lactation-and-early-infancy.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-recommendations-during-pregnancy-lactation-and-early-infancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="by-carol-l-wagner-md-fabm-in-clinical-lactation-2011-vol-21-27-31">By Carol L. Wagner, M.D., FABM in Clinical Lactation, 2011, Vol. 2(1), 27-31&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/20110000-vitamin-d-pregnancy-wagner.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D recommendations are shifting. The Institute of Medicine recently revised the Estimated Average Requirement (EAR) from 200 to 400 international units (IU), the Recommended Dietary Allowance (RDA) from 400 to 600 international units (IU), and increased the Tolerable Upper Intake Level (UL) from 2,000 to 4,000 IU per day. What does this mean for the pregnant and lactating woman? To answer this question, current guidelines are described and adapted excerpts from a recent book on the subject are provided.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High maternal vitamin D resulted in 30 percent less infant problems with breathing</title><link>/posts/high-maternal-vitamin-d-resulted-in-30-percent-less-infant-problems-with-breathing.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-maternal-vitamin-d-resulted-in-30-percent-less-infant-problems-with-breathing.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-in-pregnancy-and-risk-of-lower-respiratory-tract-infections-wheezing-and-asthma-in-offspring">Maternal Vitamin D Status in Pregnancy and Risk of Lower Respiratory Tract Infections, Wheezing, and Asthma in Offspring.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Epidemiology. 2011 Nov 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morales E, Romieu I, Guerra S, Ballester F, Rebagliato M, Vioque J, Tardón A, Rodriguez Delhi C, Arranz L, Torrent M, Espada M, Basterrechea M, Sunyer J; on behalf of the INMA Project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the a Center for Research in Environmental Epidemiology (CREAL), Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain; b Hospital del Mar Research Institute (IMIM), Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain; c CIBER Epidemiología y Salud Pública (CIBERESP), Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain; d National Institute of Public Health, Cuernavaca, Mexico; eCenter for Public Health Research (CSISP), Valencia, Spain; fUniversity of Valencia, Valencia, Spain; gRey Juan Carlos University, Madrid, Spain; hDepartmento de Salud Pública, Hospital San Agustín, Servicio de Salud del Principado de Asturias (SESPA), Avilés, Asturias, Spain; iOviedo University, Asturias, Spain; jHospital San Agustin, Servicio de Salud del Principado de Asturias (SESPA), Avilés, Asturias, Spain; kServicio de Pediatría, Hospital Universitario Donostia, Servicio Vasco de Salud, Osakidetza, Euskadi, Spain; lDepartamento de Pediatría, Facultad de Medicina y Odontología, Universidad del País Vasco (UPV/EHU), Euskadi, Spain; mArea de Salud de Menorca, IB-SALUT, Menorca, Spain; nClinical Chemistry Unity, Public Health Laboratory of Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain; and oSubdirección de Salud Pública de Gipuzkoa, Departamento de Sanidad del Gobierno Vasco, Euskadi, Spain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D given after low weight birth did not decrease death rate</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-given-after-low-weight-birth-did-not-decrease-death-rate.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-given-after-low-weight-birth-did-not-decrease-death-rate.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-weekly-vitamin-d-supplements-on-mortality-morbidity-and-growth-of-low-birthweight-term-infants-in-india-up-to-age-6-months-randomised-controlled-trial">Effect of weekly vitamin D supplements on mortality, morbidity, and growth of low birthweight term infants in India up to age 6 months: randomised controlled trial&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>BMJ. 2011; 342: d2975.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2011 May 31. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.d2975">doi: 10.1136/bmj.d2975&lt;/a>; PMCID: PMC3104477; Accepted March 14, 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Geeta Trilok Kumar, associate professor,corresponding author1 Harshpal Singh Sachdev, senior consultant in paediatrics and clinical epidemiology,2 Harish Chellani, consultant paediatrician,3 Andrea M Rehman, lecturer in medical statistics ,4 Vini Singh, research fellow,1 Harsh Arora, research fellow,1 and Suzanne Filteau, professor of international nutrition 4&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Women and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-women-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-women-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d---roles-in-womens-reproductive-health---nov-2011">Vitamin D - roles in women&amp;rsquo;s reproductive health - Nov 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#nice-summary-of-vitamin-d-levels-from-this-paper">Nice summary of vitamin D levels from this paper&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#interesting-way-of-showing-non-classical-influences-of-vitamin-d">Interesting way of showing non-classical influences of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sufficiency-is-30-60-ng-optimal-50-80-ngtoxicity-does-not-start-until-150-ng">Sufficiency is 30-60 ng, optimal 50-80 ng,toxicity does not start until 150 ng&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-costs-of-motherhood-are-rising-and-catching-women-off-guardhttpswwwnytimescom20180817upshotmotherhood-rising-costs-surprisehtml20-ny-times-aug-2018">&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/17/upshot/motherhood-rising-costs-surprise.html%20">The Costs of Motherhood Are Rising, and Catching Women Off Guard&lt;/a> NY Times Aug 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#nice-wide-ranging-description-of-pros-and-cons-of-having-a-child---dec-2023-nothing-about-vitamin-d">Nice wide-ranging description of pros and cons of having a child - Dec 2023 (nothing about Vitamin D)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Adulthood&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Insights into Vitamin D During Pregnancy, Lactation and Early Infancy</title><link>/posts/new-insights-into-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-lactation-and-early-infancy.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/new-insights-into-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-lactation-and-early-infancy.html</guid><description>&lt;p>by Carol L., M.D. Wagner (Author), Sarah N., M.D. Taylor, Bruce W., Ph.D. Hollis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$24 &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Insights-Vitamin-Pregnancy-Lactation-Infancy/dp/0982337965/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1319720528&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;tag=acleint-20">Amazon&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;833&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wagner-and-hollis-both-had-and-both-continue-to-write-extensively-on-this-topic">Wagner and Hollis both had and both continue to write extensively on this topic&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>click on highlighted category below&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300,000 IU injection loading dose of vitamin D3 stopped gestational diabetes in RCT</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-injection-loading-dose-of-vitamin-d3-stopped-gestational-diabetes-in-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-injection-loading-dose-of-vitamin-d3-stopped-gestational-diabetes-in-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-a-single-span-stylecolorf00post-partumspan-injection-of-a-high-dose-of-vitamin-d-on-glucose-tolerance-and-insulin-resistance-in-mothers-with-first-time-gestational-diabetes-mellitus">Effects of a single &lt;span style="color:#F00;">post-partum&lt;/span> injection of a high dose of vitamin D on glucose tolerance and insulin resistance in mothers with first-time gestational diabetes mellitus&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>H. Mozaffari-Khosravi1, M. Hosseinzadeh-Shamsi-Anar1, M.-A. Salami2, H. Hadinedoushan3, M. R. Mozayan4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetic Medicine Vol. 28 Issue 10&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aim? This study was performed to determine the effect of a single, large, intramuscular injection of vitamin D post-partum on glucose tolerance and insulin resistance in women with gestational diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels in first trimester vary with latitude</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-in-first-trimester-vary-with-latitude.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-in-first-trimester-vary-with-latitude.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="systematic-review-of-first-trimester-vitamin-d-normative-levels-and-outcomes-of-pregnancy">Systematic review of first-trimester vitamin D normative levels and outcomes of pregnancy.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2011 Apr 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nassar N, Halligan GH, Roberts CL, Morris JM, Ashton AW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perinatal Research, Kolling Institute of Medical Research, University of Sydney, NSW, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We undertook a systematic review to assess normative levels of vitamin D in early pregnancy and association with subsequent pregnancy outcomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>STUDY DESIGN:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medline and Embase databases and reference lists were searched. Inclusion criteria were pregnant populations, blood sample taken during the first trimester, and serum hydroxyvitamin D levels assessed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blacks have more pre-term births due to low nutrients such as vitamin D</title><link>/posts/blacks-have-more-pre-term-births-due-to-low-nutrients-such-as-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-have-more-pre-term-births-due-to-low-nutrients-such-as-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="racial-disparities-in-preterm-birth-an-overview-of-the-potential-role-of-nutrient-deficiencies">Racial disparities in preterm birth: an overview of the potential role of nutrient deficiencies.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dunlop AL, Kramer M, Hogue CJ, Menon R, Ramakrishan U.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2011 Sep 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emory University School of Medicine, Department of Family and Preventive Medicine, Emory University Rollins School of Public Health, Women and Children&amp;rsquo;s Center,Department of Epidemiology, and Emory University Rollins School of Public Health, Department of Global Health, Atlanta, Georgia, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mixed results of studies of vitamin D during pregnancy</title><link>/posts/mixed-results-of-studies-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mixed-results-of-studies-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="does-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-impact-offspring-growth-and-bone">Does vitamin D during pregnancy impact offspring growth and bone?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Proc Nutr Soc. 2011 Aug 24:1-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Specker BL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>EA Martin Program in Human Nutrition, SWC, Box 506, South Dakota State University, Brookings, SD 57007, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During pregnancy, maternal and fetal Ca demands are met through increased intestinal Ca absorption. Increased Ca absorption may be more dependent on oestrogen&amp;rsquo;s up-regulation of Ca transport genes than on vitamin D status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Numerous studies, however, have found that severe vitamin D deficiency with secondary hyperparathyroidism during pregnancy leads to abnormal Ca homoeostasis in the neonate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smoking while pregnant lowers vitamin D and increases child asthma by 3.6 X</title><link>/posts/smoking-while-pregnant-lowers-vitamin-d-and-increases-child-asthma-by-36-x.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/smoking-while-pregnant-lowers-vitamin-d-and-increases-child-asthma-by-36-x.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The title of this page is the conclusion of a &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Sept 2011&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> study – bullet point summary are below&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FACT: Being Pregnant greatly increases the need for vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FACT: Smoking reduces vitamin D in the body&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FACT: Children born of women with lots of vitamin D are 5X less likely to get asthma&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VitaminDWiki interpretation of the study: Smoking ==&amp;gt; Reduce vitamin D ==&amp;gt; Increase chance of asthma in child&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic - the cost of being female</title><link>/posts/off-topic-the-cost-of-being-female.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-the-cost-of-being-female.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>80 percent recent increase in Strokes following pregnancy</title><link>/posts/80-percent-recent-increase-in-strokes-following-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/80-percent-recent-increase-in-strokes-following-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="fact-pregnancy-increases-blood-pressure-in-some-women-preeclampsia">Fact: Pregnancy increases blood pressure in some women (preeclampsia)&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="fact-increased-strokes-with-increased-blood-pressure">Fact: Increased strokes with increased blood pressure&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="fact-preeclampsia-increases-as-there-is-less-vitamin-d">Fact: Preeclampsia increases as there is less vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="fact-a-hrefpostsdecreasing-vitamin-d-in-recent-decades-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1586decreasing-vitamin-d-in-recent-decadesa">Fact: &lt;a href="/posts/decreasing-vitamin-d-in-recent-decades" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1586">Decreasing vitamin D in recent decades&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="fact-vitamin-d-is-especially-low-after-giving-birth-or-other-large-traumahttpswwwvitamindwikicomtiki-browse_categoriesphpparentid64sort_modecreated_desc">Fact: Vitamin D is especially low after giving birth (&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=64&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">or other large trauma&lt;/a>)&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="nbsp-nbsp-nbspspan-stylecolorf00no-surprise-increasing-number-of-strokes-following-pregnancyspan">     &lt;span style="color:#F00;">No surprise: Increasing number of strokes following pregnancy&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="webmd-httpwwwwebmdcombabynews20110728strokes-during-pregnancy-childbirth-on-the-risestrokes-during-pregnancy-childbirth-on-the-rise">&lt;a href="http://www.webmd.com/baby/news/20110728/strokes-during-pregnancy-childbirth-on-the-rise">WebMD &lt;/a>Strokes During Pregnancy, Childbirth on the Rise&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="researchers-say-rising-rate-of-high-blood-pressure-is-a-factor-in-the-increase-in-stroke">Researchers Say Rising Rate of High Blood Pressure Is a Factor in the Increase in Stroke&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>2000 per year 1994-95&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High vitamin D in moms decreased MS incidence in daughters by 40%</title><link>/posts/high-vitamin-d-in-moms-decreased-ms-incidence-in-daughters-by-40-percent.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-vitamin-d-in-moms-decreased-ms-incidence-in-daughters-by-40-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="gestational-vitamin-d-and-the-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-offspring">Gestational vitamin D and the risk of multiple sclerosis in offspring.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Neurol. 2011 Jul;70(1):30-40. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.22456.">doi: 10.1002/ana.22456.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mirzaei F, Michels KB, Munger K, O&amp;rsquo;Reilly E, Chitnis T, Forman MR, Giovannucci E, Rosner B, Ascherio A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutrition, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, MA; Department of Epidemiology, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, MA. &lt;a href="mailto:fmirzaei@hsph.harvard.edu">fmirzaei@hsph.harvard.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:Vitamin D may have a protective role in the etiology of multiple sclerosis (MS), but the effect of gestational vitamin D on adult onset MS has not been studied.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UK survey of vitamin D knowledge of midwives - 2011</title><link>/posts/uk-survey-of-vitamin-d-knowledge-of-midwives-2011.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uk-survey-of-vitamin-d-knowledge-of-midwives-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="measuring-and-improving-vitamin-d-promotion-and-prescribing-to-prenatal-and-postnatal-women-within-the-north-west--portion-of-the-uk">Measuring and Improving Vitamin D Promotion and Prescribing to Prenatal and Postnatal Women within the North West portion of the UK)&lt;/h4>
&lt;h2 id="summary-by-vitamindwiki">Summary by VitaminDWiki:&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolorf00while-40-of-midwives-and-health-visitors-felt-confident-about-providing-vitamin-d-information-their-knowledge-was-very-limitedspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">While 40% of midwives and health visitors felt confident about providing vitamin D information, their knowledge was very limited&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h3 id="we-were-unable-to-extract-the-text-from-the-pdf-file-but-here-are-a-few-interesting-charts">(We were unable to extract the text from the PDF file, but here are a few interesting charts)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;658&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;659&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="notes-for-translation---6">Notes for translation - #6&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Only half knew that Oily fish, dairy and eggs provide vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – vitamin D links breastfeeding difficulties and depression</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-links-breastfeeding-difficulties-and-depression.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-links-breastfeeding-difficulties-and-depression.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ran-across-the-following-article">Ran across the following article&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="mothers-with-breastfeeding-difficulties-more-likely-to-suffer-postpartum-depressionhttpmedicalxpresscomnews2011-07-mothers-breastfeeding-difficulties-postpartum-depressionhtml20-medical-express-july-19-2011">&lt;a href="http://medicalxpress.com/news/2011-07-mothers-breastfeeding-difficulties-postpartum-depression.html%20">Mothers with breastfeeding difficulties more likely to suffer postpartum depression&lt;/a> Medical Express July 19, 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clip – – – –&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;We found that women who said they disliked breastfeeding were &lt;strong>42 percent more likely to experience postpartum depression at two months&lt;/strong> compared to women who liked breastfeeding. We also found that women with severe breast pain at day one and also at two weeks postpartum were &lt;strong>twice as likely to be depressed&lt;/strong> compared to women that did not experience pain with nursing,”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>90 percent of Indian mothers and infants had less than 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/90-percent-of-indian-mothers-and-infants-had-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/90-percent-of-indian-mothers-and-infants-had-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>300 IU vitamin D daily raised child levels to 20 ng from 8 ng</title><link>/posts/300-iu-vitamin-d-daily-raised-child-levels-to-20-ng-from-8-ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300-iu-vitamin-d-daily-raised-child-levels-to-20-ng-from-8-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="randomized-trial-of-fortified-milk-and-supplements-to-raise-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-schoolchildren-in-mongolia">Randomized trial of fortified milk and supplements to raise 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations in schoolchildren in Mongolia.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jun 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rich-Edwards JW, Ganmaa D, Kleinman K, Sumberzul N, Holick MF, Lkhagvasuren T, Dulguun B, Burke A, Frazier AL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Connors Center for Women&amp;rsquo;s Health and Gender Biology, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA and Nutrition, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, MA; Channing Laboratory, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Premature or low birth weight resulted in children 3X more likely to be anxious – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/premature-or-low-birth-weight-resulted-in-children-3x-more-likely-to-be-anxious-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/premature-or-low-birth-weight-resulted-in-children-3x-more-likely-to-be-anxious-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-psychiatric-diagnoses-in-preterm-and-full-term-children-adolescents-and-young-adults-a-meta-analysis">Prevalence of psychiatric diagnoses in preterm and full-term children, adolescents and young adults: a meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Psychological Medicine, Published online: 20 May 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. C. Burnetta1a2a3 &lt;a href="mailto:aburnett@unimelb.edu.au">aburnett@unimelb.edu.au&lt;/a>, P. J. Andersona3a4, J. Cheonga3a5a6, L. W. Doylea3a4a5a6, C. G. Daveya2a7 and S. J. Wooda2a8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a1 Department of Psychology, The University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a2 Melbourne Neuropsychiatry Centre, Department of Psychiatry, The University of Melbourne and Melbourne Health, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a3 Murdoch Childrens Research Institute, Parkville, VIC, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4000 IU Vitamin D Safe and Effective For Healthy Pregnant Women – RCT</title><link>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-safe-and-effective-for-healthy-pregnant-women-rct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-safe-and-effective-for-healthy-pregnant-women-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-during-pregnancy-double-blind-randomized-clinical-trial-of-safety-and-effectiveness">Vitamin D Supplementation during Pregnancy: Double Blind, Randomized Clinical Trial of Safety and Effectiveness&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/releases/229686.php">Medical News today&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use of vitamin D supplements during pregnancy has long been a matter of concern but now researchers writing in the Journal of Bone and Mineral Research report that even a high supplementation amount in healthy pregnant women was safe and effective in raising circulating vitamin D to a level thought by some to be optimal. The study also found no adverse effects of vitamin D supplementation, even at the highest amount, in women or their newborns.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Incredible – Obstetrics group says pregnant women not need vitamin D tests</title><link>/posts/incredible-obstetrics-group-says-pregnant-women-not-need-vitamin-d-tests.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/incredible-obstetrics-group-says-pregnant-women-not-need-vitamin-d-tests.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="no-vitamin-d-screening-in-pregnancy-committeehttpwwwreuterscomarticle20110620us-vitamin-d-pregnancy-idustre75j6yh2011062020-from-reuters">&lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/06/20/us-vitamin-d-pregnancy-idUSTRE75J6YH20110620%20">No vitamin D screening in pregnancy: committee&lt;/a> from Reuters&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>By Alison McCook, NEW YORK | Mon Jun 20, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="clips-from-article-follow">Clips from article follow&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="reuters-health---most-pregnant-women-do-not-need-to-be-screened-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-nor-given-additional-supplements-according-to-an-official-statement-issued-by-the-american-college-of-obstetricians-and-gynecologists">(Reuters Health) - Most pregnant women do not need to be screened for vitamin D deficiency, nor given additional supplements, according to an official statement issued by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The only pregnant women who might benefit from a blood test for vitamin D deficiency - and it&amp;rsquo;s not clear even for them &amp;ndash; &lt;strong>are those who are at high risk for the problem in the first place due to certain diseases or other circumstances&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Having twins takes more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/having-twins-takes-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/having-twins-takes-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="differences-in-bone-metabolism-between-singleton-pregnancy-and-twin-pregnancy">Differences in bone metabolism between singleton pregnancy and twin pregnancy.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bone. 2011 May 27./10.1016/j.bone.2011.05.016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nakayama S, Yasui T, Suto M, Sato M, Kaji T, Uemura H, Maeda K, Irahara M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Institute of Health Biosciences, The University of Tokushima Graduate School, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: The objective of this study was to examine the influence of twin pregnancy on calcium metabolism, including bone turnover markers and calcium-regulating factors, by comparison between singleton pregnancy and twin pregnancy in women during pregnancy and puerperium in cross-sectional and longitudinal studies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diseases correlated to month of birth – 2008</title><link>/posts/diseases-correlated-to-month-of-birth-2008.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diseases-correlated-to-month-of-birth-2008.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="human-responses-to--the--geophysical--daily-annual-and-lunar-cycles">Human Responses to the Geophysical Daily, Annual and Lunar Cycles&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"> 
&lt;h4 id="gray-line-shows-how-low-vitamin-d-level-is-in-the-spring">Gray line shows how low Vitamin D level is in the Spring&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;1449&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;1450&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpostsclick-here-for-details-of-graphs-above-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-868click-here-for-details-of-graphs-abovea">&lt;a href="/posts/click-here-for-details-of-graphs-above" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 868">CLICK HERE for details of graphs above&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="study-was-cited-418-times-in-google-scholarhttpsscholargooglecomscholarcites17259065163665631985as_sdt548sciodt048hlen-by-nov-2022">&amp;ldquo;Study was cited 418 times in &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?cites=17259065163665631985&amp;amp;as_sdt=5,48&amp;amp;sciodt=0,48&amp;amp;hl=en">Google Scholar&lt;/a> by Nov 2022&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="the-following-is-the-portion-of-the-2008-text-concerning-ms-and-vitamin-d">The following is the portion of the 2008 text concerning MS and vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The incidence of multiple sclerosis (MS) varies with latitude. Ebers has co-ordinated a study &lt;sup>[46]&lt;/sup> that examined more than 40,000 Canadian, British, Danish and Swedish patients with multiple sclerosis. The results show that in the Northern hemisphere, significantly fewer (8.5%) people with MS were born in November and significantly more (9.1%) were born in May. In the Southern hemisphere, the situation is reversed and November is the peak month and May the lowest. There are several clues as to the cause. An important study &lt;sup>[47]&lt;/sup> compared the risk of two or more siblings having multiple sclerosis to the risk of its occurrence in both twins in a non-identical pair. There should be no difference, but non-identical twins do have a significantly higher risk of both having MS than non-twin siblings. This suggests that the pre-natal and post-natal environment affects the overall risk. Pinpointing the actual environmental factor has been problematic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pregnancy outcomes not associated with low vitamin D – review</title><link>/posts/pregnancy-outcomes-not-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnancy-outcomes-not-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="systematic-review-of-first-trimester-vitamin-d-normative-levels-and-outcomes-of-pregnancy">Systematic review of first-trimester vitamin D normative levels and outcomes of pregnancy.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2011 Apr 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nassar N (&lt;a href="mailto:natasha.nassar@uwa.edu">natasha.nassar@uwa.edu&lt;/a>), Halligan GH, Roberts CL, Morris JM, Ashton AW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perinatal Research, Kolling Institute of Medical Research, University of Sydney, NSW, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We undertook a systematic review to assess normative levels of vitamin D in early pregnancy and association with subsequent pregnancy outcomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>STUDY DESIGN:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medline and Embase databases and reference lists were searched. Inclusion criteria were pregnant populations, blood sample taken during the first trimester, and serum hydroxyvitamin D levels assessed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autism has different causes but same inflammation in brain in half of autistics</title><link>/posts/autism-has-different-causes-but-same-inflammation-in-brain-in-half-of-autistics.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/autism-has-different-causes-but-same-inflammation-in-brain-in-half-of-autistics.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Obstetrics Improving Pregnancy and Childbirth - presentations</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-obstetrics-improving-pregnancy-and-childbirth-presentations.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-obstetrics-improving-pregnancy-and-childbirth-presentations.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="click-herehttpwwwvitamindassociationorgeventshtml-to-access-the-uk-presentations">&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindassociation.org/events.html">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> to access the UK presentations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Vitamin D &amp;amp; Obstetrics - UK Policy - Gillie (980KB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D &amp;amp; Obstetrics - Data overview - Grant (255KB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1945">Vitamin D &amp;amp; Obstetrics - Effectiveness &amp;amp; Safety - Hollis&lt;/a> (1.2MB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D &amp;amp; Obstetrics - GrassRootsHealth - Baggerly (188KB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1944">Vitamin D &amp;amp; Obstetrics - Implications for mother &amp;amp; child - Hypponen &lt;/a>(1.06MB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1943">Vitamin D &amp;amp; Obstetrics - Indian overview - Jain &lt;/a>(1.11MB)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to reduce preeclampsia</title><link>/posts/how-to-reduce-preeclampsia.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-reduce-preeclampsia.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Suggest that all pregnant women get or be tested for vitamin D</title><link>/posts/suggest-that-all-pregnant-women-get-or-be-tested-for-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/suggest-that-all-pregnant-women-get-or-be-tested-for-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-and-its-predictive-factors-in-pregnancy-in-2-australian-populations">Vitamin D status and its predictive factors in pregnancy in 2 Australian populations&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Sumathy PERAMPALAM1,2,3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kirtan GANDA2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kerri-Anne CHOW1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nicole OPIE1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter E. HICKMAN4,5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce SHADBOLT5,6,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annemarie HENNESSY3,7,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harry GRUNSTEIN2,3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christopher J. NOLAN1,5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1111/j.1479-828X.2011.01313.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Australian and New Zealand Journal of Obstetrics and Gynaecology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol. 51 Issue 2, Article first published online: 18 MAY 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:? High prevalence rates of suboptimal vitamin D levels have been observed in women who are not considered ‘at risk’. The effect of behavioural factors such as sun exposure, attire, sunscreen use and vitamin D supplementation on vitamin D levels in pregnancy is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Barriers to effective vitamin D supplementation during ante-natal care – Spring 2011</title><link>/posts/barriers-to-effective-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-ante-natal-care-spring-2011.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/barriers-to-effective-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-ante-natal-care-spring-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Arch Dis Child 2011;96:A22 doi:10.1136/adc.2011.212563.43&lt;/p>
&lt;p>British Paediatric Respiratory Society British Society of Paediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Nutrition&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R E Ling,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M Coren,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S Goldring&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paediatrics, St Mary&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Paddington, London, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aims Vitamin D deficiency in childhood is a common and recognised public health issue. National guidance recommends that all women should take 10 mcg vitamin D supplements daily during pregnancy and until their child is fully weaned, and midwives should offer this advice at the booking appointment. Two recent severe cases of vitamin D deficiency in infancy presented to our hospital, one with cardiac arrest secondary to hypocalcaemia and one with cardiomyopathy, illustrating the importance of such public health guidance. This study aimed to evaluate the knowledge, practice and barriers to implementation of vitamin D supplementation among midwives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>33 percent of pregnant women in Turkey had undetectable vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/33-percent-of-pregnant-women-in-turkey-had-undetectable-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/33-percent-of-pregnant-women-in-turkey-had-undetectable-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="bone-turnover-and-maternal-25oh-vitamin-d3-levels-during-pregnancy-and-the-postpartum-period-should-routine-vitamin-d-supplementation-be-increased-in-pregnant-women">Bone turnover and maternal 25(OH) vitamin D3 levels during pregnancy and the postpartum period: should routine vitamin D supplementation be increased in pregnant women?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Haliloglu B, Ilter E, Aksungar FB, Celik A, Coksuer H, Gunduz T, Yucel E, Ozekici U.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maltepe University, Faculty of Medicine, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Istanbul, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2011 May 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the relationship between 25(OH) vitamin D3 levels and maternal bone turnover during pregnancy and lactation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D results in severe preeclampsia and low birth weight</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-results-in-severe-preeclampsia-and-low-birth-weight.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-results-in-severe-preeclampsia-and-low-birth-weight.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-and-fetal-growth-in-early-onset-severe-preeclampsia">Maternal vitamin D and fetal growth in early-onset severe preeclampsia.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2011 Mar 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robinson CJ, Wagner CL, Hollis BW, Baatz JE, Johnson DD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, SC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, vitamin D deficiency has been associated with increased risks for preeclampsia and diagnosis of early-onset, severe preeclampsia (EOSPE). The purpose of this investigation was to examine the association between vitamin D levels and &lt;strong>small-for-gestational age (SGA)&lt;/strong> in patients with EOSPE.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone fractures not associated with vitamin D status</title><link>/posts/bone-fractures-not-associated-with-vitamin-d-status.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-fractures-not-associated-with-vitamin-d-status.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Vitamin D Status in Abused and Nonabused Children Younger Than 2 Years Old With Fractures&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online April 11, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PEDIATRICS (doi:10.1542/peds.2010-0533)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Samantha Schilling, MDa, Joanne N. Wood, MDa,b, Michael A. Levine, MDa,b, David Langdon, MDa,b, Cindy W. Christian, MDa,b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Department of Pediatrics, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Philadelphia, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Department of Pediatrics, University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective To examine vitamin D levels in children with (1) suspected abusive and accidental fractures, (2) single and multiple fractures, and (3) fracture types highly associated with inflicted trauma.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pre-term birth not associated with first tri-mester vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pre-term-birth-not-associated-with-first-tri-mester-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pre-term-birth-not-associated-with-first-tri-mester-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-nested-case-control-study-of-first-trimester-maternal-vitamin-d-status-and-risk-for-spontaneous-preterm-birth">A Nested Case-Control Study of First-Trimester Maternal Vitamin D Status and Risk for Spontaneous Preterm Birth.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Perinatol. 2011 Apr 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Baker AM, Haeri S, Camargo CA, Stuebe AM, Boggess KA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We assessed if first-trimester vitamin D deficiency is more prevalent in women who experienced a spontaneous preterm birth compared with women who delivered at term. We conducted a nested case-control study of pregnant women who had previously given blood for first-trimester combined screening for trisomy 21 and subsequently delivered at a tertiary hospital between November 2004 and July 2009. From an overall cohort of 4225 women, 40 cases of spontaneous preterm birth (? 23 (0)/ (7) and ? 34 (6)/ (7) weeks) were matched by race/ethnicity with 120 women delivering at term (? 37 (0)/ (7) weeks) with uncomplicated pregnancies. Banked maternal serum was used to measure maternal 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increase early births by 40 percent if less than 6 months to restock vitamin D</title><link>/posts/increase-early-births-by-40-percent-if-less-than-6-months-to-restock-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increase-early-births-by-40-percent-if-less-than-6-months-to-restock-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="racial-disparities-in-preterm-birth-rates-and-short-inter-pregnancy-interval-an-overview">Racial disparities in preterm birth rates and short inter-pregnancy interval. An overview.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2011 Feb 1. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0412.2011.01081.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0412.2011.01081.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hogue CJ, Menon R, Dunlop AL, Kramer MR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emory University, Rollins School of Public Health, Department of Epidemiology Emory University, School of Medicine, Department of Family and Preventive Medicine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective. We seek to expand on a biopsychosocial framework underlying the etiology of excess preterm birth experienced by African-American women by exploring short inter-pregnancy intervals as a partial explanatory factor.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skin pregnancies and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/dark-skin-pregnancies-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skin-pregnancies-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary">Summary&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#statistics-for-african-american-vs-white-births-in-the-us">Statistics for African-American vs white births in the US:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostschart-shows-that-blacks-are-almost-4x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1560chart-shows-that-blacks-are-almost-4x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-da">&lt;a href="/posts/chart-shows-that-blacks-are-almost-4x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1560">Chart shows that blacks are almost 4X more likely to have less than 20ng of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#left-curve--blacks-indoors-15-ng--right-curve--blacks-outdoors-46ng">Left curve = blacks indoors (15 ng) /// Right curve = blacks outdoors (46ng)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#on-the-web">On the web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> Avoiding the sun reduces your vitamin D intake&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> Can avoid the sun by use of sunscreen, not going outdoors, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Deficiency and Insufficiency is Common during Pregnancy</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-and-insufficiency-is-common-during-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-and-insufficiency-is-common-during-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Am J Perinatol. 2011 Jan;28(1):7-12. Epub 2010 Jul 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johnson DD, Wagner CL, Hulsey TC, McNeil RB, Ebeling M, Hollis BW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Maternal Fetal Medicine, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina 29425-0619, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:johnsodo@musc.edu">johnsodo@musc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective was to determine the incidence of vitamin D deficiency, insufficiency, and sufficiency in African-American, Hispanic, and Caucasian pregnant women. Blood samples were taken from 154 African-American, 194 Hispanic, and 146 Caucasian women at &amp;lt;14 weeks of gestation; 25 hydroxyvitamin D levels (25(OH)D) levels were measured by radioimmunoassay. The mean 25(OH)D levels in African-American, Hispanic, and Caucasian pregnant women were 15.5 ± 7.2 (standard deviation), 24.1 ± 8.7, 29.0 ± 8.5 ng/mL, respectively. Ninety-seven percent of African-Americans, 81% of Hispanics, and 67% of Caucasians were deficient (25(OH)D levels &amp;lt;20 ng/mL or &amp;lt;50 nmol/L) or insufficient (25(OH)D levels ? 20 ng/mL or &amp;lt;32 ng/mL or ? 50 nmol/L or &amp;lt;80 nmol/L). Of these pregnant women, 82% had vitamin D levels &amp;lt;32 ng/mL (&amp;lt;80 ng/mL). In logistic regression models, race was the most important risk factor for vitamin D deficiency or insufficiency. African-American women and Hispanic women were more likely to have vitamin D insufficiency and deficiency than Caucasian women. Furthermore, primigravid women were more at risk for vitamin D insufficiency. This study demonstrates widespread vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency in pregnant females living at a southern latitude. African-Americans are at greatest risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why higher levels of vitamin D reduces premature birth</title><link>/posts/why-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-reduces-premature-birth.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-reduces-premature-birth.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="adequate-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-reduces-the-risk-of-premature-birth-by-reducing-placental-colonization-by-bacterial-vaginosis-species">Adequate Vitamin D during Pregnancy Reduces the Risk of Premature Birth by Reducing Placental Colonization by Bacterial Vaginosis Species&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Letter to Editor in mBio 2(2):e00022-11. doi:10.1128/mBio.00022-11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant, Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, San Francisco, California, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The recent paper by Fichorova et al. (1) reported that placental colonization by bacterial species common in bacterial vaginosis (BV) was linked to an increased risk of premature birth and that targeting this colonization could reduce the risk of premature birth and subsequent inflammation-provoked late sequelae.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eclampsia 2X more frequent in Swedish winter</title><link>/posts/eclampsia-2x-more-frequent-in-swedish-winter.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/eclampsia-2x-more-frequent-in-swedish-winter.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="eclampsia-is-more-prevalent-during-the-winter-season-in-sweden">Eclampsia is more prevalent during the winter season in Sweden.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2011 Jan;90(1):114-7. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0412.2010.01010.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0412.2010.01010.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2010 Nov 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rylander A, Lindqvist PG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IVF Clinic, Queen Sophia Hospital, Stockholm Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Clintec, Karolinska University Hospital, Huddinge, Sweden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypertensive pregnancy conditions have shown seasonal variations and have been related to low levels of vitamin D. In Sweden, the hours of sunlight per day are few in winter. We hypothesized that eclampsia would be more common in the winter season. We performed a population-based cross-sectional study of all singleton deliveries in Sweden during a 5-year period (n= 482,759 women). All parturients with eclampsia were included as cases and those without formed control group.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The vitamin D requirement during human lactation</title><link>/posts/the-vitamin-d-requirement-during-human-lactation.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-vitamin-d-requirement-during-human-lactation.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-series-of-critical-letters-were-published-in-public-health-nutrition-vol-14-issue-4httpjournalscambridgeorgactiondisplayissuedecade2010jidphnvolumeid14issueid04iid8225288--the-following-letters-at-the-bottom-are-at-the-end-of-the-issue">A series of critical letters were published in Public Health Nutrition. &lt;a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayIssue?decade=2010&amp;amp;jid=PHN&amp;amp;volumeId=14&amp;amp;issueId=04&amp;amp;iid=8225288">Vol 14, issue 4&lt;/a> -the following letters at the bottom are at the end of the issue&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The 2010 recommendations of the American Institute of Medicine for daily intakes of vitamin&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Barbara J. Boucher&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D, how much is enough and how much is too much?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Edward Giovannucci&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D and the limits of randomized controlled trials,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Edward D. Gorham and Cedric F. Garland&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Era or error?,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Premature delivery associated with low vitamin D in Japanese women</title><link>/posts/premature-delivery-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-japanese-women.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/premature-delivery-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-japanese-women.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-prevalence-of-hypovitaminosis-d-in-pregnant-japanese-women-with-threatened-premature-delivery">High prevalence of hypovitaminosis D in pregnant Japanese women with threatened premature delivery.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Metab. 2011 Mar 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shibata M, Suzuki A, Sekiya T, Sekiguchi S, Asano S, Udagawa Y, Itoh M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Internal Medicine, Fujita Health University, 1-98 Dengakugakubo, Kutsukake-cho, Toyoake, Aichi, 470-1192, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) concentrations are thought to accurately reflect vitamin D stores, and vitamin D deficiency causes secondary hyperparathyroidism, irreversible bone loss, and increased risk of fracture.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D – pregnancy and lactation in high and low income countries</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-pregnancy-and-lactation-in-high-and-low-income-countries.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-pregnancy-and-lactation-in-high-and-low-income-countries.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="milk-intake-calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-and-lactation-effects-on-maternal-fetal-and-infant-bone-in-low--and-high-income-countries">Milk Intake, Calcium and Vitamin D in Pregnancy and Lactation: Effects on Maternal, Fetal and Infant Bone in Low- and High-Income Countries&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Prentice A;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clemens RA, Hernell O, Michaelsen KF (eds): Milk and Milk Products in Human Nutrition. Nestlé Nutr Inst Workshop Ser Pediatr Program, vol 67, pp 1–15, Nestec Ltd., Vevey/S. Karger AG, Basel, © 2011 (DOI: 10.1159/000325571)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calcium and vitamin D are essential for bone growth and maintenance. Among the bone-forming minerals, dietary calcium supply is close to biological requirements and may be limiting in some parts of the world where there are few rich dietary sources of calcium, particularly for children and women during pregnancy and lactation. Animal milk is a rich source of calcium and, in countries where milk is fortified with vitamin D, a contributor to dietary vitamin D intake.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some males conceived in the fall in the North were shorter</title><link>/posts/some-males-conceived-in-the-fall-in-the-north-were-shorter.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-males-conceived-in-the-fall-in-the-north-were-shorter.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="season-of-birth-and-subsequent-body-size-the-potential-role-of-prenatal-vitamin-d">Season of birth and subsequent body size: The potential role of prenatal vitamin D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Hum Biol. 2011 Mar;23(2):190-200. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ajhb.21101.">doi: 10.1002/ajhb.21101.&lt;/a> Epub 2010 Nov 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Krenz-Niedba?a M, Puch EA, Ko?ci?ski K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Human Evolutionary Biology, Adam Mickiewicz University, Umultowska 89, Pozna?, 61-614, Poland. &lt;a href="mailto:martak@amu.edu.pl">martak@amu.edu.pl&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: The relationship between season of birth and various physical and psychological outcomes was reported in many studies, although the underlying mechanism still remains unrecognized. The aim of this study was to explore the season-of-birth effect on body size in the sample of 1,148 eight-year-old Polish urban children and propose the mechanism responsible for this effect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and fertility and birth problems with dark skin</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-fertility-and-birth-problems-with-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-fertility-and-birth-problems-with-dark-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="racial-and-ethnic-disparities-in-assisted-reproductive-technology-pregnancy-and-live-birth-rates-within-body-mass-index-categories--fertility-and-sterility">Racial and ethnic disparities in assisted reproductive technology pregnancy and live birth rates within body mass index categories Fertility and Sterility&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.fertnstert.2010.12.035 | How to Cite or Link Using DOI&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara Luke Sc.D., M.P.H.a, b, Corresponding Author Contact Information, E-mail The Corresponding Author, Morton B. Brown Ph.D.c, Judy E. Stern Ph.D.d, Stacey A. Missmer Sc.D.e, f, g, Victor Y. Fujimoto M.D.h and Richard Leach M.D.a&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology, and Reproductive Biology, Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pregnant women 2X more dental problems when vitamin D less than 30ng</title><link>/posts/pregnant-women-2x-more-dental-problems-when-vitamin-d-less-than-30ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnant-women-2x-more-dental-problems-when-vitamin-d-less-than-30ng.html</guid><description>&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code class="language-!Vitamin" data-lang="!Vitamin">
J Periodontol. 2011 Feb;82(2):195-200. Epub 2010 Sep 1.

Boggess KA, Espinola JA, Moss K, Beck J, Offenbacher S, Camargo CA Jr.

Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC.

Background: Maternal periodontal disease is found in ?40% of pregnant women and is associated with adverse pregnancy outcomes. 

Vitamin D deficiency may play a role in periodontal disease and tooth loss, and insufficient vitamin D status is common among pregnant women. 

The objective of this study is to examine the relationship between maternal vitamin D status and periodontal disease. 

Methods: A case-control study was conducted. Cases were defined as pregnant women with clinical moderate to severe periodontal disease; controls were pregnant women who were periodontally healthy. Maternal data were chart abstracted and serum was collected between 14 and 26 weeks of gestation. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;[OH]&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;D) levels were measured using liquid chromatography?tandem mass spectrometry. Median serum 25(OH)D levels and prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency (defined as &amp;lt;75 nmol/l) were compared between cases and controls. The odds ratio and 95% confidence interval for moderate to severe periodontal disease among women with vitamin D insufficiency was calculated using multivariable logistic regression, adjusting for maternal race, season of blood draw, and other potential confounders. 

Results: A total of 117 cases were compared to 118 controls. 

Cases had lower median 25(OH)D levels than controls (59 versus 100 nmol/l; P &amp;lt;0.001) and were more likely to have vitamin D insufficiency (65% versus 29%; P &amp;lt;0.001). 

The adjusted odds ratio (95% confidence interval) for moderate to severe periodontal disease among women with vitamin D insufficiency was **2.1** (0.99 to 4.5). 

Conclusions: Vitamin D insufficiency (serum 25&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;[OH]&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;D &amp;lt;75 nmol/l) is associated with maternal periodontal disease during pregnancy. Vitamin D

---

#### See also VitaminDWiki

* &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;/posts/pregnant-women-low-on-vitamin-d-had-2x-more-periodontal-disease&amp;#34; style=&amp;#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;This link has an unknown page_id: 932&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Pregnant women low on vitamin D had 2X more periodontal disease&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; with 2000 IU in Hollis slides #27, #29
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Only 19 percent of Turkish mothers had normal levels of vitamin D – 2009</title><link>/posts/only-19-percent-of-turkish-mothers-had-normal-levels-of-vitamin-d-2009.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/only-19-percent-of-turkish-mothers-had-normal-levels-of-vitamin-d-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-turkish-mothers-and-their-neonates-and-in-women-of-reproductive-age">Vitamin D Deficiency in Turkish Mothers and Their Neonates and in Women of Reproductive Age&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Clin Res Pediatr Endocrinol. 2009 December; 1(6): 266–269.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2009 November 3. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4274/jcrpe.v1i6.266.">doi: 10.4274/jcrpe.v1i6.266.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ayça Törel Ergür,corresponding author1 Merih Berbero?lu,1 Begüm Atasay,2 Zeynep ??klar,1 Pelin Bilir,1 Saadet Arsan,2 Feride Söylemez,3 and Gönül Öcal1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Ankara University, School of Medicine, Departments of Pediatric Endocrinology, Ankara, Turkey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Ankara University, School of Medicine, Departments of Neonatology, Ankara, Turkey&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less muscle and insulin resistance for children of vitamin D deficient mothers</title><link>/posts/less-muscle-and-insulin-resistance-for-children-of-vitamin-d-deficient-mothers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-muscle-and-insulin-resistance-for-children-of-vitamin-d-deficient-mothers.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-during-pregnancy-and-body-composition-and-cardiovascular-risk-markers-in-indian-children-the-mysore-parthenon-study">Maternal vitamin D status during pregnancy and body composition and cardiovascular risk markers in Indian children: the Mysore Parthenon Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>AM J CLIN NUTR () (2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ghattu V Krishnaveni, Sargoor R Veena, Nicola R Winder, Jacqueline C Hill, Kate Noonan, Barbara J Boucher, Samuel C Karat and Caroline Hd Fall&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiology Research Unit, CSI Holdsworth Memorial Hospital, Mysore, India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Metabolic consequences of vitamin D deficiency have become a recent research focus. Maternal vitamin D status is thought to influence musculoskeletal health in children, but its relation with offspring metabolic risk is not known.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Very low vitamin D for first pregnancies and those with dark skin</title><link>/posts/very-low-vitamin-d-for-first-pregnancies-and-those-with-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/very-low-vitamin-d-for-first-pregnancies-and-those-with-dark-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-insufficiency-is-common-during-pregnancy">Vitamin D Deficiency and Insufficiency is Common during Pregnancy.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Perinatol. 2011 Jan;28(1):7-12. Epub 2010 Jul 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johnson DD, Wagner CL, Hulsey TC, McNeil RB, Ebeling M, Hollis BW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Maternal Fetal Medicine, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>– – – – – – – – – –&lt;/p>
&lt;p>^~~#F00:Average ng/ml during pregnancy: Blacks 15, Hispanic 24, Caucasian 29&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Percentage with less than 20ng/ml: Blacks 97%, Hispanic 81%, Caucasian 67%~~^&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Evaluating the vitamin D evidence - Heaney</title><link>/posts/evaluating-the-vitamin-d-evidence-heaney.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/evaluating-the-vitamin-d-evidence-heaney.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-few-images-from-a-presentation-given-in-london">A few images from a Presentation given in London&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="spantiki-download_filephpfileid1628span-to-see-entire-pdf-file">&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1628]&lt;/span> to see entire PDF file&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;367,368,369,370,371,372,373,374,375&amp;rdquo; max=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-index.php">Home page&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=86&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">All items Strength of Evidence for D&lt;/a> 7 items as of Sept 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Profound vitamin D deficiency during pregnancy</title><link>/posts/profound-vitamin-d-deficiency-during-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/profound-vitamin-d-deficiency-during-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="profound-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-a-diverse-group-of-women-during-pregnancy-living-in-a-sun-rich-environment-at-latitude-32n">Profound Vitamin D Deficiency in a Diverse Group of Women during Pregnancy Living in a Sun-Rich Environment at Latitude 32°N&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>International Journal of Endocrinology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 2010 (2010), Article ID 917428, 10 pages&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doi:10.1155/2010/917428&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Research Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stuart A. Hamilton,1 Rebecca McNeil,2 &lt;strong>Bruce W. Hollis&lt;/strong> ,3 Deborah J. Davis,1 Joyce Winkler,1 Carolina Cook,1 Gloria Warner,1 Betty Bivens,3 Patrick McShane,1 and &lt;strong>Carol L. Wagner&lt;/strong> 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1The Eau Claire Study Group, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Eau Claire Cooperative Health Centers, Columbia, SC 29204, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less child bone if mother lacked vitamin D</title><link>/posts/less-child-bone-if-mother-lacked-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-child-bone-if-mother-lacked-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-affects-bone-growth-in-early-childhood-a-prospective-cohort-study">Maternal vitamin D status affects bone growth in early childhood-a prospective cohort study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2010 Dec 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Viljakainen HT, Korhonen T, Hytinantti T, Laitinen EK, Andersson S, Mäkitie O, Lamberg-Allardt C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hospital for Children and Adolescents, Helsinki University Central Hospital, Tukholmankatu 2C, PO Box 705, 00029, Helsinki, Finland, &lt;a href="mailto:heli.viljakainen@helsinki.fi">heli.viljakainen@helsinki.fi&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/fetal-bones-helped-a-bit-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Fetal bones helped a bit by 1,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT Feb 2019">Fetal bones helped a bit by 1,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT Feb 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In this prospective study, 87 children were followed up from birth to 14 months with data on maternal vitamin D status during the pregnancy. &lt;strong>Postnatal vitamin D supplementation improved vitamin D status but only partly eliminated the differences in bone variables induced by maternal vitamin D status during the fetal period.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D researcher Dr Bruce Hollis - Interview etc</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-researcher-dr-bruce-hollis-interview-etc.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-researcher-dr-bruce-hollis-interview-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="dr-hollis-is-referenced-many-times-in-a-hrefpostsvitamindwiki-overview-of-vitamin-d-before-during-and-after-pregnancy-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-816vitamindwiki-overview-of-vitamin-d-before-during-and-after-pregnancya">Dr. Hollis is referenced many times in &lt;a href="/posts/vitamindwiki-overview-of-vitamin-d-before-during-and-after-pregnancy" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 816">VitaminDWiki Overview of Vitamin D Before, During, and After Pregnancy&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="attended-a-vitamin-d-conference-in-new-zealand-nov-2010">Attended a vitamin D conference in New Zealand Nov 2010&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1584]&lt;/span> Audio only - 2 MBytes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="click-on-arrow-below-to-listen-to-the-interview">Click on arrow below to listen to the interview&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>{MEDIAPLAYER(mp3=&amp;ldquo;tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1584&amp;rdquo;)/}&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.3news.co.nz/Full-interview-with-Bruce-Hollis-on-vitamin-D/tabid/372/articleID/186936/Default.aspx">CLICK HERE to see the video&lt;/a> Dr. Hollis talking with trees moving the the background - 19 MBytes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="description-of-the-conference">Description of the conference&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>^Massey University&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Healthy Start vitamin D supplementation in UK is a farce</title><link>/posts/healthy-start-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-uk-is-a-farce.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/healthy-start-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-uk-is-a-farce.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Birth control pills could contain Folic acid and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/birth-control-pills-could-contain-folic-acid-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/birth-control-pills-could-contain-folic-acid-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="do-we-need-vitamin-supplemented-birth-control-pillshttphealthlandtimecom20100928do-we-need-vitamin-supplemented-birth-control-pills-in-times">&lt;a href="http://healthland.time.com/2010/09/28/do-we-need-vitamin-supplemented-birth-control-pills/">Do We Need Vitamin-Supplemented Birth Control Pills?&lt;/a> in Times&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="birth-control-pills-real-success-rate-is-91---that-is---9-become-pregnant-in-the-first-year-of-use">Birth control pills real success rate is 91% - that is - 9% become pregnant in the first year of use.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="discusses-adding-folic-acid-to-birth-control-pills-ad-folic-acid-is-needed-during-pregnancy">Discusses adding Folic acid to birth control pills ad Folic acid is needed during pregnancy&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="vitamindwiki-proposes-adding-vitamin-d-to-birth-control-pills-too-a-hrefpostsclick-here-for-vitamin-d-before-during-and-after-pregnancy-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-816click-here-for-vitamin-d-before-during-and-after-pregnancya">VitaminDWiki proposes adding vitamin D to birth control pills too &lt;a href="/posts/click-here-for-vitamin-d-before-during-and-after-pregnancy" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 816">CLICK HERE for Vitamin D Before, during and after pregnancy&lt;/a>&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Women with low vitamin D 4X more likely to have preeclampsia in pregnancy</title><link>/posts/women-with-low-vitamin-d-4x-more-likely-to-have-preeclampsia-in-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-with-low-vitamin-d-4x-more-likely-to-have-preeclampsia-in-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-nested-case-control-study-of-midgestation-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-risk-of-severe-preeclampsia">A Nested Case-Control Study of Midgestation Vitamin D Deficiency and Risk of Severe Preeclampsia&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism Vol. 95, No. 11 5105-5109, Copyright © 2010 by The Endocrine Society&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arthur M. Baker &lt;a href="mailto:abaker2@med.unc.edu">abaker2@med.unc.edu&lt;/a>, Sina Haeri, Carlos A. Camargo, Jr., Janice A. Espinola and Alison M. Stuebe&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine (A.M.B., S.H., A.M.S.), Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina 27599; and Department of Emergency Medicine (C.A.C., J.A.E.), and Center for D-Receptor Activation Research (C.A.C.), Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts 02114&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>