<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About D - Introduction on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/about-d---introduction.html</link><description>Recent content in About D - Introduction on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/about-d---introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Science News Cover article on Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/science-news-cover-article-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/science-news-cover-article-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-power-of-d-sunshine-vitamins-potential-health-benefits-stir-up-split-scientists-httpwwwsciencenewsorgviewaccessid332042titlevitamind_blood_level_tablejpg">&lt;a href="http://www.sciencenews.org/view/access/id/332042/title/vitamind_blood_level_table.jpg">The power of D: Sunshine vitamin’s potential health benefits stir up, split scientists &lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>By Nathan Seppa&lt;/p>
&lt;p>July 16th, 2011; Vol.180 #2 (p. 22)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;614&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A host of studies suggest vitamin D has value that goes beyond bone health, but scientists remain divided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A nutritional supplement that is free of charge, offers a wide range of health benefits and poses little risk sounds like fodder for a late-night TV commercial. But proponents of vitamin D are increasingly convinced that the sunshine vitamin delivers the goods, no strings attached.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Michael Holick – reduce health care costs 25 percent – interview</title><link>/posts/michael-holick-reduce-health-care-costs-25-percent-interview.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/michael-holick-reduce-health-care-costs-25-percent-interview.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="by-philip-smith-for-the-life-extension-foundationhttpwwwleforgmagazinemag2010sep2010_michael-holick-the-pioneer-of-vitamin-d-research_01htm">&lt;a href="http://www.lef.org/magazine/mag2010/sep2010_Michael-Holick-The-Pioneer-of-Vitamin-D-Research_01.htm">By Philip Smith for the Life Extension Foundation&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The explosive scientific interest in the broad-spectrum benefits of vitamin D are largely due to the lifelong research of one man, Dr. Michael F. Holick. As the world’s leading vitamin D researcher, Dr. Holick has pioneered and inspired significant studies that have investigated how receptors located throughout the body can employ vitamin D to reduce the risk of cancer, heart disease, diabetes, and depression. In this exclusive interview with Life Extension Magazine®, Dr. Holick discusses the impact of his work and his future projects.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>