<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shut-In on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/shut-in.html</link><description>Recent content in Shut-In on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/shut-in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prison doctor on lack of vitamin D in solitary confinement</title><link>/posts/prison-doctor-on-lack-of-vitamin-d-in-solitary-confinement.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prison-doctor-on-lack-of-vitamin-d-in-solitary-confinement.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pressure Ulcers (bed sores) 1.87 more likely if vitamin D less than 25 ng – 2011</title><link>/posts/pressure-ulcers-bed-sores-187-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-less-than-25-ng-2011.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pressure-ulcers-bed-sores-187-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-less-than-25-ng-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-between-vitamin-d-and-pressure-ulcers-in-older-ambulatory-adults-results-of-a-matched-casecontrol-study">Association between vitamin D and pressure ulcers in older ambulatory adults: results of a matched case–control study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Interv Aging. 2011; 6: 213–219. Published online 2011 August 2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2147/CIA.S23109">doi: 10.2147/CIA.S23109&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usha R Kalava,1 Stephen S Cha,2 and Paul Y Takahashi1,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Pressure ulcers are common among older adults, but knowledge about nutritional risk factors is still developing. Vitamin D deficiency is common in the elderly population and is required for normal skin proliferation. The role of vitamin D in pressure ulceration and wound healing is not known. The purpose of this case–control study was to determine the association between vitamin D levels and pressure ulceration in an older community-dwelling cohort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D supplementation can cost 50 dollars a day (live longer)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-can-cost-50-dollars-a-day-live-longer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-can-cost-50-dollars-a-day-live-longer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dementia risk increases 60 percent if have low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dementia-risk-increases-60-percent-if-have-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dementia-risk-increases-60-percent-if-have-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="association-between-serum-25oh-vitamin-d-and-the-risk-of-cognitive-decline-in-older-women">Association between serum 25(OH) vitamin D and the risk of cognitive decline in older women.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2012 Oct;67(10):1092-8. Epub 2012 Mar 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Slinin Y, Paudel M, Taylor BC, Ishani A, Rossom R, Yaffe K, Blackwell T, Lui LY, Hochberg M, Ensrud KE; Study of Osteoporotic Fractures Research Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Chronic Disease Outcomes Research, VA Medical Center, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:slini001@umn.edu">slini001@umn.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Results of prospective studies examining the association between 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels and cognitive decline have been inconsistent. We tested the hypothesis that lower 25(OH)D levels are associated with a greater likelihood of cognitive impairment and risk of cognitive decline.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prisoners in psychiatric wards have very low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/prisoners-in-psychiatric-wards-have-very-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prisoners-in-psychiatric-wards-have-very-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="feasibility-of-screening-for-and-treating-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-forensic-psychiatric-inpatients">Feasibility of screening for and treating vitamin D deficiency in forensic psychiatric inpatients&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Forensic and Legal Medicine, Volume 19, Issue 8 , Pages 457-464, November 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jill Murie, MPH FRCGP MFFLM, GP (Forensic Physician and Primary Care Researcher), Claudia-Martina Messow, PhD (Consultant Statistician), Bridie Fitzpatrick, PhD, MSc (University Lecturer)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 8 June 2011; received in revised form 14 February 2012; accepted 8 April 2012.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neuroleptic and anti-epileptic medication, inadequate vitamin D intake and limited solar exposure increase the risk of vitamin D deficiency in high security psychiatric environments. Of the 33 inpatients (40% selected; 21% of hospital population) completing this cross-sectional study, 36% had insufficient and 58% deficient vitamin D. Five patients with vitamin D deficiency had secondary hyperparathyroidism, two of whom had osteopenia on dual-emission X-ray absorptiometry. At 1-year follow up, of the 31 patients eligible, 15 had accepted and continued supplements. Systematic screening is therefore necessary due to mental health and consent issues. Implications of supplementation and grounds access are discussed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children with limited mobility are at high risk of being vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/children-with-limited-mobility-are-at-high-risk-of-being-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-with-limited-mobility-are-at-high-risk-of-being-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-novel-pathway-to-reduce-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-a-high-risk-population">A novel pathway to reduce Vitamin D deficiency in a high risk population&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Arch Dis Child 2012;97:A64 doi:10.1136/archdischild-2012-301885.154&lt;/p>
&lt;p>British Society of Paediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Nutrition/Neonatal Nutrition Network&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LC Winckworth, E Day, J Bailey, F Katz&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Community Paediatrics, Camden MOSAIC CDC, London, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aims – Design a screening and treatment pathway for vitamin D deficiency in a targeted high risk population of children with limited mobility&lt;/p>
&lt;p>– Employ a continuous process of evaluating the steps and outcome measures resulting in ongoing service improvements&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Task force for senior fall prevention finally recommends 800 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/task-force-for-senior-fall-prevention-finally-recommends-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/task-force-for-senior-fall-prevention-finally-recommends-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="prevention-of-falls-in-community-dwelling-older-adults">Prevention of Falls in Community-Dwelling Older Adults:&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="us-preventive-services-task-force-recommendation-statement">U.S. Preventive Services Task Force Recommendation Statement&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Virginia A. Moyer, MD, MPH, on behalf of the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force, Rockville, Maryland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annals of Internal Medicine May 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Description: Update of the 1996 U.S. Preventive Services Task Force (USPSTF) recommendation statement on counseling to prevent household and recreational injuries, including falls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: The USPSTF reviewed new evidence on the effectiveness and harms of primary care–relevant interventions to prevent falls in community-dwelling older adults. The interventions were grouped into 5 main categories: multifactorial clinical assessment (with or without direct intervention), clinical management (with or without screening), clinical education or behavioral counseling, home hazard modification, and exercise or physical therapy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nursing home residents 2X more likely to die of some surgeries – perhaps lack vitamin D</title><link>/posts/nursing-home-residents-2x-more-likely-to-die-of-some-surgeries-perhaps-lack-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nursing-home-residents-2x-more-likely-to-die-of-some-surgeries-perhaps-lack-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="major-abdominal-surgery-in-nursing-home-residents-a-national-study">Major Abdominal Surgery in Nursing Home Residents: A National Study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Annals of Surgery: December 2011 - Volume 254 - Issue 6 - p 921–926&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/SLA.0b013e3182383a78">doi: 10.1097/SLA.0b013e3182383a78&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finlayson, Emily MD &lt;a href="mailto:emily.finlayson@ucsfmedctr.org">emily.finlayson@ucsfmedctr.org&lt;/a> &lt;em>,†; Wang, Li PhD‡; Landefeld, C. Seth MD§,¶; Dudley, R. Adams MD†,&lt;/em>*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To determine surgical risk in nursing home residents undergoing major abdominal surgery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Recent studies suggest that surgery can be performed safely in the very old. Surgical risk in nursing home residents is poorly understood.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1700 IU vitamin D (50000 monthly) helped antarctic explorers – RCT</title><link>/posts/1700-iu-vitamin-d-50000-monthly-helped-antarctic-explorers-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1700-iu-vitamin-d-50000-monthly-helped-antarctic-explorers-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="skeletal-and-hormonal-responses-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-sunlight-deprivation-in-antarctic-expeditioners">Skeletal and hormonal responses to vitamin D supplementation during sunlight deprivation in Antarctic expeditioners.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Jan 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Iuliano-Burns S, Ayton J, Hillam S, Jones G, King K, Macleod S, Seeman E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Austin Health, University of Melbourne, Parkville, Australia, &lt;a href="mailto:sandraib@unimelb.edu.au">sandraib@unimelb.edu.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight deprivation results in vitamin D deficiency but serum vitamin D levels can be maintained above 50nmol/L when supplemented with 50,000IU at least every alternate month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Antarctic expeditioners are exposed to prolonged sunlight deprivation resulting in vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lets go to the sunny beach, it is just down the hall</title><link>/posts/lets-go-to-the-sunny-beach-it-is-just-down-the-hall.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lets-go-to-the-sunny-beach-it-is-just-down-the-hall.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>\"Sunlight Officers\" in some Australian senior facilities</title><link>/posts/sunlight-officers-in-some-australian-senior-facilities.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunlight-officers-in-some-australian-senior-facilities.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="factors-influencing-adherence-with-therapeutic-sunlight-exposure-in-older-people-in-intermediate-care-facilities">Factors influencing adherence with therapeutic sunlight exposure in older people in intermediate care facilities.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2011 Sep 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Durvasula S, Sambrook PN, Cameron ID.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sydney Medical School, University of Sydney, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose of research: The purpose of this study was to investigate the factors influencing low adherence with therapeutic sunlight exposure in a randomized controlled trial conducted with older people living in intermediate care facilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Materials and methods: The study involved participants in the FREEDOM (Falls Risk Epidemiology: Effect of vitamin D on skeletal Outcomes and other Measures) study, a randomized controlled trial of therapeutic sun exposure to reduce falls in older people in intermediate care facilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>People with no UV for 6 months in the winter need at least 2000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/people-with-no-uv-for-6-months-in-the-winter-need-at-least-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-no-uv-for-6-months-in-the-winter-need-at-least-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-antarctic-winter-is-related-to-bmi">Response to vitamin D supplementation during Antarctic winter is related to BMI,&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>and supplementation can mitigate Epstein-Barr Virus Reactivation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2011 Apr 1;141(4):692-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zwart SR, Mehta SK, Ploutz-Snyder R, Bourbeau Y, Locke JP, Pierson DL, Smith SM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Universities Space Research Association, Houston, TX 77058, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maintaining vitamin D status without sunlight exposure is difficult without supplementation. This study was designed to better understand interrelationships between periodic vitamin D supplementation and immune function in Antarctic workers. The effect of 2 oral dosing regimens of vitamin D supplementation on vitamin D status and markers of immune function was evaluated in people in Antarctica with no UV light exposure for 6 mo.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>