<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shut-In on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/shut-in/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shut-In on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/shut-in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indoor athletes have 4.5 ng less Vitamin D (Asia in this case) – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/indoor-athletes-have-45-ng-less-vitamin-d-asia-in-this-case-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/indoor-athletes-have-45-ng-less-vitamin-d-asia-in-this-case-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;difference-in-levels-of-vitamin-d-between-indoor-and-outdoor-athletes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;Difference in Levels of Vitamin D between Indoor and Outdoor Athletes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Int J Mol Sci . 2023 Apr 20;24(8):7584. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms24087584&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/ijms24087584&lt;/a&gt; DOI: 10.3390/ijms24087584&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maria Bârsan 1, Vlad-Florin Chelaru 2, Armand-Gabriel Râjnoveanu 1, Ștefan Lucian Popa 3, Andreea-Iulia Socaciu 1, Andrei-Vlad Bădulescu 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D, its importance in different processes taking place in the human body, the effects of abnormal levels of this hormone, either too low or too high, and the need for supplementation have been extensively researched thus far. Variances in exposure to sunlight can cause vitamin D levels to fluctuate. Indoor activity can be a factor for these fluctuations and can lead to a decrease in vitamin D levels. We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis aiming to identify whether indoor compared to outdoor training has a significant influence on vitamin D levels; we also performed subgroup analyses and multivariate meta-regression. The type of training has an impact on vitamin D levels that is influenced by multiple cofounders. In a subgroup analysis not considering cofounders, the mean serum vitamin D was 3.73 ng/mL higher in outdoor athletes, a difference which barely fails to achieve significance (p = 0.052, a total sample size of 5150).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Submariners need Vitamin D (no surprise) – Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/submariners-need-vitamin-d-no-surprise-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/submariners-need-vitamin-d-no-surprise-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-status-in-active-duty-navy-military-personnel-a-systematic-review&#34;&gt;Vitamin D status in active duty Navy military personnel: a systematic review&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Occup Environ Med . 2023 Apr 3;oemed-2022-108710. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1136/oemed-2022-108710&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1136/oemed-2022-108710&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moisés Henriques 1 2, Diogo Rodrigues 3, Susana Viegas 2, Florentino Serranheira 2, Ema Sacadura-Leite 2 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objectives: Active duty Navy military personnel are prone to vitamin D deficiency due to an occupational environment detrimental to sunlight exposure. The main objective of this systematic review is to provide a worldwide overview of vitamin D status in this population.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
