<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shut-In on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/shut-in.html</link><description>Recent content in Shut-In on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/shut-in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>\"Sunlight Officers\" in some Australian senior facilities</title><link>/posts/sunlight-officers-in-some-australian-senior-facilities.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunlight-officers-in-some-australian-senior-facilities.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="factors-influencing-adherence-with-therapeutic-sunlight-exposure-in-older-people-in-intermediate-care-facilities">Factors influencing adherence with therapeutic sunlight exposure in older people in intermediate care facilities.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2011 Sep 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Durvasula S, Sambrook PN, Cameron ID.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sydney Medical School, University of Sydney, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose of research: The purpose of this study was to investigate the factors influencing low adherence with therapeutic sunlight exposure in a randomized controlled trial conducted with older people living in intermediate care facilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Materials and methods: The study involved participants in the FREEDOM (Falls Risk Epidemiology: Effect of vitamin D on skeletal Outcomes and other Measures) study, a randomized controlled trial of therapeutic sun exposure to reduce falls in older people in intermediate care facilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>People with no UV for 6 months in the winter need at least 2000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/people-with-no-uv-for-6-months-in-the-winter-need-at-least-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-no-uv-for-6-months-in-the-winter-need-at-least-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-antarctic-winter-is-related-to-bmi">Response to vitamin D supplementation during Antarctic winter is related to BMI,&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>and supplementation can mitigate Epstein-Barr Virus Reactivation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2011 Apr 1;141(4):692-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zwart SR, Mehta SK, Ploutz-Snyder R, Bourbeau Y, Locke JP, Pierson DL, Smith SM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Universities Space Research Association, Houston, TX 77058, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maintaining vitamin D status without sunlight exposure is difficult without supplementation. This study was designed to better understand interrelationships between periodic vitamin D supplementation and immune function in Antarctic workers. The effect of 2 oral dosing regimens of vitamin D supplementation on vitamin D status and markers of immune function was evaluated in people in Antarctica with no UV light exposure for 6 mo.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>