<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Top News on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/top-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Top News on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/top-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fat-soluble Vitamins go thru the slow lymph system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fat-soluble-vitamins-go-thru-the-slow-lymph-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fat-soluble-vitamins-go-thru-the-slow-lymph-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;some-vitamin-d-in-gut-goes-thru-the-lymph-system-radioactive-tracing---may-1984&#34;&gt;Some Vitamin D in gut goes thru the lymph system (radioactive tracing) - May 1984&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lymphatic absorption and transport of retinol and vitamin D-3 from rat intestine. Evidence for different pathways&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biochim Biophys Acta. 1984 May 16;772(2):109-16. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/0005-2736&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/0005-2736&lt;/a&gt;(84)90033-6.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;R Blomhoff, P Helgerud, S Dueland, T Berg, J I Pedersen, K R Norum, C A Drevon&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lymphatic absorption and transport of retinol and vitamin D-3 from rat intestine has been studied. When rats were cannulated in the intestinal lymph duct and given an intraduodenal bolus of &lt;span&gt;[3H]&lt;/span&gt;retinol and 14C-labelled vitamin D-3, 14C-labeled vitamin D-3 appeared later in the intestinal lymph than &lt;span&gt;[3H]&lt;/span&gt;retinol and the rate of absorption of vitamin D-3 was still maximal at a time when that of retinol had declined. Both vitamins were absorbed via the lymphatic route in association with  &lt;strong&gt;chylomicrons&lt;/strong&gt; . Almost all the retinol was esterified, while vitamin D-3 appeared in the chylomicrons as free vitamin D-3. In vitro incubations and in vivo studies using hepatectomized and normal rats showed that the retinyl ester was a relatively nonexchangeable component of the chylomicrons and their remnants. Hence, all the vitamin A followed the remnants in their clearance from plasma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D loading dose of 30,000 IU twice a week is safe and effective – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-loading-dose-of-30000-iu-twice-a-week-is-safe-and-effective-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-loading-dose-of-30000-iu-twice-a-week-is-safe-and-effective-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;controlled-randomized-open-label-clinical-study-comparing-the-safety-and-efficacy-of-loading-schedules-in-vitamin-d-deficient-patients&#34;&gt;Controlled randomized open label clinical study comparing the safety and efficacy of loading schedules in vitamin D deficient patients&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The J/ of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology Vol 231, July 2023,  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2023.106330&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2023.106330&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Istvan Takacs a, Bence Bakos a, Zsuzsanna Nemeth a, Bela E. Toth b, Balazs Szili a, Peter Lakatos a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rapidly restoring vitamin D levels to normal might be desirable in certain clinical situations. Larger doses of supplementation, have been shown to increase bone loss and the risk of falls. The optimal way to perform vitamin D loading safely and effectively is still not well elucidated. Our study was aimed to assess the safety and efficacy of two oral vitamin D loading protocols. Sixty-nine subjects with vitamin D deficiency (25OH-vitamin D (25(OH)D) &amp;lt; 20 ng/ml) were included. Thirty-five participants received 30 000 IU of vitamin D3 per week for 10 weeks (group Slower Loading Dose (SLD)) and thirty-four received 30 000 IU twice weekly for 5 weeks (group Moderate Loading Dose (MLD)) resulting in a loading dose of 300 000 IU for all subjects. Following this initial loading phase, both groups received 30 000 IU biweekly for 4 weeks to test whether the recommended daily vitamin D supplementation in range of 2000 IU dose-equivalent could maintain the achieved levels. Seventy-nine percent of those subjects treated in group SLD and everyone in group MLD achieved a 25(OH)D level of 30 ng/ml, which is the lower limit of the recommended normal range in Hungary. The mean increase in 25(OH)D was significantly higher in group MLD than in group SLD (38.6 ± 1.80 ng/ml vs 46,6 ± 1.80 ng/ml). No significant decrease was observed with the administration of the maintenance dose. There were no clinically significant changes in serum or urine calcium, and bone biomarkers in either group. Both protocols were found to be safe and effective, but the five-week dosing caused a significantly greater increase in 25(OH)D. A maintenance dose applied for four weeks after the loading protocol did not raise 25(OH)D levels further but maintained the achieved increase. The administration of 30 000 IU of vitamin D3 twice weekly for five weeks is a rapid, effective and safe way to treat vitamin D deficiency in vitamin D deficient patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Olive oil problem with Vitamin D (again)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/olive-oil-problem-with-vitamin-d-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/olive-oil-problem-with-vitamin-d-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-using-different-lipid-delivery-systems-in-middle-aged-and-older-adults-a-randomised-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D response to vitamin D supplementation using different lipid delivery systems in middle-aged and older adults: a randomised controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Br J Nutr . 2023 Nov 14;130(9):1548-1557. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0007114523000636&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1017/S0007114523000636&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aislinn F McCourt 1, Steven L Mulrooney 1, Graham J O&amp;rsquo;Neill 2, E Dolores O&amp;rsquo;Riordan 1, Aifric M O&amp;rsquo;Sullivan 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;olive-not-as-good-as-coconut-if-already-have-sufficient-vitamin-d&#34;&gt;Olive not as good as coconut if already have sufficient Vitamin D&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Food fortification improves vitamin D intakes but is not yet mandated in many countries. Combining vitamin D with different dietary lipids altered vitamin D absorption in in vitro and postprandial studies. This randomised, placebo-controlled trial examined the effect of the lipid composition of a vitamin D-fortified dairy drink on change in 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentrations. Sixty-three healthy adults aged 50+ years were randomised to one of the following for 4 weeks: vitamin D-fortified olive oil dairy drink, vitamin D-fortified coconut oil dairy drink, vitamin D supplement or placebo control dairy drink. All vitamin D groups received 20 µg of vitamin D3 daily. Serum was collected at baseline and post-intervention to measure 25(OH)D concentrations and biomarkers of metabolic health. Repeated-measures general linear model ANCOVA (RM GLM ANCOVA) compared changes over time. There was a significant time × treatment interaction effect on 25(OH)D concentrations for those classified as vitamin D-insufficient (P &amp;lt; 0·001) and -sufficient at baseline (P = 0·004). 25(OH)D concentrations increased significantly for all insufficient participants receiving vitamin D3 in any form. However, for vitamin D-sufficient participants at baseline, 25(OH)D concentrations only increased significantly with the coconut oil dairy drink and supplement. There was no effect of vitamin D on biomarkers of metabolic health. Vitamin D fortification of lipid-containing foods may be used in lieu of supplementation when supplement adherence is low or for individuals with dysphagia. These results are important given the recent recommendation to increase vitamin D intakes to 15-20 µg for older adults in Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D which dissolves in mouth for those having poor response due to poor guts, HSCT etc.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-which-dissolves-in-mouth-for-those-having-poor-response-due-to-poor-guts-hsct-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-which-dissolves-in-mouth-for-those-having-poor-response-due-to-poor-guts-hsct-etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;optimized-vitamin-d-repletion-in-refractory-patients-undergoing-stem-cell-transplant-with-oral-thin-film-cholecalciferol&#34;&gt;Optimized Vitamin D Repletion in Refractory Patients Undergoing Stem Cell Transplant with Oral Thin Film Cholecalciferol&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blood Adv. 2023 Jun 7;bloodadvances.2023009855. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1182/bloodadvances.2023009855&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1182/bloodadvances.2023009855&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Allison L Bartlett &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Allison.bartlett@cchmc.org&#34;&gt;Allison.bartlett@cchmc.org&lt;/a&gt; 1, Grace Zhang 2, Gregory Wallace 3, Stacie McLean 3, Kasiani C Myers 1, Ashley Teusink-Cross 3, Cynthia Taggart 4, Bhaumik Patel 5, Robert Davidson 5, Stella M Davies 1, Sonata Jodele 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1Division of Bone Marrow Transplantation and Immune Deficiency, Cincinnati Children’s Hospital Medical Center, Cincinnati, OH&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large dose Vitamin D before surgery was found to help by 35 studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/large-dose-vitamin-d-before-surgery-was-found-to-help-by-35-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/large-dose-vitamin-d-before-surgery-was-found-to-help-by-35-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;This small study would probably have gotten statistically significant results if they have given the 300,000 IU of Vitamin D 3 days BEFORE the surgery. It takes several days for oral vitamin D to get to the cells (injection is slower, nanoemulsion is faster)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;optimal-vitamin-d-status-at-admission-appears-to-improve-survival-after-craniotomy-in-patients-with-brain-malignancies&#34;&gt;Optimal vitamin D status at admission appears to improve survival after craniotomy in patients with brain malignancies&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clinical Nutrition ESPEN Vol 55, June 2023, Pages 428-433 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnesp.2023.04.009&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnesp.2023.04.009&lt;/a&gt; $25 paywall&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Kidney Disease needs Vitamin D: how much, what kind - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-needs-vitamin-d-how-much-what-kind-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-needs-vitamin-d-how-much-what-kind-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-decreases-vitamin-d-in-4-ways-nov-2017chronic-kidney-dise-level-in-4-ways&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Chronic Kidney Disease decreases Vitamin D in 4 ways – Nov 2017|Chronic Kidney Disease decreases Vitamin D level in 4 ways&#34;&gt;Chronic Kidney Disease decreases Vitamin D in 4 ways – Nov 2017|Chronic Kidney Disease decreases Vitamin D level in 4 ways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/4x-more-chronic-kidney-disease-patients-are-now-using-vitamin-d&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: 4X more Chronic Kidney disease patients are now using vitamin D – March 2014&#34;&gt;4X more Chronic Kidney disease patients are now using vitamin D – March 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 billion people have less than 75 nmol (30 ng) of Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/6-billion-people-have-less-than-75-nmol-30-ng-of-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/6-billion-people-have-less-than-75-nmol-30-ng-of-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;global-and-regional-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-population-based-studies-from-2000-to-2022-a-pooled-analysis-of-79-million-participants&#34;&gt;Global and regional prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in population-based studies from 2000 to 2022: A pooled analysis of 7.9 million participants&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front. Nutr., 17 March 2023  Sec. Nutritional Epidemiology Volume 10 - 2023 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2023.1070808&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2023.1070808&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aiyong Cui1†, Tiansong Zhang2†, Peilong Xiao3†, Zhiqiang Fan4, Hu Wang4* and Yan Zhuang4*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Department of Orthopaedics, Honghui Hospital, Xi&amp;rsquo;an Jiaotong University, Xi&amp;rsquo;an, China&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Jing&amp;rsquo;an District Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shanghai, China&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
