<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Noontime Sun and D on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/noontime-sun-and-d.html</link><description>Recent content in Noontime Sun and D on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/noontime-sun-and-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Being in shade or wearing long sleeves reduces vitamin D in blood</title><link>/posts/being-in-shade-or-wearing-long-sleeves-reduces-vitamin-d-in-blood.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/being-in-shade-or-wearing-long-sleeves-reduces-vitamin-d-in-blood.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sun-protective-behaviors-and-vitamin-d-levels-in-the-us-population-nhanes-2003-2006">Sun protective behaviors and vitamin D levels in the US population: NHANES 2003-2006.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2011 Nov 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Linos E, Keiser E, Kanzler M, Sainani KL, Lee W, Vittinghoff E, Chren MM, Tang JY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Stanford University School of Medicine, Pavilion B 2nd Floor, 450 Broadway St, Redwood City, CA, 94063, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:linos@stanford.edu">linos@stanford.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sun protection is recommended for skin cancer prevention, yet little is known about the role of sun protection on vitamin D levels. Our aim was to investigate the relationship between different types of sun protective behaviors and serum 25(OH)D levels in the general US population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use of tanning beds would reduce associated deaths by 10X</title><link>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-sun-sunbeds-and-health">Vitamin D, sun, sunbeds and health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Oct 24:1-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moan J, Baturaite Z, Juzeniene A, Porojnicu AC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, The Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Ullernchausseen 70, Montebello N-0310 Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To review the health effects of solar radiation, sunbeds and vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DESIGN: The literature was searched in the electronic database MEDLINE to indentify published data between 1981 and 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV every two weeks maintains summer vitamin D level – RCT</title><link>/posts/uv-every-two-weeks-maintains-summer-vitamin-d-level-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-every-two-weeks-maintains-summer-vitamin-d-level-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Modelling Vitamin D from the sun in Poland – 2011</title><link>/posts/modelling-vitamin-d-from-the-sun-in-poland-2011.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/modelling-vitamin-d-from-the-sun-in-poland-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-mathematical-model-for-seasonal-variability-of-vitamin-d-due-to-solar-radiation">A mathematical model for seasonal variability of vitamin D due to solar radiation&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Photochemistry and Photobiology B: Biology xxx (2011) xxx-xxx&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J.W. Krzyscin , J. Jaroslawski, P.S. Sobolewski&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Geophysics, Polish Academy of Sciences, 64 Ksiecia Janusza St., 01-452 Warsaw, Poland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accepted 25 July 2011, Available online xxxx&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It is widely recognized that vitamin D deficiency has detrimental health consequences. The ultraviolet (UV) B radiation increases the serum vitamin D level, expressed by 25-hydroxyvitamin-D3 &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>. An analytical model is presented to calculate the serum 25(OH)D changes throughout a year, caused by the solar exposure variability due to geophysical and habitual factors. The model is tuned by taking into account recent experimental results of serum 25(OH)D changes, after a series of artificial (by fluorescent tubes) UV exposures. The model uses the erythemal and vitamin D weighted irradiances, inferred from the Brewer spectrophotometer and the Kipp and Zonen broad-band meter measurements, carried out in Belsk (52°N, 21°E), Poland, in 2010. The modeled seasonal pattern of the serum 25(OH)D concentration in Polish indoor workers is only slightly different, than in subjects with typical outdoor activity habits, and in those with sun-seeking behavior. A deep minimum in the serum 25(OH)D concentration appears in late winter, regardless of outdoor activity habits. An extra sunbathing to boost the vitamin D level is not worth taking, because of a minor improvement of the vitamin D status, and because of a greater erythema risk. It would be much safer and more effective to maintain an adequate vitamin D level through diet supplements, even in summer, for non sun-seeking subjects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Military in hot climates and vitamin D deficiency - 2010</title><link>/posts/military-in-hot-climates-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2010.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/military-in-hot-climates-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2010.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Most young Americans not getting even 600 IU of vitamin D from the sun – FDA</title><link>/posts/most-young-americans-not-getting-even-600-iu-of-vitamin-d-from-the-sun-fda.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/most-young-americans-not-getting-even-600-iu-of-vitamin-d-from-the-sun-fda.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="solar-uv-doses-of-young-americans-and-vitamin-d3-production">Solar UV Doses of Young Americans and Vitamin D3 Production.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Environ Health Perspect. 2011 Aug 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="godar-de-pope-sj-grant-wb-holick-mf">Godar DE, Pope SJ, Grant WB, Holick MF.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Food and Drug Administration&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Sunlight contains UVB radiation (290-315 nm) that affects human health in both detrimental (skin cancers) and beneficial (vitamin D3) ways. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations of young Americans (?19 yr) show many have deficient (&amp;lt;50 nmol/L, 20 ng/ml) or insufficient (&amp;lt;75 nmol/L, 30 ng/ml) vitamin D levels, indicating they are not getting enough sun exposure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Excessive sun increases cancer all around the body</title><link>/posts/excessive-sun-increases-cancer-all-around-the-body.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/excessive-sun-increases-cancer-all-around-the-body.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Photosensitivity (sun allergy) and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/photosensitivity-sun-allergy-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/photosensitivity-sun-allergy-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact:&lt;/strong> Some people get reactions from having their skin exposed to the sun&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact:&lt;/strong> Only some of the causes of photosensitivity are known&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact:&lt;/strong> If you avoid the sun, you most likely vitamin D deficient, and should take supplements&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Possibility:&lt;/strong> Taking vitamin D might decrease your photosensitivity - anecdotal reports&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#photosensitive-people-have-low-levels-of-vitamin-d--aug-2014">Photosensitive people have low levels of vitamin D – Aug 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#suns-rays-may-leave-mysterious-markshttpwwwnytimescom20110726health26brodyhtml-july-2011-nyt">&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/07/26/health/26brody.html">Sun’s Rays May Leave Mysterious Marks&lt;/a> July 2011 NYT&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mayo-clinic--sun-allergyhttpwwwmayocliniccomhealthsun-allergyds01178">&lt;a href="http://www.mayoclinic.com/health/sun-allergy/DS01178">Mayo Clinic Sun Allergy&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#extreme-photosensitivity---epp-erythropoietic-protoporphyria---very-rare">Extreme photosensitivity - EPP (Erythropoietic Protoporphyria) - very rare&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="photosensitive-people-have-low-levels-of-vitamin-d--aug-2014">Photosensitive people have low levels of vitamin D – Aug 2014&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindcouncil.org/blog/new-study-highlights-importance-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-patients-sensitive-to-the-sun/">New study highlights importance of vitamin D supplementation in patients sensitive to the sun&lt;/a> Vitamin D Council&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hawaiians had 39 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hawaiians-had-39-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hawaiians-had-39-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-healthy-adults-in-hawaii">25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels in Healthy Adults in Hawaii&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Rev, Vol. 32 (03_MeetingAbstracts): P2-130&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2011 by The Endocrine Society&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jaya R Kothapally, MD1, Laura Armas, MD1, Mohammed Akhter, PhD1 and Julie A Chang, MD2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinology (JRK,LA,MA), Creighton University, Omaha, NE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pulmonary Disease and Critical Care Medicine (JAC), Pulmonary Associates, Aiea, HI&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been reported in 30% - 50% of adults and children in the lower contiguous United States. Latitude, altitude, season, skin pigmentation, and age are recognized factors that influence how much vitamin D can be made by solar exposure. The aim of this study was to quantify how much sun and skin exposure influence vitamin D status. We report here 25(OH)D levels in healthy adults residing in and around Honolulu, Hawaii (latitude 21.3ºN). The subjects (n=90, age 20-59 yr, females = 63 , males = 27) were a convenient sample of healthy, community-dwelling adults with limited non-solar sources of vitamin D. They reported their race as: 25 Asian/Pacific Islander, 1 Black, not Hispanic, 1 Hispanic, 56 White, not Hispanic, 4 reported more than one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Natural ways to prevent a sunburn – 2011, 2016</title><link>/posts/natural-ways-to-prevent-a-sunburn-2011-2016.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/natural-ways-to-prevent-a-sunburn-2011-2016.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#how-to-treat-sunburn-naturally---2016">How to Treat Sunburn Naturally - 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#8-natural-ways-to-prevent-a-sunburn-and-sunscreens-not-one-of-them--july-2011">8 Natural Ways to Prevent a Sunburn (And Sunscreen’s Not One of Them) July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-treat-sunburn-naturally---2016">How to Treat Sunburn Naturally - 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sunburn.aspx?utm_source=dnl&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=secon&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20160727Z1_NB&amp;amp;et_cid=DM112183&amp;amp;et_rid=1591593821">Mercola&lt;/a> excellent long article on all aspects of safe sun&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Home Remedy Recipes to Treat and Soothe Sunburns&lt;/strong> includes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aloe vera, Honey - Vinegar -Coriander oil - Green tea - Strawberries -Cucumbers Lettuce Calendula&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Opt for natural and safe alternatives to sunscreens&lt;/strong> :&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skinned teens use media much more</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-teens-use-media-much-more.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-teens-use-media-much-more.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="clipped-from-good-website-kids-of-color-consume-a-lot-more-media-than-white-kidshttpwwwgoodispostkids-of-color-consume-a-lot-more-media-than-white-kids-june-2011">Clipped from Good website: &lt;a href="http://www.good.is/post/kids-of-color-consume-a-lot-more-media-than-white-kids/">Kids of Color Consume a Lot More Media Than White Kids&lt;/a> June 2011&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A &lt;a href="http://www.northwestern.edu/newscenter/stories/2011/06/media-usa-youth-wartella.html">new study&lt;/a> at Northwestern University found a huge difference between the amount of media white and nonwhite kids consume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Minority children ages 8 to 18 consume an average of 13 hours of media content a day—about 4-and-a-half hours more than their white counterparts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In the last ten years, this number has doubled for black children and quadrupled for Hispanics&lt;/strong> .&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – you will get the most vitamin D from sun if you do not tan</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-you-will-get-the-most-vitamin-d-from-sun-if-you-do-not-tan.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-you-will-get-the-most-vitamin-d-from-sun-if-you-do-not-tan.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypothesis--can-concurrently">Hypothesis – can concurrently:&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Maximize the amount of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Minimize the risk of skin cancer / melanoma&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="by-the-admin-of-the-vitamindwiki-june-2011">By the admin of the VitaminDWiki, June 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="facts">Facts&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tanning is one way for the skin to reduce the damaging effect of excessive UVB&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sun burn is another way that the body uses to stop excessive UVB&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A sun burned person keeps out of the sun&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Note: people who have frequently sunburned are 6X more likely to get skin cancer&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunscreen regulations in US improved somewhat – UVB and UVA both important</title><link>/posts/sunscreen-regulations-in-us-improved-somewhat-uvb-and-uva-both-important.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunscreen-regulations-in-us-improved-somewhat-uvb-and-uva-both-important.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="help-is-on-the-way-if-youre-confused-by-sunscreen-claims">Help is on the way if you&amp;rsquo;re confused by sunscreen claims&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="update-may-2012httpwwwcbsnewscom8301-504763_162-57434390-10391704fda-delays-sunscreen-label-changes-by-6-months---fda-delayed-labeling-rules">&lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-504763_162-57434390-10391704/fda-delays-sunscreen-label-changes-by-6-months/">Update May 2012&lt;/a> - FDA delayed labeling rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>till Dec 2012 for the big companies&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>till Dec 2013 for the small companies&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The FDA took a major step backwards today and as a result, more consumers will likely get burned this summer,&amp;rdquo; said Sen. Jack Reed, D-R.I., who had long urged the FDA to tighten its regulation of sunscreens.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wear glasses when getting vitamin D from the sun</title><link>/posts/wear-glasses-when-getting-vitamin-d-from-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wear-glasses-when-getting-vitamin-d-from-the-sun.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Less UV means 2X more Breast Cancer</title><link>/posts/less-uv-means-2x-more-breast-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-uv-means-2x-more-breast-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="ultraviolet-sunlight-exposure-during-adolescence-and-adulthood-and-breast-cancer-risk-population-based-case-control-study-among-ontario-women">Ultraviolet Sunlight Exposure During Adolescence and Adulthood and Breast Cancer Risk: Population-based Case-Control Study Among Ontario Women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Epidemiol. 2011 Jun 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anderson LN, Cotterchio M, Kirsh VA, Knight JA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent studies suggest that vitamin D may be associated with reduced breast cancer risk, but most studies have evaluated only dietary vitamin D intake. The associations among ultraviolet radiation from sunlight, factors related to cutaneous vitamin D production, and breast cancer risk were evaluated in a population-based case-control study conducted in Ontario, Canada, between 2003 and 2004 (n = 3,101 cases and n = 3,471 controls).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Vitamin D in Malay women –less time in sun –sun screen -obesity</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-malay-women-less-time-in-sun-sun-screen-obesity.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-malay-women-less-time-in-sun-sun-screen-obesity.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-and-its-associated-factors-of-free-living-malay-adults-in-a-tropical-country-malaysia">Vitamin D status and its associated factors of free living Malay adults in a tropical country, Malaysia.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Photochem Photobiol B. 2011 May 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moy FM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Julius Centre University of Malaya, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, 50603 Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D status is influenced by sun exposure, geographic latitude, daily outdoor activities, body surface exposed to sunlight and dietary intakes. Malaysia, is sunny all year round. However, the vitamin D status of this population especially among the healthy and free living adults is not known. Therefore a study of vitamin D status and associated factors was initiated among an existing Malay cohort in Kuala Lumpur. A total of 380 subjects were sampled to have their vitamin D status assessed using 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D). A short questionnaire enquiring socio-demographic characteristics, exposure to sunlight and clothing style was administered. Their mean age was 48.5±5.2years and the mean 25(OH)D for males and females were 56.2±18.9nmol/L and 36.2±13.4nmol/L respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shade is better than sunscreen – does not eliminate the vitamin D</title><link>/posts/shade-is-better-than-sunscreen-does-not-eliminate-the-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shade-is-better-than-sunscreen-does-not-eliminate-the-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="hat-shade-long-sleeves-or-sunscreen-rethinking-us-sun-protection-messages-based-on-their-relative-effectiveness">Hat, shade, long sleeves, or sunscreen? Rethinking US sun protection messages based on their relative effectiveness&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cancer Causes and Control&lt;/strong> , DOI: 10.1007/s10552-011-9780-1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eleni Linos, Elizabeth Keiser, Teresa Fu, Graham Colditz, Suephy Chen and Jean Y. Tang&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sun protection messages in the United States emphasize sunscreen use, although its efficacy in skin cancer prevention remains controversial.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We used data from NHANES 2003–2006, restricted to adult whites (n = 3,052) to evaluate how Americans protect themselves from the sun. Participants completed questionnaires on the frequency with which they used sunscreen, wore a hat, long sleeves, or stayed in the shade, in addition to the number of sunburns in the past year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Most Australian GPs still believe the myth than 10 minutes of sun a day is enough</title><link>/posts/most-australian-gps-still-believe-the-myth-than-10-minutes-of-sun-a-day-is-enough.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/most-australian-gps-still-believe-the-myth-than-10-minutes-of-sun-a-day-is-enough.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prescribing-sunshine-a-cross-sectional-survey-of-500-australian-general-practitioners-practices-and-attitudes-about-vitamin-d">Prescribing sunshine: A cross-sectional survey of 500 Australian general practitioners&amp;rsquo; practices and attitudes about vitamin D&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Billie Bonevski1,*,†, Afaf Girgis1, Parker Magin2, Graeme Horton2, Irena Brozek3, Bruce Armstrong4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International Journal of Cancer DOI: 10.1002/ijc.26225&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study aimed to assess the attitudes, practices and knowledge of general practitioners (GPs) with regards to vitamin D. A cross-sectional survey of a random sample of GPs stratified by location of practice (rural/remote or metropolitan) and employment status (full-time or part-time) in New South Wales (NSW), Australia was conducted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No – 10 minutes per day of sun-UVB is NOT enough</title><link>/posts/no-10-minutes-per-day-of-sun-uvb-is-not-enough.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-10-minutes-per-day-of-sun-uvb-is-not-enough.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolorf00vitamindwiki-videospan-a-hrefpostsdoes-less-sun-mean-more-disease-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-does-less-sun-mean-more-diseasedoes-less-sun-mean-morediseasea">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">VitaminDWiki video&lt;/span> &lt;a href="/posts/does-less-sun-mean-more-disease" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Does Less Sun mean More Disease">Does Less Sun mean More Disease&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="time-in-the-sun-to-get-4000iu">Time in the sun to get 4000 IU&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostsvitamin-d-workshop-for-seniors-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1912vitamin-d-workshop-for-seniorsa-contains-the-following-summarychart">&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-workshop-for-seniors" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1912">Vitamin D Workshop for Seniors&lt;/a> contains the following summary chart&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Assumes&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>2X more minutes going to Seattle, which is at a higher latitude (47 instead of 32)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>3X more for seniors instead of youth&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Urban residents had 2X less vitamin D – 2008</title><link>/posts/urban-residents-had-2x-less-vitamin-d-2008.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/urban-residents-had-2x-less-vitamin-d-2008.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="urban-tropospheric-ozone-increases-the-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-among-belgian-postmenopausal-women-with-outdoor-activities-during-summer">Urban Tropospheric Ozone Increases the Prevalence of Vitamin D Deficiency among Belgian Postmenopausal Women with Outdoor Activities during Summer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Daniel-Henri Manicourt &lt;a href="mailto:manicourt@bchm.ucl.ac.be">manicourt@bchm.ucl.ac.be&lt;/a> and Jean-Pierre Devogelaer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Rheumatology (D.-H.M., J.-P.D.), St. Luc University Hospital, and Christian de Duve Institute of Cellular Pathology (D.H.M), Université Catholique de Louvain, 1200 Brussels, Belgium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Context: By absorbing sunlight UVB and thereby reducing cutaneous vitamin D photosynthesis, ozone, a common urban pollutant, could cause hypovitaminosis D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perhaps not burn from the sun if have enough vitamin D</title><link>/posts/perhaps-not-burn-from-the-sun-if-have-enough-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/perhaps-not-burn-from-the-sun-if-have-enough-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="paleohacks-nov-2010httppaleohackscomquestions14104skin-cancer-dangeraxzz1nw8nuhqn">&lt;a href="http://paleohacks.com/questions/14104/skin-cancer-danger#axzz1NW8nuhQn">Paleohacks Nov 2010?&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>My ability to tan and not burn has improved dramatically this year. I attribute it to supplementing with vitamin D, getting off statins, reducing n6 PUFA, adding fish oil and generally doing things that reduce inflammation (no grains, low carb, improving gut health).&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="tan-today-april-2010httpwwwtantodaycomforumsscience-uv-vitamin-d40316-vitamin-d-newsletter-discusses-abuse-liquid-vitaminshtml">&lt;a href="http://www.tantoday.com/forums/science-uv-vitamin-d/40316-vitamin-d-newsletter-discusses-abuse-liquid-vitamins.html">Tan Today April 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>My friend took high doses of vitamin D for a few weeks before rafting and, for the first time in his life, did not burn when rafting the Snake River.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For small amounts of sunshine the amount of skin exposed may not matter</title><link>/posts/for-small-amounts-of-sunshine-the-amount-of-skin-exposed-may-not-matter.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/for-small-amounts-of-sunshine-the-amount-of-skin-exposed-may-not-matter.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="interdependence-between-body-surface-area-and-ultraviolet-b-dose-in-vitamin-d-production-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Interdependence between body surface area and ultraviolet B dose in vitamin D production: a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Br J Dermatol. 2011 Jan;164(1):163-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.10082.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.10082.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bogh MK, Schmedes AV, Philipsen PA, Thieden E, Wulf HC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Copenhagen University Hospital, Bispebjerg Bakke 23, DK-2400 Copenhagen NV, Denmark. &lt;a href="mailto:bogh@dadlnet.dk">bogh@dadlnet.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Ultraviolet (UV) B radiation increases serum vitamin D level expressed as 25-hydroxyvitamin-D(3) &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>, but the relationship to body surface area and UVB dose needs investigation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>9 minutes a day of sun improved BMD Parkinsons disease patients</title><link>/posts/9-minutes-a-day-of-sun-improved-bmd-parkinsons-disease-patients.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/9-minutes-a-day-of-sun-improved-bmd-parkinsons-disease-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="amelioration-of-osteoporosis-and-hypovitaminosis-d-by-sunlight-exposure-in-parkinsons-disease">Amelioration of osteoporosis and hypovitaminosis D by sunlight exposure in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2011 Jan;17(1):22-6. Epub 2010 Nov 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sato Y, Iwamoto J, Honda Y.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Mitate Hospital, 3237 Yugeta, Tagawa 826-0041, Japan. &lt;a href="mailto:y-sato@ktarn.or.jp">y-sato@ktarn.or.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A high incidence of fractures, particularly of the hip, represents an important problem in patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD), who are prone to falls and have osteoporosis. We previously showed that 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) deficiency due to sunlight deprivation with compensatory hyperparathyroidism causes reduced bone mineral density (BMD) in elderly patients with PD. The present study was undertaken to address the possibility that sunlight exposure may maintain BMD and reduce the incidence of hip fracture in elderly patients with PD. In a prospective study, PD patients were assigned to regular sunlight exposure (n=162) or usual lifestyle (n=162), and followed for 2 years. BMD of the second metacarpal bone was measured using a computed X-ray densitometer. Incidence of hip fracture in the two patient groups during the 2 year follow-up period was assessed. At baseline, patients of both groups showed vitamin D deficiency due to sunlight deprivation with compensatory hyperparathyroidism. The exposed group patients were exposed to sunlight (3231 min/year).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Difficult to get 1000 IU of vitamin D in 30 minutes If UVI less than 3</title><link>/posts/difficult-to-get-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-in-30-minutes-if-uvi-less-than-3.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/difficult-to-get-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-in-30-minutes-if-uvi-less-than-3.html</guid><description>&lt;p>1Burning daylight: balancing vitamin D requirements with sensible sun exposure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Med J Aust. 2011 Apr 4;194(7):345-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stalgis-Bilinski KL, Boyages J, Salisbury EL, Dunstan CR, Henderson SI, Talbot PL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Westmead Breast Cancer Institute, University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia. &lt;a href="mailto:Kellie.Bilinski@bci.org.au">Kellie.Bilinski@bci.org.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To examine the feasibility of balancing sunlight exposure to meet vitamin D requirements with sun protection guidelines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DESIGN AND SETTING: We used standard erythemal dose and Ultraviolet Index (UVI) data for 1 June 1996 to 30 December 2005 for seven Australian cities to estimate duration of sun exposure required for fair-skinned individuals to synthesise 1000 IU (25 µg) of vitamin D, with 11% and 17% body exposure, for each season and hour of the day. Periods were classified according to whether the UVI was &amp;lt; 3 or ? 3 (when sun protection measures are recommended), and whether required duration of exposure was ? 30 min, 31-60 min, or &amp;gt; 60 min.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin tone changes with season – high BMI different</title><link>/posts/skin-tone-changes-with-season-high-bmi-different.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-tone-changes-with-season-high-bmi-different.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="skin-color-change-in-caucasian-postmenopausal-women-predicts-summer-winter-change-in-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-findings-from-the-ansavid-cohort-study">Skin Color Change in Caucasian Postmenopausal Women Predicts Summer-Winter Change in 25-Hydroxyvitamin D: Findings from the ANSAViD Cohort Study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Mar 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Macdonald HM, Mavroeidi A, Aucott LA, Diffey BL, Fraser WD, Ormerod AD, Reid DM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Applied Medicine (H.M.M., A.M., L.A.A., A.D.O., D.M.R.), University of Aberdeen, Foresterhill, Aberdeen AB25 2ZD, United Kingdom; Dermatological Sciences (B.L.D.), Institute of Cellular Medicine, University of Newcastle, Newcastle Upon Tyne NE1 7RU, United Kingdom; and Department of Musculoskeletal Biology (W.D.F.), University of Liverpool, Liverpool L69 3GA, United Kingdom.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Suntan, melanoma and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-suntan-melanoma-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-suntan-melanoma-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#consensus-on-the-following">Consensus on the following:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#confusiondisagreement">Confusion/Disagreement&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#note-after-skin-cancer-diagnosis-internal-cancer-rates-often-increase-due-to-sun-phobia">Note: After skin cancer diagnosis, internal cancer rates often increase due to sun phobia&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki---span-stylecolor00fuva-and-melanomaspan">See also VitaminDWiki &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">UVA and Melanoma&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clipped-from-skincheck-orghttpwwwskincheckorgpage5htm-where-does-melanoma-occur">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.skincheck.org/Page5.htm">SkinCheck org&lt;/a> Where does Melanoma occur&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#from-vitamin-d-from-sunbeds">From: Vitamin D from Sunbeds&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#from-sunbed-survey-in-ireland">From: Sunbed survey in Ireland&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#from-uv-creates-vitamin-dhttpswwwvitamindwikicomtiki-download_filephpfileid1690">From: &lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1690">UV creates Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#grassrootshealthhttpwwwgrassrootshealthnet-melanoma--sunscreen-associated-in-7-studies-pdf-and-videohttpwwwucsdtvsearch-detailsaspxshowid15770">&lt;a href="http://www.grassrootshealth.net/">GrassrootsHealth&lt;/a> Melanoma &amp;amp; sunscreen associated in 7 studies (PDF and &lt;a href="http://www.ucsd.tv/search-details.aspx?showID=15770">video&lt;/a>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#chart-from-httpwwwdeterteccomsun_radiometryhtml">Chart from &lt;a href="http://www.detertec.com/sun_radiometry.html">http://www.detertec.com/sun_radiometry.html&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#germany-also-considers-that-adding-vitamin-d-might-reduce-melanoma">Germany also considers that adding vitamin D might reduce melanoma&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-chinese-are-really-wanting-to-get-whiter-skin-or-avoid-skin-cancerwrinkles">Some Chinese are really wanting to get whiter skin or avoid Skin Cancer/Wrinkles&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sunshine-dangerous-or-healthyhttpwwwschachtercentercomsunshinehtm-2009">&lt;a href="http://www.schachtercenter.com/sunshine.htm">Sunshine: Dangerous or Healthy?&lt;/a> 2009&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#alcohol-and-melanoma-more-proof-that-this-deadly-skin-cancer-is-not-caused-by-sunlighthttpwwwsunlightinstituteorgalcohol-and-melanoma-more-proof-deadly-skin-cancer-not-caused-sunlight20">&lt;a href="http://www.sunlightinstitute.org/alcohol-and-melanoma-more-proof-deadly-skin-cancer-not-caused-sunlight%20">Alcohol and Melanoma: More Proof that this Deadly Skin Cancer is not caused by Sunlight&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#if-already-have-had-skin-cancer-a-form-of-vitamin-b3-lowers-the-rate-of-future-ones-by-23---rct-may-2015">If already have had skin cancer, a form of Vitamin B3 lowers the rate of future ones by 23% - RCT May 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ai-found-99-of-skin-cancers---nov-2023">AI found &amp;gt;99% of skin cancers - Nov 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="consensus-on-the-following">Consensus on the following:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>UV radiation at the ground consists mainly of UVA, some UVB, and a tiny amount of UVC&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Concealing clothing resulted in only 8 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/concealing-clothing-resulted-in-only-8-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/concealing-clothing-resulted-in-only-8-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="risk-factors-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-women-aged-20-50-years-consulting-in-general-practice-a-cross-sectional-study">Risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in women aged 20-50 years consulting in general practice: a cross-sectional study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Gen Pract. 2011 Feb 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Le Goaziou MF, Contardo G, Dupraz C, Martin A, Laville M, Schott-Pethelaz AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of General Practice, University Claude Bernard, Lyon 1, &lt;strong>France.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: Vitamin D deficiency is often unidentified, although treatment is simple and inexpensive. Our objective was to estimate the influence of concealing clothes and other risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in women aged 20 to 50 years consulting general practitioners.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scared Out of the Sun for Fifty Years</title><link>/posts/scared-out-of-the-sun-for-fifty-years.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/scared-out-of-the-sun-for-fifty-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="posted-20-jan-2011--by-vitamin-d-survivorhttppandemicsurvivorwordpresscom">Posted: 20 Jan 2011 by &lt;a href="http://pandemicsurvivor.wordpress.com/">Vitamin D Survivor&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It seems the American Academy of Dermatology has released a new position statement for vitamin D. &lt;a href="http://www.aad.org/forms/policies/uploads/ps/ps-vitamin%20d.pdf">Here is the PDF&lt;/a>. An amazing statement in the opening paragraph is a ‘true grabber’. &lt;strong>“Vitamin D should not be obtained from unprotected exposure to ultraviolet (UV) radiation.”&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our ancient relationship with the sun has changed forever – to paraphrase a statement made by Dr. Edward Gorham, Ph.D. from UCSD about sunscreen. It is amazing to me that the AAD would attempt to continue its fifty year position on the sun with all of the new science.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Whites with some sunshine can achieve more than 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/whites-with-some-sunshine-can-achieve-more-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/whites-with-some-sunshine-can-achieve-more-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-vitamin-d-debate-translating-controlled-experiments-into-reality-for-human-sun-exposure-times">The Vitamin D Debate: Translating Controlled Experiments into Reality for Human Sun Exposure Times&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ann R. Webb1, &lt;a href="mailto:ann.webb@manchester.ac.uk">ann.webb@manchester.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Richard Kift1,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Jacqueline L. Berry2,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Lesley E. Rhodes3&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1111/j.1751-1097.2011.00898.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photochemistry and Photobiology&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> School of Earth Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences, University of Manchester, UK
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Vitamin D Research Laboratory, School of Biomedical Sciences, University of Manchester, Manchester Royal Infirmary, Manchester, UK
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Photobiology Unit, Dermatological Sciences, School of Translational Medicine, University of Manchester, Manchester Academic Health Science Centre, Salford Royal NHS Foundation Hospital, Manchester, UK.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Accepted manuscript online: 18 JAN 2011, . Received Date : 03-Dec-2010Accepted Date : 07-Jan-2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D from the sun 3 to 12 months of the year in the US</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-from-the-sun-3-to-12-months-of-the-year-in-the-us.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-from-the-sun-3-to-12-months-of-the-year-in-the-us.html</guid><description>&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;1410&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="uv-index-must-be-greater-than-3--span-stylecolor090above-the-green-span-to-generate-any-vitamin-d">UV Index must be greater than 3 ( &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#090;">above the green) &lt;/span>&lt;/strong> to generate any vitamin D&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="people-in-anchorage-vitamin-d-for-span-stylecolorf003-months-of-the-yearspan">People in Anchorage: vitamin D for &lt;span style="color:#F00;">3 months of the year&lt;/span>&lt;/h1>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"> 
&lt;h1 id="people-in-minnesota-vitamin-d-for-span-stylecolorf006-months-of-the-yearspan">People in Minnesota: vitamin D for &lt;span style="color:#F00;">6 months of the year&lt;/span>&lt;/h1>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"> 
&lt;h1 id="people-in-florida-vitamin-d-for-span-stylecolorf0012-months-of-the-yearspan">People in Florida: vitamin D for &lt;span style="color:#F00;">12 months of the year&lt;/span>&lt;/h1>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h2 id="click-herehttpwwwcpcnoaagovproductsstratosphereuv_indexuv_annualshtml-for-other-us-uv-index">&lt;a href="http://www.cpc.noaa.gov/products/stratosphere/uv_index/uv_annual.shtml">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for other US UV index&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="you-only-get-enough-vitamin-d-with-10-minutes-in-the-sun-noontime-in-florida-from-april-thru-sept">You only get enough vitamin D with 10 minutes in the sun noontime in Florida from April thru Sept&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="a-hrefpostshow-much-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-766how-much-da-includes-equations">&lt;a href="/posts/how-much-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 766">How Much D&lt;/a> includes equations&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="a-hrefpostsnational-and-experts-recommendations-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1293national-and-experts-recommendationsa-of-how-much-vitamin-d-you-should-have">&lt;a href="/posts/national-and-experts-recommendations" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1293">National and Experts Recommendations&lt;/a> of How Much vitamin D you should have&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="click-here-for-vitamindwiki-home-pagehttpswwwvitamindwikicomtiki-indexphp-for-overviews-and-lots-more-details">&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-index.php">CLICK HERE for VitaminDWiki Home Page&lt;/a> for Overviews and lots more details&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=709">Introduction to Vitamin D&lt;/a> page 6 If shadow TALLER than you are tall, you CANNOT make vitamin D, also UV Index 3&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and latitude Masterjohn</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-latitude-masterjohn.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-latitude-masterjohn.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d----problems-with-the-latitude-hypothesishttpwwwwestonapriceorgblogsvitamin-d-problems-with-the-latitude-hypothesishtml">&lt;a href="http://www.westonaprice.org/blogs/vitamin-d-problems-with-the-latitude-hypothesis.html">Vitamin D &amp;ndash; Problems With the Latitude Hypothesis&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="notes-from-his-3-page-article">Notes from his 3 page article&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>1988 paper by Webb and Hollick postulated a limitation of vitamin D production with latitude and season&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/2009-paper" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1257">2009 paper&lt;/a> appear to say that is only true for caucasians&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A major analysis published in 2009 (3) pooled together the results of 394 studies examining vitamin D levels in over 30,000 people all across the globe in order to investigate the effect of latitude on vitamin D status. The authors only included people who were native to the area in which they were living, and who were free-living. They concluded that there was only an effect of latitude in Caucasians. There was no effect of latitude in people with non-Caucasian ancestry.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D not change with latitude unless caucasian - 2009</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-not-change-with-latitude-unless-caucasian-2009.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-not-change-with-latitude-unless-caucasian-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="global-vitamin-d-levels-in-relation-to-age-gender-skin-pigmentation-and-latitude-an-ecologic-meta-regression-analysis">Global vitamin D levels in relation to age, gender, skin pigmentation and latitude: an ecologic meta-regression analysis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2009 Jan;20(1):133-40. Epub 2008 May 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hagenau T, Vest R, Gissel TN, Poulsen CS, Erlandsen M, Mosekilde L, Vestergaard P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism C, Aarhus Amtssygehus, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We performed a meta-analysis of cross-sectional studies on serum 25(OH)D status globally. Serum 25(OH)D levels on average were 54 nmol/l, were higher in women than men, and higher in Caucasians than in non-Caucasians. There was no trend in serum 25(OH)D level with latitude. Vitamin D deficiency was widespread. INTRODUCTION: We studied vitamin D status (expressed as serum 25-hydroxy-vitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>) in native subjects worldwide.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Consensus Vitamin D position statement – UK</title><link>/posts/consensus-vitamin-d-position-statement-uk.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/consensus-vitamin-d-position-statement-uk.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="this-page-includes-comments-by-span-stylecolorf33vitamindwiki-embededspan-and-followed-by-natural-news">This page includes comments by &lt;span style="color:#F33;">VitaminDWiki (embeded)&lt;/span> and followed by Natural News&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="this-consensus-statement-represents-the-unified-views-of-the">This consensus statement represents the unified views of the&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>British Association of Dermatologists,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cancer Research UK,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Diabetes UK,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Multiple Sclerosis Society,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>National Heart Forum,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>National Osteoporosis Society and&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Primary Care Dermatology Society.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is essential for good bone health and for most people sunlight is the most important source of vitamin D. The time required to make sufficient vitamin D varies according to a number of environmental, physical and personal factors, but is typically short and less than the amount of time needed for skin to redden and burn. Enjoying the sun safely, while taking care not to burn, can help to provide the benefits of vitamin D without unduly raising the risk of skin cancer. Vitamin D supplements and specific foods can help to maintain sufficient levels of vitamin D, particularly in people at risk of deficiency. However, there is still a lot of uncertainty around what levels qualify as “optimal” or “sufficient”, how much sunlight different people need to achieve a given level of vitamin D, whether vitamin D protects against chronic diseases such as cancer, heart disease and diabetes, and the benefits and risks of widespread supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An overview analysis of the time people spend outdoors</title><link>/posts/an-overview-analysis-of-the-time-people-spend-outdoors.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/an-overview-analysis-of-the-time-people-spend-outdoors.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Br J Dermatol. 2010 Dec 3. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.10165.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.10165.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diffey BL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dermatological Sciences, Institute of Cellular Medicine, University of Newcastle NE2 4HH, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background ? An important factor in determining our exposure to sunlight, and the consequent impact on skin health and vitamin D status, is the time we spend outdoors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives? To determine estimates of the typical times per day spent outdoors during weekdays, weekends and holidays during a summer season.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4X more suburban UV than urban UV</title><link>/posts/4x-more-suburban-uv-than-urban-uv.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4x-more-suburban-uv-than-urban-uv.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lycopene blocks some UVA</title><link>/posts/lycopene-blocks-some-uva.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lycopene-blocks-some-uva.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="first-ran-across-lycopene-and-uv-in-a-mercola-article-nov-2010httpwwwnaturalnewscom030500_vitamin_d_absorptionhtml">First ran across lycopene and UV in a &lt;a href="http://www.naturalnews.com/030500_vitamin_D_absorption.html">Mercola Article Nov 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;If you burn easily, consider supplementing your diet with lycopene, a key nutrient that is found in heavy concentration in tomatoes. Studies recently showed that those with high levels of lycopene had a much higher &amp;ldquo;internal sunscreen,&amp;rdquo; and burned much less easily, than those who did not take in a lot of lycopene. In fact, antioxidants in general may give your skin an edge against UV sensitivity and cut down on burning.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>80 percent of vitamin D from sun rather than from food</title><link>/posts/80-percent-of-vitamin-d-from-sun-rather-than-from-food.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/80-percent-of-vitamin-d-from-sun-rather-than-from-food.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sunlight-and-dietary-contributions-to-the-seasonal-vitamin-d-status-of-cohorts-of-healthy-postmenopausal-women-living-at-northerly-latitudes-a-major-cause-for-concern">Sunlight and dietary contributions to the seasonal vitamin D status of cohorts of healthy postmenopausal women living at northerly latitudes: a major cause for concern?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int () (2010)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>H M Macdonald, A Mavroeidi, W D Fraser, A L Darling, A J Black, L Aucott, F O&amp;rsquo;Neill, K Hart, J L Berry, S A Lanham-New and D M Reid&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Aberdeen, Foresterhill, Aberdeen, AB25 2ZD, UK, &lt;a href="mailto:h.macdonald@abdn.ac.uk">h.macdonald@abdn.ac.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We assessed sunlight and dietary contributions to vitamin D status in British postmenopausal women. Our true longitudinal 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) measurements varied seasonally, being lower in the north compared to the south and lower in Asian women. Sunlight exposure in summer and spring provided 80% total annual intake of vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moscow prison to install tanning beds</title><link>/posts/moscow-prison-to-install-tanning-beds.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/moscow-prison-to-install-tanning-beds.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://law.rightpundits.com/?p=2486">http://law.rightpundits.com/?p=2486&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a lawyer died in jail who might have been there illegally&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nice move to improve health conditions in prisons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially good for those who do not get outside much and during the winter&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/life-style/health/tanning-bed-users-confess-whey-back-article-1.1185585">NY Daily News, Oct 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A session will cost about 33 cents a minute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It would be far more cheaper to buy vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Bit of history: Dr. Cannell, the head of the Vitamin D Council, first noticed the lack of vitamin D when working in a prison-like environment&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>