<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ovarian Cancer on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/ovarian-cancer.html</link><description>Recent content in Ovarian Cancer on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/ovarian-cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D helps women in many ways – but not sure about ovarian and endometrial cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-women-in-many-ways-but-not-sure-about-ovarian-and-endometrial-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-women-in-many-ways-but-not-sure-about-ovarian-and-endometrial-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ovarian cancer risk increases 27 percent for each 8 ng lower level of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ovarian-cancer-risk-increases-27-percent-for-each-8-ng-lower-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ovarian-cancer-risk-increases-27-percent-for-each-8-ng-lower-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ovarian Cancer – 7 percent more likely to survive longer for every 4 ng higher vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ovarian-cancer-7-percent-more-likely-to-survive-longer-for-every-4-ng-higher-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ovarian-cancer-7-percent-more-likely-to-survive-longer-for-every-4-ng-higher-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-survival-in-women-with-ovarian-cancer">Circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D and survival in women with ovarian cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2015 Jul;102(1):109-14. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3945/ajcn.114.102681.">doi: 10.3945/ajcn.114.102681.&lt;/a> Epub 2015 May 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Webb PM1, de Fazio A2, Protani MM3, Ibiebele TI4, Nagle CM4, Brand AH5, Blomfield PI6, Grant P7, Perrin LC8, Neale RE4; Australian Ovarian Cancer Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D status might be associated with cancer survival. Survival after ovarian cancer is poor, but the association with vitamin D has rarely been examined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ovarian Cancer re-occurrence 50 percent more likely if still low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ovarian-cancer-re-occurrence-50-percent-more-likely-if-still-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ovarian-cancer-re-occurrence-50-percent-more-likely-if-still-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Increased risk of some female cancers if low vitamin D (due to genes) – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/increased-risk-of-some-female-cancers-if-low-vitamin-d-due-to-genes-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-risk-of-some-female-cancers-if-low-vitamin-d-due-to-genes-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D helps women in many ways – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-women-in-many-ways-review.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-women-in-many-ways-review.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cancer - Ovarian</title><link>/posts/cancer-ovarian.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-ovarian.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>See also Web&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D Intake, Blood 25-Hydroxyvitamin D, and Risk of Ovarian Cancer: A Meta-Analysis of Observational Studies - May 2023 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1089/jwh.2022.0432">https://doi.org/10.1089/jwh.2022.0432&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;people with high blood 25(OH)D levels had 37% lower risk of ovarian cancer than those with low levels &amp;quot;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/ovarian-cancer-what-we-think-we-know-may-harm-us">Ovarian Cancer: What We Think We Know May Harm Us&lt;/a> Green Medical Info June 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>False-positive diagnosis = 3,285, but actual Ovarian cancer = only 212 (False positive error rate = about &lt;strong>15X&lt;/strong> )&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ovarian Cancer: Interplay of Vitamin D Signaling and miRNA Action. – 2014</title><link>/posts/ovarian-cancer-interplay-of-vitamin-d-signaling-and-mirna-action-2014.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ovarian-cancer-interplay-of-vitamin-d-signaling-and-mirna-action-2014.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2014;15(8):3359-62.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Attar R1, Gasparri ML, Donato VD, Yaylim I, Halim TA, Zaman F, Farooqi AA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Increasing attention is being devoted to the mechanisms by which cells receive signals and then translate these into decisions for growth, death, or migration. Recent findings have presented significant breakthroughs in developing a deeper understanding of the activation or repression of target genes and proteins in response to various stimuli and of how they are assembled during signal transduction in cancer cells. Detailed mechanistic insights have unveiled new maps of linear and integrated signal transduction cascades, but the multifaceted nature of the pathways remains unclear. Although new layers of information are being added regarding mechanisms underlying ovarian cancer and how polymorphisms in VDR gene influence its development, the findings of this research must be sequentially collected and re-interpreted. We divide this multi-component review into different segments: how vitamin D modulates molecular network in ovarian cancer cells, how ovarian cancer is controlled by tumor suppressors and oncogenic miRNAs and finally how vitamin D signaling regulates miRNA expression. Intra/inter-population variability is insufficiently studied and a better understanding of genetics of population will be helpful in getting a step closer to personalized medicine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ovarian Cancer 5.8 X more likely if both low vitamin D and Fok1 gene change</title><link>/posts/ovarian-cancer-58-x-more-likely-if-both-low-vitamin-d-and-fok1-gene-change.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ovarian-cancer-58-x-more-likely-if-both-low-vitamin-d-and-fok1-gene-change.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-vdr-gene-polymorphism-foki-in-epithelial-ovarian-cancer-in-indian-population">Vitamin D and VDR gene polymorphism (FokI) in epithelial ovarian cancer in Indian population.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Ovarian Res. 2013 May 26;6(1):37.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohapatra S, Saxena A, Gandhi G, Koner BC, Ray PC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Vitamin D deficiency and vitamin D receptor (VDR) gene polymorphism, FokI, is reported to increase the risk of many cancers. Role of vitamin D and its receptor polymorphisms in ovarian cancer has not been clearly defined.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To study the levels of serum vitamin D and occurrence of vitamin D receptor gene polymorphism (FokI) in cases of ovarian cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ovarian cancer: more likely to survive if more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ovarian-cancer-more-likely-to-survive-if-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ovarian-cancer-more-likely-to-survive-if-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="25ohd3-in-patients-with-ovarian-cancer-and-its-correlation-with-survival">25(OH)D3 in patients with ovarian cancer and its correlation with survival&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ma?gorzata Walentowicz-Sadlecka,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, ul. Ujejskiego 75, 85–168 Bydgoszcz, Poland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 19 April 2012. Revised 28 June 2012. Accepted 27 July 2012. Available online 4 August 2012.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.clinbiochem.2012.07.110">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.clinbiochem.2012.07.110&lt;/a>, How to Cite or Link Using DOI&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study was to examine vitamin 25(OH)D3 concentration in ovarian cancer patients in relation to a pathological subtype of the tumor, FIGO stage, grading, menopause status and overall 5-year survival.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>