<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer - Lymphoma on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer---lymphoma.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer - Lymphoma on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer---lymphoma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Some childhood cancer 30% less likely in parts of California with more UVB</title><link>/posts/some-childhood-cancer-30-percent-less-likely-in-parts-of-california-with-more-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-childhood-cancer-30-percent-less-likely-in-parts-of-california-with-more-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="solar-uv-radiation-and-cancer-in-young-children">Solar UV radiation and cancer in young children&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Christina A. Lombardi 1, Julia E. Heck 2, Myles Cockburn 3, and Beate Ritz 4,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Epidemiology, UCLA Fielding School of Public Health&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Public Health, University of California&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Preventive Medicine, University of Southern California&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 UCLA Fielding School of Public Health&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵* Corresponding Author: Beate Ritz, UCLA Fielding School of Public Health, United States &lt;a href="mailto:britz@ucla.edu">britz@ucla.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Studies have shown that higher UV radiation exposure (UVR) may be related to lower risk of some cancers in adults. Recently an ecological study reported lower risks of some cancers among children living in higher UVR cities and countries. In a large population-based case-control study in California we tested the hypothesis that specific childhood cancers may be influenced by UVR.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The sun appears better at reducing incidence of some cancers than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-prevention-of-cancer-by-sun-exposure-more-than-just-the-effect-of-vitamin-d--a-systematic-review-of-epidemiological-studies">Is prevention of cancer by sun exposure more than just the effect of vitamin D? -A systematic review of epidemiological studies.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Cancer. 2012 Dec 10. pii: S0959-8049(12)00885-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.">doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van der Rhee H, Coebergh JW, de Vries E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Hagaziekenhuis, P.O. Box 40551, Leyweg 275, 2504 LN Den Haag, Zuid-Holland, The Netherlands. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:hvdrhee@casema.nl">hvdrhee@casema.nl&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The number of studies reporting on the association between sunlight exposure, vitamin D and cancer risk is steadily increasing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Risk of Rarer Cancers</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-risk-of-rarer-cancers.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-risk-of-rarer-cancers.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="shedding-light-on-serum-vitamin-d-concentrations-and-the-risk-of-rarer-cancers">Shedding Light on Serum Vitamin D Concentrations and the Risk of Rarer Cancers&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.65-69 (5)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Kathy J. Helzlsouer, Lisa Gallicchio&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer is a broad term for many disparate diseases with different etiologies, commonly classified by affected organ site. This review summarizes the published evidence from prospective cohort studies examining the associations between vitamin D, measured as serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) concentrations, and the risk of rarer cancer sites including&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer - Lymphoma</title><link>/posts/cancer-lymphoma.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-lymphoma.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="ai-able-to-detect-90-of-lymphoma-sites---march-2024">AI able to detect 90% of Lymphoma sites - March 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.trialsitenews.com/a/ai-detects-90-of-lymphatic-cancer-cases-introducing-lars-or-lymphoma-artificial-reader-system-6cb21bf8">TrialSiteNews&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Does not appear to mention % caught by humans&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="2x-more-likely-to-die-of-lymphoma-if-low-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-march-2021">2X more likely to die of lymphoma if low vitamin D - meta-analysis March 2021&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Meta-analysis of the prognostic and clinical value of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in previously untreated lymphoma&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Future Oncol. 2021 Mar 17. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2217/fon-2020-0914">doi: 10.2217/fon-2020-0914&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yunxia Tao 1, Haizhu Chen 1, Yu Zhou 1, Yuankai Shi 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: This meta-analysis explored the prognostic and clinical value of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D, 25(OH)D, levels in previously untreated lymphoma.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hodgkin’s lymphoma and Vitamin D Receptor</title><link>/posts/hodgkins-lymphoma-and-vitamin-d-receptor.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hodgkins-lymphoma-and-vitamin-d-receptor.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-receptor-is-highly-expressed-in-hodgkins-lymphoma">Vitamin D3 receptor is highly expressed in Hodgkin’s lymphoma.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Christoph Renne, Alexander Benz and Martin L Hansmann&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Cancer 2012, 12:215 doi:10.1186/1471-2407-12-215; Published: 6 June 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hodkin’s lymphoma is one of the most frequent lymphoma in western world. Despite an overall good prognosis some patients suffer relapsing tumors which are difficult to cure. Over a long period Vitamin D has been shown to be a potential treatment for cancer. Vitamin D acts via the vitamin D receptor, a nuclear receptor, acting as an inducible transcription factor. We aimed to investigate the expression of vitamin D receptor as potential therapeutic target structure in Hodgkin’s lymphoma as well as in non Hodgkin’s lymphoma.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hours of sun per week decreased probability of NH lymphoma by 32 percent</title><link>/posts/hours-of-sun-per-week-decreased-probability-of-nh-lymphoma-by-32-percent.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hours-of-sun-per-week-decreased-probability-of-nh-lymphoma-by-32-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="early-life-sun-exposure-vitamin-d-related-gene-variants-and-risk-of-non-hodgkin-lymphoma">Early life sun exposure, vitamin D-related gene variants, and risk of non-Hodgkin lymphoma.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2012 Apr 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kelly JL, Drake MT, Fredericksen ZS, Asmann YW, Liebow M, Shanafelt TD, Feldman AL, Ansell SM, Macon WR, Herr MM, Wang AH, Nowakowski GS, Call TG, Habermann TM, Slager SL, Witzig TE, Cerhan JR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Rochester, 601 Elmwood Avenue, Box 704, Rochester, NY, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/early-life-sun-exposure-vitamin-d-related-gene-variants-and-risk-of-non-hodgkin-lymphoma.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting little UV is associated with 15 types of Cancer</title><link>/posts/getting-little-uv-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/getting-little-uv-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="ecological-studies-of-the-uvbvitamin-dcancer-hypothesis">Ecological Studies of the UVB–Vitamin D–Cancer Hypothesis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Anticancer Research January 2012 vol. 32 no. 1 223-236&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WILLIAM B. GRANT, Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, P.O. Box 641603, San Francisco, CA 94164-1603, U.S.A. &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aim: This paper reviews ecological studies of the ultraviolet-B (UVB)–vitamin D–cancer hypothesis based on geographical variation of cancer incidence and/or mortality rates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Materials and Methods: The review is based largely on three ecological studies of cancer rates from the United States; one each from Australia, China, France, Japan, and Spain; and eight multicountry, multifactorial studies of cancer incidence rates from &lt;strong>more than 100 countries&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer patients 64% less likely to die if have high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cancer-patients-64-percent-less-likely-to-die-if-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-patients-64-percent-less-likely-to-die-if-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-survival-in-norwegian-patients-with-cancer-of-breast-colon-lung-and-lymphoma-a-population-based-study">Serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D and survival in Norwegian patients with cancer of breast, colon, lung, and lymphoma: a population-based study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2011 Dec 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tretli S, Schwartz GG, Torjesen PA, Robsahm TE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cancer Registry of Norway, Institute of Population-based Cancer Research, PB 5313, Majorstuen, 0304, Oslo, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no">steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: We investigated the association between serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) and risk of death in Norwegian cancer patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Living in areas with more UV decreased lymph problems by 42 percent</title><link>/posts/living-in-areas-with-more-uv-decreased-lymph-problems-by-42-percent.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/living-in-areas-with-more-uv-decreased-lymph-problems-by-42-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="adulthood-residential-ultraviolet-radiation-sun-sensitivity-dietary-vitamin-d-and-risk-of-lymphoid-malignancies-in-the-california-teachers-study">Adulthood residential ultraviolet radiation, sun sensitivity, dietary vitamin D, and risk of lymphoid malignancies in the California Teachers Study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ellen T. Chang1,2; Alison J. Canchola1; Myles Cockburn3; Yani Lu4; Sophia S. Wang4; Leslie Bernstein4; Christina A. Clarke1,2; and Pamela L. Horn-Ross1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Cancer Prevention Institute of California, Fremont, CA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Division of Epidemiology, Department of Health Research and Policy, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, CA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Division of Epidemiology, Department of Preventive Medicine, Norris Comprehensive Cancer Center, University of Southern California Keck School of Medicine, Los Angeles, CA; and&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>