<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meta-Analysis on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/meta-analysis.html</link><description>Recent content in Meta-Analysis on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/meta-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cognitive Impairment 2.4X more likely if low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cognitive-impairment-24x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cognitive-impairment-24x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-cognitive-impairment-and-dementia-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D Deficiency, Cognitive Impairment and Dementia: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord 2012 Vol. 33, No. 5, 2012 ;33:297-305&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thorleif Etgena,b &lt;a href="mailto:thorleif.etgen@klinikum-traunstein.de">thorleif.etgen@klinikum-traunstein.de&lt;/a>, Dirk Sanderc,d, Horst Bickela, Kerstin Sanderd, Hans Förstla&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Technische Universität München,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Department of Neurology, Kliniken Südostbayern – Klinikum Traunstein,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Department of Neurology, Benedictus Krankenhaus Tutzing, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D Department of Neurology, Technische Universität München, Munich, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Recent preventive strategies for patients with cognitive impairment include the identification of modifiable somatic risk factors like vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shift workers 23 percent more likely to have cardiovascular events – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/shift-workers-23-percent-more-likely-to-have-cardiovascular-events-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shift-workers-23-percent-more-likely-to-have-cardiovascular-events-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="shift-work-and-vascular-events-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Shift work and vascular events: systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>BMJ 2012; 345 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.e4800">doi: 10.1136/bmj.e4800&lt;/a> (Published 26 July 2012)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cite this as: BMJ 2012;345:e4800&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manav V Vyas, graduate student1, Amit X Garg, professor123, Arthur V Iansavichus, information specialist3, John Costella, research and instructional librarian4, Allan Donner, professor15, Lars E Laugsand, PhD candidate6, Imre Janszky, researcher67, Marko Mrkobrada, assistant professor25, Grace Parraga, associate professor8, Daniel G Hackam, associate professor125&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Western University, London, ON, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fractures reduced 30 percent with 800 IU of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-pooled-analysis-of-vitamin-d-dose-requirements-for-fracture-prevention">A pooled analysis of vitamin D dose requirements for fracture prevention.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med. 2012 Jul 5;367(1):40-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Willett WC, Orav EJ, Lips P, Meunier PJ, Lyons RA, Flicker L, Wark J, Jackson RD, Cauley JA, Meyer HE, Pfeifer M, Sanders KM, Stähelin HB, Theiler R, Dawson-Hughes B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center on Aging and Mobility, University of Zurich and Waid City Hospital, Zurich, Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The results of meta-analyses examining the relationship between vitamin D supplementation and fracture reduction have been inconsistent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D increased probability of low birth weight by 60 percent – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increased-probability-of-low-birth-weight-by-60-percent-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increased-probability-of-low-birth-weight-by-60-percent-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-maternal-neonatal-and-infant-health-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D During Pregnancy and Maternal, Neonatal and Infant Health Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Andrew Thorne-Lyman1,*, Wafaie W. Fawzi1,2,3; Article first published online: 28 JUN 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2012 Blackwell Publishing Ltd&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paediatric and Perinatal Epidemiology, Volume 26, Issue Supplement s1, pages 75–90, July 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Special Issue: Improving maternal, newborn, and child health outcomes through better designed policies and programs that enhance the nutrition of women&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:>85%">
&lt;p>The only daily vitamin D data used in the meta-analysis was 1000 IU of vitamin &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">D2&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>