<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer - Skin on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer---skin.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer - Skin on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer---skin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Melanoma and Vitamin D - association is not certain - 2012</title><link>/posts/melanoma-and-vitamin-d-association-is-not-certain-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/melanoma-and-vitamin-d-association-is-not-certain-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-and-melanoma-incidence-and-mortality">Vitamin D and melanoma incidence and mortality.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Pigment Cell Melanoma Res. 2013 Jan;26(1):9-15. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/pcmr.12015.">doi: 10.1111/pcmr.12015.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Oct 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Berwick M, Erdei EO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Epidemiology, Biostatistics and Preventive Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, University of New Mexico Cancer Center, Albuquerque, NM, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:mberwick@salud.unm.edu">mberwick@salud.unm.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of vitamin D (25-OH-D, or 25-hydroxyvitamin D) and its potential confounders in relationship to melanoma risk and mortality is discussed. The paradox that ultraviolet radiation (UVR) exposure is the major environmental risk factor for melanoma etiology as well as a major source of vitamin D might be explained by viewing vitamin D levels as the result of a healthy lifestyle rather than a cause of health.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On-job UV associated with LESS, not more, skin cancer</title><link>/posts/on-job-uv-associated-with-less-not-more-skin-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/on-job-uv-associated-with-less-not-more-skin-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dermatologists in Australia – Squamous cell carcinoma not a function of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dermatologists-in-australia-squamous-cell-carcinoma-not-a-function-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dermatologists-in-australia-squamous-cell-carcinoma-not-a-function-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="actually-they-found-that-squamous-cell-carcinoma-50-percent-less-likely-if-the-vitamin-d-cut-point-is-30-ng-but-no-difference-if-cut-point-is-20-ng">Actually: they found that squamous cell carcinoma 50 percent LESS likely if the vitamin D cut point is 30 ng, but no difference if cut point is 20 ng&lt;/h4>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-status-and-skin-cancer-risk-span-stylecolorf00independent-of-time-outdoorsspan-11-year-prospective-study-in-an-australian-community">Vitamin D status and skin cancer risk &lt;span style="color:#F00;">independent of time outdoors&lt;/span>: 11-year prospective study in an Australian community.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Invest Dermatol. 2013 Mar;133(3):637-41. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/jid.2012.346.">doi: 10.1038/jid.2012.346.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Oct 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van der Pols JC, Russell A, Bauer U, Neale RE, Kimlin MG, Green AC.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunlight, Vitamin D and Skin Cancer – 2nd edition</title><link>/posts/sunlight-vitamin-d-and-skin-cancer-2nd-edition.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunlight-vitamin-d-and-skin-cancer-2nd-edition.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Sunlight-Vitamin-Advances-Experimental-Medicine/dp/0387775730/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1366405896&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=Sunlight%2C+Vitamin+D+and+Skin+Cancer%20">Amazon &lt;/a> 2008 edition&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Approx $200 for entire book or you can buy individual chapters for about $20&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/skin-cancer-scc-minimized-if-get-sun-time-around-noon" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Skin Cancer (SCC) minimized if get sun time around noon – Nov 2015">Skin Cancer (SCC) minimized if get sun time around noon – Nov 2015&lt;/a> some of the same authors&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-suntan-melanoma-and-vitamin-d">Overview Suntan, melanoma and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.landesbioscience.com/curie/chapter/5426/">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for the website&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following are abstracts of many of the chapers&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Melanoma reduces by half the amount of vitamin D activated by the skin</title><link>/posts/melanoma-reduces-by-half-the-amount-of-vitamin-d-activated-by-the-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/melanoma-reduces-by-half-the-amount-of-vitamin-d-activated-by-the-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="expression-of-the-vitamin-d-activating-enzyme-1α-hydroxylase-cyp27b1-decreases-during-melanoma-progression">Expression of the vitamin D-activating enzyme 1α-hydroxylase (CYP27B1) decreases during melanoma progression.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Hum Pathol. 2013 Mar;44(3):374-87. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.humpath.2012.03.031.">doi: 10.1016/j.humpath.2012.03.031.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Sep 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brożyna AA, Jóźwicki W, Janjetovic Z, Slominski AT &lt;a href="mailto:aslominski@uthsc.edu">aslominski@uthsc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Tumor Pathology and Pathomorphology, Oncology Centre-Prof. Franciszek Łukaszczyk Memorial Hospital, The Ludwik Rydygier Collegium Medicum, Nicolaus Copernicus University, 85-796 Bydgoszcz, Poland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1α-Hydroxylase (CYP27B1), the enzyme responsible for the synthesis of the biologically active form of vitamin D (1,25(OH)(2)D(3)), is expressed in the skin. To assess the correlation between progression of melanocytic tumors and CYP27B1, we analyzed its expression in 29 benign nevi, 75 primary cutaneous melanomas, 40 metastases, and 4 re-excision and 6 normal skin biopsies. Immunoreactivity for CYP27B1 was significantly lower in the vertical growth phase and metastatic melanomas (0.6 and 0.5 arbitrary units, respectively) in comparison with nevi and radial growth phase tumors (1.2 and 1.1 arbitrary units, respectively); and expression was reduced in more advanced lesions (Clark levels III-V, Breslow thickness ≥2.1 mm; 0.8 and 0.7 arbitrary units, respectively). There was an inverse correlation between CYP27B1 and Ki-67 expression. Furthermore, CYP27B1 expression was reduced in primary melanomas that created metastases in comparison with non-metastasizing melanomas. Reduced CYP27B1 expression in radial growth phase was related to shorter overall survival (810 versus 982 versus 1151 days in melanomas with absent, low, and high CYP27B1 immunoreactivity), and low CYP27B1 expression in radial growth phase and vertical growth phase was related to shorter disease-free survival (114 versus 339 versus 737 days and 129 versus 307 versus 737 days, respectively, in melanomas with absent, low, and high CYP27B1). Also, CYP27B1 expression was inversely related to melanin in melanoma cells in vivo and melanoma cells cultured in vitro. Thus, reduction of CYP27B1 correlates with melanoma phenotype and behavior, and its lack affects the survival of melanoma patients, indicating a role in the pathogenesis and progression of this cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Merkel cell carcinoma (a rare skin cancer) recurrence 3X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/merkel-cell-carcinoma-a-rare-skin-cancer-recurrence-3x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/merkel-cell-carcinoma-a-rare-skin-cancer-recurrence-3x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-greater-tumor-size-and-poorer-outcome-in-merkel-cell-carcinoma-patients">Vitamin D deficiency is associated with greater tumor size and poorer outcome in Merkel cell carcinoma patients&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. Samimi1,2,3,*, A. Touzé1,2, H. Laude4,5, E. Le Bidre3,6, F. Arnold1,2, A. Carpentier1,2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C. Gardair2,7, A. Carlotti4,5, E. Maubec8, N. Dupin4,5, F. Aubin9, M.F. Avril4,5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>F. Rozenberg4,5, M. Avenel-Audran10, S. Guyetant2,7, G. Lorette1,2,3, L. Machet2,3, P. Coursaget1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Merkel cell polyomavirus has been recognized to be associated with Merkel cell carcinoma (MCC), but the evolution of this cancer probably depends on various factors. Vitamin D deficiency, defined by serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels &amp;lt;50 nmol/L, seems to influence cancer behavior and progression, but has never been assessed in MCC patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunshine: Dangerous or Healthy – Schachter Center 2009</title><link>/posts/sunshine-dangerous-or-healthy-schachter-center-2009.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunshine-dangerous-or-healthy-schachter-center-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sunshine-dangerous-or-healthyhttpwwwschachtercentercomsunshinehtm20-2009">&lt;a href="http://www.schachtercenter.com/sunshine.htm%20">Sunshine: Dangerous or Healthy?&lt;/a> 2009&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>By Tom Petrie, B.S., C.D.N. of Schachter Center&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As with so many health topics in America, the public is often misinformed. Such is the case with the &amp;ldquo;health dangers of sunshine&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-dangers-of-sun-exposure">The Dangers of Sun Exposure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently, some 600,000 new cases of skin cancer are reported every year.(1) Over the years, there have been numerous publications making the claim that sunshine exposure increases the risk of developing skin cancer as well as hastens aging of the skin. It would seem, therefore, that &amp;ldquo;avoiding the sun&amp;rdquo; would be an obvious response to this problem. It is believed that Ultraviolet A rays are the cause of hastened aging and skin cancer while the Ultraviolet B rays are the source of sunburn. The UVB rays are also the source for making Vitamin D in the skin. Melanomas are currently the tenth most common form of cancer in the U.S.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Most German skin cancer doctors recommend both sunscreen and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/most-german-skin-cancer-doctors-recommend-both-sunscreen-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/most-german-skin-cancer-doctors-recommend-both-sunscreen-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-supply-from-sun-or-pill-">Vitamin D supply: from sun or pill? –&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="attitudes-and-recommendation-on-vitamin-d-and-impact-on-sun-protection-practices-among-german-general-practitioners-evaluated-by-the-network-of-dermato-oncologists-onkoderm-ev">Attitudes and recommendation on vitamin D and impact on sun protection practices among German general practitioners evaluated by the network of dermato-oncologists, Onkoderm e.V.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Oncol Lett. 2012 Dec;4(6):1392-1396. Epub 2012 Sep 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reinhold U, Dirschka T, Hartgens K, Kirchesch H, Ostendorf R, Petering H, Prieur H, Krähn-Senftleben G, Malaisse WJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology and Dermatological Oncology, Medical Center Bonn Friedensplatz, Bonn;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recommendations concerning the intake of vitamin D and/or sunlight exposure in the handling of patients with vitamin D deficiency remain a matter of debate. The present study of the German network of dermato-oncologists (Onkoderm e.V.) refers to an inquiry conducted among general practitioners on this and related issues. Based on 448 answers provided to 10 distinct questions, the consulted physicians &lt;strong>recommended vitamin D intake (94% replies)&lt;/strong> and/or exposure to sunlight (63% replies) in their patients with vitamin D deficiency. An average of approximately 26 min daily unprotected exposure to sunlight at midday in spring and summer was recommended. Nevertheless, &lt;strong>91% of the physicians considered the use of creams protecting against sunlight to be judicious&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Melanoma less likely when far from equator</title><link>/posts/melanoma-less-likely-when-far-from-equator.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/melanoma-less-likely-when-far-from-equator.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="biologically-efficient-solar-radiation">Biologically efficient solar radiation:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-production-and-induction-of-cutaneous-malignant-melanoma">Vitamin D production and induction of cutaneous malignant melanoma&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.landesbioscience.com/journals/dermatoendocrinology/article/22941/%20">Dermato Endocrinology Volume 4, Issue 4&lt;/a> October/November/December 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Mantas Grigalavicius, Asta Juzeniene, Zivile Baturaite, Arne Dahlback and Johan Moan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Solar UV (UV) radiation is the main source of vitamin D production and is also the most important environmental risk factor for cutaneous malignant melanoma (CMM) development. In the present study the relationship between daily or seasonal UV radiation doses and vitamin D status, dietary vitamin D intake and CMM incidence rates at different geographical latitudes were investigated. South-North gradients of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) generation and CMM induction were calculated, based on known action spectra, and compared with measured vitamin D levels and epidemiological data on CMM. The relative roles of UVA and UVB in CMM induction are discussed. Latitudinal dependencies of serum 25(OH)D levels and CMM incidence rates can only partly be explained by ambient UV doses. The UV sensitivity is obviously different for different populations. This is well known for CMM, but seems also to be true for vitamin D status. The fact that UV-induced vitamin D may reduce the risk of CMM complicates the discussion. To some extent high dietary vitamin D intake seems to compensate low UV doses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indoor tanning not apparently associated with skin cancer</title><link>/posts/indoor-tanning-not-apparently-associated-with-skin-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/indoor-tanning-not-apparently-associated-with-skin-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Risk of skin cancer vs. risk of low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/risk-of-skin-cancer-vs-risk-of-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/risk-of-skin-cancer-vs-risk-of-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sunlight Vitamin D and Skin Cancer</title><link>/posts/sunlight-vitamin-d-and-skin-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunlight-vitamin-d-and-skin-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.83-97 (15)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Rebecca S. Mason, Jorg Reichrath&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, there is a controversial debate in many scientific and public communities on how much sunlight is appropriate to balance between the positive and negative effects of solar UV-exposure. UV exposure undoubtedly causes DNA damage of skin cells and is a major environmental risk factor for all types of skin cancers. In geographic terms, living in parts of the world with increased erythemal UV or high average annual bright sun results in increased risks of skin cancers, with the greatest increased risk for squamous cell carcinoma, followed by basal cell carcinoma and then melanoma. On the other hand, sunlight exerts positive effects on human health, that are mediated in part via UV-B-mediated cutaneous photosynthesis of vitamin D. It has been estimated that at present, approximately 1 billion people worldwide are vitamin D-deficient or –insufficient. This epidemic causes serious health problems that are still widely under-recognized. Vitamin D deficiency leads to well documented problems for bone and muscle function. There are also associations between vitamin D-deficiency and increased incidence of and/or unfavourable outcome for a broad variety of independent diseases, including various types of malignancies (e.g. colon-, skin-, and breast cancer), autoimmune diseases, infectious diseases, and cardiovascular diseases. In this review, the present literature is analyzed to summarize our present knowledge about the important relationship of sunlight, vitamin D and skin cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red-haired mice can get melanoma without UV</title><link>/posts/red-haired-mice-can-get-melanoma-without-uv.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/red-haired-mice-can-get-melanoma-without-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="an-ultraviolet-radiation-independent-pathway-to-melanoma-carcinogenesis-in-the-red-hairfair-skin-background">An ultraviolet-radiation-independent pathway to melanoma carcinogenesis in the red hair/fair skin background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Devarati Mitra,	 Xi Luo,	 Ann Morgan,	 Jin Wang,	 Mai P. Hoang,	 Jennifer Lo,	 Candace R. Guerrero,	 Jochen K. Lennerz,	 Martin C. Mihm,	 Jennifer A. Wargo,	 Kathleen C. Robinson, Suprabha P. Devi,	 Jillian C. Vanover,	 John A. D’Orazio,	 Martin McMahon,	 Marcus W. Bosenberg,	 Kevin M. Haigis,	 Daniel A. Haber,	 Yinsheng Wang	 &amp;amp; David E. Fisher&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AffiliationsContributionsCorresponding author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v491/n7424/full/nature11624.html">Nature 491, 449–453 (15 November 2012) doi:10.1038/nature11624&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer - Skin</title><link>/posts/cancer-skin.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-skin.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects mouse from skin cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-mouse-from-skin-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-mouse-from-skin-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects DNA against UV skin damage – 5 studies 2012-2013</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-dna-against-uv-skin-damage-5-studies-2012-2013.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-dna-against-uv-skin-damage-5-studies-2012-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Extensive proof that Vitamin D protects DNA in skin from UV damage&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Observation:&lt;/strong> People get a sunburn when getting lots of sun after months of little sun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Question:&lt;/strong> Would they not get a sunburn if they first stocked up on vitamin D?&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sunlight-and-vitamin-d-affect-dna-damage-cell-division-and-cell-death-in-human-lymphocytes-a-cross-sectional-study-in-south-australia">Sunlight and vitamin D affect DNA damage, cell division and cell death in human lymphocytes: a cross-sectional study in South Australia.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3-enhances-cellular-defences-against-uv-induced-oxidative-and-other-forms-of-dna-damage-in-skin">1?,25 Dihydroxyvitamin D(3) enhances cellular defences against UV-induced oxidative and other forms of DNA damage in skin.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#perspective-protective-actions-of-vitamin-d-in-uvb-induced-skin-cancer">Perspective Protective actions of vitamin D in UVB induced skin cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#active-vitamin-d-protects-skin-against-sunlight-damage--nov-2012">Active vitamin D protects skin against sunlight damage – Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-death-by-sunshine">Vitamin D and Death by Sunshine&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biologically-efficient-solar-radiation-vitamin-d-production-and-induction-of-cutaneous-malignant-melanoma">Biologically efficient solar radiation: Vitamin D production and induction of cutaneous malignant melanoma&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="sunlight-and-vitamin-d-affect-dna-damage-cell-division-and-cell-death-in-human-lymphocytes-a-cross-sectional-study-in-south-australia">Sunlight and vitamin D affect DNA damage, cell division and cell death in human lymphocytes: a cross-sectional study in South Australia.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mutagenesis. 2012 Sep;27(5):609-14. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/mutage/ges026.">doi: 10.1093/mutage/ges026.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Apr 29.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: vitamin D suppresses skin cancer</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-suppresses-skin-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-suppresses-skin-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>No association found between melanoma and low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/no-association-found-between-melanoma-and-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-association-found-between-melanoma-and-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Pre-diagnostic circulating vitamin D and risk of melanoma in men.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(4):e35112. Epub 2012 Apr 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Major JM, Kiruthu C, Weinstein SJ, Horst RL, Snyder K, Virtamo J, Albanes D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Cancer Epidemiology and Genetics, National Cancer Institute, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland, United States of America. &lt;a href="mailto:jacqueline.major@nih.gov">jacqueline.major@nih.gov&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Various studies have examined the association between serum vitamin D levels and different cancers; however, this is the first prospective study of this association with melanoma risk. The aim of this study is to investigate the association between serum vitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and melanoma in a cohort of older, middle-aged Finnish male smokers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Too much UVB: skin cancer, too little UVB: other cancers due to low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/too-much-uvb-skin-cancer-too-little-uvb-other-cancers-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/too-much-uvb-skin-cancer-too-little-uvb-other-cancers-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="hope-and-challenge-the-importance-of-ultraviolet-uv-radiation-for-cutaneous-vitamin-d-synthesis-and-skin-cancer">Hope and challenge: The importance of ultraviolet (UV) radiation for cutaneous Vitamin D synthesis and skin cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>April 2012, Vol. 72, No. S243 , Pages 112-119&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jörg Reichrath &amp;amp; Sandra Reichrath&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Klinik für Dermatologie, Venerologie und Allergologie, Universitätsklinikum des Saarlandes, 66421 Homburg/Saar, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Jörg Reichrath, Klinik für Dermatologie, Venerologie und Allergologie, Universitätsklinikum des Saarlandes, D-66421 Homburg/Saar, Germany. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:joerg.reichrath@uks.eu">joerg.reichrath@uks.eu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Solar ultraviolet (UV)-radiation is the most important environmental risk factor for the development of non-melanoma skin cancer (most importantly basal and squamous cell carcinomas), that represent the most common malignancies in Caucasian populations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Zealand doctors are starting to prescribe more sunshine</title><link>/posts/new-zealand-doctors-are-starting-to-prescribe-more-sunshine.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/new-zealand-doctors-are-starting-to-prescribe-more-sunshine.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypothesis – Increasing Folate or vitamin D decreases probability of skin cancer</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-increasing-folate-or-vitamin-d-decreases-probability-of-skin-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-increasing-folate-or-vitamin-d-decreases-probability-of-skin-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Seniors, like everyone else, need vitamin D and should avoid sunburns – 2011</title><link>/posts/seniors-like-everyone-else-need-vitamin-d-and-should-avoid-sunburns-2011.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-like-everyone-else-need-vitamin-d-and-should-avoid-sunburns-2011.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Dermatologist's Perspective on Vitamin D - Mayo Clinic</title><link>/posts/a-dermatologists-perspective-on-vitamin-d-mayo-clinic.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-dermatologists-perspective-on-vitamin-d-mayo-clinic.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>UVB, Smoking and second cancers after melanoma</title><link>/posts/uvb-smoking-and-second-cancers-after-melanoma.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-smoking-and-second-cancers-after-melanoma.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="on-the-roles-of-solar-ultraviolet-irradiance-and-smoking-on-the-diagnosis-of-second-cancers-after-diagnosis-of-melanoma">On the roles of solar ultraviolet irradiance and smoking on the diagnosis of second cancers after diagnosis of melanoma&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="for-debate">For Debate&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dermato Endocrinology Volume 4, Issue 1 January/February/March 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">(Note: The words are in original order at the bottom of this page)&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several recent papers have reported &lt;strong>standardized incidence ratios (SIRs)&lt;/strong> for second cancers after diagnosis of cutaneous malignant melanoma.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This review divides the types of cancer into five types:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many Organ transplants cause skin cancer – what is the role of UV</title><link>/posts/many-organ-transplants-cause-skin-cancer-what-is-the-role-of-uv.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-organ-transplants-cause-skin-cancer-what-is-the-role-of-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="photoprotection-in-transplant-recipients">Photoprotection in transplant recipients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Curr Probl Dermatol. 2012;43:171-96. Epub 2012 Feb 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Surber C, Pittelkow M, Lautenschlager S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, University Hospital of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skin cancers remain the most commonly diagnosed neoplasms among organ transplant recipients (OTRs), comprising nearly 40% of all posttransplant malignancies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The occurrence of skin tumors has a considerable impact on the quality of life and the overall survival of OTRs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet radiation (UVR) is the major environmental cause of nonmelanoma skin cancers, and it is therefore pivotal to protect the skin from UVR in order to prevent de novo and progression of preinvasive and invasive malignancies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nonmelanoma Skin Cancer associated with more than 15 ng of vitamin D in HMO Cohort</title><link>/posts/nonmelanoma-skin-cancer-associated-with-more-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d-in-hmo-cohort.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nonmelanoma-skin-cancer-associated-with-more-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d-in-hmo-cohort.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-nonmelanoma-skin-cancer-in-a-health-maintenance-organization-cohort">Vitamin D and Nonmelanoma Skin Cancer in a Health Maintenance Organization Cohort&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Melody J. Eide, MD, MPH; Dayna A. Johnson, MSW, MPH; Gordon R. Jacobsen, MS; Richard J. Krajenta, BS; D. Sudhaker Rao, MB,BS; Henry W. Lim, MD; Christine C. Johnson, MPH, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>(Note: all of the authors are part of Kaiser HMO)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arch Dermatol. 2011;147(12):1379-1384. doi:10.1001/archdermatol.2011.231&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective To examine the association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) with the risk of nonmelanoma skin cancer (NMSC), defined as squamous cell carcinoma (SCC) and basal cell carcinoma (BCC).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Head and neck cancer occurrence and deaths associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/head-and-neck-cancer-occurrence-and-deaths-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/head-and-neck-cancer-occurrence-and-deaths-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-is-associated-with-disease-free-survival-and-overall-survival-time-in-patients-with-squamous-cell-carcinoma-of-the-upper-aerodigestive-tract">Vitamin D status is associated with disease-free survival and overall survival time in patients with squamous cell carcinoma of the upper aerodigestive tract.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2011 Aug;268(8):1201-4. Epub 2011 Jan 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gugatschka M, Kiesler K, Obermayer-Pietsch B, Groselj-Strele A, Griesbacher A, Friedrich G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Phoniatrics, ENT University Hospital Graz, Medical University Graz, Auenbruggerplatz 26-28, 8036 Graz, Austria. &lt;a href="mailto:markus.gugatschka@klinikum-graz.at">markus.gugatschka@klinikum-graz.at&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Considerable clinical and experimental data suggest that vitamin D plays a role in pathogenesis and progression of cancer; nevertheless clinical data for head and neck squamous cell carcinoma (HNSCC) are not available. The aim of our study was to associate tumor and clinical characteristics with status of vitamin D &lt;span>[25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D)]&lt;/span>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – worldwide increase in Melanoma due to UVA</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-worldwide-increase-in-melanoma-due-to-uva.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-worldwide-increase-in-melanoma-due-to-uva.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Use of tanning beds would reduce associated deaths by 10X</title><link>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-sun-sunbeds-and-health">Vitamin D, sun, sunbeds and health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Oct 24:1-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moan J, Baturaite Z, Juzeniene A, Porojnicu AC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, The Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Ullernchausseen 70, Montebello N-0310 Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To review the health effects of solar radiation, sunbeds and vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DESIGN: The literature was searched in the electronic database MEDLINE to indentify published data between 1981 and 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Circadian rhythm affects skin cancer risk in mice</title><link>/posts/circadian-rhythm-affects-skin-cancer-risk-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/circadian-rhythm-affects-skin-cancer-risk-in-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="oct-25-2011httpwwwabcnetausciencearticles201110253346713htm">&lt;a href="http://www.abc.net.au/science/articles/2011/10/25/3346713.htm">Oct 25, 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dr Aziz Sancar, of the University of North Carolina Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center, and colleagues, report their findings online this week in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Our research would suggest that restricting sunbathing or visits to the tanning booth to morning hours would reduce the risk of skin cancer in humans,&amp;rdquo; says Sancar, and colleague Professor Sarah Graham Kenan from the UNC School of Medicine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancers and Vitamin D Council</title><link>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>UVA most likely causes melanoma to progress</title><link>/posts/uva-most-likely-causes-melanoma-to-progress.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uva-most-likely-causes-melanoma-to-progress.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-photobiology-of-melanocytes-modulates-the-impact-of-uva-on-sunlight-induced-melanoma">The photobiology of melanocytes modulates the impact of UVA on sunlight-induced melanoma&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Photochemical &amp;amp; Photobiological Sciences; DOI: 10.1039/C1PP05146F&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 16 May 2011, Accepted 11 Aug 2011; First published on the web 02 Sep 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David Mitchell and André Fernandez&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet radiation is responsible for melanoma. In this review, we address the role of the different UV spectra in melanoma. The data suggest that only UVB is capable of initiating melanoma, and that both UVA and UVB are involved in the progression of the disease. The etiology of sunlight-induced melanoma may be different for chronically-exposed tumors and for those located on body surfaces with considerably less exposure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>People who were outdoors more got more skin cancer</title><link>/posts/people-who-were-outdoors-more-got-more-skin-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-who-were-outdoors-more-got-more-skin-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-nonmelanoma-skin-cancer-in-a-health-maintenance-organization-cohort">Vitamin D and Nonmelanoma Skin Cancer in a Health Maintenance Organization Cohort.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arch Dermatol. 2011 Aug 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eide MJ, Johnson DA, Jacobsen GR, Krajenta RJ, Rao DS, Lim HW, Johnson CC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Public Health Sciences (Drs Eide and Johnson, Ms Johnson, and Mssrs Jacobsen and Krajenta), and Internal Medicine (Dr Rao) and Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes, and Bone and Mineral Disorders (Dr Rao), Henry Ford Hospital, Detroit, Michigan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To examine the association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) with the risk of nonmelanoma skin cancer (NMSC), defined as squamous cell carcinoma (SCC) and basal cell carcinoma (BCC).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sun exposure is associated with increased survival from melanoma – 2005</title><link>/posts/sun-exposure-is-associated-with-increased-survival-from-melanoma-2005.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sun-exposure-is-associated-with-increased-survival-from-melanoma-2005.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Native American Indians mostly died of skin cancer (nope)</title><link>/posts/native-american-indians-mostly-died-of-skin-cancer-nope.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/native-american-indians-mostly-died-of-skin-cancer-nope.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The beginning of : &lt;a href="http://arizonaadvancedmedicine.com/articles/skin_cancer.html">Vitamin D, Sun, Skin Cancer&lt;/a> probably late 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By Arizona Center for Advanced Medicine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1) Centuries ago, when Vikings and other European seafarers took to the high seas for years at a time, they pioneered new trade routes and they mostly died of skin cancer.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2)Native American Indians, living mostly outdoors, also mostly died of skin cancer.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What?&lt;br>
You never heard that?&lt;br>
Right. &lt;span style="color:#F00;">Because it didn&amp;rsquo;t happen&lt;/span>.&lt;br>
Here are a few things that really did happen:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A vitamin D analog reduced UV generated skin cancer in mice</title><link>/posts/a-vitamin-d-analog-reduced-uv-generated-skin-cancer-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-vitamin-d-analog-reduced-uv-generated-skin-cancer-in-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="alpha25oh2-vitamin-d-and-a-non-genomic-vitamin-d-analog-inhibit-ultraviolet-radiation-induced-skin-carcinogenesis">{alpha},25(OH)2-vitamin D and a non-genomic vitamin D analog inhibit ultraviolet radiation-induced skin carcinogenesis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Cancer Prev Res (Phila). 2011 Jul 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dixon KM, Norman AW, Sequeira VB, Mohan R, Rybchyn MS, Reeve VE, Halliday GM, Mason RS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Discipline of Physiology and Bosch Institute, The University of Sydney.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exposure to ultraviolet radiation (UVR) can lead to a range of deleterious responses in the skin. An important form of damage is the DNA photo-lesion cyclobutane pyrimidine dimer (CPD). CPDs can be highly mutagenic if not repaired prior to cell division and can lead to UVR-induced immunosuppression making them potentially carcinogenic. UVR exposure also produces vitamin D, a pre-hormone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium with vitamin D decreased risk of subsequent skin cancer by 2X</title><link>/posts/calcium-with-vitamin-d-decreased-risk-of-subsequent-skin-cancer-by-2x.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-with-vitamin-d-decreased-risk-of-subsequent-skin-cancer-by-2x.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Melanoma and Vitamin D genes - multiple papers</title><link>/posts/melanoma-and-vitamin-d-genes-multiple-papers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/melanoma-and-vitamin-d-genes-multiple-papers.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki-summary-melanoma-27-more-likely-with-bsmi-variant-of-vitamin-d-receptor-2011">VitaminDWiki Summary: Melanoma 27% more likely with BsmI variant of vitamin D receptor (2011)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#melanoma-risk-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-march-2014">Melanoma risk is associated with vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms (March 2014)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="vitamindwiki-summary-melanoma-27-more-likely-with-bsmi-variant-of-vitamin-d-receptor-2011">VitaminDWiki Summary: Melanoma 27% more likely with BsmI variant of vitamin D receptor (2011)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sun exposure, vitamin D receptor polymorphisms FokI and BsmI and risk of multiple primary melanoma&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiol. 2011 May 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mandelcorn-Monson R, Marrett L, Kricker A, Armstrong BK, Orlow I, Goumas C, Paine S, Rosso S, Thomas N, Millikan RC, Pole JD, Cotignola J, Rosen C, Kanetsky PA, Lee-Taylor J, Begg CB, Berwick M.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If avoiding sun for medical reasons you need oral vitamin D</title><link>/posts/if-avoiding-sun-for-medical-reasons-you-need-oral-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-avoiding-sun-for-medical-reasons-you-need-oral-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="seasonal-variations-in-vitamin-d-levels-in-melanoma-patients-a-single-centre-prospective-pilot-comparative-study">Seasonal variations in vitamin D levels in melanoma patients: a single-centre prospective pilot comparative study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2011 Apr 27. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-3083.2011.04087.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1468-3083.2011.04087.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Failla V, Cavalier E, El Hayderi L, Paurobally D, Chapelle J, Dezfoulian B, Nikkels A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Dermatology Clinical Chemistry, University Hospital Sart Tilman, University of Liège, Liège, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background? More than 90% of vitamin D synthesis is dependent on UV exposure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photosensitive disorders such as lupus erythematosus, protoporphyria and xeroderma require strict sun avoidance, and vitamin D deficiency has been demonstrated in these patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perhaps 28-40 ng of vitamin D would be good for Melanoma patients</title><link>/posts/perhaps-28-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-would-be-good-for-melanoma-patients.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/perhaps-28-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-would-be-good-for-melanoma-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="melanoma-and-vitamin-d">Melanoma and vitamin D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Mol Oncol. 2011 Feb 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Field S, Newton-Bishop JA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Section of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Leeds Institute of Molecular Medicine, University of Leeds, Leeds LS97TF, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a fat-soluble steroid hormone, which is essential to health and for which epidemiological studies suggest a role in autoimmune disease, infections, cardiovascular disease and cancer. It is ingested in foods such as oily fish and supplements, so that average levels vary between countries, but most individuals worldwide make most of their vitamin D as a result of the effects of sun exposure on the skin.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>