<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer - Skin on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer---skin.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer - Skin on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer---skin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hypothesis – worldwide increase in Melanoma due to UVA</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-worldwide-increase-in-melanoma-due-to-uva.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-worldwide-increase-in-melanoma-due-to-uva.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Use of tanning beds would reduce associated deaths by 10X</title><link>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-sun-sunbeds-and-health">Vitamin D, sun, sunbeds and health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Oct 24:1-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moan J, Baturaite Z, Juzeniene A, Porojnicu AC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, The Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Ullernchausseen 70, Montebello N-0310 Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To review the health effects of solar radiation, sunbeds and vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DESIGN: The literature was searched in the electronic database MEDLINE to indentify published data between 1981 and 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Circadian rhythm affects skin cancer risk in mice</title><link>/posts/circadian-rhythm-affects-skin-cancer-risk-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/circadian-rhythm-affects-skin-cancer-risk-in-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="oct-25-2011httpwwwabcnetausciencearticles201110253346713htm">&lt;a href="http://www.abc.net.au/science/articles/2011/10/25/3346713.htm">Oct 25, 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dr Aziz Sancar, of the University of North Carolina Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center, and colleagues, report their findings online this week in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Our research would suggest that restricting sunbathing or visits to the tanning booth to morning hours would reduce the risk of skin cancer in humans,&amp;rdquo; says Sancar, and colleague Professor Sarah Graham Kenan from the UNC School of Medicine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancers and Vitamin D Council</title><link>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>UVA most likely causes melanoma to progress</title><link>/posts/uva-most-likely-causes-melanoma-to-progress.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uva-most-likely-causes-melanoma-to-progress.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-photobiology-of-melanocytes-modulates-the-impact-of-uva-on-sunlight-induced-melanoma">The photobiology of melanocytes modulates the impact of UVA on sunlight-induced melanoma&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Photochemical &amp;amp; Photobiological Sciences; DOI: 10.1039/C1PP05146F&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 16 May 2011, Accepted 11 Aug 2011; First published on the web 02 Sep 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David Mitchell and André Fernandez&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet radiation is responsible for melanoma. In this review, we address the role of the different UV spectra in melanoma. The data suggest that only UVB is capable of initiating melanoma, and that both UVA and UVB are involved in the progression of the disease. The etiology of sunlight-induced melanoma may be different for chronically-exposed tumors and for those located on body surfaces with considerably less exposure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>People who were outdoors more got more skin cancer</title><link>/posts/people-who-were-outdoors-more-got-more-skin-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-who-were-outdoors-more-got-more-skin-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-nonmelanoma-skin-cancer-in-a-health-maintenance-organization-cohort">Vitamin D and Nonmelanoma Skin Cancer in a Health Maintenance Organization Cohort.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arch Dermatol. 2011 Aug 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eide MJ, Johnson DA, Jacobsen GR, Krajenta RJ, Rao DS, Lim HW, Johnson CC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Public Health Sciences (Drs Eide and Johnson, Ms Johnson, and Mssrs Jacobsen and Krajenta), and Internal Medicine (Dr Rao) and Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes, and Bone and Mineral Disorders (Dr Rao), Henry Ford Hospital, Detroit, Michigan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To examine the association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) with the risk of nonmelanoma skin cancer (NMSC), defined as squamous cell carcinoma (SCC) and basal cell carcinoma (BCC).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sun exposure is associated with increased survival from melanoma – 2005</title><link>/posts/sun-exposure-is-associated-with-increased-survival-from-melanoma-2005.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sun-exposure-is-associated-with-increased-survival-from-melanoma-2005.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Native American Indians mostly died of skin cancer (nope)</title><link>/posts/native-american-indians-mostly-died-of-skin-cancer-nope.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/native-american-indians-mostly-died-of-skin-cancer-nope.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The beginning of : &lt;a href="http://arizonaadvancedmedicine.com/articles/skin_cancer.html">Vitamin D, Sun, Skin Cancer&lt;/a> probably late 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By Arizona Center for Advanced Medicine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1) Centuries ago, when Vikings and other European seafarers took to the high seas for years at a time, they pioneered new trade routes and they mostly died of skin cancer.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2)Native American Indians, living mostly outdoors, also mostly died of skin cancer.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What?&lt;br>
You never heard that?&lt;br>
Right. &lt;span style="color:#F00;">Because it didn&amp;rsquo;t happen&lt;/span>.&lt;br>
Here are a few things that really did happen:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A vitamin D analog reduced UV generated skin cancer in mice</title><link>/posts/a-vitamin-d-analog-reduced-uv-generated-skin-cancer-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-vitamin-d-analog-reduced-uv-generated-skin-cancer-in-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="alpha25oh2-vitamin-d-and-a-non-genomic-vitamin-d-analog-inhibit-ultraviolet-radiation-induced-skin-carcinogenesis">{alpha},25(OH)2-vitamin D and a non-genomic vitamin D analog inhibit ultraviolet radiation-induced skin carcinogenesis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Cancer Prev Res (Phila). 2011 Jul 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dixon KM, Norman AW, Sequeira VB, Mohan R, Rybchyn MS, Reeve VE, Halliday GM, Mason RS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Discipline of Physiology and Bosch Institute, The University of Sydney.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exposure to ultraviolet radiation (UVR) can lead to a range of deleterious responses in the skin. An important form of damage is the DNA photo-lesion cyclobutane pyrimidine dimer (CPD). CPDs can be highly mutagenic if not repaired prior to cell division and can lead to UVR-induced immunosuppression making them potentially carcinogenic. UVR exposure also produces vitamin D, a pre-hormone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium with vitamin D decreased risk of subsequent skin cancer by 2X</title><link>/posts/calcium-with-vitamin-d-decreased-risk-of-subsequent-skin-cancer-by-2x.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-with-vitamin-d-decreased-risk-of-subsequent-skin-cancer-by-2x.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Melanoma and Vitamin D genes - multiple papers</title><link>/posts/melanoma-and-vitamin-d-genes-multiple-papers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/melanoma-and-vitamin-d-genes-multiple-papers.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki-summary-melanoma-27-more-likely-with-bsmi-variant-of-vitamin-d-receptor-2011">VitaminDWiki Summary: Melanoma 27% more likely with BsmI variant of vitamin D receptor (2011)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#melanoma-risk-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-march-2014">Melanoma risk is associated with vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms (March 2014)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="vitamindwiki-summary-melanoma-27-more-likely-with-bsmi-variant-of-vitamin-d-receptor-2011">VitaminDWiki Summary: Melanoma 27% more likely with BsmI variant of vitamin D receptor (2011)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sun exposure, vitamin D receptor polymorphisms FokI and BsmI and risk of multiple primary melanoma&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiol. 2011 May 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mandelcorn-Monson R, Marrett L, Kricker A, Armstrong BK, Orlow I, Goumas C, Paine S, Rosso S, Thomas N, Millikan RC, Pole JD, Cotignola J, Rosen C, Kanetsky PA, Lee-Taylor J, Begg CB, Berwick M.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If avoiding sun for medical reasons you need oral vitamin D</title><link>/posts/if-avoiding-sun-for-medical-reasons-you-need-oral-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-avoiding-sun-for-medical-reasons-you-need-oral-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="seasonal-variations-in-vitamin-d-levels-in-melanoma-patients-a-single-centre-prospective-pilot-comparative-study">Seasonal variations in vitamin D levels in melanoma patients: a single-centre prospective pilot comparative study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2011 Apr 27. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-3083.2011.04087.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1468-3083.2011.04087.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Failla V, Cavalier E, El Hayderi L, Paurobally D, Chapelle J, Dezfoulian B, Nikkels A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Dermatology Clinical Chemistry, University Hospital Sart Tilman, University of Liège, Liège, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background? More than 90% of vitamin D synthesis is dependent on UV exposure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photosensitive disorders such as lupus erythematosus, protoporphyria and xeroderma require strict sun avoidance, and vitamin D deficiency has been demonstrated in these patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perhaps 28-40 ng of vitamin D would be good for Melanoma patients</title><link>/posts/perhaps-28-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-would-be-good-for-melanoma-patients.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/perhaps-28-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-would-be-good-for-melanoma-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="melanoma-and-vitamin-d">Melanoma and vitamin D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Mol Oncol. 2011 Feb 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Field S, Newton-Bishop JA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Section of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Leeds Institute of Molecular Medicine, University of Leeds, Leeds LS97TF, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a fat-soluble steroid hormone, which is essential to health and for which epidemiological studies suggest a role in autoimmune disease, infections, cardiovascular disease and cancer. It is ingested in foods such as oily fish and supplements, so that average levels vary between countries, but most individuals worldwide make most of their vitamin D as a result of the effects of sun exposure on the skin.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>