<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pain - Chronic on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/pain---chronic.html</link><description>Recent content in Pain - Chronic on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/pain---chronic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Most immigrant women in Sweden had little vitamin D and lots of muscle pain</title><link>/posts/most-immigrant-women-in-sweden-had-little-vitamin-d-and-lots-of-muscle-pain.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/most-immigrant-women-in-sweden-had-little-vitamin-d-and-lots-of-muscle-pain.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-intake-and-status-in-immigrant-and-native-swedish-women-a-study-at-a-primary-health-care-centre-located-at-60on-in-sweden">Vitamin D intake and status in immigrant and native Swedish women: a study at a primary health care centre located at 60oN in Sweden&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Food &amp;amp; Nutrition Research eISSN 1654-661X&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Åsa Andersson, Anne Björk, Per Kristiansson, Gunnar Johansson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Immigration to Sweden from lower latitude countries has increased in recent years. Studies in the general population in other Nordic countries have demonstrated that these groups are at risk of developing vitamin D deficiency, but studies in primary health care patients are rare.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Chronic Pain: Promising Correlates</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-pain-promising-correlates.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-pain-promising-correlates.html</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>Colleen E. Nadolski, RN, MSN, ANP-C&lt;/b>&lt;br />&lt;i>Adult Nurse Practitioner, Home-Based Primary Care, Cedar Park, Texas&lt;/i>, 7/18/2012&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;strong>&lt;span style="font-size:12px;">&lt;a href="http://www.uspharmacist.com/content/d/featured%20articles/c/35567/">&lt;span style="color:#0000cd;">&lt;em>US Pharm&lt;/em>. 2012;37(7):42-44.&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="p4">
&lt;p>How we think about the etiology and treatment of chronic pain varies considerably depending on the type or description of pain, the history of injury or metabolic disorder, the site of pain, what makes it better or worse, and the age of the patient. In primary care, we frequently determine a vitamin B&lt;sub>12&lt;/sub> level for patients with neuropathy, and we know that replacing or repleting B&lt;sub>12&lt;/sub> can potentially reverse neuropathic pain. Similarly, in patients presenting with depression, a thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH) level is generally determined prior to starting a patient on an antidepressant, as it is well known that abnormal TSH levels can cause various mental health symptoms. As will be discussed in this article, consideration of applicable research literature suggests that vitamin D levels should be determined in patients who present with chronic pain, as there are diverse pain syndromes that seem to occur in the presence of low vitamin D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sleep disorder and nonspecific pain implies low vitamin D, especially if dark skin</title><link>/posts/sleep-disorder-and-nonspecific-pain-implies-low-vitamin-d-especially-if-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sleep-disorder-and-nonspecific-pain-implies-low-vitamin-d-especially-if-dark-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="nonspecific-pain-is-a-marker-for-hypovitaminosis-d-in-patients-undergoing-evaluation-for-sleep-disorders-a-pilot-study">Nonspecific pain is a marker for hypovitaminosis D in patients undergoing evaluation for sleep disorders: a pilot study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Published Date March 2013 Volume 2013:5 Pages 37 - 42, DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.2147/NSS.S42641">http://dx.doi.org/10.2147/NSS.S42641&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David E McCarty,1 Aronkumar Reddy,1 Quinton Keigley,2 Paul Y Kim,1 Stephen Cohen,2 Andrew A Marino1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Sleep Medicine, Department of Neurology, Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Medicine, Louisiana State University, Shreveport, LA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: The purpose of this cross-sectional study was to test the hypothesis that serum vitamin D levels are abnormally low in sleep clinic patients admitting to chronic nonspecific musculoskeletal pain and to assess the associated risk factors. A secondary purpose was to identify a clinical biomarker for vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Quality of Life</title><link>/posts/quality-of-life.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/quality-of-life.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="qol-computation-based-on-400-850-iu-vitamin-d--oct-2014">QoL computation based on 400-850 IU Vitamin D – Oct 2014&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Finding the Optimum Scenario in Risk-benefit Assessment: An Example on Vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>European Journal of Nutrition &amp;amp; Food Safety, ISSN: 2347-5641 ,Vol.: 4, Issue.: 4 (October-December)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>F. L. Berjia1*, J. Hoekstra2, H. Verhagen2,3, M. Poulsen4, R. Andersen5 and M. Nauta1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Epidemiology and Risk Modeling, The National Food Institute, Technical University of Denmark, Mørkhøj Bygade 19, 2860 Søborg, Denmark.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D injections of a total of 1,800,000 IU reduced shinbone tenderness</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-injections-of-a-total-of-1800000-iu-reduced-shinbone-tenderness.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-injections-of-a-total-of-1800000-iu-reduced-shinbone-tenderness.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="tibial-tenderness-identifies-secondary-hyperparathyroidism-responding-to-high-dose-vitamin-d-in-pakistani-women">Tibial Tenderness Identifies Secondary Hyperparathyroidism Responding to High Dose Vitamin D in Pakistani Women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2013 Feb 20:1-20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ali B, Butt A, Fatima A, McDonnell ME, Masud F.; Department of Medicine, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To assess the utility of &lt;strong>anterior tibial tenderness&lt;/strong> (ATT) measured by visual analogue score (VAS) as a clinical diagnostic tool for vitamin D deficiency in a high-risk population of Pakistani women&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: ATT using a VAS was assessed in 75 premenopausal women, ages 17-56 (mean 41.3) with generalized aches and pains and calcium of less than 11.0mg/dl (normal: 8-11) at a tertiary care center in Lahore, Pakistan. This was followed by administration of &lt;strong>1.8 million units of vitamin D3&lt;/strong> in divided doses. ATT, vitamin D and parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels were checked before and after the injections. Correlation between ATT, vitamin D and PTH as well as change in ATT, vitamin D and (PTH) following supplementation was determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduced skeletal pain in 85 percent of the patients</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-skeletal-pain-in-85-percent-of-the-patients.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-skeletal-pain-in-85-percent-of-the-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-vitamin-d-deficiency-associated-with-non-specific-musculoskeletal-pain">Is Vitamin D Deficiency associated with Non Specific Musculoskeletal Pain?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Glob J Health Sci. 2012 Nov 11;5(1):107-11. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5539/gjhs.v5n1p107.">doi: 10.5539/gjhs.v5n1p107.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abbasi M, Hashemipour S, Hajmanuchehri F, Kazemifar AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Metabolic Diseases Research Center, Qazvin University of Medical Science, Qazvin, Iran. &lt;a href="mailto:Hashemipour.sima@yahoo.com">Hashemipour.sima@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUNDS: Vitamin D deficiency is common worldwide, including Iran. It has been suggested that vitamin D deficiency is associated with non-specific musculoskeletal pain. The aim of this study is evaluation of the association of musculoskeletal pain with vitamin D deficiency and the response of the patients to vitamin D supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>150,000 IU vitamin D reduced pain in immigrants – RCT</title><link>/posts/150000-iu-vitamin-d-reduced-pain-in-immigrants-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/150000-iu-vitamin-d-reduced-pain-in-immigrants-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-for-nonspecific-musculoskeletal-pain-in-non-western-immigrants">Vitamin D Supplementation for Nonspecific Musculoskeletal Pain in Non-Western Immigrants:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A Randomized Controlled Trial&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ann Fam Med November/December 2012 vol. 10 no. 6 547-555&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ferdinand Schreuder , and colleagues&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many non-Western immigrants suffer musculoskeletal pain that is hard to treat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study examines the effect of high-dose vitamin D on nonspecific persistent musculoskeletal complaints in vitamin-D-deficient non-Western immigrants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What This Study Found&lt;/p>
&lt;p>High-dose vitamin D supplementation may have a positive effect on persistent musculoskeletal pain among vitamin D-deficient patients. A study of 84 non-Western immigrants in Western Europe, a population prone to vitamin D deficiency and musculoskeletal problems, revealed a small positive effect on pain 6 weeks after supplementation with 150,000 IU of Vitamin D3 on vitamin D-deficient patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pain - chronic</title><link>/posts/pain-chronic.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pain-chronic.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cbd-reduced-thumb-osteoarthitis-pain-from-5-to-2-in-just-two-weeks---rct--may-2022">CBD reduced thumb osteoarthitis pain from 5 to 2 in just two weeks - RCT May 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="cbd-reduced-thumb-osteoarthitis-pain-from-5-to-2-in-just-two-weeks---rct--may-2022">CBD reduced thumb osteoarthitis pain from 5 to 2 in just two weeks - RCT May 2022&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A Randomized Controlled Trial of Topical Cannabidiol for the Treatment of Thumb Basal Joint Arthritis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Behind $31 paywall &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhsa.2022.03.002">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhsa.2022.03.002&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Described in &lt;a href="ttps://www.consumerlab.com/reviews/cbd-oil-hemp-review/cbd-oil/">ConsumerLab report on CBD&lt;/a> - free 5 day trial&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/excellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlab" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Excellent reviews of supplements at ConsumerLab">Excellent reviews of supplements at ConsumerLab&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RADICAL discussion of vitamin D and Nonspecific Musculoskeletal Pain</title><link>/posts/radical-discussion-of-vitamin-d-and-nonspecific-musculoskeletal-pain.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/radical-discussion-of-vitamin-d-and-nonspecific-musculoskeletal-pain.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blacks had lower vitamin D and more quantifiable pain than whites with knee osteoarthritis</title><link>/posts/blacks-had-lower-vitamin-d-and-more-quantifiable-pain-than-whites-with-knee-osteoarthritis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-had-lower-vitamin-d-and-more-quantifiable-pain-than-whites-with-knee-osteoarthritis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-race-and-experimental-pain-sensitivity-in-older-adults-with-knee-osteoarthritis">Vitamin D, race, and experimental pain sensitivity in older adults with knee osteoarthritis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Arthritis &amp;amp; Rheumatism DOI: 10.1002/art.37687&lt;/p>
&lt;p>T.L. Glover1,3,*, B.R. Goodin2, A.L. Horgas3, L.L. Kindler4, C.D. King1, K.T. Sibille1, C.A. Peloquin5, J.L. Riley III1, R. Staud6, L.A. Bradley7, R.B. Fillingim1,8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 University of Florida, College of Dentistry, Community Dentistry &amp;amp; Behavioral Science&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 University of Florida, College of Dentistry, Comprehensive Center for Pain Research&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 University of Florida, College of Nursing&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer medicine pain reduced with 4300 IU vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-medicine-pain-reduced-with-4300-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-medicine-pain-reduced-with-4300-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="highlight-from-vitamin-d-may-help-breast-cancer-survivors-stay-on-track-httpwwwmedscapecomviewarticle76627320medscape-medical-news">Highlight from &lt;a href="http://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/766273%20">Vitamin D May Help Breast Cancer Survivors Stay on Track &lt;/a>Medscape Medical News&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>2012 Annual Meeting of the American Society of Clinical Oncology®&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>aromatase inhibitors&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>half of the women have severe musculoskeletal pain from these agents, and 18% to 30% report fatigue, &lt;span>[resulting in]&lt;/span> a discontinuation rate of about 10% each year,&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>30,000 IU of oral vitamin D3 weekly on starting letrozole therapy achieved significant benefits in terms of fatigue, joint pain, and disability from joint pain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>7 improvements in lives of veterans with chronic pain with 50,000 IU vitamin D weekly</title><link>/posts/7-improvements-in-lives-of-veterans-with-chronic-pain-with-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7-improvements-in-lives-of-veterans-with-chronic-pain-with-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="improvement-of-pain-sleep-and-quality-of-life-in-chronic-pain-patients-with-vitamin-d-supplementation">Improvement of Pain, Sleep, and Quality of Life in Chronic Pain Patients With Vitamin D Supplementation.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin J Pain. 2012 Jun 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Huang W &lt;a href="mailto:whuang4@emory.edu">whuang4@emory.edu&lt;/a>, Shah S, Long Q, Crankshaw AK, Tangpricha V.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation ?Geriatrics, Extended Care Service Line, Atlanta VA Medical Center, Decatur&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine §Department of Medicine, Division of Endocrinology, Metabolism &amp;amp; Lipids, Emory University School of Medicine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Biostatistics and Bioinformatics, Rollins School of Public Health, Emory University, Atlanta, GA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU of vitamin D reduced fatigue of advanced cancer – RCT</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-fatigue-of-advanced-cancer-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-fatigue-of-advanced-cancer-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-supplementation-to-improve-fatigue-in-patients-with-advanced-cancer">Vitamin D3 supplementation to improve fatigue in patients with advanced cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology, 2012 ASCO Annual Meeting Proceedings (Post-Meeting Edition).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol 30, No 15_suppl (May 20 Supplement), 2012: 9097&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2012 American Society of Clinical Oncology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dragan Trivanovic, Stjepko Plestina, Renata Dobrilla-Dintinjana, Lorena Honovic, Lems Jerin and Irena Hrstic&lt;/p>
&lt;p>General Hospital Pula, Pula, Croatia; University Hospital Centre Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia; Internal Clinic, Rijeka, Croatia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Fatigue is one of the most common symptoms of patients diagnosed with cancer. Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with an increased risk of mortality in oncology patients. We conducted a prospective vitamin D (cholecalciferol) supplementation study to analyse the response to oral D3 supplementation on fatigue in this population of chemo-naïve patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If you cannot readily get medical treatment, consider Alternative Med such as vitamin D</title><link>/posts/if-you-cannot-readily-get-medical-treatment-consider-alternative-med-such-as-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-you-cannot-readily-get-medical-treatment-consider-alternative-med-such-as-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="having-lots-of-vitamin-d">Having lots of vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>reduces many chronic pains&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>allows the body the heal itself of some diseases&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>reduces the progress of some diseases&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>apparently increases many different “growth factors”, which help in healing&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how-much-is-a-high-level-of-vitamin-d">How much is a high level of vitamin D?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Minimum of 40 nanograms, preferably 50 nanograms and perhaps &amp;gt; 80 nanograms.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-go-about-getting-lots-of-vitamin-d-under-medical-supervision-if-you-can-afford-it">How to go about getting lots of vitamin D (under medical supervision if you can afford it)&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Make sure you are not &lt;a href="/posts/allergic-to-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2433">allergic to vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>take perhaps a single 1,000 IU dose and watch for an allergic reaction in the next few days&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Menstrual Pain (PMS) reduced by vitamin D – RCT 2012, 2014, 2016</title><link>/posts/menstrual-pain-pms-reduced-by-vitamin-d-rct-2012-2014-2016.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/menstrual-pain-pms-reduced-by-vitamin-d-rct-2012-2014-2016.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#25000-iu-of-vitamin-d-every-2-weeks-reduced-pms---rct--aug-2016">25,000 IU of Vitamin D every 2 weeks reduced PMS - RCT Aug 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dysmenorrhea-treated-by-single-dose-of-300000-iu---rct-feb-2012">Dysmenorrhea treated by single dose of 300,000 IU - RCT Feb 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24405636?dopt=Abstract">Vitamin D and PTH Status among Adolescent and Young Females with Severe Dysmenorrhea.&lt;/a> Jan 2014&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>(80%) had insufficient plasma vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Serum vitamin D concentrations in young Turkish women with primary dysmenorrhea: A randomized controlled study - 2018&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/dysmenorrhea-2018.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Raynaud's pain decreased with 600,000 IU monthly vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/raynauds-pain-decreased-with-600000-iu-monthly-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/raynauds-pain-decreased-with-600000-iu-monthly-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="raynauds-phenomenon-and-vitamind">Raynaud&amp;rsquo;s phenomenon and vitamin D.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Rheumatol Int. 2012 May 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hélou J, Moutran R, Maatouk I &lt;a href="mailto:ismaelmaatouk@yahoo.com">ismaelmaatouk@yahoo.com&lt;/a> , Haddad F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dermatology Department, Hôtel-Dieu de France Hospital, Ashrafieh, Beirut, Lebanon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>To our knowledge, there have not been studies to evaluate the effect of vitamin D supplementation on Raynaud&amp;rsquo;s phenomenon (RP)&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To test in a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, and prospective way whether 8 weeks of 600,000 IU monthly supplementation of oral vitamin D3 would contribute to improvements in RP, 53 patients describing RP were recruited during the winter of 2010-2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half of seniors with pain had low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/half-of-seniors-with-pain-had-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-of-seniors-with-pain-had-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>After back surgery failure, vitamin D greatly reduced the pain of every person</title><link>/posts/after-back-surgery-failure-vitamin-d-greatly-reduced-the-pain-of-every-person.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/after-back-surgery-failure-vitamin-d-greatly-reduced-the-pain-of-every-person.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="serum-25-hydroxy-calciferol-level-and-failed-back-surgery-syndrome">Serum 25-hydroxy-calciferol level and failed back surgery syndrome.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Orthop Surg (Hong Kong). 2012 Apr;20(1):18-22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Waikakul S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE. To assess the association of serum 25-hydroxy-calciferol levels with pain and low back function in patients with failed back surgery syndrome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS. Records of 6 men and 3 women aged 25 to 54 (mean, 39.2) years who had failed back surgery syndrome after pedicular screw and rod instrumentation for lower lumbar degenerative diseases were reviewed. They had moderate-to-severe pain (visual analogue scale &lt;span>[VAS]&lt;/span> score of &amp;gt;6) and low back function disability (Japanese Orthopaedic Association &lt;span>[JOA]&lt;/span> back score of &amp;lt;10). In all patients, the serum 25-hydroxy-calciferol level was &amp;lt;30 ng/ ml, indicating vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Pain and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-pain-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-pain-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostspain-sources-vs-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-pain-sources-vs-vitamin-d---jan-2025pain-sources-vs-vitamin-d---jan-2025a">&lt;a href="/posts/pain-sources-vs-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Pain sources vs. Vitamin D - Jan 2025">Pain sources vs. Vitamin D - Jan 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#fibromyalgia-and-widespread">Fibromyalgia and Widespread&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#serious-chronic-pain-list-from-institute-of-medicinehttpwwwnapeduread13172chapter324-all-helped-by-vitamin-d">Serious &lt;a href="http://www.nap.edu/read/13172/chapter/3#24">chronic pain list from Institute of Medicine&lt;/a> (all helped by Vitamin D)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-chronic-pain---nov-2013">Vitamin D and Chronic Pain - Nov 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d---a-neglected-analgesic-for-chronic-musculoskeletal-pain--an-evidence-based-review--clinical-practice-guidance---2008">Vitamin D - A Neglected &amp;lsquo;Analgesic&amp;rsquo; for Chronic Musculoskeletal Pain- An Evidence-Based Review &amp;amp; Clinical Practice Guidance - 2008&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pain-relievers-can-extend-duration-of-back-pain---and-sometimes-turning-it-into-a-chronic-pain---may-2022">Pain relievers can extend duration of back pain - and sometimes turning it into a chronic pain - May 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#people-in-pain-having-low-vitamin-d-levels-will-benefit-from-supplementation---oct-2017">People in pain having low vitamin D levels will benefit from supplementation - Oct 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pain-factoids-from-the-body-by-bill-bryson-2019">Pain Factoids from the Body by Bill Bryson, 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="a-hrefpostspain-sources-vs-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-pain-sources-vs-vitamin-d---jan-2025pain-sources-vs-vitamin-d---jan-2025a">&lt;a href="/posts/pain-sources-vs-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Pain sources vs. Vitamin D - Jan 2025">Pain sources vs. Vitamin D - Jan 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/webp/pain-sources.webp" alt="image" width="550">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="fibromyalgia-and-widespread">Fibromyalgia and Widespread&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/fibromyalgia-treated-with-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly-for-3-months-2016-2017-2018-2019" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Fibromyalgia treated with Vitamin D (50,000 IU weekly for 3 months) – 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019">Fibromyalgia treated with Vitamin D (50,000 IU weekly for 3 months) – 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fibromalgia reduced with 50,000 IU weekly vitamin D2</title><link>/posts/fibromalgia-reduced-with-50000-iu-weekly-vitamin-d2.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fibromalgia-reduced-with-50000-iu-weekly-vitamin-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-relation-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-fibromyalgia-syndrome-in-women">The relation between vitamin D deficiency and fibromyalgia syndrome in women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Matthana MH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saudi Med J. 2011 Sep;32(9):925-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical Research Center, Sultan Bin Abdulaziz Humanitarian City, Riyadh, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. &lt;a href="mailto:monamathna@hotmail.com">monamathna@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To define the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and fibromyalgia syndrome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a prospective cohort study for description of a medical disorder. The study was carried out in Sultan Bin Abdulaziz Humanitarian City, Riyadh, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia from May 2007 to March 2010. One hundred women suffering from fibromyalgia syndrome were included.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poor sleep and lack of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/poor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Literature review of Fibromyalgia and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/literature-review-of-fibromyalgia-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/literature-review-of-fibromyalgia-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="fibromyalgia---should-we-be-testing-and-treating-for-vitamin-d-deficiency">Fibromyalgia - should we be testing and treating for vitamin D deficiency?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Aust Fam Physician. 2011 Sep;40(9):712-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daniel D, Pirotta MV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MBBS, FRACGP, DCH, was an academic registrar, Department of General Practice, University of Melbourne, Victoria.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aim This review aims to synthesise the evidence regarding any association between vitamin D deficiency and fibromyalgia, addressing whether general practitioners should be testing and treating these patients for vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods A systematic literature review was performed, using MEDLINE as the primary database, to find and critically appraise all relevant research fulfilling inclusion criteria from January 1990 until September 2010.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Severe chronic disease associated with less than 10 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/severe-chronic-disease-associated-with-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/severe-chronic-disease-associated-with-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-geriatric-inpatients-a-marker-of-severity-of-chronic-diseases">Hypovitaminosis D in geriatric inpatients: a marker of severity of chronic diseases.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Aging Clin Exp Res. 2011 Jul 5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beauchet O, Hélard L, Montero-Odasso M, de Decker L, Berrut G, Annweiler C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine and Geriatrics, Angers University Hospital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and aims. Hypovitaminosis D is associated with adverse health outcomes including several bone and non-bone chronic diseases. It remains unclear whether hypovitaminosis D leads to more numerous or more severe chronic diseases. Our objective was to determine whether there was an association between the serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D deficiency (i.e., 25OHD -25nmol/L) and, respectively, the number and the severity of chronic diseases assessed with the &lt;strong>Kaplan-Feinstein index (KFI)&lt;/strong> among geriatric inpatients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>100 Million Americans Have Chronic Pain – IoM</title><link>/posts/100-million-americans-have-chronic-pain-iom.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/100-million-americans-have-chronic-pain-iom.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Increased D levels responsible for Dead Sea therapy</title><link>/posts/increased-d-levels-responsible-for-dead-sea-therapy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-d-levels-responsible-for-dead-sea-therapy.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="increased-vitamin-d-serum-levels-correlate-with-clinical-improvement-of-rheumatic-diseases-after-dead-sea-climatotherapy">Increased vitamin D serum levels correlate with clinical improvement of rheumatic diseases after Dead Sea climatotherapy.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Isr Med Assoc J. 2011 Apr;13(4):212-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harari M, Dramsdahl E, Shany S, Baumfeld Y, Ingber A, Novack V, Sukenik S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DMZ Medical Center, Lot Spa Hotel, Dead Sea, Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet B (UVB) rays are required by the skin for the production of vitamin D. The intensity of UVB at the Dead Sea area is the lowest in the world. Low vitamin D levels are often associated with musculoskeletal symptoms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D relieves pain – 2008 2010</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-relieves-pain-2008-2010.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-relieves-pain-2008-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="evidence-based-pain-management-practices-by-stewart-b-leavitt-ma-phd">Evidence-based pain-management practices by Stewart B. Leavitt, MA, PhD&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://updates.pain-topics.org/2010/01/vitamin-d-for-pain-update-of-research.html">Vitamin D for Pain: Update of Research Evidence&lt;/a> Jan 17, 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See original article for most hyperlinks&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of this page is an update from previous work by Stewart B. Leavitt, MA, PhD, &lt;a href="http://pain-topics.org/vitamind">http://pain-topics.org/vitamind&lt;/a> – see items at the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://updates.pain-topics.org/search/label/vitamin%20D">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for newer items by the same author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a review last fall, practitioners from the University of Miami School of Medicine reiterated how research evidence has expanded our perspectives on the importance of adequate vitamin D for overall health (Stechschulte et al. 2009). They note that, in addition to traditionally reducing the risk for bone disease, vitamin D has demonstrated benefits in reducing falls and decreasing musculoskeletal pain, as well as stemming autoimmune diseases, cancers, heart disease, cognitive declines, and overall mortality. On this basis, improving the vitamin D status in all patients has become an essential aspect of healthcare, especially since deficiency or insufficiency can be safely prevented or corrected via inexpensive supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leg pain 7X more prevalent when vitamin D lower than 20 ng</title><link>/posts/leg-pain-7x-more-prevalent-when-vitamin-d-lower-than-20-ng.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/leg-pain-7x-more-prevalent-when-vitamin-d-lower-than-20-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="association-between-nonspecific-skeletal-pain-and-vitamin-d-deficiency">Association between nonspecific skeletal pain and vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int J Rheum Dis. 2010 Oct;13(4):340-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1756-185X.2010.01561.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1756-185X.2010.01561.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2010 Aug 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Association between nonspecific skeletal pain and vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heidari B, Shirvani JS, Firouzjahi A, Heidari P, Hajian-Tilaki KO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deparment of Medicine, Division of Rheumatology Deparment of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Rouhani Hospital, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol Faculty of Medicine, Islamic Azad University, Tehran Department of Social Medicine, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol, Iran.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back pain gone and grew 3 inches with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/back-pain-gone-and-grew-3-inches-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/back-pain-gone-and-grew-3-inches-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="one-individuals-experience-with-vitamin-d-and-back-pain">One individual&amp;rsquo;s experience with vitamin D and back pain&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="5000-iu-in-summer-and-10000-iu-in-winter">5,000 IU in summer and 10,000 IU in winter&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="is-ioms-food-and-nutrition-board-wrong-posted-03-dec-2010-by-vitamin-d-survivor">Is IoM’s Food and Nutrition Board Wrong? Posted: 03 Dec 2010 by Vitamin D Survivor&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As doctors scruple over the amount of vitamin D that we need as humans, the best approach is common sense. I started to write this blog because my back healed after 25 years of pain. It turns out that by following the standards that were just set by the IoM; my spine failed. I had two surgeries and was looking at the possibility of many more. I started to take 5,000 IU of vitamin D3 in the summer and 10,000 IU in the winter. This kept my serum level of 25(OH)D at 50 to 80 ng/ml. It turns out that people who live between the latitude of +/- 30 degrees have this value of vitamin D as normal as long as they do not intentionally avoid the sun (54 to 90 ng/ml reported by Dr’s Grant and Holick). At this level of supplementation my spine healed. I just had another MRI done after five years and the disc in my lumbar region are twice as thick now as they were five years ago. Let me repeat that in case you missed it. They are &lt;strong>TWICE AS THICK&lt;/strong> now as they were five years ago. Yes and I did grow &lt;strong>three inches taller&lt;/strong> in my mid-fifties as my spine healed. If I had followed the advice of the IoM’s recent report I would definitely be in a wheel chair or most likely dead either from a heart attack or sleep apnea.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>