<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pain - Chronic on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/pain---chronic.html</link><description>Recent content in Pain - Chronic on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/pain---chronic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Poor sleep and lack of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/poor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Literature review of Fibromyalgia and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/literature-review-of-fibromyalgia-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/literature-review-of-fibromyalgia-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="fibromyalgia---should-we-be-testing-and-treating-for-vitamin-d-deficiency">Fibromyalgia - should we be testing and treating for vitamin D deficiency?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Aust Fam Physician. 2011 Sep;40(9):712-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daniel D, Pirotta MV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MBBS, FRACGP, DCH, was an academic registrar, Department of General Practice, University of Melbourne, Victoria.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aim This review aims to synthesise the evidence regarding any association between vitamin D deficiency and fibromyalgia, addressing whether general practitioners should be testing and treating these patients for vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods A systematic literature review was performed, using MEDLINE as the primary database, to find and critically appraise all relevant research fulfilling inclusion criteria from January 1990 until September 2010.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Severe chronic disease associated with less than 10 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/severe-chronic-disease-associated-with-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/severe-chronic-disease-associated-with-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-geriatric-inpatients-a-marker-of-severity-of-chronic-diseases">Hypovitaminosis D in geriatric inpatients: a marker of severity of chronic diseases.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Aging Clin Exp Res. 2011 Jul 5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beauchet O, Hélard L, Montero-Odasso M, de Decker L, Berrut G, Annweiler C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine and Geriatrics, Angers University Hospital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and aims. Hypovitaminosis D is associated with adverse health outcomes including several bone and non-bone chronic diseases. It remains unclear whether hypovitaminosis D leads to more numerous or more severe chronic diseases. Our objective was to determine whether there was an association between the serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D deficiency (i.e., 25OHD -25nmol/L) and, respectively, the number and the severity of chronic diseases assessed with the &lt;strong>Kaplan-Feinstein index (KFI)&lt;/strong> among geriatric inpatients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>100 Million Americans Have Chronic Pain – IoM</title><link>/posts/100-million-americans-have-chronic-pain-iom.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/100-million-americans-have-chronic-pain-iom.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Increased D levels responsible for Dead Sea therapy</title><link>/posts/increased-d-levels-responsible-for-dead-sea-therapy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-d-levels-responsible-for-dead-sea-therapy.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="increased-vitamin-d-serum-levels-correlate-with-clinical-improvement-of-rheumatic-diseases-after-dead-sea-climatotherapy">Increased vitamin D serum levels correlate with clinical improvement of rheumatic diseases after Dead Sea climatotherapy.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Isr Med Assoc J. 2011 Apr;13(4):212-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harari M, Dramsdahl E, Shany S, Baumfeld Y, Ingber A, Novack V, Sukenik S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DMZ Medical Center, Lot Spa Hotel, Dead Sea, Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet B (UVB) rays are required by the skin for the production of vitamin D. The intensity of UVB at the Dead Sea area is the lowest in the world. Low vitamin D levels are often associated with musculoskeletal symptoms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D relieves pain – 2008 2010</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-relieves-pain-2008-2010.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-relieves-pain-2008-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="evidence-based-pain-management-practices-by-stewart-b-leavitt-ma-phd">Evidence-based pain-management practices by Stewart B. Leavitt, MA, PhD&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://updates.pain-topics.org/2010/01/vitamin-d-for-pain-update-of-research.html">Vitamin D for Pain: Update of Research Evidence&lt;/a> Jan 17, 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See original article for most hyperlinks&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of this page is an update from previous work by Stewart B. Leavitt, MA, PhD, &lt;a href="http://pain-topics.org/vitamind">http://pain-topics.org/vitamind&lt;/a> – see items at the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://updates.pain-topics.org/search/label/vitamin%20D">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for newer items by the same author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a review last fall, practitioners from the University of Miami School of Medicine reiterated how research evidence has expanded our perspectives on the importance of adequate vitamin D for overall health (Stechschulte et al. 2009). They note that, in addition to traditionally reducing the risk for bone disease, vitamin D has demonstrated benefits in reducing falls and decreasing musculoskeletal pain, as well as stemming autoimmune diseases, cancers, heart disease, cognitive declines, and overall mortality. On this basis, improving the vitamin D status in all patients has become an essential aspect of healthcare, especially since deficiency or insufficiency can be safely prevented or corrected via inexpensive supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leg pain 7X more prevalent when vitamin D lower than 20 ng</title><link>/posts/leg-pain-7x-more-prevalent-when-vitamin-d-lower-than-20-ng.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/leg-pain-7x-more-prevalent-when-vitamin-d-lower-than-20-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="association-between-nonspecific-skeletal-pain-and-vitamin-d-deficiency">Association between nonspecific skeletal pain and vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int J Rheum Dis. 2010 Oct;13(4):340-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1756-185X.2010.01561.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1756-185X.2010.01561.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2010 Aug 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Association between nonspecific skeletal pain and vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heidari B, Shirvani JS, Firouzjahi A, Heidari P, Hajian-Tilaki KO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deparment of Medicine, Division of Rheumatology Deparment of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Rouhani Hospital, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol Faculty of Medicine, Islamic Azad University, Tehran Department of Social Medicine, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol, Iran.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back pain gone and grew 3 inches with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/back-pain-gone-and-grew-3-inches-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/back-pain-gone-and-grew-3-inches-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="one-individuals-experience-with-vitamin-d-and-back-pain">One individual&amp;rsquo;s experience with vitamin D and back pain&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="5000-iu-in-summer-and-10000-iu-in-winter">5,000 IU in summer and 10,000 IU in winter&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="is-ioms-food-and-nutrition-board-wrong-posted-03-dec-2010-by-vitamin-d-survivor">Is IoM’s Food and Nutrition Board Wrong? Posted: 03 Dec 2010 by Vitamin D Survivor&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As doctors scruple over the amount of vitamin D that we need as humans, the best approach is common sense. I started to write this blog because my back healed after 25 years of pain. It turns out that by following the standards that were just set by the IoM; my spine failed. I had two surgeries and was looking at the possibility of many more. I started to take 5,000 IU of vitamin D3 in the summer and 10,000 IU in the winter. This kept my serum level of 25(OH)D at 50 to 80 ng/ml. It turns out that people who live between the latitude of +/- 30 degrees have this value of vitamin D as normal as long as they do not intentionally avoid the sun (54 to 90 ng/ml reported by Dr’s Grant and Holick). At this level of supplementation my spine healed. I just had another MRI done after five years and the disc in my lumbar region are twice as thick now as they were five years ago. Let me repeat that in case you missed it. They are &lt;strong>TWICE AS THICK&lt;/strong> now as they were five years ago. Yes and I did grow &lt;strong>three inches taller&lt;/strong> in my mid-fifties as my spine healed. If I had followed the advice of the IoM’s recent report I would definitely be in a wheel chair or most likely dead either from a heart attack or sleep apnea.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>