<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pain - Chronic on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/pain---chronic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pain - Chronic on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/pain---chronic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Willow Bark Extract and Aspirin have many health benefits (Vitamin D might be better)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/willow-bark-extract-and-aspirin-have-many-health-benefits-vitamin-d-might-be-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/willow-bark-extract-and-aspirin-have-many-health-benefits-vitamin-d-might-be-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-broad-spectrum-antiviral-effects-of-willow-bark-extract---mercolahttpsarticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20231226willow-barkaspxuid738e3df52a8a14aea9298fe6ec5bc113ed0d6d7922f31861727d54a43cbe29dsd20121119cid_sourcednlcid_mediumemailcid_contentart2hlcid20231226fodatefalsemiddm1508229rid2002031810&#34;&gt;The Broad-Spectrum Antiviral Effects of Willow Bark Extract - &lt;a href=&#34;https://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2023/12/26/willow-bark.aspx?ui=d738e3df52a8a14aea9298fe6ec5bc113ed0d6d7922f31861727d54a43cbe29d&amp;amp;sd=20121119&amp;amp;cid_source=dnl&amp;amp;cid_medium=email&amp;amp;cid_content=art2HL&amp;amp;cid=20231226&amp;amp;foDate=false&amp;amp;mid=DM1508229&amp;amp;rid=2002031810&#34;&gt;Mercola&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Willow bark is perhaps most widely known as aspirin’s forerunner, but it appears to have powerful  &lt;strong&gt;antiviral effects&lt;/strong&gt;  as well&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Willow bark extract has broad-spectrum, antiviral effects against coronaviruses and enteroviruses&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Willow bark is effective against both enveloped and nonenveloped viruses, causing the viruses to cluster together rather than spread apart&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a study, willow bark broke down the  &lt;strong&gt;enveloped coronaviruses&lt;/strong&gt; , while the nonenveloped enteroviruses were “locked down,” meaning their genome wasn’t released and they couldn’t reproduce&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central Nervous System protection by Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-nervous-system-protection-by-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-nervous-system-protection-by-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;molecular-regulation-of-the-cns-by-vitamin-d&#34;&gt;Molecular Regulation of the CNS by Vitamin D&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Physiol Res 2023 Dec 17;72(S4):S339-S356.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;L Máčová 1, R Kancheva, M Bičíková&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;Factors that are up-regulated are marked in green&lt;/span&gt;%%%  &lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;factors that are down-regulated are in red&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D is a lipid-soluble vitamin that can be found in some foods. It is also produced endogenously (in the presence of ultraviolet light), transported through the blood to the targets organs and this is the reason to consider vitamin D as a hormone. It is known that vitamin D has genomic and non-genomic effects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fibromyalgia pain, fatigue, etc. reduced by 50,000 IU of Vitamin D for 12 weeks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fibromyalgia-pain-fatigue-etc-reduced-by-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-12-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fibromyalgia-pain-fatigue-etc-reduced-by-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-12-weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-effect-of-vitamin-d-treatment-on-quality-of-life-in-patients-with-fibromyalgia&#34;&gt;The effect of vitamin D treatment on quality of life in patients with fibromyalgia&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Irish Journal of Medical Science (1971 -) &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11845-023-03521-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11845-023-03521-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sedef Ersoy, Fatma Nur Kesiktas, Busra Sirin, Derya Bugdayci &amp;amp; Nurdan Paker (Turkey)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;FIQ consists of 10 questions that inquire about the level of impact on daily activities, fatigue, pain level, morning discomfort, and mood over the past week. The maximum score is 80, and the minimum score is 0&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pain relieved by Vitamin D if trial lasted more than 5 months (endometriosis, 50K weekly for 12 months)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pain-relieved-by-vitamin-d-if-trial-lasted-more-than-5-months-endometriosis-50k-weekly-for-12-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pain-relieved-by-vitamin-d-if-trial-lasted-more-than-5-months-endometriosis-50k-weekly-for-12-months/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another endometriosis-related pain trial lasting only 3 months did not result in a benefit.%%%It takes at least 5 months for vitamin D dosing to fully respond without a loading dose%%%Loading doses, on the other hand, result in a response/benefit in &amp;lt; 1 month&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;antioxidant-vitamins-supplementation-reduce-endometriosis-related-pelvic-pain-in-humans-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;Antioxidant vitamins supplementation reduce endometriosis related pelvic pain in humans: a systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reproductive Biology and Endocrinology Vol 21, # 79 (2023) &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s12958-023-01126-1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/s12958-023-01126-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Less morphine recall if preceded by twice a week Vitamin D (400 IU per kg in rats, human weights 80 kg)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/less-morphine-recall-if-preceded-by-twice-a-week-vitamin-d-400-iu-per-kg-in-rats-human-weights-80-kg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/less-morphine-recall-if-preceded-by-twice-a-week-vitamin-d-400-iu-per-kg-in-rats-human-weights-80-kg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;attenuation-of-morphine-conditioned-place-preference-and-reinstatement-by-vitamin-d&#34;&gt;Attenuation of morphine conditioned place preference and reinstatement by vitamin D&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Behav Pharmacol. 2023 Aug 15. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1097/FBP.0000000000000747&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1097/FBP.0000000000000747&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mahdieh Akbari 1, Houman Parsaei 2, Katayoun Sedaghat 1, Fatemeh Mousavi 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Research Center of Physiology, Semnan University of Medical Sciences, Semnan and.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Department of Anatomy, School of Medicine, Iran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opioid&lt;/strong&gt;  action in the brain involves the dopamine-reward system as well as non-dopamine pathways. Since vitamin D also modulates the brain&amp;rsquo;s dopamine system, the question of this study was how vitamin D might affect the  &lt;strong&gt;opioid&lt;/strong&gt;  influences on the reward system. Therefore, the objective of this study was to investigate the possible effect of vitamin D on the conditioned place preference (CPP) induced by  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt; , as a valuable model of assessment of the reinforcing properties of  &lt;strong&gt;opioids&lt;/strong&gt;  by associating the context to the rewarding properties of the addictive drugs. Male Wistar rats were randomly divided into two main groups that either received saline ( &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  vehicle) or  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  (5 mg/kg, intraperitoneally) for CPP. Each of the main groups was divided into three vitamin D treatment subgroups: vitamin D vehicle and vitamin D (5 and 10 μg/kg, intraperitoneally). Vitamin D injections were started 1 week ahead of the experiment (two injections) or immediately after post-conditioning and in both cases, it was continued twice weekly throughout the CPP. Administration of vitamin D (10 μg/kg) before conditioning in CPP markedly attenuated  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  expression in the post-conditioning test. Receiving vitamin D (5 or 10 μg/kg) before or after conditioning significantly attenuated  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  reinstatement. Administration of vitamin D after  &lt;strong&gt;opioid&lt;/strong&gt;  conditioning facilitated  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  memory extinction and attenuated  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  reinstatement. Vitamin D is probably a valuable addition to be considered as a part of the treatment for prevention or minimizing the dependency or relapse to  &lt;strong&gt;opioids&lt;/strong&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pain not reduced by 60,000 IU monthly vitamin D (need 50,000 IU weekly) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pain-not-reduced-by-60000-iu-monthly-vitamin-d-need-50000-iu-weekly-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pain-not-reduced-by-60000-iu-monthly-vitamin-d-need-50000-iu-weekly-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-pain-an-analysis-of-data-from-the-d-health-randomised-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;The effect of vitamin D supplementation on pain: an analysis of data from the D-Health randomised controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trial Br J Nutr. 2023 Aug 28;130(4):633-640. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S000711452200356&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1017/S000711452200356&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aninda Rahman 1, Mary Waterhouse 2, Catherine Baxter 2, Briony Duarte Romero 2, Donald S A McLeod 2 3, Bruce K Armstrong 4, Peter R Ebeling 5, Dallas R English 6 7, Gunter Hartel 2, Michael G Kimlin 8, Rachel O&amp;rsquo;Connell 9, Jolieke C van der Pols 10, Alison J Venn 11, Penelope M Webb 2 12, David C Whiteman 2 12, Rachel E Neale 2 12&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muscle pain in obese women reduced by aerobic exercise plus 50,000 IU Vitamin D - RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/muscle-pain-in-obese-women-reduced-by-aerobic-exercise-plus-50000-iu-vitamin-d-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/muscle-pain-in-obese-women-reduced-by-aerobic-exercise-plus-50000-iu-vitamin-d-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;efficacy-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-addition-to-aerobic-exercise-training-in-obese-women-with-perceived-myalgia-a-single-blinded-randomized-controlled-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;Efficacy of Vitamin D Supplementation in Addition to Aerobic Exercise Training in Obese Women with Perceived Myalgia: A Single-Blinded Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2021, 13(6), 1819; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu13061819&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu13061819&lt;/a&gt; Egypt&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;If 2X- 3X larger doses of Vitamin D, %%%&amp;gt;40 ng and more decrease in pain %%%&lt;del&gt;hs&lt;/span&gt;hs&lt;/del&gt;  100,000 to 150,000 IU per week~~&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obese women were more susceptible to myalgia because of their significantly lower vitamin D concentrations; the present study investigated the efficacy of vitamin D in addition to an aerobic interval training in the management of obese women with myalgia. Forty-five obese women with vitamin D deficiency and myalgia (30 to 40 years old) were assigned randomly into three equal groups. Group A received an aerobic interval training with vitamin D supplementation, Group B received vitamin D supplementation only, and Group C received aerobic interval training only; participants in all groups were on calorie deficient diets. The study outcomes were the Visual Analog Scale (VAS) for Pain Evaluation, serum vitamin D level, and Cooper 12-Minute Walk Test for Functional Capacity Evaluation, while the Short-Form Health Survey (SF) was used for assessment of quality of life. We detected a significant improvement in pain intensity level, serum vitamin D level, and quality of life in all groups with significant difference between Group A and groups B and C. We also detected a significant improvement in functional capacity in groups A and C, with no significant change in Group B. Aerobic interval training with vitamin D supplementation was more effective for the management of obese women with perceived myalgia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large dose Vitamin D before surgery was found to help by 35 studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/large-dose-vitamin-d-before-surgery-was-found-to-help-by-35-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/large-dose-vitamin-d-before-surgery-was-found-to-help-by-35-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;This small study would probably have gotten statistically significant results if they have given the 300,000 IU of Vitamin D 3 days BEFORE the surgery. It takes several days for oral vitamin D to get to the cells (injection is slower, nanoemulsion is faster)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;optimal-vitamin-d-status-at-admission-appears-to-improve-survival-after-craniotomy-in-patients-with-brain-malignancies&#34;&gt;Optimal vitamin D status at admission appears to improve survival after craniotomy in patients with brain malignancies&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clinical Nutrition ESPEN Vol 55, June 2023, Pages 428-433 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnesp.2023.04.009&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnesp.2023.04.009&lt;/a&gt; $25 paywall&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
