<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Women on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/women.html</link><description>Recent content in Women on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/women/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weak bones (Osteopenia) in 93 percent of women in Pakistan attending University and wearing Islamic clothes</title><link>/posts/weak-bones-osteopenia-in-93-percent-of-women-in-pakistan-attending-university-an-islamic-clothes.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/weak-bones-osteopenia-in-93-percent-of-women-in-pakistan-attending-university-an-islamic-clothes.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Total hip replacement: 14 times more likely to redo if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/total-hip-replacement-14-times-more-likely-to-redo-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/total-hip-replacement-14-times-more-likely-to-redo-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="influence-of-vitamin-d-levels-on-revision-and-complication-rates-following-total-joint-arthroplasty">INFLUENCE OF VITAMIN D LEVELS ON REVISION AND COMPLICATION RATES FOLLOWING TOTAL JOINT ARTHROPLASTY&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Orthopaedic Proceedings, vol. 99-B no. SUPP 5 88 1 March 2017&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J.F. Plate, T.M. Seyler, A.D. Wohler, M.K. Langfitt, J.E. Lang&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wake Forest School of Medicine - Winston-Salem, USA &lt;a href="mailto:jplate@wakehealth.edu">jplate@wakehealth.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:750px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Brief summary of many studies on hip fractures and vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1) Having a high level of vitamin D greatly reduces the risk of hip fractures&lt;br>
2) &lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-insufficiency-increased-after-hip-replacement-38-percent-before-68-percent-the-next-day">A hip fracture consumes vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;br>
3) Far fewer complications after hip fracture if add sun/uv or vitamin D&lt;br>
4) 14X more likely to need revision surgery within 3 years if Vitamin D remains &amp;lt; 30 ng (this study)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Role of Vitamin D in Menopausal Medicine</title><link>/posts/the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-menopausal-medicine.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-menopausal-medicine.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D helps women in many ways – but not sure about ovarian and endometrial cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-women-in-many-ways-but-not-sure-about-ovarian-and-endometrial-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-women-in-many-ways-but-not-sure-about-ovarian-and-endometrial-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Muscle strength of senior women increased 25 percent with vitamin D, decreased 6 percent with placebo</title><link>/posts/muscle-strength-of-senior-women-increased-25-percent-with-vitamin-d-decreased-6-percent-with-placebo.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/muscle-strength-of-senior-women-increased-25-percent-with-vitamin-d-decreased-6-percent-with-placebo.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency 4X more likely if illiterate or have bone pain – Lahore Pakistan</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-4x-more-likely-if-illiterate-or-have-bone-pain-lahore-pakistan.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-4x-more-likely-if-illiterate-or-have-bone-pain-lahore-pakistan.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="high-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-among-women-of-child-bearing-age-in-lahore-pakistan-associating-with-lack-of-sun-exposure-and-illiteracy">High prevalence of vitamin D deficiency among women of child-bearing age in Lahore Pakistan, associating with lack of sun exposure and illiteracy.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Womens Health. 2015 Oct 12;15:83. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/s12905-015-0242-x.">doi: 10.1186/s12905-015-0242-x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Junaid K1, Rehman A2, Jolliffe DA3, Wood K4, Martineau AR5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Microbiology and Molecular Genetics, University of the Punjab, Quaid-e-Azam Campus, Lahore, 5400, Pakistan. &lt;a href="mailto:kashaf_junaid@hotmail.com">kashaf_junaid@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Microbiology and Molecular Genetics, University of the Punjab, Quaid-e-Azam Campus, Lahore, 5400, Pakistan. &lt;a href="mailto:rehman_mmg@yahoo.com">rehman_mmg@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Centre for Primary Care and Public Health, Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London, E1 2AB, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:d.a.jolliffe@qmul.ac.uk">d.a.jolliffe@qmul.ac.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Coronary Heart Disease 3 times more likely if endometriosis before age 40 (vitamin D not mentioned)</title><link>/posts/coronary-heart-disease-3-times-more-likely-if-endometriosis-before-age-40-vitamin-d-not-mentioned.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/coronary-heart-disease-3-times-more-likely-if-endometriosis-before-age-40-vitamin-d-not-mentioned.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="endometriosis-and-risk-of-coronary-heart-disease">Endometriosis and Risk of Coronary Heart Disease&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>CIRCOUTCOMES.115.002224, Published online before print March 29, 2016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fan Mu, ScD, Janet Rich-Edwards, ScD, Eric B. Rimm, ScD, Donna Spiegelman, ScD and Stacey A. Missmer, ScD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Department of Epidemiology (F.M., J.R.-E., E.B.R., D.S., S.A.M.), Department of Nutrition (E.B.R., D.S.), and Department of Biostatistics (D.S.), Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, Boston, MA; Connors Center for Women’s Health and Gender Biology, Brigham and Women’s Hospital, Boston, MA (J.R.-E.); Channing Division of Network Medicine, Department of Medicine(E.B.R., S.A.M.) and Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology, and Reproductive Biology (S.A.M.), Brigham and Women’s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poor menstrual cycles 2X more likely if poor vitamin D levels - many studies</title><link>/posts/poor-menstrual-cycles-2x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-levels-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poor-menstrual-cycles-2x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-levels-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#irregular-cycles">Irregular cycles&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#irregular-menstrual-cycles-133-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---dec-2021">Irregular menstrual cycles 13.3 X more likely if low Vitamin D - Dec 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#19x-more-likely-to-have-irregular-menstrual-cycles-if-10-ng-less-vitamin-d-march-2015-has-pdf">1.9X more likely to have irregular menstrual cycles if 10 ng less vitamin D (March 2015, has PDF)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#long-cycles">Long cycles&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#long-menstrual-cycles-were-28-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d--jan-2018">Long menstrual cycles were 2.8 X more likely if low Vitamin D – Jan 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2x-less-likely-to-have-long-menstrual-cycles-if-2x-higher-vitamin-d-level">2X less likely to have long menstrual cycles if 2X higher vitamin D level&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="irregular-cycles">Irregular cycles&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="irregular-menstrual-cycles-133-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---dec-2021">Irregular menstrual cycles 13.3 X more likely if low Vitamin D - Dec 2021&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Association between serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D level and menstrual cycle length and regularity: A cross-sectional observational study&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PMS reduced by half in girls who had low levels of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/pms-reduced-by-half-in-girls-who-had-low-levels-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pms-reduced-by-half-in-girls-who-had-low-levels-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-on-premenstrual-syndrome-related-mood-disorders-in-adolescents-with-severe-hypovitaminosis-d">Vitamin D Supplementation on Premenstrual Syndrome-Related Mood Disorders in Adolescents with Severe Hypovitaminosis D.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Pediatr Adolesc Gynecol. 2015 Dec 24. pii: S1083-3188(15)00444-1. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpag.2015.12.006.">doi: 10.1016/j.jpag.2015.12.006.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tartagni M1, Cicinelli MV1, Tartagni MV2, Alrasheed H3, Matteo M1, Baldini D3, De Salvia M1, Loverro G1, Montagnani M4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Biomedical Sciences and Human Oncology, School of Medicine, University of Bari &amp;ldquo;Aldo Moro&amp;rdquo;, Bari, ITALY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Centro di Fecondazione Medicalmente Assistita MoMò Fertilife, Bisceglie, ITALY; Department of Biomedical Sciences and Human Oncology, School of Medicine, University of Bari &amp;ldquo;Aldo Moro&amp;rdquo;, Bari, ITALY.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overweight women on caloric restriction diet got 3X benefits from 8 weeks of Omega-3 – RCT</title><link>/posts/overweight-women-on-caloric-restriction-diet-got-3x-benefits-from-8-weeks-of-omega-3-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overweight-women-on-caloric-restriction-diet-got-3x-benefits-from-8-weeks-of-omega-3-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Obese are 3.4 X more likely to be Vitamin D deficient – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/obese-are-34-x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-are-34-x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-meta-analysis-of-the-relationship-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-obesity">A meta-analysis of the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and obesity&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Clin Exp Med 2015;8(9):14977-14984 &lt;a href="https://www.iicem.com">www.iicem.com&lt;/a> /ISSN:1940-5901/IJCEM0011016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yingshui Yao, Lijun Zhu, Lianping He, Ying Duan, Wei Liang, Zhonghua Nie, Yuelong Jin, Xiaolu Wu, Yun Fang&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Public Health, Wannan Medical College, Wuhu 241002, Anhui, China&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received June 3, 2015; Accepted August 7, 2015; Epub September 15, 2015; Published September 30, 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/obesity-meta.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Previous epidemiologic studies suggested that vitamin D deficiency may be a risk factor of obesity. However, the result is still controversial. This meta-analysis aims to provide a comprehensive summary on the association between vitamin D deficiency and obesity. We systematically searched Pubmed database, Chinese Wanfang Data Knowledge Service Platform, and Chinese National Knowledge Infrastructure (CNKI), for the literatures on the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and obesity published from 2010 to 2015. The effect sizes of overall odds ratio (OR) and 95% confidence interval (CI) were estimated using Stata 11.0. Heterogeneity was evaluated using random-effects model and forest plots. Fifteen studies were eligible for inclusion in the meta-analysis, which included 3867 subjects with obesity and 9342 health subjects. Meta-analysis results showed that the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency was difference between obesity group and control group, and the pooled OR (95% CI) was &lt;strong>3.43&lt;/strong> (2.33-5.06).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uterine Fibroids (uterine leiomyoma, need hysterectomy) 1.9 more likely if a Vitamin D receptor problem</title><link>/posts/uterine-fibroids-uterine-leiomyoma-need-hysterectomy-19-more-likely-if-a-vitamin-d-receptor-problem.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uterine-fibroids-uterine-leiomyoma-need-hysterectomy-19-more-likely-if-a-vitamin-d-receptor-problem.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="exploring-the-link-between-vdr-rs2228570-and-uterine-leiomyoma-in-iranian-women">Exploring the link between VDR rs2228570 and uterine leiomyoma in Iranian women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Egyptian Journal of Medical Human Genetics, doi:10.1016/j.ejmhg.2015.08.007&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shirin Shahbazi,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evidences are growing toward an inhibitory role of vitamin D3 in uterine leiomyoma pathogenesis. Uterine leiomyoma commonly affects women of reproductive age and is referred to as one of the &lt;strong>most common indications for hysterectomy&lt;/strong> , worldwide. The effects of vitamin D are mediated through the vitamin D receptor. A single nucleotide polymorphism of the VDR gene results in longer protein with decreased activity. The present study has focused on the distribution of FokI polymorphism in Iranian patients with uterine leiomyoma. Using the PCR-RFLP method 45 cases and 53 controls were assessed. The results demonstrated a correlation between VDR TT genotype and uterine leiomyoma by Odds Ratio of 1.886 (CI, .767–4.640). The examination of heterozygous CT genotype also showed the same result by Odds Ratio of 1.875 (CI, .629–5.590).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Depression 13X more likely with polycystic ovary syndrome if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/depression-13x-more-likely-with-polycystic-ovary-syndrome-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/depression-13x-more-likely-with-polycystic-ovary-syndrome-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="predictors-of-depression-in-women-with-polycystic-ovary-syndrome">Predictors of depression in women with polycystic ovary syndrome.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Arch Womens Ment Health. 2015 Feb;18(1):95-101. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00737-014-0458-z.">doi: 10.1007/s00737-014-0458-z.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Sep 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Naqvi SH1, Moore A, Bevilacqua K, Lathief S, Williams J, Naqvi N, Pal L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study is to assess the prevalence and predictors of depressive symptoms in women with polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS). In a cross-sectional study of 114 women seeking consultation for symptoms of PCOS (menstrual irregularity, hirsutism, and/or acne), personal and family &lt;strong>history of depression (HD&lt;/strong> and FHD respectively) were enquired. Vitamin D status (n = 104) and manifest depressive symptoms assessed by personal health questionnaire (PHQ) (MD) were evaluated in a subset (85). Relationships between HD and MD with PCOS symptoms, FHD, and vitamin D status were assessed using adjusted analyses. Thirty-five percent acknowledged a HD; MD (PHQ &amp;gt; 4) was apparent in 43 %.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency again associated with higher cost of health care</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-again-associated-with-higher-cost-of-health-care.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-again-associated-with-higher-cost-of-health-care.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-and-monitoring-in-female-veterans">Vitamin D status and monitoring in female veterans.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Women Health. 2015;55(4):367-77. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/03630242.2015.1022685.">doi: 10.1080/03630242.2015.1022685.&lt;/a> Epub 2015 Apr 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alazzeh A1, Cooper MM, Bailey B, Youssef DA, Manning T, Peiris AN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1a Department of Internal Medicine, James H. Quillen College of Medicine , East Tennessee State University , Johnson City , Tennessee , USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An increasing number of women are serving in the military. We initiated a retrospective study to evaluate vitamin D status and monitoring in female veterans, and to examine the potential link between vitamin D status, age, race, post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), health care costs, and utilization. Approximately 44 percent of the 3,608 female veterans evaluated between 2001 and 2010 were vitamin D deficient (25(OH)D &amp;lt; 20 ng/ml), a rate substantially higher than that of the general population. While younger (&amp;lt;55 years) and older (55+ years) women did not differ significantly in initial vitamin D status, older women had significantly more vitamin D monitoring and follow-up testing than younger women. Approximately 44 percent of vitamin D deficient women did not receive follow-up vitamin D testing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bacterial vaginosis reduced 10 times by 2,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/bacterial-vaginosis-reduced-10-times-by-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bacterial-vaginosis-reduced-10-times-by-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-is-an-effective-method-in-the-elimination-of-asymptomatic-bacterial-vaginosis-a-placebo--controlled-randomized-clinical-trial">Treatment of vitamin D deficiency is an effective method in the elimination of asymptomatic bacterial vaginosis: A placebo- controlled randomized clinical trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Indian J Med Res 141, June 2015, pp 799-806 DOI:10.4103/0971-5916.160707&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mahshid Taheri1, Azam Baheiraei2, Abbas Rahimi Foroushani3, Bahram Nikmanesh4 &amp;amp; Maryam Modarres1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Midwifery, School of Nursing &amp;amp; Midwifery,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Reproductive Health Department, Tehran University of Medical Sciences,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Departments of Epidemiology &amp;amp; Biostatistics &amp;amp; Medical Parasitology &amp;amp; Mycology,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D for depression and PCOS: killing two birds with one stone ( should be 60 birds)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-for-depression-and-pcos-killing-two-birds-with-one-stone-should-be-60-birds.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-for-depression-and-pcos-killing-two-birds-with-one-stone-should-be-60-birds.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-for-depression-in-women-with-polycystic-ovary-syndrome-killing-two-birds-with-one-stone">Vitamin D supplementation for depression in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: killing two birds with one stone?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arch Womens Ment Health. 2015 Jul 16&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Xiang S1, Wu Y, Wang L, Hua F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Endocrinology, Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, 213003, Jiangsu, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:400px">
&lt;p>1 page letter to editor, Case report - 1 woman&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1200 IU daily for 6 months&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Raised vitamin D level from 16 ng ==&amp;gt; 43 ng&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improved muscle function in postmenopausal women with just 1,000 IU of vitamin D daily – RCT</title><link>/posts/improved-muscle-function-in-postmenopausal-women-with-just-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/improved-muscle-function-in-postmenopausal-women-with-just-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-alone-on-muscle-function-in-postmenopausal-women-a-randomized-double-blind-placebo-controlled-clinical-trial">Effect of vitamin D supplementation alone on muscle function in postmenopausal women: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2015 May 9. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cangussu LM 1 &lt;a href="mailto:lucianacangussu@gmail.com">lucianacangussu@gmail.com&lt;/a>, Nahas-Neto J, Orsatti CL, Bueloni-Dias FN, Nahas EA.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:500px">
&lt;p>postmenopausal women with a history of falls (associated with low vitamin D)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1,000 IU daily for 9 months&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="--vitamin-dplacebo">|| | Vitamin D|Placebo&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D at start|15 ng|17 ng&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D after 9 months|28 ng| 14 ng&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D helps women in many ways – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-women-in-many-ways-review.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-women-in-many-ways-review.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Post menopausal vaginal dryness treated with vitamin D vaginal suppositories – RCT</title><link>/posts/post-menopausal-vaginal-dryness-treated-with-vitamin-d-vaginal-suppositories-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/post-menopausal-vaginal-dryness-treated-with-vitamin-d-vaginal-suppositories-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-vaginal-atrophy-in-postmenopausal-women">The effect of vitamin D on vaginal atrophy in postmenopausal women&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Iranian Journal of Nursing and MidWifery Research Vol 20, No 2 (2015)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parastou Rad, Mitra Tadayon, Mohammadreza Abbaspour, Seyed Mahmood Latifi, Iran Rashidi, Hamdollah Delaviz&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:850px">
&lt;p>44 women in 8 week Random Controlled Trial&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vaginal suppositories: 1000 IU vitamin D or placebo&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/vaginal-atrophy.jpg" alt="image" width="800">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-women-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Women and Vitamin D">Overview Women and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Irregular menstrual cycles associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/irregular-menstrual-cycles-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/irregular-menstrual-cycles-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="lower-plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-is-associated-with-irregular-menstrual-cycles-in-a-cross-sectional-study">Lower plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D is associated with irregular menstrual cycles in a cross-sectional study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Reproductive Biology and Endocrinology 2015, 13:20 doi:10.1186/s12958-015-0012-5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anne Marie Z Jukic1 Anne MZ Jukic &lt;a href="mailto:jukica@niehs.nih.gov">jukica@niehs.nih.gov&lt;/a>, Anne Z Steiner2 and Donna D Baird1&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>15 year old Uterine Fibroid Study of black women&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low average level of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2X more likely to have irregular cycles for each 10ng less vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-women-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Women and Vitamin D">Overview Women and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ALL of the top 10 health problems of women are associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/all-of-the-top-10-health-problems-of-women-are-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/all-of-the-top-10-health-problems-of-women-are-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="major-causes-of-all-dalys-2003--2023--females">Major Causes of all DALYs 2003 &amp;amp; 2023 – Females&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="condition2003-2023">||Condition|2003| |2023|&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=48&amp;amp;deep=off&amp;amp;type=">Anxiety - Depression&lt;/a>|10.0%|1|8.7%|1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-diabetes-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Diabetes and vitamin D">Type 2 Diabetes&lt;/a>|4.9%|4|8.0%|2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-alzheimers-cognition-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Alzheimer's-Cognition and Vitamin D">Dementia&lt;/a>|4.8%|5|7.4%|3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-cardiovascular-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Cardiovascular and vitamin D">Ischaemic Heart&lt;/a> |8.9%|2|6.1%|4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-stroke-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Stroke and vitamin D">Stroke&lt;/a>|5.1%|3|3.8%|5&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low iron in teenage girls is 2X more likely if low vitamin D – 2014</title><link>/posts/low-iron-in-teenage-girls-is-2x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-2014.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-iron-in-teenage-girls-is-2x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-2014.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-vitamin-d-levels-are-associated-with-both-iron-deficiency-and-anemia-in-children-and-adolescents">Low Vitamin D Levels Are Associated with Both Iron Deficiency and Anemia in Children and Adolescents&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatric Hematology-Oncology, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3109/08880018.2014.983623">doi: 10.3109/08880018.2014.983623&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jun Ah Lee, Jin Soon Hwang, Il Tae Hwang, Dong Ho Kim, Ju-Hee Seo, and Jung Sub Lim&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Pediatrics, Korea Cancer Center Hospital, Republic of Korea, Seoul&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Pediatrics, Ajou University School of Medicine, Suwon, Korea&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Pediatrics, Hallym University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address correspondence to Jung Sub Lim, Ph.D., M.D., Department of Pediatrics, Korea Cancer Center Hospital, 215 Gongneungdong, Nowon-gu, Seoul 139-706 Republic of Korea. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:limjs@kcch.re.kr">limjs@kcch.re.kr&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hormonal contraceptives associated with higher vitamin D levels - 2013, 2018</title><link>/posts/hormonal-contraceptives-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-levels-2013-2018.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hormonal-contraceptives-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-levels-2013-2018.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#positive-association-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-c-reactive-protein-is-confounded-by-hormonal-contraceptive-use-may-2013">Positive association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D and C-reactive protein is confounded by hormonal contraceptive use= May 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hormonal-contraceptives--increased-vitamin-d-levels-26---rct--june-2018">Hormonal Contraceptives increased Vitamin D levels 26% - RCT June 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="positive-association-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-c-reactive-protein-is-confounded-by-hormonal-contraceptive-use-may-2013">Positive association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D and C-reactive protein is confounded by hormonal contraceptive use= May 2013&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2013 May;22(5):417-25. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1089/jwh.2012.4046.">doi: 10.1089/jwh.2012.4046.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>García-Bailo B1, Josse AR, Jamnik J, Badawi A, El-Sohemy A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutritional Sciences, Faculty of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, M5S 3E2, Canada.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perhaps women have lower levels of Vitamin D because vitamin D hides in fat</title><link>/posts/perhaps-women-have-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d-because-vitamin-d-hides-in-fat.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/perhaps-women-have-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d-because-vitamin-d-hides-in-fat.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="oops---conflict-about-which-sex-has-lower-vitamin-d-level-women-or-men">Oops - conflict about which sex has lower vitamin D level: women or men&lt;/h4>
&lt;h3 id="body-fat-percentagehttpwwwwikiwandcomenbody_fat_percentage-wikipedia">&lt;a href="http://www.wikiwand.com/en/Body_fat_percentage">Body fat percentage&lt;/a> Wikipedia&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/fat-percentage---wikipeida.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Click on chart for details&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/half-of-the-women-who-are-fat-do-not-have-a-high-bmi" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Half of the women who are fat do not have a high BMI – March 2012">Half of the women who are fat do not have a high BMI – March 2012&lt;/a> has the following&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F06;">Women&lt;/span> who were actually fat (40% to 50% fat), but had low BMI are the &lt;span style="color:#F06;">red dots&lt;/span> in the &lt;span style="color:#F0F;">pink region&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vaginosis not reduced by average of 2800 IU vitamin D daily – RCT</title><link>/posts/vaginosis-not-reduced-by-average-of-2800-iu-vitamin-d-daily-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vaginosis-not-reduced-by-average-of-2800-iu-vitamin-d-daily-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-blinded-randomized-controlled-trial-of-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplementation-to-reduce-recurrence-of-bacterial-vaginosis">A blinded, randomized controlled trial of high-dose vitamin D supplementation to reduce recurrence of bacterial vaginosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>American Journal of Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology, Volume 211, Issue 5, Pages 479.e1–479.e13, November 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presented at the joint meeting of the International Society for Sexually Transmitted Disease Research and the International Union against Sexually Transmitted Infections, Vienna, Austria, July 13-17, 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abigail Norris Turner, PhDemail, Patricia Carr Reese, MPH, Karen S. Fields, RN, Julie Anderson, MPH, Melissa Ervin, MT(ASCP), John A. Davis, MD, PhD, Raina N. Fichorova, MD, PhD, Mysheika Williams Roberts, MD, MPH, Mark A. Klebanoff, MD, MPH, Rebecca D. Jackson, MD&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Senior Korean women have much less vitamin D than men (possible reasons)</title><link>/posts/senior-korean-women-have-much-less-vitamin-d-than-men-possible-reasons.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/senior-korean-women-have-much-less-vitamin-d-than-men-possible-reasons.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="high-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-adults-aged-50-years-and-older-in-gwangju-korea-the-dong-gu-study">High prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in adults aged 50 years and older in Gwangju, Korea: the Dong-gu Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Korean Med Sci. 2014 Jan;29(1):149-52. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3346/jkms.2014.29.1.149.">doi: 10.3346/jkms.2014.29.1.149.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Dec 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Song HR1, Kweon SS2, Choi JS1, Rhee JA1, Lee YH3, Nam HS4, Jeong SK5, Park KS6, Ryu SY7, Choi SW7, Shin MH1.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:>80%">
&lt;p>Have often read that women have lower levels of circulating vitamin D than men&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Possible reasons include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and menopause -A narrative review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-menopause-a-narrative-review.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-menopause-a-narrative-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/Search+Results?hl=en&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search&amp;amp;googles.x=0&amp;amp;googles.y=0&amp;amp;q=menopause&amp;amp;domains=VitaminDWiki.com&amp;amp;sitesearch=VitaminDWiki.com">Search VitaminDWiki for MENOPAUSE&lt;/a> 301 hits as of July 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-women-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Women and Vitamin D">Overview Women and Vitamin D&lt;/a> which has the following graphic&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.vitamindcouncil.org/vitamin-d-news/recent-study-reports-no-effect-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-on-menopausal-symptoms/">Recent study reports no effect of vitamin D and calcium on menopausal symptoms&lt;/a> June 2015&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Study used only 400 IU of vitamin D - too little to make a difference&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>STD not decreased by metronidazole plus increasing the vitamin D levels to 30 ng</title><link>/posts/std-not-decreased-by-metronidazole-plus-increasing-the-vitamin-d-levels-to-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/std-not-decreased-by-metronidazole-plus-increasing-the-vitamin-d-levels-to-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-blinded-randomized-controlled-trial-of-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplementation-to-reduce-recurrence-of-bacterial-vaginosis">A blinded, randomized controlled trial of high-dose vitamin D supplementation to reduce recurrence of bacterial vaginosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Obstetrics and Gynecology, DOI: 10.1016/j.ajog.2014.06.023&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abigail Norris Turner, PhD1, Corresponding author contact information, E-mail the corresponding author, Ms. Patricia Carr Reese, MPH1, Ms. Karen S. Fields, RN2, Ms. Julie Anderson, MPH2, Ms. Melissa Ervin, MT (ASCP)2, John A. Davis, MD, PhD1, Raina N. Fichorova, PhD, MD3, Mysheika Williams Roberts, MD, MPH2, Mark A. Klebanoff, MD, MPH4, 5, Rebecca D. Jackson, MD6&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ovarian Cancer: Interplay of Vitamin D Signaling and miRNA Action. – 2014</title><link>/posts/ovarian-cancer-interplay-of-vitamin-d-signaling-and-mirna-action-2014.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ovarian-cancer-interplay-of-vitamin-d-signaling-and-mirna-action-2014.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2014;15(8):3359-62.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Attar R1, Gasparri ML, Donato VD, Yaylim I, Halim TA, Zaman F, Farooqi AA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Increasing attention is being devoted to the mechanisms by which cells receive signals and then translate these into decisions for growth, death, or migration. Recent findings have presented significant breakthroughs in developing a deeper understanding of the activation or repression of target genes and proteins in response to various stimuli and of how they are assembled during signal transduction in cancer cells. Detailed mechanistic insights have unveiled new maps of linear and integrated signal transduction cascades, but the multifaceted nature of the pathways remains unclear. Although new layers of information are being added regarding mechanisms underlying ovarian cancer and how polymorphisms in VDR gene influence its development, the findings of this research must be sequentially collected and re-interpreted. We divide this multi-component review into different segments: how vitamin D modulates molecular network in ovarian cancer cells, how ovarian cancer is controlled by tumor suppressors and oncogenic miRNAs and finally how vitamin D signaling regulates miRNA expression. Intra/inter-population variability is insufficiently studied and a better understanding of genetics of population will be helpful in getting a step closer to personalized medicine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Excess body hair in women (hirsutism): not much evidence that vitamin D helps</title><link>/posts/excess-body-hair-in-women-hirsutism-not-much-evidence-that-vitamin-d-helps.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/excess-body-hair-in-women-hirsutism-not-much-evidence-that-vitamin-d-helps.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hirsutism-an-evidence-based-treatment-update">Hirsutism: An Evidence-Based Treatment Update.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Dermatol. 2014 Jun 3. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somani N1, Turvy D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Indiana University School of Medicine, 550 N. University Blvd., Suite 3240, Indianapolis, IN, 46202, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:somanin@att.net">somanin@att.net&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hirsutism has a relatively high prevalence among women. Depending upon societal and ethnic norms, it can cause significant psychosocial distress. Importantly, hirsutism may be associated with underlying disorders and co-morbidities. Hirsutism should not simply be looked upon as an issue of cosmesis. Patients require appropriate evaluation so that underlying etiologies and associated sequelae are recognized and managed. Treatment of hirsutism often requires a multidisciplinary approach, and a variety of physical or pharmacologic modalities can be employed. Efficacy of these therapies is varied and depends, among other things, upon patient factors including the underlying etiology, hormonal drive, and local tissue sensitivity to androgens.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vaginal Vitamin D reduced vaginal infections</title><link>/posts/vaginal-vitamin-d-reduced-vaginal-infections.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vaginal-vitamin-d-reduced-vaginal-infections.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Female mortality predicted better by vitamin D than by C-Reactive Protein</title><link>/posts/female-mortality-predicted-better-by-vitamin-d-than-by-c-reactive-protein.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/female-mortality-predicted-better-by-vitamin-d-than-by-c-reactive-protein.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-predicts-all-cause-and-cardiac-mortality-in-females-with-suspected-acute-coronary-syndrome">Vitamin D Predicts All-Cause and Cardiac Mortality in Females with Suspected Acute Coronary Syndrome:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A Comparison with Brain Natriuretic Peptide and High-Sensitivity C-Reactive Protein&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiology Research and Practice, Volume 2013 (2013), Article ID 398034, 8 pages, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2013/398034">http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2013/398034&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patrycja A. Naesgaard,1,2 Ricardo A. León de la Fuente,1,3 Stein Tore Nilsen,4 Leik Woie,1,3 Torbjoern Aarsland,4 Harry Staines,5 and Dennis W. T. Nilsen1,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Cardiology, Stavanger University Hospital, 4068 Stavanger, Norway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Institute of Medicine, University of Bergen, 5021 Bergen, Norway&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Being on “the pill” increases low vitamin D levels by about 20 percent</title><link>/posts/being-on-the-pill-increases-low-vitamin-d-levels-by-about-20-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/being-on-the-pill-increases-low-vitamin-d-levels-by-about-20-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="increased-plasma-concentrations-of-vitamin-d-metabolites-and-vitamin-d-binding-protein-in-women-using-hormonal-contraceptives-a-cross-sectional-study">Increased Plasma Concentrations of Vitamin D Metabolites and Vitamin D Binding Protein in Women Using Hormonal Contraceptives: A Cross-Sectional Study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(9), 3470-3480; doi:10.3390/nu5093470&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ulla K. Møller 1, &lt;a href="mailto:kristine.moller@ki.au.dk">kristine.moller@ki.au.dk&lt;/a>, Susanna við Streym 1, Lars T. Jensen 2, Leif Mosekilde 1, Inez Schoenmakers 3, Shailja Nigdikar 3 and Lars Rejnmark 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Endocrinology and Internal Medicine, THG, Aarhus University Hospital, Tage Hansens Gade&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2, DK, Aarhus 8000, Denmark 2 Department of Clinical Physiology, Glostrup University Hospital, Copenhagen DK-2900, Denmark&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolic syndrome 2.4 X more likely if senior women had low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-24-x-more-likely-if-senior-women-had-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-24-x-more-likely-if-senior-women-had-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-serum-vitamin-d-level-is-associated-with-high-risk-of-metabolic-syndrome-in-post-menopausal-women">Low serum vitamin D level is associated with high risk of metabolic syndrome in post-menopausal women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Endocrinol Invest. 2013 Nov;36(10):791-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Song HR, Park CH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology, Graduate School of Public Health, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Serum vitamin D status, as indicated by 25-(OH)D, is inversely associated with glucose homeostasis, lipid profiles, and blood pressure. Evidence on the association of serum vitamin D with metabolic syndrome (MS) however, is very limited in post-menopausal women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Endometriosis treated, and perhaps prevented, by vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/endometriosis-treated-and-perhaps-prevented-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/endometriosis-treated-and-perhaps-prevented-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Introduction:&lt;br>
Endometrial tissue inside the uterus expands and then is shed during menstruation.&lt;br>
Sometimes the tissue attaches itself on the outside of the uterus or elsewhere in the body.&lt;br>
It continues to cycle in size with each menstrual cycle.&lt;br>
Normally the autoimmune system destroys these attachments.&lt;br>
There is some effort to call Endo an autoimmune disorder&lt;br>
Note: High-Dose Vitamin D + Magnesium + Omega-3 is claimed to &lt;a href="/posts/video-by-dr-coimbra-95-percent-of-auto-immune-cured-with-vitamin-d-in-high-doses">treat 95% of all autoimmune disorders&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death of women from cancer 24% less likely if 20 ng more vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/death-of-women-from-cancer-24-percent-less-likely-if-20-ng-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-of-women-from-cancer-24-percent-less-likely-if-20-ng-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-serum-concentration-and-total-cancer-incidence-and-mortality-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D serum concentration and total cancer incidence and mortality: a systematic review and meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Prev Med. 2013 Sep 10. pii: S0091-7435(13)00318-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2013.08.026.">doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2013.08.026.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yin L, Mena JM, Chen T, Schöttker B, Arndt V, Brenner H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Clinical Epidemiology and Aging Research, German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ), Heidelberg, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To conduct a systematic review and meta-analysis of longitudinal studies on the association of 25(OH)D with total cancer incidence and mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X increased chance of anemia (low iron) associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/2x-increased-chance-of-anemia-low-iron-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-increased-chance-of-anemia-low-iron-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="non-linear-relationship-between-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-hemoglobin-in-korean-females-the-korean-national-health-and-nutrition-examination-survey-2010-2011">Non-Linear Relationship between Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Hemoglobin in Korean Females: The Korean National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2010-2011.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PLOS One PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Han SS, Kim M, Kim H, Lee SM, Oh YJ, Lee JP, Kim S, Joo KW, Lim CS, Kim YS, Kim&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Anemia and vitamin D deficiency are both important health issues; however, the nature of the association between vitamin D and either hemoglobin or anemia remains unresolved in the general population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Huge variation in taking vitamin D supplements with age of female, less than 1000 IU not help much</title><link>/posts/huge-variation-in-taking-vitamin-d-supplements-with-age-of-female-less-than-1000-iu-not-help-much.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/huge-variation-in-taking-vitamin-d-supplements-with-age-of-female-less-than-1000-iu-not-help-much.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="characteristics-of-users-of-supplements-containing-vitamin-d-in-canada-and-associations-between-dose-and-25-hydroxvitamin-d">Characteristics of users of supplements containing vitamin D in Canada and associations between dose and 25-hydroxvitamin D.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2013 Jul;38(7):707-15. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1139/apnm-2012-0316.">doi: 10.1139/apnm-2012-0316.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Jan 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Greene-Finestone LS, Langlois KA, Whiting SJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Social Determinants and Science Integration Directorate, Public Health Agency of Canada, AL 6809A, Room 926A3, 785 Carling Avenue, Ottawa, ON K1A 0K9, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Canadians using supplements containing vitamin D are more likely to have 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels consistent with the Recommended Dietary Allowance, particularly with the low UVB exposure during the winter. This study aimed to determine these users&amp;rsquo; characteristics and to examine the relationship between dosage and 25(OH)D using the 2007-2009 Canadian Health Measures Survey (n = 5604, 6-79 years of age). Logistic regression models examined the odds of supplement use within the preceding 30 days.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Micronutrients such as vitamin D for women and childhood</title><link>/posts/review-of-micronutrients-such-as-vitamin-d-for-women-and-childhood.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-micronutrients-such-as-vitamin-d-for-women-and-childhood.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="micronutrients-food-fortification-and-its-impact-on-woman-and-child-health-a-systematic-review">Micronutrients food fortification and its impact on woman and child health: a systematic review.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Syst Rev. 2013 Aug 23;2(1):67.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Das JK, Salam RA, Kumar R, Bhutta ZA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamins and minerals are essential for growth and metabolism. The World Health Organization estimates that more than 2 billion people are deficient in key vitamins and minerals. Groups most vulnerable to these micronutrient deficiencies are pregnant and lactating women and young children, given their increased demands. Food fortification is one of the strategies that has been used safely and effectively to prevent vitamin and mineral deficiencies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deficiencies of iron and vitamin D are interrelated in women</title><link>/posts/deficiencies-of-iron-and-vitamin-d-are-interrelated-in-women.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/deficiencies-of-iron-and-vitamin-d-are-interrelated-in-women.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="relationship-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-bone-remodelling-and-iron-status-in-iron-deficient-young-women-consuming-an-iron-fortified-food">Relationship between vitamin D deficiency, bone remodelling and iron status in iron-deficient young women consuming an iron-fortified food.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Nutr. 2013 Mar;52(2):695-703. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00394-012-0375-8.">doi: 10.1007/s00394-012-0375-8.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 May 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Blanco-Rojo R, Pérez-Granados AM, Toxqui L, Zazo P, de la Piedra C, Vaquero MP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Metabolism and Nutrition, Institute of Food Science, Technology and Nutrition (ICTAN), Spanish National Research Council (CSIC), Madrid, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:Iron and vitamin D deficiencies are two of the most widespread nutritional disorders in the world. Our aim was to know whether the consumption of an iron-fortified fruit juice modifies bone remodelling and the possible influence of baseline vitamin D status on the recovery of iron status in a group of iron-deficient women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recurrent urinary tract infection 4X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/recurrent-urinary-tract-infection-4x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/recurrent-urinary-tract-infection-4x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-association-between-serum-levels-of-vitamin-d-and-recurrent-urinary-tract-infections-in-premenopausal-women">The association between serum levels of vitamin D and recurrent urinary tract infections in premenopausal women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Infect Dis. 2013 Aug 1. pii: S1201-9712(13)00219-1. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2013.06.007.">doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2013.06.007.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nseir W, Taha M, Nemarny H, Mograbi J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, EMMS Nazareth, The Nazareth Hospital, Nazareth, Israel; Infectious Diseases Unit, EMMS Nazareth, The Nazareth Hospital, Nazareth, Israel; Faculty of Medicine in the Galilee, Bar-Ilan University, Safed, Israel. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:w.nseir@yahoo.com">w.nseir@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: To examine whether there is any association between serum levels of 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25(OH) vitamin D) and the recurrence of urinary tract infections (UTIs) among premenopausal women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2400 IU raised both black and white women to 40 ng of vitamin D – RCT 2013</title><link>/posts/2400-iu-raised-both-black-and-white-women-to-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-rct-2013.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2400-iu-raised-both-black-and-white-women-to-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-rct-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-young-caucasian-and-african-american-women">Vitamin D supplementation in young Caucasian and African American women&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Journal of Bone and Mineral Research Vol. 28 Issue 7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christopher J Gallagher MD1,*,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prachi S Jindal MBBS1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lynette M Smith MS2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is limited information on the effects of vitamin D on serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D in young people and none on African Americans. The main objective of this trial was to measure the effect of different doses of Vitamin D3 on serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) and serum PTH (parathyroid hormone) in young women with vitamin D insufficiency (serum 25OHD&amp;lt; 20ngml (50nmol/L). A randomized double blind placebo controlled trial of vitamin D3 was conducted in young Caucasian and African American women, age 25–45 years. 198 healthy Caucasian (60 percent) and African American (40 percent) women were randomly assigned to placebo, vitamin D3 &lt;strong>400, 800, 1600 or 2400 IU&lt;/strong> daily. Calcium supplements were added to maintain a total calcium intake of 1200–1400 mg daily. The primary outcomes of the study were the final serum 25OHD and PTH levels at 12 months. The absolute increase in serum 25OHD with vitamin D 400, 800, 1600 and 2400 IU daily was slightly greater in African Americans than Caucasian women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Those low on vitamin D were 2.4X more likely to gain weight</title><link>/posts/those-low-on-vitamin-d-were-24x-more-likely-to-gain-weight.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/those-low-on-vitamin-d-were-24x-more-likely-to-gain-weight.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="hypovitaminosis-d-and-incidence-of-obesity-a-prospective-study-short-communication">Hypovitaminosis D and incidence of obesity: a prospective study, Short Communication&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Clinical Nutrition (2013) 67, 680–682; doi:10.1038/ejcn.2013.48;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I González-Molero1,2, G Rojo-Martínez1,2, S Morcillo1,2, C Gutierrez1,2, E Rubio1,2, V Pérez-Valero3, I Esteva1,2, M S Ruiz de Adana1,2, M C Almaraz1,2, N Colomo1,2, G Olveira1,2 and F Soriguer1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Servicio de Endocrinología y Nutrición, Hospital Regional Universitario Carlos Haya de Málaga, Málaga, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Ciber de Diabetes y Metabolismo (CIBERDEM), Barcelona, Spain&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Japanese women 20X more likely to be vitamin D deficient than men, etc. – Many 2013</title><link>/posts/japanese-women-20x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-men-etc-many-2013.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/japanese-women-20x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-men-etc-many-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="profiles-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-and-deficiency-in-japanese-men-and-women-association-with-biological-environmental-and-nutritional-factors-and-coexisting-disorders-the-road-study">Profiles of vitamin D insufficiency and deficiency in Japanese men and women: association with biological, environmental, and nutritional factors and coexisting disorders: the ROAD study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2013 May 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yoshimura N, Muraki S, Oka H, Morita M, Yamada H, Tanaka S, Kawaguchi H, Nakamura K, Akune T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Joint Disease Research, 22nd Century Medical and Research Center, Graduate School of Medicine, The University of Tokyo, 7-3-1 Hongo, Bunkyo-ku, Tokyo, 113-8655, Japan, &lt;a href="mailto:YOSHIMURAN-ORT@h.u-tokyo.ac.jp">YOSHIMURAN-ORT@h.u-tokyo.ac.jp&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uterine fibroids (hysterectomy) 32 percent more likely if less than 20 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/uterine-fibroids-hysterectomy-32-percent-more-likely-if-less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uterine-fibroids-hysterectomy-32-percent-more-likely-if-less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/gif/education-fibroid-tumors.gif" alt="image">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>African American women are 2X to 3X more likely to get fibroids than Caucasian women&lt;/strong> Wikipedia&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-uterine-fibroidsreview-of-the-literature-and-novel-concepts---july-2018">Vitamin D and Uterine Fibroids—Review of the Literature and Novel Concepts - July 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#3x-reduction-in-uf-after-1-year-of-vitamin-d-less-than-half-got--30-ng-level--2016">3x reduction in UF after 1 year of vitamin D (less than half got &amp;gt; 30 ng level)- 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-vitamindwiki">See VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-the-risk-of-uterine-fibroids---2013">Vitamin d and the risk of uterine fibroids - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-in-women-with-uterine-leiomyomas-aug-2013">Vitamin D status in women with uterine leiomyomas. (Aug 2013)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#racial-and-ethnic-differences-in-the-pathogenesis-and-clinical-manifestations-of-uterine-leiomyoma-sept-2013">Racial and ethnic differences in the pathogenesis and clinical manifestations of uterine leiomyoma. (Sept 2013)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-vitamin-d-associated-with-high-volume-of-uterine-fibroid-in-dark-skinned-women---feb-2013">Low Vitamin D associated with high volume of uterine fibroid in dark skinned women - Feb 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-uterine-fibroidsreview-of-the-literature-and-novel-concepts---july-2018">Vitamin D and Uterine Fibroids—Review of the Literature and Novel Concepts - July 2018&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2018, 19(7), 2051; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms19072051">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms19072051&lt;/a> (registering DOI)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The women who most need vitamin D are the least to get it – thesis</title><link>/posts/the-women-who-most-need-vitamin-d-are-the-least-to-get-it-thesis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-women-who-most-need-vitamin-d-are-the-least-to-get-it-thesis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-among-women-of-childbearing-age-prevalence-and-disparities">Vitamin D Supplementation Among Women of Childbearing Age: Prevalence and Disparities&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Deborah Beth Gardner&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A thesis submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Master of Public Health&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Washington 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Committee: Janice Bell Mario Kratz Daniel A. Enquobahrie&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Program Authorized to Offer Degree: Maternal and Child Health Leadership Training Program, Health Services&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deborah Gardner, MPHc University of Washington - Health Services, Maternal and Child Health&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Endometriosis 24 percent less likely if high predicted vitamin D level</title><link>/posts/endometriosis-24-percent-less-likely-if-high-predicted-vitamin-d-level.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/endometriosis-24-percent-less-likely-if-high-predicted-vitamin-d-level.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dairy-food-calcium-magnesium-and-vitamin-d-intake-and-endometriosis-a-prospective-cohort-study">Dairy-Food, Calcium, Magnesium, and Vitamin D Intake and Endometriosis: A Prospective Cohort Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am. J. Epidemiol. (2013) &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/aje/kws243">doi: 10.1093/aje/kws243&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Holly R. Harris*, Jorge E. Chavarro, Susan Malspeis, Walter C. Willett and Stacey A. Missmer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵*Correspondence to Dr. Holly R. Harris, Ob/Gyn Epidemiology Center, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, 221 Longwood Avenue, Boston, MA 02115 (e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:hharris3@partners.org">hharris3@partners.org&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The etiology of endometriosis is poorly understood, and few modifiable risk factors have been identified. Dairy foods and some nutrients can modulate inflammatory and immune factors, which are altered in women with endometriosis. We investigated whether intake of dairy foods, nutrients concentrated in dairy foods, and &lt;strong>predicted&lt;/strong> plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels were associated with incident laparoscopically confirmed endometriosis among 70,556 US women in Nurses’ Health Study II. Diet was assessed via food frequency questionnaire. A score for predicted 25(OH)D level was calculated for each participant. During 737,712 person-years of follow-up over a 14-year period (1991–2005), 1,385 cases of incident laparoscopically confirmed endometriosis were reported. Intakes of total and low-fat dairy foods were associated with a lower risk of endometriosis. Women consuming more than 3 servings of total dairy foods per day were 18% less likely to be diagnosed with endometriosis than those reporting 2 servings per day (rate ratio = 0.82, 95% confidence interval: 0.71, 0.95; Ptrend = 0.03). In addition, &lt;strong>predicted&lt;/strong> plasma 25(OH)D level was inversely associated with endometriosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D almost as good as dydrogesterone in improving women’s general health</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-almost-as-good-as-dydrogesterone-in-improving-womens-general-health.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-almost-as-good-as-dydrogesterone-in-improving-womens-general-health.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-comparison-between-the-efficacy-of-dydrogesterone-and-calcium-plus-vitamin-d-in-improving-womens-general-health">A comparison between the efficacy of dydrogesterone and calcium plus vitamin D in improving women&amp;rsquo;s general health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Afr J Psychiatry (Johannesbg). 2010 Jul;13(3):218-24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Khajehei M, Abdali K, Tabatabaee HR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>College of Nursing &amp;amp; Midwifery, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial was to evaluate the effect of dydrogesterone and calcium plus vitamin D on young women&amp;rsquo;s general health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHOD:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One hundred and eighty students studying at Shiraz University were recruited. Students completed the General Health Questionnaires (GHQ-28) prior to participation. They were then randomly assigned to take a tablet containing either 5 mg of dydrogesterone, 500 mg of calcium plus 200 mg of vitamin D, or a placebo twice daily from the 15th to the 24th day of their menstrual cycle for 2 consecutive cycles, and to complete the same questionnaires during both the intervention cycles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less weight gain by senior women if vitamin D levels over 30 ng – Kaiser</title><link>/posts/less-weight-gain-by-senior-women-if-vitamin-d-levels-over-30-ng-kaiser.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-weight-gain-by-senior-women-if-vitamin-d-levels-over-30-ng-kaiser.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#associations-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-weight-gain-in-elderly-women">Associations between 25-hydroxyvitamin D and weight gain in elderly women.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="associations-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-weight-gain-in-elderly-women">Associations between 25-hydroxyvitamin D and weight gain in elderly women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2012 Oct;21(10):1066-73. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1089/jwh.2012.3506.">doi: 10.1089/jwh.2012.3506.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jun 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LeBlanc ES, Rizzo JH, Pedula KL, Ensrud KE, Cauley J, Hochberg M, Hillier TA; Study Of Osteoporotic Fractures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Health Research, Kaiser Permanente Northwest, Portland, OR 97227, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:erin.s.leblanc@kpchr.org">erin.s.leblanc@kpchr.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>25-Hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels are lower in obese individuals. Determining whether low vitamin D status can predispose weight gain requires a longitudinal study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fertility and sperm</title><link>/posts/fertility-and-sperm.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fertility-and-sperm.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-greatly-improves-fertility">Vitamin D greatly improves Fertility&lt;/h4>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start2 ~/tc~ -->
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-is-needed-for-human-fertility-goal-is-50-ng" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Vitamin D is needed for human fertility – goal is 50 ng – Sept 2018">Vitamin D is needed for human fertility – goal is 50 ng – Sept 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/in-vitro-fertilization-costs-at-least-10000-dollars-vitamin-d-costs-5-dollars" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: In-vitro Fertilization costs at least 10,000 dollars, Vitamin D costs 5 dollars">In-vitro Fertilization costs at least 10,000 dollars, Vitamin D costs 5 dollars&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: CVD: the primary cause of death in senior women, is increasing</title><link>/posts/off-topic-cvd-the-primary-cause-of-death-in-senior-women-is-increasing.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-cvd-the-primary-cause-of-death-in-senior-women-is-increasing.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="changing-long-held-beliefs-is-never-easy">Changing Long-Held Beliefs is Never Easy:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-proposal-for-multimodal-approaches-in-female-healthcare---an-integrative-view">A Proposal for Multimodal Approaches in Female Healthcare - An Integrative View&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The EPMA Journal 2012, 3:14 &lt;a href="http://www.epmajournal.eom/content/3/14">http://www.epmajournal.eom/content/3/14&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olga Golubnitschaja, Secretary-General of EPMA, and Vincenzo Costigliola, President of EPMA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>   {EPMA = European Association for Predictive, Preventive and Personalised Medicine.}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="worldwide-cardiovascular-disease-cvd-is-the-leading-cause-of-mortality-in-women-cardiovascular-health-in-females-is-not-improving-as-fast-as-that-of-males">Worldwide cardiovascular disease (CVD) is the leading cause of mortality in women: cardiovascular health in females is not improving as fast as that of males&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Worldwide a third of all deaths of women and &lt;strong>half of all deaths of women over 50 years old in developing countries are caused by CVD&lt;/strong> &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. Several studies have been recently dedicated to the question of CVD-related death with particular focus on gender-dependent aspects. Although CVD is traditionally considered as the major health burden of male subpopulations surprising statistics have been collected for worsening the situation in females. New trends obviously demonstrate a shifting of the problem into healthcare of female populations: from 25 countries selected by World Health Organisation in the years 1990-2000, more than a half (15 countries, 60%) currently demonstrate either increase in CVD-related death in females or, even if the rates are decreased then less compared to men &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>During basic training white females decreased vitamin D but non-whites increased</title><link>/posts/during-basic-training-white-females-decreased-vitamin-d-but-non-whites-increased.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/during-basic-training-white-females-decreased-vitamin-d-but-non-whites-increased.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Women around the world want whiter skin</title><link>/posts/women-around-the-world-want-whiter-skin.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-around-the-world-want-whiter-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-hrefpostsmany-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1586many-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic-a-aug-2012">&lt;a href="/posts/many-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1586">Many reasons why vitamin D deficiency has become epidemic &lt;/a> Aug 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Want whiter skin - especially women&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://innerreflectionstranscribed.wordpress.com/2007/04/25/fair-skin-desirable/">Here&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=K8PCYtg1SocC&amp;amp;pg=PT81&amp;amp;lpg=PT81&amp;amp;dq=desirability+of+white+skin&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=CI7w34zn6X&amp;amp;sig=2ma4FM-zouS59Afbz4tggXdxUNI&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ei=eaTaTbniI4HGsAOz0dGFDA&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;oi=book_result&amp;amp;ct=result&amp;amp;resnum=5&amp;amp;ved=0CDQQ6AEwBA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=desirability%20of%20white%20skin&amp;amp;f=false">Here (Helen of Troy)&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.abcdlady.com/2005-07/art6.php">Being Fair-Skinned in Today&amp;rsquo;s World&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/suntan-popularity-is-fading" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 304">Suntan: Popularity is fading&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/perhaps-not-burn-from-the-sun-if-have-enough-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1669">Perhaps not burn from the sun if have enough vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/09/23/thai-vulva-bleaching-product.html">Thai vulva-bleaching product&lt;/a> Sept 2012&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In many countries across south-east Asia, fairer skin has long been equated with higher class as it suggests a life not spent toiling in rice paddies under the sun. The Thai language is peppered with cultural expressions that denigrate dark skin, such as the insult dam mhuen e-ga – &amp;ldquo;black like a crow&amp;rdquo;. These days, rice farmers wear long sleeves, trousers, wide-brimmed hats and gloves&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fertility problem (PCOS) reduced by vitamin D, etc: many studies</title><link>/posts/fertility-problem-pcos-reduced-by-vitamin-d-etc-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fertility-problem-pcos-reduced-by-vitamin-d-etc-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-risk-decreased-27-by-omega-3-mendelian-study--sept-2024">PCOS risk decreased 27% by Omega-3 (Mendelian study) – Sept 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-treatment-needs-about-3000-iu-of-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-sept-2024">PCOS treatment needs about 3,000 IU of Vitamin D - meta-analysis Sept 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#need-more-pcos-studies-with-3000-iu-dosing---meta-analysis-sept-2023">Need more PCOS studies with &amp;gt;3,000 IU dosing - meta-analysis Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-and-vitamin-d-a-clinical-appraisal---sept-2023">PCOS and vitamin D: a clinical appraisal - Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-is-more-than-just-a-fertility-problem---pcos-reduces-longevity-by-1-year---2023">PCOS is more than just a fertility problem - PCOS reduces longevity by 1 year - 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-appears-to-be-helped-by-vitamn-d-probiotics-omega-3-etc---meta-analysis-sept-2022">PCOS appears to be helped by Vitamn D, probiotics, Omega-3, etc - meta-analysis Sept 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-physiopathology-and-vitamin-d-deficiency---aug-2022">PCOS Physiopathology and Vitamin D Deficiency - Aug 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos---menstrual-frequency-improved-by-50000-iu-vitamin-dweek--low-calorie-diet---rct-may-2018">PCOS - menstrual frequency improved by 50,000 IU Vitamin D/week &amp;amp; low calorie diet - RCT May 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-problems-reduced-by-vitamin-d-plus-omega-3--rct-june-2018">PCOS problems reduced by Vitamin D plus Omega-3 – RCT June 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos--live-birth-strongly-a-function-of-vitamin-d-level--rct-may-2016">PCOS – Live birth strongly a function of vitamin D level – RCT May 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-decreased-by-23-x-with-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-feb-2017">PCOS decreased by 2.3 X with Vitamin D - meta-analysis Feb 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-problems-greatly-reduced-by-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly--oct-2015">PCOS problems greatly reduced by Vitamin D (50,000 IU weekly) – Oct 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#therapeutic-implications-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-in-overweight-women-with-polycystic-ovary-syndrome-8500-iu-2012">Therapeutic implications of vitamin D and calcium in overweight women with polycystic ovary syndrome. (8500 IU, 2012)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-seems-to-have-helped-pcos-somewhat-2012">Vitamin D seems to have helped PCOS somewhat (2012)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#probable-connection-antimüllerian-hormone-levels---april-2014-50000-iu-weekly-helped">Probable connection: antimüllerian hormone levels - April 2014 50,000 IU weekly helped&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#-30-ng-recommended-to-reduce-pcos-june-2014">&amp;gt; 30 ng recommended to reduce PCOS (June 2014)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-may-be-due-to-being-overweight---turkey-which-also-has-low-vit-d-oct-2014">PCOS may be due to being overweight - Turkey (which also has low Vit D) Oct 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#wikipedia-highlights-on-pcos">Wikipedia highlights on PCOS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-decreased-by-magnesium-zinc-calcium-and-200-iu-of-vitamind---march-2018">PCOS decreased by Magnesium, Zinc, Calcium, and 200 IU of VitaminD - March 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-treatment-by-vitamin-d-is-aided-by-metformin---meta-analysis-feb-2024">PCOS treatment by Vitamin D is aided by Metformin - meta-analysis Feb 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="pcos-risk-decreased-27-by-omega-3-mendelian-study--sept-2024">PCOS risk decreased 27% by Omega-3 (Mendelian study) – Sept 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Causal relationship between fertility nutrients supplementation and PCOS risk: a Mendelian randomization study&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Female Athlete health problems may be due to lack of vitamin D and Iron</title><link>/posts/female-athlete-health-problems-may-be-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d-and-iron.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/female-athlete-health-problems-may-be-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d-and-iron.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>