<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UV and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/uv-and-vitamin-d.html</link><description>Recent content in UV and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/uv-and-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>UVA decreased vitamin D levels (again)</title><link>/posts/uva-decreased-vitamin-d-levels-again.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uva-decreased-vitamin-d-levels-again.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="phototherapy-with-uvb-narrowband-uvauvbnb-and-uva1-differentially-impacts-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3">Phototherapy with UVB narrowband, UVA/UVBnb, and UVA1 differentially impacts serum 25-hydroxyvitamin-D3.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Am Acad Dermatol. 2013 Jul 11. pii: S0190-9622(13)00539-2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/0.1016/j.jaad.2013.04.058.">doi: 0.1016/j.jaad.2013.04.058.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feldmeyer L, Shojaati G, Spanaus KS, Navarini A, Theler B, Donghi D, Urosevic-Maiwald M, Glatz M, Imhof L, Barysch MJ, Dummer R, Roos M, French LE, Surber C, Hofbauer GF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, University Hospital Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:laurence.feldmeyer@chuv.ch">laurence.feldmeyer@chuv.ch&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Ultraviolet (UV) B radiation increases serum 25-hydroxyvitamin-D3 &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>, but the influence of UVA1 and UVA/narrowband UVB (UVBnb) phototherapy on serum vitamin D is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D seasonality is a function of amount of atmosphere in the way</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-seasonality-is-a-function-of-amount-of-atmosphere-in-the-way.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-seasonality-is-a-function-of-amount-of-atmosphere-in-the-way.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-25ohd-serum-seasonality-in-the-united-states">Vitamin D (25OHD) Serum Seasonality in the United States&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PLOS ONE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amy K. Kasahara, Ravinder J. Singh, Andrew Noymer &lt;a href="mailto:noymer@uci.edu">noymer@uci.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D is an important micronutrient for health. Hypovitaminosis D is thought to play a role in the seasonality of a number of diseases and adverse health conditions. To refine hypotheses about the links between vitamin D and seasonal diseases, good estimates of the cyclicality of serum vitamin D are necessary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>68 percent got vitamin D above 40 ng by regular use of tanning bed</title><link>/posts/68-percent-got-vitamin-d-above-40-ng-by-regular-use-of-tanning-bed.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/68-percent-got-vitamin-d-above-40-ng-by-regular-use-of-tanning-bed.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="chart-from-grassroots-health">Chart from Grassroots Health&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/grassroots-tanning.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-uv-and-vitamin-d">Overview UV and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-from-low-cost-uvb-lamps">Vitamin D from low-cost UVB lamps&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-produced-by-uvb">Vitamin D produced by UVB – June 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/uva-decreased-serum-levels-of-vitamin-d-rct">UVA decreased serum levels of vitamin D - RCT Oct 2012&lt;/a> - be sure that UV source has enough UVB&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/uvb-added-in-classroom-reduced-cavities-increased-height-increased-academics-etc">UVB added in classroom reduced cavities, increased height, increased academics. etc&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/top-uk-soccer-coach-installed-vitamin-d-booths-in-his-club">Top UK soccer coach installed vitamin D booths in his club – Dec 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D produced by UVB</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-produced-by-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-produced-by-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="small-doses-from-artificial-uv-sources-elucidate-the-photo-production-of-vitamin-d">Small doses from artificial UV sources elucidate the photo-production of vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Photochem. Photobiol. Sci., 2013, June, DOI: 10.1039/C3PP50041A&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Richard McKenzie, &lt;a href="mailto:richard.mckenzie@niwa.co.nz">richard.mckenzie@niwa.co.nz&lt;/a> a Ben Liley,a Paul Johnston,a Robert Scragg,b Alistair Stewart,b Anthony I. Reederc and Martin W. Allend&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A National Institute of Water and Atmospheric Research, NIWA Lauder, Central Otago, New Zealand&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B School of Population Health, University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Cancer Society Social and Behavioural Research Unit, Department of Preventive and Social Medicine, Dunedin School of Medicine, New Zealand&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV decreases Multiple Sclerosis via cis-urocanic acid (and via vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/uv-decreases-multiple-sclerosis-via-cis-urocanic-acid-and-via-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-decreases-multiple-sclerosis-via-cis-urocanic-acid-and-via-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="modulation-of-multiple-sclerosis-by-sunlight-exposure-role-of-cis-urocanic-acid">Modulation of multiple sclerosis by sunlight exposure: Role of cis-urocanic acid&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Jorge Correale &lt;a href="mailto:jcorreale@fleni.org.ar">jcorreale@fleni.org.ar&lt;/a> , Mauricio F. Farez&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 16 March 2013; published online 24 June 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of cis-urocanic acid (UCA) as a UV-mediated immunomodulator in MS patients was investigated. Plasma levels of cis-UCA were significantly lower in MS patients compared to controls. Stimulation of MBP- and MOG-specific T cells in the presence of cis-UCA, significantly increased IL-10, and inhibited IFN-γ production. PBMCs cultured in the presence of cis-UCA increased CD4+CD25+FoxP3+ regulatory T cell percentages. Dendritic cells cultured in the presence of cis-UCA significantly reduced Ag presentation capacity. Finally, cis-UCA activated the 5-HT2A receptor, inducing the increase in phosphorylated forms of ERK 1/2 and JNK2. Thus, in addition to vitamin D, cis-UCA also appears to be an additional UV-mediated immunomodulator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dermatologists view of UV radiation and the Skin</title><link>/posts/dermatologists-view-of-uv-radiation-and-the-skin.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dermatologists-view-of-uv-radiation-and-the-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="uv-radiation-and-the-skin">UV Radiation and the Skin&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2013, 14(6), 12222-12248; doi:10.3390/ijms140612222&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John D&amp;rsquo;Orazio 1,* email, Stuart Jarrett 2 email, Alexandra Amaro-Ortiz 3 email and Timothy Scott 3 email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Graduate Center for Toxicology and the Departments of Pediatrics, Biomedical and Molecular Pharmacology and Physiology, Markey Cancer Center, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA 2 Markey Cancer Center, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA 3 Graduate Center for Toxicology, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV workshops in New Zealand</title><link>/posts/uv-workshops-in-new-zealand.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-workshops-in-new-zealand.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="new-zealand-had-workshops-on-uv-in-2002-2006-2010">New Zealand had workshops on UV in 2002, 2006, 2010&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.niwa.co.nz/our-services/online-services/uv-and-ozone/workshops">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> to get to page which has all of 2010 abstracts and posters in a single HUGE file - 19 MByte&lt;/p>
&lt;p>File is too large to post on VitaminDWiki.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-few-images">A few images&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/nz-uv1.jpg" alt="image" width="500">&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/nz-uv2.jpg" alt="image" width="500">&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/nz-uv3.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A proposed different action specta for UV/vitamin D on the skin&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/nz-qut1.jpg" alt="image" width="500">&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/nz-qut2.jpg" alt="image" width="500">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="abstracts">Abstracts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>UV Workshop Overview Ozone:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Past, Present and Future&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Antarctic Ozone Hole: Didn&amp;rsquo;t we fix that already?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Those low on vitamin D get the most sunbed benefit</title><link>/posts/those-low-on-vitamin-d-get-the-most-sunbed-benefit.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/those-low-on-vitamin-d-get-the-most-sunbed-benefit.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="increase-in-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-in-humans-after-sunbed-exposures-compared-to-previtamin-d3-synthesis-in-vitro">Increase in serum 25-hydroxyvitamin-D3 in humans after sunbed exposures compared to previtamin D3 synthesis in vitro.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Photochem Photobiol B. 2013 Mar 28;122C:32-36. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotobiol.2013.03.006.">doi: 10.1016/j.jphotobiol.2013.03.006.&lt;/a> Orlova T, Moan J, Lagunova Z, Aksnes L, Terenetskaya I, Juzeniene A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Optical Quantum Electronics, Institute of Physics, National Academy of Sciences of Ukraine, 03680 Kiev, Ukraine. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:orlovat@iop.kiev.ua">orlovat@iop.kiev.ua&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet (UV) radiation is liable to cause skin cancer but it is the main source of vitamin D. Vitamin D photosynthesis takes place in skin at sub-erythemogenic UV doses, while larger exposures destroy vitamin D and increase DNA damage. Proper UV dosimetry is needed to obtain an optimal vitamin D status when skin cancer risk is minimal. A simple approach to such dosimetry using physically measured accumulated UV dose cannot provide a satisfactory quantification of vitamin D because of the complexity of the processes involved in vitamin D synthesis. A biological dosimeter of vitamin D synthetic UV radiation (&amp;lsquo;D-dosimeter&amp;rsquo;) has been introduced earlier on the basis of an in vitro model of previtamin D photosynthesis. In the present study in vivo generation of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) in serum of healthy volunteers exposed to UV radiation from the sunbed was accompanied by in vitro measurements of vitamin D formation using &amp;lsquo;D-dosimeter&amp;rsquo;. It was found that the increase in serum 25(OH)D concentration depended both on the initial 25(OH)D level and on the cumulative sunbed exposure time. The observed linear correlation between in vivo and in vitro data can be used to estimate changes in vitamin D status after UV exposure using only one pre-exposure blood sample combined with further in vitro measurements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV and Vitamin D with in vitro model – PhD WJ Olds 2010</title><link>/posts/uv-and-vitamin-d-with-in-vitro-model-phd-wj-olds-2010.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-and-vitamin-d-with-in-vitro-model-phd-wj-olds-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="elucidating-the-links-between-uv-radiation-and-vitamin-d-synthesis-using-an-in-vitro-model">Elucidating the Links Between UV Radiation and Vitamin D Synthesis: Using an In Vitro Model&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>William James Olds&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BAppSc (Hons) (Physics) QUT, GradCert Res Commercialisation QUT&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the degree of Doctor of Philosophy, 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Public Health Faculty of Health&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Health and Biomedical Innovation Queensland University of Technology Kelvin Grove, Queensland, 4059, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet radiation (UV) is the carcinogen that causes the most common malignancy in humans - skin cancer. However, moderate UV exposure is essential for producing vitamin D in our skin. Vitamin D increases the absorption of calcium from the diet, and adequate calcium is necessary for the building and maintenance of bones. Thus, low levels of vitamin D can cause osteomalacia and rickets and contribute to osteoporosis. Emerging evidence also suggests vitamin D may protect against falls, internal cancers, psychiatric conditions, autoimmune diseases and cardiovascular diseases. Since the dominant source of vitamin D is sunlight exposure, there is a need to understand what is a &amp;ldquo;balanced&amp;rdquo; level of sun exposure to maintain an adequate level of vitamin D but minimise the risks of eye damage, skin damage and skin cancer resulting from excessive UV exposure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some childhood cancer 30% less likely in parts of California with more UVB</title><link>/posts/some-childhood-cancer-30-percent-less-likely-in-parts-of-california-with-more-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-childhood-cancer-30-percent-less-likely-in-parts-of-california-with-more-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="solar-uv-radiation-and-cancer-in-young-children">Solar UV radiation and cancer in young children&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Christina A. Lombardi 1, Julia E. Heck 2, Myles Cockburn 3, and Beate Ritz 4,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Epidemiology, UCLA Fielding School of Public Health&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Public Health, University of California&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Preventive Medicine, University of Southern California&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 UCLA Fielding School of Public Health&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵* Corresponding Author: Beate Ritz, UCLA Fielding School of Public Health, United States &lt;a href="mailto:britz@ucla.edu">britz@ucla.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Studies have shown that higher UV radiation exposure (UVR) may be related to lower risk of some cancers in adults. Recently an ecological study reported lower risks of some cancers among children living in higher UVR cities and countries. In a large population-based case-control study in California we tested the hypothesis that specific childhood cancers may be influenced by UVR.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVA decreased serum levels of vitamin D - RCT</title><link>/posts/uva-decreased-serum-levels-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uva-decreased-serum-levels-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="changes-in-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-cholecalciferol-after-one-whole-body-exposure-in-a-commercial-tanning-bed-a-randomized-study">Changes in serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and cholecalciferol after one whole-body exposure in a commercial tanning bed: a randomized study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocrine. 2012 Oct;42(2):430-5. Epub 2012 Mar 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Langdahl JH, Schierbeck LL, Bang UC, Jensen JE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Faculty of Health Science, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We wanted to evaluate the cutaneous synthesis of 25OHD and cholecalciferol after &lt;strong>one&lt;/strong> whole-body exposure to ultraviolet radiation type B (UVB) in a randomized setup. Healthy volunteers were randomized to one whole-body exposure in a commercial tanning bed with UVB emission (UVB/UVA ratio 1.8-2.0%) or an identical placebo tanning bed without UVB. The output in the 280-320 nm range was 450 µW/cm². Blood samples were analyzed for 25OHD and cholecalciferol at baseline and during 7 days after treatment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tuberculosis varies with UVB in Australia</title><link>/posts/tuberculosis-varies-with-uvb-in-australia.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tuberculosis-varies-with-uvb-in-australia.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="link-between-vitamin-d-levels-and-developing-tuberculosishttpwwwscoopconzstoriesge1303s00078link-between-vitamin-d-levels-and-developing-tuberculosishtm">&lt;a href="http://www.scoop.co.nz/stories/GE1303/S00078/link-between-vitamin-d-levels-and-developing-tuberculosis.htm">Link between vitamin D levels and developing tuberculosis&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="press-release-by-australasian-society-for-infectious-diseases">Press Release by Australasian Society for Infectious Diseases&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>New research presented at this week’s Annual Scientific Meeting of the Australasian Society for Infectious Diseases (ASID) in Canberra, Australia, suggests a link between vitamin D levels and the risk of developing tuberculosis (TB), with rates of &lt;strong>TB incidence up to 37% higher following darker winter months&lt;/strong> than during the rest of the year. The research is by Jennifer MacLachlan, Victorian Infectious Diseases Reference Laboratory, Melbourne, and University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia, and Dr Benjamin Cowie (the same affiliations plus the Royal Melbourne Hospital, VIC, Australia).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Texas company claimed tanning beds prevent cancer – had to pay 142,000 dollar fine</title><link>/posts/texas-company-claimed-tanning-beds-prevent-cancer-had-to-pay-142000-dollar-fine.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/texas-company-claimed-tanning-beds-prevent-cancer-had-to-pay-142000-dollar-fine.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="texas-co-penalized-for-claim-that-indoor-tanning-prevents-cancerhttpwwwbeaumontenterprisecomdefaultarticletexas-co-penalized-for-claim-that-indoor-tanning-4348225php20">&lt;a href="http://www.beaumontenterprise.com/default/article/Texas-Co-penalized-for-claim-that-indoor-tanning-4348225.php%20">Texas Co. penalized for claim that indoor tanning prevents cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Company name = Darque (dark) Tan LLC&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x">Use of tanning beds would reduce associated deaths by 10X – Oct 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/sunshine-dangerous-or-healthy-schachter-center-2009">Sunshine: Dangerous or Healthy – Schachter Center 2009&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-suntan-melanoma-and-vitamin-d">Overview Suntan, melanoma and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/interview-with-transcript-concerning-uva-uvb-and-health-grant">Interview with transcript concerning UVA, UVB, and health – Grant Dec 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/a-review-of-the-evidence-regarding-the-solar-ultraviolet-b-vitamin-d-cancer-hypothesis">A review of the evidence regarding the solar ultraviolet-B-vitamin D-cancer hypothesis - Oct 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20 percent less Rheumatoid Arthritis if got lots of sunshine</title><link>/posts/20-percent-less-rheumatoid-arthritis-if-got-lots-of-sunshine.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/20-percent-less-rheumatoid-arthritis-if-got-lots-of-sunshine.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="exposure-to-ultraviolet-b-and-risk-of-developing-rheumatoid-arthritis-among-women-in-the-nurses-health-study">Exposure to ultraviolet-B and risk of developing rheumatoid arthritis among women in the Nurses’ Health Study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ann Rheum Dis doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2012-202302&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elizabeth V Arkema1,2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jaime E Hart3,4,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kimberly A Bertrand1,3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Francine Laden1,3,4,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Francine Grodstein1,3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bernard A Rosner3,5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elizabeth W Karlson2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karen H Costenbader2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Epidemiology, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, Massachusetts, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Division of Rheumatology, Immunology and Allergy, Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB added in classroom reduced cavities, increased height, increased academics. etc</title><link>/posts/uvb-added-in-classroom-reduced-cavities-increased-height-increased-academics-etc.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-added-in-classroom-reduced-cavities-increased-height-increased-academics-etc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Top UK soccer coach installed vitamin D booths in his club</title><link>/posts/top-uk-soccer-coach-installed-vitamin-d-booths-in-his-club.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/top-uk-soccer-coach-installed-vitamin-d-booths-in-his-club.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="clipped-from-various-places-on-the-web-dec-20-2012">Clipped from various places on the web Dec 20, 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sir Alex Ferguson, manager of Manchester United soccer club, has revealed that United had a Vitamin D machine installed for compensate for Manchester&amp;rsquo;s lack of natural sunlight.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Used 3X per week by each of the soccer players&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Now Manchester United can combat lack of sun&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Manchester has a reputation as being one of the wettest places in the UK, so it&amp;rsquo;s little wonder Sir Alex Ferguson had a tanning booth installed so the players could top up their Vitamin D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview with transcript concerning UVA, UVB, and health – Grant</title><link>/posts/interview-with-transcript-concerning-uva-uvb-and-health-grant.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/interview-with-transcript-concerning-uva-uvb-and-health-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-uv-exposure-and-vitamin-d-dilemma-explained--interview-with-dr-william-b-grant">The UV-Exposure and Vitamin D Dilemma Explained – Interview with Dr William B Grant&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>UV-exposure and Vitamin D must be addressed in parallel.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.thetanningguru.com/the-uv-exposure-and-vitamin-d-dilemma-explained-interview-with-dr-william-b-grant/#axzz2FT35go8P">Tanning Blog&lt;/a> Dec 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That seems to be the only thing that the experts on the adverse effects from UV-exposure and the experts on vitamin D can agree upon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dilemma of Vitamin D and UV-exposure becomes bigger and bigger for every day as the mountain of evidence of the health benefits of vitamin D continues to grow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The sun appears better at reducing incidence of some cancers than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-prevention-of-cancer-by-sun-exposure-more-than-just-the-effect-of-vitamin-d--a-systematic-review-of-epidemiological-studies">Is prevention of cancer by sun exposure more than just the effect of vitamin D? -A systematic review of epidemiological studies.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Cancer. 2012 Dec 10. pii: S0959-8049(12)00885-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.">doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van der Rhee H, Coebergh JW, de Vries E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Hagaziekenhuis, P.O. Box 40551, Leyweg 275, 2504 LN Den Haag, Zuid-Holland, The Netherlands. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:hvdrhee@casema.nl">hvdrhee@casema.nl&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The number of studies reporting on the association between sunlight exposure, vitamin D and cancer risk is steadily increasing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting sunshine improves your health provided you do not sunburn - Grant</title><link>/posts/getting-sunshine-improves-your-health-provided-you-do-not-sunburn-grant.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/getting-sunshine-improves-your-health-provided-you-do-not-sunburn-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Re: &lt;a href="http://www.icnirp.de/activities.htm#UVI">Validity and Use of the UV Index&lt;/a>; a response to the UVI Working Group of the ICNIRP&lt;/p>
&lt;p>    &lt;strong>their response is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant, Ph.D., Sunlight, Nutrition and Health Research Center, San Francisco, CA, 94164-1603, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.sunarc.org">www.sunarc.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>December 10, 2012;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2005, the &lt;strong>International Commission on Non-ionizing Radiation Protection&lt;/strong> (ICNIRP) held an international workshop on UV exposure guidance: a balanced approach between health risks and health benefits of UV and vitamin D &lt;span>[no authors, 2006]&lt;/span>. I attended that workshop and presented a paper reviewing the epidemiology of disease risk in relation to vitamin D insufficiency &lt;span>[Grant, 2006]&lt;/span>. Of the 22 papers arising from that workshop, six of the seven papers with the highest citations according to scholar.google.com (includes journals and websites) were on vitamin D and its health benefits &lt;span>[Grant, 2006 (113 citations); Holick, 2006 (168 citations); Lips, 2006 (373 citations); Webb, 2006 (150 citations); Vieth, 2006 (121 citations); Zittermann, 2006 (233 citations)]&lt;/span> but only one regarding the adverse health effects of UV irradiance &lt;span>[Gallagher and Lee, 2006 (124 citations)]&lt;/span>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solar UVB reduces Cancer Risk – Grant,</title><link>/posts/solar-uvb-reduces-cancer-risk-grant.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/solar-uvb-reduces-cancer-risk-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="update-on-evidence-that-support-a-role-of-solar-ultraviolet-b-irradiance-in-reducing-cancer-risk">Update on Evidence that Support a Role of Solar Ultraviolet-B Irradiance in Reducing Cancer Risk&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.140-146 (7)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author: William B. Grant&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="this-paper-was-in-a-jan-2013-issue-of-span-stylecolor090anti-cancer-agents-in-medicinal-chemistryspan">This paper was in a Jan 2013 issue of &lt;span style="color:#090;">Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h5 id="articles-copied-to-vitamindwiki-include">Articles copied to VitaminDWiki include&lt;/h5>
&lt;html xmlns:v="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:vml"
&lt;p>xmlns:o=&amp;ldquo;urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>xmlns:w=&amp;ldquo;urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:word&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>xmlns=&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40%22%3E">http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;head>
&lt;meta http-equiv=Content-Type content="text/html; charset=windows-1252">
&lt;meta name=ProgId content=Word.Document>
&lt;meta name=Generator content="Microsoft Word 10">
&lt;meta name=Originator content="Microsoft Word 10">
&lt;link rel=File-List href="Jan%202013%20Special%20Issue_files/filelist.xml">
&lt;title>• Solar UVB reduces Cancer Risk – Grant, Jan 2013&lt;/title>
&lt;!--[if gte mso 9]>&lt;xml>

&lt;/xml>&lt;![endif]-->&lt;!--[if gte mso 9]>&lt;xml>
&lt;p>&lt;/xml>&amp;lt;![endif]&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A review of the evidence regarding the solar ultraviolet-B-vitamin D-cancer hypothesis</title><link>/posts/a-review-of-the-evidence-regarding-the-solar-ultraviolet-b-vitamin-d-cancer-hypothesis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-review-of-the-evidence-regarding-the-solar-ultraviolet-b-vitamin-d-cancer-hypothesis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects mouse from skin cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-mouse-from-skin-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-mouse-from-skin-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects DNA against UV skin damage – 5 studies 2012-2013</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-dna-against-uv-skin-damage-5-studies-2012-2013.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-dna-against-uv-skin-damage-5-studies-2012-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Extensive proof that Vitamin D protects DNA in skin from UV damage&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Observation:&lt;/strong> People get a sunburn when getting lots of sun after months of little sun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Question:&lt;/strong> Would they not get a sunburn if they first stocked up on vitamin D?&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sunlight-and-vitamin-d-affect-dna-damage-cell-division-and-cell-death-in-human-lymphocytes-a-cross-sectional-study-in-south-australia">Sunlight and vitamin D affect DNA damage, cell division and cell death in human lymphocytes: a cross-sectional study in South Australia.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3-enhances-cellular-defences-against-uv-induced-oxidative-and-other-forms-of-dna-damage-in-skin">1?,25 Dihydroxyvitamin D(3) enhances cellular defences against UV-induced oxidative and other forms of DNA damage in skin.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#perspective-protective-actions-of-vitamin-d-in-uvb-induced-skin-cancer">Perspective Protective actions of vitamin D in UVB induced skin cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#active-vitamin-d-protects-skin-against-sunlight-damage--nov-2012">Active vitamin D protects skin against sunlight damage – Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-death-by-sunshine">Vitamin D and Death by Sunshine&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biologically-efficient-solar-radiation-vitamin-d-production-and-induction-of-cutaneous-malignant-melanoma">Biologically efficient solar radiation: Vitamin D production and induction of cutaneous malignant melanoma&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="sunlight-and-vitamin-d-affect-dna-damage-cell-division-and-cell-death-in-human-lymphocytes-a-cross-sectional-study-in-south-australia">Sunlight and vitamin D affect DNA damage, cell division and cell death in human lymphocytes: a cross-sectional study in South Australia.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mutagenesis. 2012 Sep;27(5):609-14. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/mutage/ges026.">doi: 10.1093/mutage/ges026.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Apr 29.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV improves immune system without increasing vitamin D levels in male mice</title><link>/posts/uv-improves-immune-system-without-increasing-vitamin-d-levels-in-male-mice.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-improves-immune-system-without-increasing-vitamin-d-levels-in-male-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="acute-erythemal-ultraviolet-radiation-causes-systemic-immunosuppression-in-the-absence-of-increased-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-levels-in-male-mice">Acute Erythemal Ultraviolet Radiation Causes Systemic Immunosuppression in the Absence of Increased 25-Hydroxyvitamin D(3) Levels in Male Mice.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(9):e46006. Epub 2012 Sep 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gorman S, Scott NM, Tan DH, Weeden CE, Tuckey RC, Bisley JL, Grimbaldeston MA, Hart PH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telethon Institute for Child Health Research and Centre for Child Health Research, University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is synthesised by ultraviolet (UV) irradiation of skin and is hypothesized to be a direct mediator of the immunosuppression that occurs following UV radiation (UVR) exposure. Both UVR and vitamin D drive immune responses towards tolerance by ultimately increasing the suppressive activities of regulatory T cells. To examine a role for UVR-induced vitamin D, vitamin D(3)-deficient mice were established by dietary vitamin D(3) restriction. In comparison to vitamin D(3)-replete mice, vitamin D(3)-deficient mice had significantly reduced serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3) (25(OH)D(3), &amp;lt;20 nmol.L(-1)) and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) (1,25(OH)(2)D(3), &amp;lt;20 pmol.L(-1)). Following either acute erythemal UVR, or chronic sub-erythemal UVR (8 exposures over 4 weeks) treatment, serum 25(OH)D(3) levels significantly increased in vitamin D(3)-deficient female &lt;strong>but not male mice&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Benefits of sun are more than vitamin D – 2008</title><link>/posts/benefits-of-sun-are-more-than-vitamin-d-2008.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/benefits-of-sun-are-more-than-vitamin-d-2008.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="benefits-of-sunlight-a-bright-spot-for-human-health">Benefits of Sunlight: A Bright Spot for Human Health&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Environ Health Perspect. 2008 April; 116(4): A160–A167.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. Nathaniel Mead&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each day, Apollo’s fiery chariot makes its way across the sky, bringing life-giving light to the planet. For the ancient Greeks and Romans, Apollo was the god of medicine and healing as well as of sun and light—but Apollo could bring sickness as well as cure. Today’s scientists have come to a similarly dichotomous recognition that exposure to the ultraviolet radiation (UVR) in sunlight has both beneficial and deleterious effects on human health.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intense UV damages cadaver skin</title><link>/posts/intense-uv-damages-cadaver-skin.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/intense-uv-damages-cadaver-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="solar-uv-radiation-reduces-the-barrier-function-of-human-skin">Solar UV radiation reduces the barrier function of human skin&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PNAS October 1, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Krysta Biniek, Kemal Levi, and Reinhold H. Dauskardt &lt;a href="mailto:dauskardt@stanford.edu">dauskardt@stanford.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA 94305&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Edited by John W. Hutchinson, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA, and approved August 31, 2012 (received for review April 25, 2012)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ubiquitous presence of solar UV radiation in human life is essential for vitamin D production but also leads to skin photoaging, damage, and malignancies. Photoaging and skin cancer have been extensively studied, but the effects of UV on the critical mechanical barrier function of the outermost layer of the epidermis, the stratum corneum (SC), are not understood. The SC is the first line of defense against environmental exposures like solar UV radiation, and its effects on UV targets within the SC and subsequent alterations in the mechanical properties and related barrier function are unclear. Alteration of the SC’s mechanical properties can lead to severe macroscopic skin damage such as chapping and cracking and associated inflammation, infection, scarring, and abnormal desquamation. Here, we show that UV exposure has dramatic effects on cell cohesion and mechanical integrity that are related to its effects on the SC’s intercellular components, including intercellular lipids and corneodesmosomes. We found that, although the keratin-controlled stiffness remained surprisingly constant with UV exposure, the intercellular strength, strain, and cohesion decreased markedly. We further show that solar UV radiation poses a double threat to skin by both increasing the biomechanical driving force for damage while simultaneously decreasing the skin’s natural ability to resist, compromising the critical barrier function of the skin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB 3X per week raise vitamin D levels more than did 1600 IU daily</title><link>/posts/uvb-3x-per-week-raise-vitamin-d-levels-more-than-did-1600-iu-daily.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-3x-per-week-raise-vitamin-d-levels-more-than-did-1600-iu-daily.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Too much UVB: skin cancer, too little UVB: other cancers due to low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/too-much-uvb-skin-cancer-too-little-uvb-other-cancers-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/too-much-uvb-skin-cancer-too-little-uvb-other-cancers-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="hope-and-challenge-the-importance-of-ultraviolet-uv-radiation-for-cutaneous-vitamin-d-synthesis-and-skin-cancer">Hope and challenge: The importance of ultraviolet (UV) radiation for cutaneous Vitamin D synthesis and skin cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>April 2012, Vol. 72, No. S243 , Pages 112-119&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jörg Reichrath &amp;amp; Sandra Reichrath&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Klinik für Dermatologie, Venerologie und Allergologie, Universitätsklinikum des Saarlandes, 66421 Homburg/Saar, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Jörg Reichrath, Klinik für Dermatologie, Venerologie und Allergologie, Universitätsklinikum des Saarlandes, D-66421 Homburg/Saar, Germany. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:joerg.reichrath@uks.eu">joerg.reichrath@uks.eu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Solar ultraviolet (UV)-radiation is the most important environmental risk factor for the development of non-melanoma skin cancer (most importantly basal and squamous cell carcinomas), that represent the most common malignancies in Caucasian populations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D from low-cost UVB lamps</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-from-low-cost-uvb-lamps.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-from-low-cost-uvb-lamps.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolorf00must-wear-glasses-when-near-uvb---it-can-damage-your-eyes-perhaps-within-minutesspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Must wear glasses when near UVB - it can damage your eyes, perhaps within minutes.&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Plastic contact lenses might pass UVB unless you have paid for UV blocking feature&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without UV blocking contacts you must wear glasses/ski goggles/whatever if you might look at the bulb&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Light years2 - out of business - Update Jan 2019&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>Founder of VitaminDWiki bought a GE lamp fixture Jan 2019 and used UVB bulk from previous Light Year 2 fixture&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D from the sun without the heat (silver-coated plexiglass)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-from-the-sun-without-the-heat-silver-coated-plexiglass.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-from-the-sun-without-the-heat-silver-coated-plexiglass.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="plexiglass--g-uvt">Plexiglass -G UVT&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>will pass UVB&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Is used in tanning beds&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Is used as covers for some pet cages&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="should-be-useful-as-a-window-glass-for-you-or-your-pet">Should be useful as a window ‘’glass’’ for you or your pet.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;1535&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="plexiglass--g-uvt-can-also-be-used-to-make-a-heat-shield-to-get-vitamin-d-from-the-sun-without-getting-too-hot">Plexiglass -G UVT can also be used to make a &amp;ldquo;heat shield&amp;rdquo; to get vitamin D from the sun without getting too hot.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Just need to add a coating to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>to absorb/reflect some of all of the UVA and IR portions of the spectra&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB produced 8X more vitamin D as solar UV</title><link>/posts/uvb-produced-8x-more-vitamin-d-as-solar-uv.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-produced-8x-more-vitamin-d-as-solar-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="increase-in-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-in-humans-after-solar-exposure-under-natural-conditions-compared-to-artificial-uvb-exposure-of-hands-and-face">Increase in serum 25-hydroxyvitamin-D(3) in humans after solar exposure under natural conditions compared to artificial UVB exposure of hands and face.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Photochem Photobiol Sci. 2012 Jul 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Datta P, Bogh MK, Olsen P, Eriksen P, Schmedes AV, Grage MM, Philipsen PA, Wulf HC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Copenhagen University Hospital, Bispebjerg, Bispebjerg Bakke 23, 2400 Copenhagen, NV, Denmark. &lt;a href="mailto:Pameli@mail.dk">Pameli@mail.dk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D studies are often performed under controlled laboratory conditions and the findings may be difficult to translate to natural conditions. We aimed to determine and compare the doses of natural solar ultraviolet radiation (UVR) with doses of artificial UVB radiation of hands and face needed to increase serum 25-hydroxyvitamin-D(3) (25(OH)D). Furthermore, we aimed to investigate the natural course of 25(OH)D due to solar exposure from April to September. 46 Caucasian volunteers were included. 17 volunteers received solar UVR (Group 1) in their natural Danish environment. Individual daily solar UVR doses in standard erythema doses (SEDs) were determined with personal wristwatch UV-dosimeters. 29 volunteers (Group 2) received artificial UVB doses of 6 SEDs (N = 14) and 3 SEDs (N = 15) on hands and face during late-winter/early-spring when outdoor UVB is negligible. 25(OH)D-levels were determined around every second week during study periods. Solar-UVR doses and sun-exposure diaries with information of sun-exposed areas were available from 8 volunteers and used for comparison with artificial UVB doses. However no significant solar-induced ?25(OH)D was observed when sun-exposed areas were limited to hands and face. Instead the earliest period (week 17-19) with significant ?25(OH)D, occurring after a mean of 2 days of sun-exposing more than hands and face, was used to estimate an approximate UVR dose required to increase 25(OH)D. This estimate resulted in a dose of 4.1 solar SEDs required to increase 25(OH)D by 1 nmol l(-1). The artificial dose of 6 SEDs of only hands and face significantly increased 25(OH)D and resulted in a dose of 0.52 SEDs required to increase 25(OH)D significantly by 1 nmol l(-1).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D from phototherapy lamps, tanning beds, and the sun</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-from-phototherapy-lamps-tanning-beds-and-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-from-phototherapy-lamps-tanning-beds-and-the-sun.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Sun provides more than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-sun-provides-more-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-sun-provides-more-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-moderate-sun-exposure-and-control-of-immune-diseases">Vitamin D supplementation, moderate sun exposure, and control of immune Diseases.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hart PH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Inflammation, Telethon Institute for Child Health Research, University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia 6008, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Discov Med. 2012 Jun;13(73):397-404.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is considerable debate about the benefits of vitamin D supplementation for multiple sclerosis, allergic asthma, and type 1 diabetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This has been driven mainly by observational studies linking vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency with increased prevalence of autoimmune and other diseases driven by immune processes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solar UV Doses of Adult Americans and Vitamin D3 Production</title><link>/posts/solar-uv-doses-of-adult-americans-and-vitamin-d3-production.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/solar-uv-doses-of-adult-americans-and-vitamin-d3-production.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Beneficial effects of UV radiation other than via vitamin D production</title><link>/posts/beneficial-effects-of-uv-radiation-other-than-via-vitamin-d-production.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/beneficial-effects-of-uv-radiation-other-than-via-vitamin-d-production.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Dermato-EndocrinologyVolume 4, Issue 2 April/May/June 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Asta Juzeniene and Johan Moan&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#abstract">Abstract:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cosmetic-tanning">Cosmetic Tanning&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#photoprotection">Photoprotection&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mood-enhancing-effects">Mood Enhancing Effects&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#phototherapy">Phototherapy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#modern-phototherapy">Modern phototherapy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mechanism-of-action">Mechanism of action&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#psoriasis">Psoriasis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitiligo">Vitiligo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#atopic-dermatitis">Atopic dermatitis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#localized-scleroderma">Localized scleroderma&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pain-relief">Pain Relief&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#uv-effects-on-skin-barrier-functions">UV Effects on Skin Barrier Functions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#uv-effects-on-other-diseases">UV Effects on Other Diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#beneficial-roles-of-uva-induced-nitric-oxide-no-on-human-health">Beneficial Roles of UVA-induced Nitric Oxide (NO•) on Human Health&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#no2---h--no--o--">NO2- + h? ? NO• + O•- .&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#protective-effects-of-uv-induced-no">Protective effects of UV-induced NO•&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#conclusions">Conclusions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Most of the positive effects of solar radiation are mediated via UV B (UVB) induced production of vitamin D in skin. However, several other pathways may exist for the action of UV (UV) radiation on humans as focused on in this review. One is induction of cosmetic tanning (immediate pigment darkening, persistent pigment darkening and delayed tanning). UVB-induced, delayed tanning (increases melanin in skin after several days), acts as a sunscreen. Several human skin diseases, like psoriasis, vitiligo, actopic dermatitis and localized scleroderma, can be treated with solar radiation (heliotherapy) or artificial UV radiation (phototherapy). UV exposure can suppress the clinical symptoms of multiple sclerosis independently of vitamin D synthesis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More UVB is associated with less cancer – study of 450,000 people</title><link>/posts/more-uvb-is-associated-with-less-cancer-study-of-450000-people.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-uvb-is-associated-with-less-cancer-study-of-450000-people.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prospective-study-of-ultraviolet-radiation-exposure-and-risk-of-cancer-in-the-us">Prospective study of ultraviolet radiation exposure and risk of cancer in the U.S.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Cancer. 2012 Apr 26. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ijc.27619.">doi: 10.1002/ijc.27619.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lin SW, Wheeler DC, Park Y, Cahoon EK, Hollenbeck AR, Michal Freedman D, Abne CC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer Prevention Fellowship Program, National Cancer Institute, Bethesda, MD; Division of Cancer Epidemiology &amp;amp; Genetics, National Cancer Institute, Bethesda, MD. &lt;a href="mailto:lins4@mail.nih.gov">lins4@mail.nih.gov&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ecologic studies have reported that solar ultraviolet radiation (UVR) exposure is associated with cancer, but little evidence is available from prospective studies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Macular Degeneration decreased with UV and perhaps Vitamin D genetics</title><link>/posts/macular-degeneration-decreased-with-uv-and-perhaps-vitamin-d-genetics.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/macular-degeneration-decreased-with-uv-and-perhaps-vitamin-d-genetics.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="systems-biology-based-analysis-implicates-a-novel-role-for-vitamin-d-metabolism-in-the-pathogenesis-of-age-related-macular-degeneration">Systems biology-based analysis implicates a novel role for vitamin D metabolism in the pathogenesis of age-related macular degeneration.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Hum Genomics. 2011 Oct;5(6):538-68.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morrison MA, Silveira AC, Huynh N, Jun G, Smith SE, Zacharaki F, Sato H, Loomis S, Andreoli MT, Adams SM, Radeke MJ, Jelcick AS, Yuan Y, Tsiloulis AN, Chatzoulis DZ, Silvestri G, Kotoula MG, Tsironi EE, Hollis BW, Chen R, Haider NB, Miller JW, Farrer LA, Hageman GS, Kim IK, Schaumberg DA, DeAngelis MM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Possible DNA damage of skin if vitamin D levels less than 20 nanograms</title><link>/posts/possible-dna-damage-of-skin-if-vitamin-d-levels-less-than-20-nanograms.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/possible-dna-damage-of-skin-if-vitamin-d-levels-less-than-20-nanograms.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sunlight-and-vitamin-d-affect-dna-damage-cell-division-and-cell-death-in-human-lymphocytes-a-cross-sectional-study-in-south-australia">Sunlight and vitamin D affect DNA damage, cell division and cell death in human lymphocytes: a cross-sectional study in South Australia&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Visalini Nair-Shalliker1,2,visalinin@nswcc.org.au, Michael Fenech3, Peta M. Forder4,5, Mark S. Clements6,7 and Bruce K. Armstrong1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Sydney School of Public Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales 2006, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Cancer Epidemiology Research Unit, Cancer Council New South Wales, Sydney, New South Wales 2011, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 CSIRO Food and Nutritional Sciences, PO Box 10041, Adelaide, South Australia 5000, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is the UVB action spectrum for vitamin D correct – no vitamin D winter - 2010</title><link>/posts/is-the-uvb-action-spectrum-for-vitamin-d-correct-no-vitamin-d-winter-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-the-uvb-action-spectrum-for-vitamin-d-correct-no-vitamin-d-winter-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="is-the-action-spectrum-for-the-uv-induced-production-of-previtamin-d3-in-human-skin-correct">Is the action spectrum for the UV-induced production of previtamin D3 in human skin correct?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Photochemical &amp;amp; Photobiological Sciences Issue 1, 2010 Partner Societies&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary Norval , Lars Olof Björn and Frank R. de Gruijl&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photochem. Photobiol. Sci., 2010, 9, 11-17&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1039/B9PP00012G&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 02 Jun 2009, Accepted 16 Sep 2009; First published on the web 19 Oct 2009&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Biomedical Sciences, University of Edinburgh Medical School, Teviot Place, Edinburgh, EH8 9AG, UK. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:M.Norval@ed.ac.uk">M.Norval@ed.ac.uk&lt;/a>; Tel: +44 131 650 3167&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tanning bed, like vitamin D supplements, has non-linear relationship with blood levels</title><link>/posts/tanning-bed-like-vitamin-d-supplements-has-non-linear-relationship-with-blood-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tanning-bed-like-vitamin-d-supplements-has-non-linear-relationship-with-blood-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Even small amounts of UVB result in increased vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/even-small-amounts-of-uvb-result-in-increased-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/even-small-amounts-of-uvb-result-in-increased-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-responses-to-multiple-uv-exposures-from-solaria-inferences-for-exposure-to-sunlight">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin-D responses to multiple UV exposures from solaria: inferences for exposure to sunlight.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Richard McKenzie, Robert Scragg, Ben Liley, Paul Johnston, John Wishart, Alistair Stewart and Roshani Prematunga; &lt;a href="http://pubs.rsc.org/en/content/articlelanding/2012/pp/c2pp05403e">all New Zealand&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 11 Dec 2011, Accepted 18 Feb 2012; First published on the web 13 Mar 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photochem Photobiol Sci () (2012) PMID 22411223 DOI: 10.1039/c2pp05403e&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We investigate the relationship between blood serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and UV exposure from two artificial sources. We then use the results to test the validity of the action spectrum for vitamin D production, and to infer the production from summer and winter sunlight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVA from some tanning beds and most windows decrease vitamin D blood levels</title><link>/posts/uva-from-some-tanning-beds-and-most-windows-decrease-vitamin-d-blood-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uva-from-some-tanning-beds-and-most-windows-decrease-vitamin-d-blood-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Even cows need more than 90 minutes in the sun each day</title><link>/posts/even-cows-need-more-than-90-minutes-in-the-sun-each-day.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/even-cows-need-more-than-90-minutes-in-the-sun-each-day.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxycholecalciferol-status-in-plasma-is-span-stylecolor00flinearly-correlatedspan--to-daily-summer-pasture-time-in-cattle-at-56n">25-Hydroxycholecalciferol status in plasma is &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">linearly correlated&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> to daily summer pasture time in cattle at 56°N.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2012 Feb 6:1-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hymøller L, Jensen SK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Animal Science, Aarhus University, Blichers Allé 20, Box 50, DK-8830 Tjele, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In vitro studies with skin samples or pure precursors of cholecalciferol indicated that cholecalciferol synthesis during UV light exposure is a non-linear process. However, in vitro studies indicate nothing about the relationship between sunlight exposure and physiological cholecalciferol status of living organisms. Due to the lack of cholecalciferol in plant material, this relationship is important for herbivores including domestic cattle, particularly in organic agriculture, because the use of synthetic additives, like cholecalciferol, is restricted in order to fulfil the principles of sustainable organic production. The major physiological metabolite of cholecalciferol is the liver-derived 25-hydroxycholecalciferol (25(OH)D3). The purpose of the present study was to determine the relationship between sunlight exposure and 25(OH)D3 status in vivo in large herbivores during mid-summer at 56°N.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1 watt optical output UVB LED array</title><link>/posts/1-watt-optical-output-uvb-led-array.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1-watt-optical-output-uvb-led-array.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="note-by-henry-lahore-of-vitamindwiki">Note by Henry Lahore of VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>All thru 2011 I was only aware of 1/100 watt UVB LED. There now are UVB LED which are 100X more powerfu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They cost $500 in Feb 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price dropped to $367 by Dec 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update Aug 2014&lt;/strong> UVB LED no longer being sold by Avnet nor Mouser&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="from--uv-leds-ramp-up-the-quiet-side-of-the-led-market-magazinehttpwwwledsmagazinecomfeatures925">From &lt;a href="http://www.ledsmagazine.com/features/9/2/5">UV LEDs ramp up the quiet side of the LED market (MAGAZINE)&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Relative to visible LEDs, UV LEDs are a quiet market at only $30 million, yet recent breakthroughs in radiant power and intensity have enabled the displacement of mercury-vapor lamps in applications including UV curing and counterfeit detection, reports LAURA PETERS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS prevention by UV is 2X better than prevention by vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/ms-prevention-by-uv-is-2x-better-than-prevention-by-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-prevention-by-uv-is-2x-better-than-prevention-by-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sunlight-is-associated-with-decreased-multiple-sclerosis-risk-no-interaction-with-human-leukocyte-antigen-drb115">Sunlight is associated with decreased multiple sclerosis risk: no interaction with human leukocyte antigen-DRB1*15.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Neurol. 2012 Jan 31. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2011.03650.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1468-1331.2011.03650.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bäärnhielm M, Hedström AK, Kockum I, Sundqvist E, Gustafsson SA, Hillert J, Olsson T, Alfredsson L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Environmental Medicine, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm Department of Clinical Neuroscience and Center for Molecular Medicine, Karolinska Institutet at Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm Department of Molecular Medicine and Surgery, Karolinska Institutet at Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting little UV is associated with 15 types of Cancer</title><link>/posts/getting-little-uv-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/getting-little-uv-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="ecological-studies-of-the-uvbvitamin-dcancer-hypothesis">Ecological Studies of the UVB–Vitamin D–Cancer Hypothesis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Anticancer Research January 2012 vol. 32 no. 1 223-236&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WILLIAM B. GRANT, Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, P.O. Box 641603, San Francisco, CA 94164-1603, U.S.A. &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aim: This paper reviews ecological studies of the ultraviolet-B (UVB)–vitamin D–cancer hypothesis based on geographical variation of cancer incidence and/or mortality rates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Materials and Methods: The review is based largely on three ecological studies of cancer rates from the United States; one each from Australia, China, France, Japan, and Spain; and eight multicountry, multifactorial studies of cancer incidence rates from &lt;strong>more than 100 countries&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of health insurance varies with latitude - inversely with UV</title><link>/posts/lack-of-health-insurance-varies-with-latitude-inversely-with-uv.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-health-insurance-varies-with-latitude-inversely-with-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="map-from-wikipediahttpenwikipediaorgwikifilehealth_uninsurance_rates_in_the_united_states_by_state_2009svg-jan-2011">&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Health_uninsurance_rates_in_the_United_States_by_state,_2009.svg">Map from wikipedia&lt;/a> Jan 2011&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;992&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;993&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="uv-in-jan">UV in Jan.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;1361&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="perhaps-not-need-health-insurance-as-much-if-get-enough-winter-uvvitamin-d">Perhaps not need health insurance as much if get enough winter UV/vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-varies-with-latitude-map-of-chile" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Vitamin D varies with latitude - map of Chile">Vitamin D varies with latitude - map of Chile&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Lack of solar UVB in US is associated with some Cancers - 2006</title><link>/posts/lack-of-solar-uvb-in-us-is-associated-with-some-cancers-2006.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-solar-uvb-in-us-is-associated-with-some-cancers-2006.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="solar-ultraviolet-b-exposure-and-cancer-incidence-and-mortality-in-the-united-states-1993-2002">Solar ultraviolet-B exposure and cancer incidence and mortality in the United States, 1993-2002.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>BMC Cancer. 2006 Nov 10;6:264.Boscoe FP, Schymura MJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, University at Albany, Rensselaer, NY 12144, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:fpb01@health.state.ny.us">fpb01@health.state.ny.us&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An inverse relationship between solar ultraviolet-B (UV-B) exposure and non-skin cancer mortality has long been reported. Vitamin D, acquired primarily through exposure to the sun via the skin, is believed to inhibit tumor development and growth and reduce mortality for certain cancers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Psoriasis treatment by narrowband UV B – review</title><link>/posts/psoriasis-treatment-by-narrowband-uv-b-review.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/psoriasis-treatment-by-narrowband-uv-b-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="narrowband-ultraviolet-b-in-the-treatment-of-psoriasis-the-journey-so-far">Narrowband ultraviolet B in the treatment of psoriasis: The journey so far!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SYMPOSIUM - PSORIASIS&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Year : 2010 | Volume : 76 | Issue : 6 | Page : 652-661; 12-Nov-2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunil Dogra &lt;a href="mailto:sundogra@hotmail.com">sundogra@hotmail.com&lt;/a> , Dipankar De&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Venereology and Leprology, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMID: 21079308&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ever since artificial TL-01 lamps were developed, narrowband ultraviolet B (NBUVB) has gained giant strides in dermatology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolic Syndrome reduced 2X after one year of more sunlight</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-reduced-2x-after-one-year-of-more-sunlight.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-reduced-2x-after-one-year-of-more-sunlight.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Use of tanning beds would reduce associated deaths by 10X</title><link>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-sun-sunbeds-and-health">Vitamin D, sun, sunbeds and health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Oct 24:1-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moan J, Baturaite Z, Juzeniene A, Porojnicu AC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, The Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Ullernchausseen 70, Montebello N-0310 Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To review the health effects of solar radiation, sunbeds and vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DESIGN: The literature was searched in the electronic database MEDLINE to indentify published data between 1981 and 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV every two weeks maintains summer vitamin D level – RCT</title><link>/posts/uv-every-two-weeks-maintains-summer-vitamin-d-level-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-every-two-weeks-maintains-summer-vitamin-d-level-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>UV far from the equator</title><link>/posts/uv-far-from-the-equator.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-far-from-the-equator.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="availability-of-vitamin-d-photoconversion-weighted-uv-radiation-in-southern-south-america">Availability of vitamin D photoconversion weighted UV radiation in southern South America.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Photochem Photobiol Sci. 2011 Oct 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diaz S, Vernet M, Paladini A, Fuenzalida H, Deferrari G, Booth CR, Cabrera S, Casiccia C, Dieguez M, Lovengreen C, Pedroni J, Rosales A, Vrsalovic J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instituto de Genética y Biología Molecular (INGEBI), Centro Austral de Inverstigaciones Cientificas (CADIC), CONICET, Vuelta de Obligado 2490, 1428, Argentina.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet radiation (UVR) plays a key role in several biological functions, including human health. Skin exposure to UVR is the main factor in vitamin D photoconversion. There is also evidence relating low levels of vitamin D with certain internal cancers, mainly colon, breast and prostate, as well as other diseases. Several epidemiological studies have shown an inverse relationship between the above-mentioned diseases and latitude, in accordance with the ultraviolet radiation latitudinal gradient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview UV and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-uv-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-uv-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;1410&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#consensus">Consensus&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#confusiondisagreement">Confusion/Disagreement&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#spectrum">Spectrum&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#uvb-and-uva-are-very-different">UVB and UVA are very different&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#uv-different-spectra-uvb--vitamin-d-uva--pigmentations">UV: Different Spectra: UVB = Vitamin D, UVA = Pigmentations&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hypothesis-uva-decreases-vitamin-d-many-hints">Hypothesis: UVA decreases vitamin D: many hints&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#measure-uv">Measure UV&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#uv-thru-glass">UV thru glass&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#span-stylecolor00fno-uvb-vitamin-dspan-gets-thru-but-span-stylecolor600most--uva-tanspan-gets-thru">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">No UVB (Vitamin D)&lt;/span> gets thru, but &lt;span style="color:#600;">most UVA (Tan)&lt;/span> gets thru&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sunscreens">Sunscreens&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#increased-sunscreen--increased-melanoma">Increased sunscreen ==&amp;gt; increased melanoma&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#red--sunlight-other-lines--amount-of-light-filtered-thru-sunscreens">Red = sunlight; other lines = amount of light filtered thru sunscreens&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="consensus">Consensus&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>UV radiation at the ground consists mainly of UVA, some UVB, and a tiny amount of UVC&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Health and Light - Ott 1973</title><link>/posts/health-and-light-ott-1973.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/health-and-light-ott-1973.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Health and Light by John N. Ott&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-effects-of-natural-and-artificial-light-on-man-and-other-living-things">The Effects of Natural and Artificial Light on Man and Other Living Things.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>How light can work for you &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>for your health, your emotional well-being and your vibrant energy &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>no matter where you live or work!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published by Pocket Books – New York; Copyright John Ott Pictures, Inc. ; First printing 1973 – ISBN: 0-671-80537-1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reprint edition (April 1, 2000) – ISBN: 0-898-04098-1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perhaps UV is Addicting</title><link>/posts/perhaps-uv-is-addicting.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/perhaps-uv-is-addicting.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-tanning-changes-the-brainhttpwellblogsnytimescom20110812how-tanning-changes-the-brainnew-york-times-article-aug-12-2011">&lt;a href="http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/08/12/how-tanning-changes-the-brain/">How Tanning Changes the Brain&lt;/a>New York Times Article Aug 12, 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Clip - - -&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>On one occasion, the study subjects experienced a normal tanning session. But on another occasion, the researchers used a special filter that blocked only the UV light, although the tanners weren’t told of the change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brain images later showed that during regular tanning sessions, when the study subjects were exposed to UV rays, several key areas of the brain lighted up. Among those areas were the dorsal striatum, the left anterior insula and part of the orbitofrontal cortex – all areas that have been implicated in addiction. But when the UV light was filtered out, those areas of the brain showed far less activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>There is more in UV than vitamin D which suppresses MS in mice</title><link>/posts/there-is-more-in-uv-than-vitamin-d-which-suppresses-ms-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/there-is-more-in-uv-than-vitamin-d-which-suppresses-ms-in-mice.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>UV produces more than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/uv-produces-more-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-produces-more-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="modulation-of-the-immune-system-by-uv-radiation-more-than-just-the-effects-of-vitamin-d">Modulation of the immune system by UV radiation: more than just the effects of vitamin D?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Immunol. 2011 Aug 19. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nri3045.">doi: 10.1038/nri3045.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hart PH, Gorman S, Finlay-Jones JJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telethon Institute for Child Health Research, Centre for Child Health Research, University of Western Australia, PO Box 855, Perth, Western Australia 6872, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Humans obtain most of their vitamin D through the exposure of skin to sunlight. The immunoregulatory properties of vitamin D have been demonstrated in studies showing that vitamin D deficiency is associated with poor immune function and increased disease susceptibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Living in areas with more UV decreased lymph problems by 42 percent</title><link>/posts/living-in-areas-with-more-uv-decreased-lymph-problems-by-42-percent.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/living-in-areas-with-more-uv-decreased-lymph-problems-by-42-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="adulthood-residential-ultraviolet-radiation-sun-sensitivity-dietary-vitamin-d-and-risk-of-lymphoid-malignancies-in-the-california-teachers-study">Adulthood residential ultraviolet radiation, sun sensitivity, dietary vitamin D, and risk of lymphoid malignancies in the California Teachers Study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ellen T. Chang1,2; Alison J. Canchola1; Myles Cockburn3; Yani Lu4; Sophia S. Wang4; Leslie Bernstein4; Christina A. Clarke1,2; and Pamela L. Horn-Ross1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Cancer Prevention Institute of California, Fremont, CA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Division of Epidemiology, Department of Health Research and Policy, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, CA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Division of Epidemiology, Department of Preventive Medicine, Norris Comprehensive Cancer Center, University of Southern California Keck School of Medicine, Los Angeles, CA; and&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some cancer due to low UV – Grant</title><link>/posts/some-cancer-due-to-low-uv-grant.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-cancer-due-to-low-uv-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="an-ecological-study-of-cancer-mortality-rates-in-the-united-states-with-respect-to-solar-ultraviolet-b-doses-smoking-alcohol-consumption-and-urbanrural-residence">An ecological study of cancer mortality rates in the United States with respect to solar ultraviolet-B doses, smoking, alcohol consumption and urban/rural residence.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Grant WB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight, Nutrition and Health Research Center (SUNARC); San Francisco, CA USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2010 Apr;2(2):68-76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cohort Consortium Vitamin D Polling Project of Rarer Cancers (VDPP ) study failed to find a beneficial role of prediagnostic serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels on risk of seven types of rarer cancer: endometrial, esophageal, gastric, kidney, ovarian and pancreatic cancer and non-Hodgkin&amp;rsquo;s lymphoma (NHL).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In Defence of the Sun – reduce 400000 premature deaths – 2009</title><link>/posts/in-defence-of-the-sun-reduce-400000-premature-deaths-2009.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/in-defence-of-the-sun-reduce-400000-premature-deaths-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="in-defense-of-the-sun--an-estimate-of-changes-in-mortality-rates-in-the-united-states-if-mean-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-were-raised-to-45-ngml-by-solar-ultraviolet-b-irradiance">In defense of the sun -An estimate of changes in mortality rates in the United States if mean serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were raised to 45 ng/mL by solar ultraviolet-B irradiance&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2009 Jul-Aug; 1(4): 207–214. PMCID: PMC2835876&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B Grant. Sunlight, Nutrition and Health Research Center (SUNARC); San Francisco, CA USA, &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emerging scientific evidence strongly supports the beneficial role of vitamin D in reducing the risk of incidence and death from many chronic and infectious diseases. This study estimates increases in melanoma and nonmelanoma skin cancer mortality rates and decreases in chronic and infectious disease mortality rates in the US from the standpoint of approximately doubling population doses of solar UVB to increase mean serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels from 16 ng/mL for black Americans and 25 ng/mL for white Americans to 45 ng/mL. The primary benefits are expected to come from reductions in cancer and cardiovascular diseases. Although a few thousand excess deaths per year might occur from melanoma and skin cancer, the avoided premature death rate could be near 400,000/ year, with most of the avoided deaths coming late in life. While oral sources of vitamin D could be used instead of UVB or when UVB irradiance is not available, public health policies do not yet recommend the 3,000–4,000 IU/day required to raise serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels to the levels required for optimal health, which would be required before vitamin D fortification levels in food can be raised. Until then, moderate solar UVB irradiance remains an import source, and the health benefits greatly outweigh the risks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low UVB countries have higher leukemia rates</title><link>/posts/low-uvb-countries-have-higher-leukemia-rates.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-uvb-countries-have-higher-leukemia-rates.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ultraviolet Radiation and the Anterior Eye</title><link>/posts/ultraviolet-radiation-and-the-anterior-eye.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ultraviolet-radiation-and-the-anterior-eye.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eye Contact Lens. 2011 Jun 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coroneo M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Department of Ophthalmology, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The eye is on the one hand dependent on visible light energy and on the other hand can be damaged by these and the contiguous ultraviolet (UV) and infrared wavelengths.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diseases of the eye in which sunlight has been implicated have been termed the ophthalmohelioses, and these conditions pose a significant problem to the eye health of many communities. The ophthalmohelioses have a tremendous impact on patients&amp;rsquo; quality of life and have significant implications on the cost of health care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wear glasses when getting vitamin D from the sun</title><link>/posts/wear-glasses-when-getting-vitamin-d-from-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wear-glasses-when-getting-vitamin-d-from-the-sun.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Less UV means 2X more Breast Cancer</title><link>/posts/less-uv-means-2x-more-breast-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-uv-means-2x-more-breast-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="ultraviolet-sunlight-exposure-during-adolescence-and-adulthood-and-breast-cancer-risk-population-based-case-control-study-among-ontario-women">Ultraviolet Sunlight Exposure During Adolescence and Adulthood and Breast Cancer Risk: Population-based Case-Control Study Among Ontario Women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Epidemiol. 2011 Jun 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anderson LN, Cotterchio M, Kirsh VA, Knight JA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent studies suggest that vitamin D may be associated with reduced breast cancer risk, but most studies have evaluated only dietary vitamin D intake. The associations among ultraviolet radiation from sunlight, factors related to cutaneous vitamin D production, and breast cancer risk were evaluated in a population-based case-control study conducted in Ontario, Canada, between 2003 and 2004 (n = 3,101 cases and n = 3,471 controls).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2200X more problems from no UVB than too much UVB - WHO 2006</title><link>/posts/2200x-more-problems-from-no-uvb-than-too-much-uvb-who-2006.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2200x-more-problems-from-no-uvb-than-too-much-uvb-who-2006.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="world-health-organization-report-from-2006">World Health Organization report from 2006&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="click-herehttpswwwvitamindwikicomtiki-download_filephpfileid1892-for-pdf">&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1892">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for PDF&lt;/h4>
&lt;h5 id="optimal--not-too-much-and-not-to-little-uvb">optimal = Not too much and not to little UVB&lt;/h5>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"> 
&lt;h3 id="summary-daily-adjusted-life-years">Summary: Daily Adjusted Life Years&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If could get less UVB - &lt;strong>1.5 million DALYs&lt;/strong> could have been avoided&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If get no UVB &lt;strong>3,304 million DALYs&lt;/strong> would have been lost due to vitamin D deficiency diseases – rickets, osteomalacia and osteoporosis.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolorf00-2200x-more-disability-if-have-no-uvb-than-if-have-too-much-uvbspan">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">= 2200X more disability if have no UVB than if have too much UVB&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="what-the-above-chart-should-look-like-using-the-who-data">What the above chart should look like using the WHO data&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;1642&amp;rdquo; max = &amp;ldquo;350&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Plants and UVB</title><link>/posts/plants-and-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/plants-and-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Many people say that all plants should not be out in the sun – too much UVB&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Some people disagree - and say that plants need UVB&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#in-pursuit-of-vitamin-d-in-plants---2017">In Pursuit of Vitamin D in Plants - 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#uv-a-radiation-effects-on-higher-plants-exploring-the-known-unknown---feb-2017">UV-A radiation effects on higher plants: Exploring the known unknown - Feb 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#molecular-mechanisms-involved-in-adaptive-responses-to-radiation-uv-light-and-heat--2009">Molecular mechanisms involved in adaptive responses to radiation, UV light, and heat -2009&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#acute-exposure-to-uv-b-sensitizes-cucumber-tomato-and-arabidopsis-plants-to-photooxidative-stress-by-inhibiting-thermal-energy-dissipation-and-antioxidant-defense--2011">Acute exposure to UV-B sensitizes cucumber, tomato, and Arabidopsis plants to photooxidative stress by inhibiting thermal energy dissipation and antioxidant defense.- 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-effect-of-ultraviolet-radiation-on-the-accumulation-of-medicinal-compounds-in-plants---2009">The effect of ultraviolet radiation on the accumulation of medicinal compounds in plants - 2009&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#plant-stress-and-human-health-do-human-consumers-benefit-from-uv-b-acclimated-crops-2008">Plant stress and human health: Do human consumers benefit from UV-B acclimated crops? 2008&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="in-pursuit-of-vitamin-d-in-plants---2017">In Pursuit of Vitamin D in Plants - 2017&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/in-pursuit-of-vitamin-d-in-plants.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For small amounts of sunshine the amount of skin exposed may not matter</title><link>/posts/for-small-amounts-of-sunshine-the-amount-of-skin-exposed-may-not-matter.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/for-small-amounts-of-sunshine-the-amount-of-skin-exposed-may-not-matter.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="interdependence-between-body-surface-area-and-ultraviolet-b-dose-in-vitamin-d-production-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Interdependence between body surface area and ultraviolet B dose in vitamin D production: a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Br J Dermatol. 2011 Jan;164(1):163-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.10082.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.10082.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bogh MK, Schmedes AV, Philipsen PA, Thieden E, Wulf HC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Copenhagen University Hospital, Bispebjerg Bakke 23, DK-2400 Copenhagen NV, Denmark. &lt;a href="mailto:bogh@dadlnet.dk">bogh@dadlnet.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Ultraviolet (UV) B radiation increases serum vitamin D level expressed as 25-hydroxyvitamin-D(3) &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>, but the relationship to body surface area and UVB dose needs investigation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – UV treat epilepsy</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-uv-treat-epilepsy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-uv-treat-epilepsy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="light-therapy-as-a-treatment-for-epilepsy">Light therapy as a treatment for epilepsy.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Med Hypotheses. 2011 Feb 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Baxendale SA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical and Experimental Epilepsy, Institute of Neurology UCL, Queen Square, London, UK; National Society for Epilepsy, Chalfont St. Peter, Buckinghamshire, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From a neurobiological level to epidemiological studies, there are four strands of evidence in the scientific literature that indicate that light therapy could be an effective treatment for some people with epilepsy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(1) Sunlight is important in the endogenous production and regulation of melatonin and vitamin D, both of which influence seizure thresholds. Although melatonin influences seizure thresholds, the relationship is complex. General down-regulating effects may have different effects on seizure thresholds for people with generalised and partial epilepsy syndromes. Specific actions within the hippocampus may mean that patients with temporal lobe epilepsy are particularly susceptible to the endogenous expression of melatonin via inhibitory actions on dopaminergic activity reducing seizure thresholds.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reptiles ate as well with all UV sources</title><link>/posts/reptiles-ate-as-well-with-all-uv-sources.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reptiles-ate-as-well-with-all-uv-sources.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-vitamin-d-levels-and-skeletal-and-general-development-of-young-bearded-dragon-lizards-pogona-vitticeps-under-different-conditions-of-uv-b-radiation-exposure">Serum Vitamin D Levels and Skeletal and General Development of Young Bearded Dragon Lizards (Pogona vitticeps), under Different Conditions of UV-B Radiation Exposure&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>K.R. Kroenlein, K.L. Zimmerman, G. Saunders and S.D. Holladay&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Animal and Veterinary Advances&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Year: 2011 | Volume: 10 | Issue: 2 | Page No.: 229-234&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.3923/javaa.2011.229.234&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="click-herehttpwwwmedwelljournalscomfulltextdoijavaa2011229234-for-full-research">&lt;a href="http://www.medwelljournals.com/fulltext/?doi=javaa.2011.229.234">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for full research&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Tried many different UV sources, but the bearded dragon reptiles ate as much under each UV source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cystic Fibrosis - vitamin D level in blood varies with UV</title><link>/posts/cystic-fibrosis-vitamin-d-level-in-blood-varies-with-uv.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cystic-fibrosis-vitamin-d-level-in-blood-varies-with-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sunlight-is-an-important-determinant-of-vitamin-d-serum-concentrations-in-cystic-fibrosis">Sunlight is an important determinant of vitamin D serum concentrations in cystic fibrosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jan 19. doi:10.1038/ejcn.2010.280&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robberecht E, Vandewalle S, Wehlou C, Kaufman JM, De Schepper J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CF Centre Ghent University Hospital, Ghent, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/sunlight-is-an-important-determinant-of-vitamin-d-.pdf">Download the PDF from Research Gate via VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Objectives:The increase of bone disease in adult cystic fibrosis (CF) patients is partly attributed to inadequate serum concentrations of 25-OH cholecalciferol (25 (OH) D) blamed on fat malabsorption. Based on physiological, clinical and biochemical observations this pathogenesis is debatable. The objective was to ascertain the relative importance of different 25 (OH) D sources.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Weekly UV almost doubled elderly Vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/weekly-uv-almost-doubled-elderly-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/weekly-uv-almost-doubled-elderly-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lack of UV 20X more associated with MS than any other variable</title><link>/posts/lack-of-uv-20x-more-associated-with-ms-than-any-other-variable.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-uv-20x-more-associated-with-ms-than-any-other-variable.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-quantitative-analysis-of-suspected-environmental-causes-of-ms">A Quantitative Analysis of Suspected Environmental Causes of MS.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Can J Neurol Sci 38(1):98-105 (2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scott Sloka, Claudia Silva, William Pryse-Phillips, Scott Patten, Luanne Metz and V Wee Yong&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Grand River Hospital, Kitchener, Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a disease with purported environmental causes. Consistent correlations have been found in various settings for &lt;strong>latitude, smoking exposure, sunlight, and vitamin D deficiency&lt;/strong> . We analysed the contribution of various environmental factors to the risk of developing MS from a population perspective.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perhaps more benefits from UV than just vitamin D - 2006</title><link>/posts/perhaps-more-benefits-from-uv-than-just-vitamin-d-2006.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/perhaps-more-benefits-from-uv-than-just-vitamin-d-2006.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Considering the potential benefits as well as adverse effects of sun exposure: can all the potential benefits be provided by oral vitamin D supplementation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prog Biophys Mol Biol. 2006 Sep;92(1):140-9. Epub 2006 Feb 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lucas RM, Ponsonby AL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>National Centre for Epidemiology and Population Health, The Australian National University, Canberra 0200, Australia. &lt;a href="mailto:Robyn.lucas@anu.edu.au">Robyn.lucas@anu.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exposure to ultraviolet radiation (UVR) is associated with both adverse and beneficial health effects. While many of the adverse effects of excessive exposure are well known, the adverse effects of insufficient UVR exposure are less clear-cut, but may include a heightened risk of several cancers and autoimmune disorders as well as of bone diseases such as rickets, osteomalacia and osteoporosis. Although some of the postulated beneficial effects of UVR exposure may occur through the maintenance of adequate levels of vitamin D, it is not clear that this can account for all of these effects. We briefly review the epidemiological literature with respect to vitamin D, UVR exposure and autoimmune diseases. We further outline alternative pathways, whereby UVR could alter the risk of development of some cancers and autoimmune disorders, independent of effects on vitamin D synthesis. Recognition of the beneficial effects of UVR exposure has led to a reconsideration of sun avoidance policies. It is important to recognize that all of the beneficial effects of UVR exposure may not occur only through UVR-induced vitamin D synthesis. Thus maintaining current sun avoidance policies while supplementing food with vitamin D may not be sufficient to avoid the risks of insufficient exposure to UVR. PMID: 16616326&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV overview at WHO -with infographic</title><link>/posts/uv-overview-at-who-with-infographic.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-overview-at-who-with-infographic.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.who.int/uv/uv_and_health/en/index.html">http://www.who.int/uv/uv_and_health/en/index.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;354&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="note-press-ctrl-and--concurrently-to-increase-the-size-of-any-web-page">Note: Press Ctrl and &amp;lsquo;+&amp;quot; concurrently to increase the size of any web page&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="pressing-ctrl-and-0-will-return-magnification-to-zero">Pressing Ctrl and 0 will return magnification to zero&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-at-vitamindwiki">See also at VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=10&amp;amp;deep=off&amp;amp;type=">All items in category UV&lt;/a> 157 items as of Nov 2011&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>