<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kidney on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/kidney.html</link><description>Recent content in Kidney on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/kidney/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Standard oral vitamin D is not a good way to supplement if have Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/standard-oral-vitamin-d-is-not-a-good-way-to-supplement-if-have-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/standard-oral-vitamin-d-is-not-a-good-way-to-supplement-if-have-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Depression in Chronic Kidney Disease is predicted to be 6 times more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/depression-in-chronic-kidney-disease-is-predicted-to-be-6-times-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/depression-in-chronic-kidney-disease-is-predicted-to-be-6-times-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D for kidney disease – use native or active form</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-for-kidney-disease-use-native-or-active-form.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-for-kidney-disease-use-native-or-active-form.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>2.4 times more likely to die if have Chronic Kidney Disease and low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/24-times-more-likely-to-die-if-have-chronic-kidney-disease-and-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/24-times-more-likely-to-die-if-have-chronic-kidney-disease-and-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kidney failure – still debating what form of vitamin D to use</title><link>/posts/kidney-failure-still-debating-what-form-of-vitamin-d-to-use.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-failure-still-debating-what-form-of-vitamin-d-to-use.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pro-should-we-correct-vitamin-d-deficiencyinsufficiency-in-chronic-kidney-disease-patients-with-inactive-forms-of-vitamin-d-or-just-treat-them-with-active-vitamin-d-forms">Pro: Should we correct vitamin D deficiency/insufficiency in chronic kidney disease patients with inactive forms of vitamin D or just treat them with active vitamin D forms?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation Volume 31, Issue 5Pp. 698-705.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David J.A. Goldsmith, &lt;a href="mailto:david.goldsmith@gstt.nhs.uk">david.goldsmith@gstt.nhs.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Guy&amp;rsquo;s and St Thomas’ Hospitals, London, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evidence for the usefulness of using vitamin D to treat ‘renal bone disease’ is now nearly six decades old. In regular clinical practice, however, it is more like three decades, at most, that we have routinely been using vitamin D to try to prevent, or reverse, the impact of hyperparathyroidism on the skeleton of patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD). The practice has been in the main to use high doses of synthetic vitamin D compounds, not naturally occurring ones. However, the pharmacological impacts of the different vitamin D species and of their different modes, and styles of administration cannot be assumed to be uniform across the spectrum. It is disappointingly true to say that even in 2016 there is a remarkable paucity of evidence concerning the clinical benefits of vitamin D supplementation to treat vitamin D insufficiency in patients with stage 3b–5 CKD. This is even more so if we consider the non-dialysis population. While there are a number of studies that report the impact of vitamin D supplementation on serum vitamin D concentrations (unsurprisingly, usually reporting an increase), and some variable evidence of parathyroid hormone concentration suppression, there has been much less focus on hard or semi-rigid clinical end point analysis (e.g. fractures, hospitalizations and overall mortality). Now, in 2016, with the practice pattern changes of first widespread clinical use of vitamin D and second widespread supplementation of cholecalciferol or ergocalciferol by patients (alone, or as multivitamins), it is now, in my view, next to impossible to run a placebo-controlled trial over a decent period of time, especially one which involved clinically meaningful (fractures, hospitalisation, parathyroidectomy, death) end-points. In this challenging situation, we need to ask what it is we are trying to achieve here, and how best to balance potential benefits with potential harm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney failure 1.7X more likely - Vitamin D Binding Protein</title><link>/posts/kidney-failure-17x-more-likely-vitamin-d-binding-protein.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-failure-17x-more-likely-vitamin-d-binding-protein.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biomarkers-of-vitamin-d-status-and-risk-of-esrd---feb-2016">Biomarkers of Vitamin D Status and Risk of ESRD - Feb 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#kideny-cancer-3x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-binding-protein---july-2018">Kideny Cancer 3X more likely if poor Vitamin D Binding Protein - July 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="biomarkers-of-vitamin-d-status-and-risk-of-esrd---feb-2016">Biomarkers of Vitamin D Status and Risk of ESRD - Feb 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Kidney Diseases, Volume 67, Issue 2, February 2016, Pages 235–242, doi:10.1053/j.ajkd.2015.08.026&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Casey M. Rebholz, PhD, MS, MPH1, , , Morgan E. Grams, MD, PhD, MHS1, 2, Pamela L. Lutsey, PhD, MPH3, Andrew N. Hoofnagle, MD, PhD4, Jeffrey R. Misialek, MPH3, Lesley A. Inker, MD, MS5, Andrew S. Levey, MD5, Elizabeth Selvin, PhD, MPH1, 6, Chi-yuan Hsu, MD, MSc7, Paul L. Kimmel, MD8, Ramachandran S. Vasan, MD9, 10, John H. Eckfeldt, MD, PhD11, Josef Coresh, MD, PhD, MHS1, 6, on behalf of the Chronic Kidney Disease Biomarkers&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney cancer 22 percent less likely if high vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/kidney-cancer-22-percent-less-likely-if-high-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-cancer-22-percent-less-likely-if-high-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="examining-the-association-of-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-with-kidney-cancer-risk-a-meta-analysis">Examining the association of circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D with kidney cancer risk: a meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Clin Exp Med. 2015; 8(11): 20499–20507. Published online 2015 Nov 15, PMCID: PMC4723811&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Guangzheng Lin,1,* Ling Ning,2,* Di Gu,1,* Shi Li,1 Zhe Yu,1 Qicheng Long,1 Li-Na Hou,3 and Wan-Long Tan1&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:650px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>No indication of how many years elapsed (if any) between Vitamin D test and kidney cancer diagnosis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>No indication if kidney was failing before kidney cancer, and thus not producing active vitamin D needed to fight cancer&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Psoriasis is associated with kidney disease, heart problems, diabetes, etc</title><link>/posts/psoriasis-is-associated-with-kidney-disease-heart-problems-diabetes-etc.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/psoriasis-is-associated-with-kidney-disease-heart-problems-diabetes-etc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease not treated by 1400 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-not-treated-by-1400-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-not-treated-by-1400-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-and-cholecalciferol-supplementation-in-chronic-kidney-disease-patients-an-italian-cohort-report">Vitamin D status and cholecalciferol supplementation in chronic kidney disease patients: an Italian cohort report&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>International Journal of Nephrology and Renovascular Disease November 2015 Volume 2015:8 Pages 151—157&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cupisti A, Vigo V, Baronti ME, D’Alessandro C, Ghiadoni L, Egidi MF&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nephrology, Transplant and Dialysis Division, AOUP, Department of Clinical and Experimental Medicine, University of Pisa, Pisa, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study investigated the factors associated with hypovitaminosis D, in a cohort of 405 prevalent patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) stages 2–4, living in Italy and followed-up in tertiary care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidneys, Vitamin D and Calcium</title><link>/posts/kidneys-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidneys-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-the-kidneys-a-fascinating-relationship--editorial">Vitamin D and the kidneys: a fascinating relationship – EDITORIAL&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J. Bras. Patol. Med. Lab. vol.51 no.5 Rio de Janeiro Sept./Oct. 2015, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.5935/1676-2444.20150045">http://dx.doi.org/10.5935/1676-2444.20150045&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>José Gilberto Henriques Vieira 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Escola Paulista de Medicina da Universidade Federal de São Paulo (EPM/Unifesp)&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/kidney-vitamin-d-ca.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;p>The complexity of the physiological system that controls serum calcium levels is remarkable. In the Figure we present a very simplified view of this system, stressing the crucial role of vitamin D and the kidneys in the overall complex. No wonder, the system without normal renal function turns out to be highly deranged. Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is, unfortunately, very frequent, and metabolic bone disease, the result of specific alterations in calcium and phosphorus metabolism, one of its main complications(1). The availability of kidney transplantation provided a real step forward in CKD patients&amp;rsquo; survival and quality of life. For the majority of transplant patients, a return to nearly normal renal function is the more likely result(2).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Every child with kidney problems (ideopathic nephrotic syndrome) had low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/every-child-with-kidney-problems-ideopathic-nephrotic-syndrome-had-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/every-child-with-kidney-problems-ideopathic-nephrotic-syndrome-had-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Magnesium reduced calcitriol (active vitamin D) artery calcification in CKD by 50 percent</title><link>/posts/magnesium-reduced-calcitriol-active-vitamin-d-artery-calcification-in-ckd-by-50-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/magnesium-reduced-calcitriol-active-vitamin-d-artery-calcification-in-ckd-by-50-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="magnesium-modifies-the-impact-of-calcitriol-treatment-on-vascular-calcification-in-experimental-chronic-kidney-disease">Magnesium Modifies the impact of Calcitriol Treatment on Vascular Calcification in Experimental Chronic Kidney Disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2015 Oct 20. pii: jpet.115.228106. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zelt JG1, McCabe KM1, Svajger B1, Barron H1, Laverty K1, Holden RM1, Adams MA2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Queen&amp;rsquo;s University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Queen&amp;rsquo;s University &lt;a href="mailto:adams@queensu.ca">adams@queensu.ca&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) patients are commonly treated with vitamin D analogs, such as calcitriol. Recent epidemiological evidence revealed a significant interaction between vitamin D and magnesium, since an inverse relationship between vitamin D levels and mortality mainly occurs in patients with a high magnesium intake. The aim of the study was to assess the mechanisms involved by determining whether magnesium alone or combined with calcitriol treatments differentially impact vascular calcification (VC) in male Sprague-Dawley rats with adenine-induced CKD. Treatment with moderate doses of calcitriol (80ug/kg) suppressed PTH to near or slightly below control levels. Given alone, this dose of calcitriol increased the prevalence of VC; but when magnesium was given in combination, the severity of calcification was attenuated in the abdominal aorta (51% reduction), iliac (44%) and carotid arteries (46%) compared to CKD controls. The decreases in vascular calcium content were associated with 20-50% increase in vascular Mg. Calcitriol treatment alone significantly decreased TRPM7 protein (↓ to ~11%) whereas the combination treatment increased both the mRNA (1.7X) and protein (6.8X) expression compared to calcitriol alone. In summary, calcitriol increased VC in certain conditions; but magnesium prevented the reduction in TRPM7 and reduced the severity of VC, thereby increasing the bioavailable magnesium in the vascular microenvironment. These findings suggest that modifying the adverse effect profile of calcitriol with Mg may be a plausible approach to benefiting the increasing number of CKD patients being prescribed calcitriol.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>X-ray contrast agents can injure kidney in low vitamin D rats</title><link>/posts/x-ray-contrast-agents-can-injure-kidney-in-low-vitamin-d-rats.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/x-ray-contrast-agents-can-injure-kidney-in-low-vitamin-d-rats.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-a-potential-risk-factor-for-contrast-induced-nephropathy">Vitamin D deficiency is a potential risk factor for contrast-induced nephropathy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>American Journal of Physiology - Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology Published 1 August 2015 Vol. 309 no. 3, R215-R222 DOI: 10.1152/ajpregu.00526.2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weverton M. Luchi, Maria Heloisa M. Shimizu, Daniele Canale, Pedro Henrique F. Gois, Ana Carolina de Bragança, Rildo A. Volpini, Adriana C. C. Girardi, Antonio C. Seguro&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency (VDD) is widespread in the general population. Iodinated (IC) or gadolinium-based contrast media (Gd) may decrease renal function in high-risk patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney Cancer differences with skin color probably due to vitamin D differences</title><link>/posts/kidney-cancer-differences-with-skin-color-probably-due-to-vitamin-d-differences.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-cancer-differences-with-skin-color-probably-due-to-vitamin-d-differences.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="differences-in-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-may-explain-the-black-white-differences">Differences in 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentrations May Explain the Black-White Differences&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>in Chronic Kidney Disease and Risk of Renal Cell Carcinoma&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiology • Volume XX, Number XXX, XXX 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To the Editor:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The recent article by Hofmann and colleagues1 reported increased association of chronic kidney disease with renal cell carcinoma for blacks, Asians, and Hispanics, but not whites. The black-white disparity for renal cell carcinoma incidence for blacks was attributed to hypertension and chronic kidney disease. The authors recommended additional studies to evaluate the possible factors underlying the association between chronic kidney disease and risk of renal cell carcinoma. This letter outlines the evidence that racial differences in 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations may explain the findings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, the autonomic nervous system, and cardiovascular risk - Editorial</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-the-autonomic-nervous-system-and-cardiovascular-risk-editorial.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-the-autonomic-nervous-system-and-cardiovascular-risk-editorial.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Physiological Reports &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.14814/phy2.12349">doi: 10.14814/phy2.12349&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michelle Catherine Mann, Morley D. Hollenberg, David A. Hanley &amp;amp; Sofia B. Ahmed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cumming School of Medicine, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/cns-cvd.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Cardiovascular disease (CVD) and vitamin D deficiency are extremely prevalent worldwide (Holick 2007; World Health Organization 2011). The potential link between vitamin D deficiency and CVD-related death in both healthy and diseased populations is a growing area of translational research. Historically, the traditional role of vitamin D in maintaining calcium homeostasis and mineral metabolism has been extensively studied (Lieben and Carmeliet 2013). Vitamin D, via its classical genomic transcriptional activity, is known to affect the physiological function of a number of target organs such as the heart, bone, and kidneys (Lieben et al. 2011). Furthermore, as highlighted in a paper published recently in Physiological Resports (Foong et al. 2014), there appears to be a link between vitamin D deficiency and respiratory symptoms in chronic lung disease. In addition, a number of nongenomic, rapid action roles of vitamin D are now known to affect tissue function, which fall outside the traditional role of regulating mineral metabolism (Gniadecki 1998; Brown et al. 1999; Norman et al. 2002; Haussler et al. 2011). While calcium and phosphate have long been regarded as the major players in the interactions observed between mineral metabolism dysfunction and CVD- related deaths, (Peacock 2010; Bolland et al. 2011; Brini et al. 2013), these newer nongenomic roles outside of the traditional target organs suggest that vitamin D itself may have intrinsic actions outside the realm of mineral metabolism (Gniadecki 1998; Brown et al. 1999; Norman et al. 2002; Haussler et al. 2011).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Itchy skin (pruritus) due to kidney disease was treated with topical vitamin D</title><link>/posts/itchy-skin-pruritus-due-to-kidney-disease-was-treated-with-topical-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/itchy-skin-pruritus-due-to-kidney-disease-was-treated-with-topical-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-topical-vitamin-d-on-chronic-kidney-disease-associated-pruritus-an-open-label-pilot-study">Effect of topical vitamin D on chronic kidney disease-associated pruritus: An open-label pilot study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Japanese Dermatological Association, Article first published online: 28 APR 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1111/1346-8138.12895&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kyung Eun Jung1, Yu Ri Woo1, Joong Sun Lee1, Jong Ho Shin2, Jin Uk Jeong2, Dae Won Koo1 andKi Tae Bang2,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Dermatology, School of Medicine, Eulji University Hospital, Daejeon, Korea&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Internal Medicine (Nephrology), School of Medicine, Eulji University Hospital, Daejeon, Korea&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modified release active Vitamin D (calcifediol ) for those with poor Kidney function (USD 10,000 per year)</title><link>/posts/modified-release-active-vitamin-d-calcifediol-for-those-with-poor-kidney-function-usd-10000-per-year.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/modified-release-active-vitamin-d-calcifediol-for-those-with-poor-kidney-function-usd-10000-per-year.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hemodialysis not helped by weekly vitamin D2 – RCT</title><link>/posts/hemodialysis-not-helped-by-weekly-vitamin-d2-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hemodialysis-not-helped-by-weekly-vitamin-d2-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blacks have 4X more Kidney disease than whites – probably due to low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/blacks-have-4x-more-kidney-disease-than-whites-probably-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-have-4x-more-kidney-disease-than-whites-probably-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="kidney-failure-a-leading-cause-of-death-in-african-americanshttpbaystatebannercomnews2015mar18kidney-failure-leading-cause-death-african-america-bay-state-banner">&lt;a href="http://baystatebanner.com/news/2015/mar/18/kidney-failure-leading-cause-death-african-america/">Kidney failure: A leading cause of death in African Americans&lt;/a> Bay State Banner&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>“The problem is that kidney disease is initially silent. Damage progresses slowly and quietly through five stages. Stage 5 is considered end-stage kidney failure. At that point, only two procedures — dialysis or transplantation — can keep a person alive.”&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Dark skin ==&amp;gt; Low Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Smoking ==&amp;gt; Low Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obesity ==&amp;gt; Low Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low vitamin D ==&amp;gt; Diabetes ==&amp;gt; Kidney failure&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Not as much active vitamin D if poor kidney function and low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/not-as-much-active-vitamin-d-if-poor-kidney-function-and-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/not-as-much-active-vitamin-d-if-poor-kidney-function-and-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kidney disease helped by active or high dose Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/kidney-disease-helped-by-active-or-high-dose-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-disease-helped-by-active-or-high-dose-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-beneficial-impact-of-vitamin-d-treatment-in-ckd-patients-whats-next---editorial-comment">The beneficial impact of vitamin D treatment in CKD patients: what&amp;rsquo;s next? - Editorial Comment&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Kidney J (2015) 8:38-40 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ckj/sfu135">doi: 10.1093/ckj/sfu135&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) have markedly higher rates of severe vitamin D deficiency and reduced ability to convert 25-(OH)vitamin D into the active form, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. In the setting of CKD, secondary hyperparathyroidism develops as a consequence of reduced renal production of active vitamin D and phosphate retention resulting in hypocalcaemia and hyperpho- sphataemia. This is a process that is dangerously linked with metabolic bone disease, arterial calcifications and cardiovascular mortality &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>. Therefore, the conventional rationale for vitamin D treatment in CKD is to slow the progression of secondary hyperparathyroidism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcitriol (active Vitamin D) recommended after kidney transplant</title><link>/posts/calcitriol-active-vitamin-d-recommended-after-kidney-transplant.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcitriol-active-vitamin-d-recommended-after-kidney-transplant.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="therapeutic-use-of-calcitriol">Therapeutic use of calcitriol.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Curr Vasc Pharmacol. 2014 Mar;12(2):294-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rodriguez M, Munoz-Castaneda JR, Almaden Y1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The synthesis of 1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (Calcitriol) takes place mostly in the kidneys through the action of 1α-hydroxylase (CYP27B1) which converts 25(OH)D into 1,25(OH)2D3. Renal production of calcitriol is stimulated by PTH, low calcium and low phosphate and it is reduced by high phosphate and FGF23. Binding of 1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 to its receptor (VDR) causes gut absorption of calcium and phosphate, decrease in PTH synthesis, stimulation of FGF23. At the bone level calcitriol suppresses pre-osteoblasts and activates mature osteoblasts. VDR is present in a large variety of cells that do not have any direct role in the regulation of mineral metabolism. Calcitriol regulates immune and inflammatory response, cell turnover, cell differentiation, Renin production, reduces proteinuria and others. In patients with Chronic Kidney Disease (CKD) there is a decrease in calcitriol that is apparent at early stages of renal disease; this is probably due to the elevation of FGF23 which is present since very early stage of CKD. In CKD stage, 3-4 moderate doses of calcitriol are effective to control secondary hyperparathyroidism and observational studies suggest that calcitriol therapy increases survival and slows the progression of renal disease as long as phosphate and calcium levels are controlled. Calcitriol (0.5 µg calcitriol twice per week) has been effective in decreasing proteinuria in patients with IgA nephropathy. In dialysis patients, the administration of calcitriol reduces serum PTH levels but it is also known that high doses of calcitriol are associated with hypercalcemia and worse control of hyperphosphatemia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D status unrelated to fractures with Kidney disease (should not be a surprise) – 2015</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-status-unrelated-to-fractures-with-kidney-disease-should-not-be-a-surprise-2015.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-status-unrelated-to-fractures-with-kidney-disease-should-not-be-a-surprise-2015.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Failed kidney cannot activate vitamin D, so measured vitamin D (before kidney) is not relevant&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-appears-unrelated-to-fractures-in-patients-with-chronic-kidney-disease">Vitamin D status appears unrelated to fractures in patients with chronic kidney disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>British Journal of Medicine and Medical Research 2015 Vol. 6 No. 4 pp. 439-445&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ISSN 2231-0614 DOI 10.9734/BJMMR/2015/14532&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Banerjee, A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Although lack of Vitamin D is widespread in chronic kidney disease, data is scarce in the role Vitamin D may play in fractures in such cases. Methods: Retrospective analysis of all patients visiting Nephrology outpatients department in 1 UK District General Hospital over 2 years. Chronic kidney disease was categorised by estimated glomerular filtration rate, total Vitamin D and fracture details obtained from Hospital Information Technology system. Total Vitamin D &amp;lt;50 nmol/L was considered inadequate. Logistic regression was used to assess the relationships of eGFR and total Vitamin D with fracture incidence. Spearman&amp;rsquo;s correlation coefficient (rs) was used to assess the relationship between continuous variables.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Peritoneal Dialysis nicely treated by active vitamin D</title><link>/posts/peritoneal-dialysis-nicely-treated-by-active-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/peritoneal-dialysis-nicely-treated-by-active-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="treatment-with-oral-active-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-decreased-risk-of-peritonitis-and-improved-survival-in-patients-on-peritoneal-dialysis">Treatment with Oral Active Vitamin D Is Associated with Decreased Risk of Peritonitis and Improved Survival in Patients on Peritoneal Dialysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;h3 id="chart-was-created-from-study-data">Chart was created from study data&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/kerschbaum.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>PLOS One 2013DOI: 10.1371/journal.pone.0067836&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Julia Kerschbaum, Andreas Vychytil, Karl Lhotta, Friedrich C. Prischl, Martin Wiesholzer, Veronika Machhold-Fabrizii, Gertrude Kopriva-Altfahrt, Christoph Schwarz, Peter Balcke, Rainer Oberbauer, Reinhard Kramar, Paul König, Michael Rudnicki mail&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peritonitis is a major complication of peritoneal dialysis (PD) being associated with hospitalization, catheter loss, technique failure, and increased mortality. Data on incidence rates and risk factors for peritonitis episodes vary between centers. In seven Austrian PD units clinical and laboratory data on each peritonitis episode were collected from all patients (n = 726) who performed PD between January 2000 and December 2009. The peritonitis incidence rate was 0.32 episodes/patient-year. In a multivariate analysis the risk of peritonitis was decreased by 57% in patients treated with oral active vitamin D (HR 0.43; 95% CI 0.28–0.64). Renal disease classified as “other or unknown” (HR 1.65; 95% CI 1.08–2.53) and serum albumin &amp;lt;3500 mg/dl (HR 1.49; 95% CI 1.04–2.15) were also associated with an increased risk of peritonitis. Albumin levels &amp;lt;3500 mg/dl (HR 1.89; 95% CI 1.13–3.17), age (HR 1.06 per year; 95% CI 1.03–1.09), and cardiomyopathy (HR 3.01; 95% CI 1.62–5.59) were associated with increased mortality, whereas treatment with oral active vitamin D was associated with a significantly lower risk of death (HR 0.46; 95% CI 0.27–0.81). In this retrospective multi-center study we identified several factors being related to increased risk of peritonitis in PD patients. Treatment with oral active vitamin D was identified as being independently associated with decreased risk of peritonitis, and decreased all-cause mortality in PD patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>25,0000 IU vitamin D weekly only raised 60 percent on hemodialysis above 30 ng</title><link>/posts/250000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-only-raised-60-percent-on-hemodialysis-above-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/250000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-only-raised-60-percent-on-hemodialysis-above-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="biochemical-parameters-after-cholecalciferol-repletion-in-hemodialysis-results-from-the-vitadial-randomized-trial">Biochemical parameters after cholecalciferol repletion in hemodialysis: results From the VitaDial randomized trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Kidney Dis. 2014 Nov;64(5):696-705. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1053/j.ajkd.2014.04.020.">doi: 10.1053/j.ajkd.2014.04.020.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 May 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Massart A1, Debelle FD2, Racapé J3, Gervy C4, Husson C5, Dhaene M2, Wissing KM6, Nortier JL7.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>25,000 IU weekly is not nearly enough for even a healthy person&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: Publication did not appear until 5 years after the trial had ended&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/1700-iu-of-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-help-hemodialysis-patients">1700 IU of vitamin D not enough to help hemodialysis patients – March 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetic Nephropathy – active vitamin D helps</title><link>/posts/diabetic-nephropathy-active-vitamin-d-helps.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetic-nephropathy-active-vitamin-d-helps.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="relationship-of-vitamin-d-with-diabetes-mellitus-and-diabetic-nephropathy">Relationship of Vitamin D with Diabetes Mellitus and Diabetic Nephropathy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Port J Nephrol Hypert 2014; 28(2): 108-118, Advance Access publication 16 June 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ana Paula Silva, Andre Fragoso, Pedro Leao Neves&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nephrology, Hospital de Faro - Centro Hospitalar do Algarve. Faro, Portugal&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetic nephropathy (DN) is a major public health problem whose prevalence has been increasing in recent years. It is characterized by a progressive pattern and is associated with high morbidity and mortality rates. Several factors are associated with the onset and progression of DN, such as glycaemic control, hypertension, obesity and inflammation status. In addition, vitamin D also seems to be involved through a pleiotropic regulatory activity/protection with promising applicability, either in prevention or progression of renal disease. The purpose of this review was to summarize the scientific evidence that supports the role of vitamin D in diabetes mellitus and DN.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB increases vitamin D even if poor kidney by changing CYP27B1 genes in skin</title><link>/posts/uvb-increases-vitamin-d-even-if-poor-kidney-by-changing-cyp27b1-genes-in-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-increases-vitamin-d-even-if-poor-kidney-by-changing-cyp27b1-genes-in-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-narrow-band-ultraviolet-b-course-improves-vitamin-d-balance-and-alters-cutaneous-cyp27a1-and-cyp27b1-mrna-expression-levels-in-haemodialysis-patients-supplemented-with-oral-vitamin-d">A narrow-band ultraviolet B course improves vitamin D balance and alters cutaneous CYP27A1 and CYP27B1 mRNA expression levels in haemodialysis patients supplemented with oral vitamin D.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephron Clin Pract. 2013;124(1-2):17-22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1159/000355010.">doi: 10.1159/000355010.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Sep 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ala-Houhala MJ1, Vähävihu K, Snellman E, Hasan T, Kautiainen H, Karisola P, Dombrowski Y, Schauber J, Saha H, Reunala T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Tampere University Hospital, Tampere, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND/AIMS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) patients on dialysis are prone to vitamin D insufficiency despite oral vitamin D supplementation. Here, we studied whether narrow-band ultraviolet B (NB-UVB) exposures improve vitamin D balance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease study not aware of appropriate forms of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-study-not-aware-of-appropriate-forms-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-study-not-aware-of-appropriate-forms-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-resistance-in-chronic-kidney-disease-ckd">Vitamin D resistance in chronic kidney disease (CKD).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Nephrol. 2014 Mar 19;15(1):47. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2369-15-47.">doi: 10.1186/1471-2369-15-47.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parikh A, Chase HS, Vernocchi L, Stern L1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous studies have shown that treatment with ergocalciferol in patients with CKD stage 3 + 4 is not effective with less than 33% of patients achieving a 25-OH vitamin D target of &amp;gt;30 ng/ml. The aim of this study was to test the response to cholecalciferol in CKD. We attempted to replete 25-OH vitamin D to a target level of 40-60 ng/ml using the response to treatment and PTH suppression as an outcome measure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and chronic kidney disease</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Korean J Intern Med. Jul 2014; 29(4): 416–427.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online Jun 27, 2014. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3904/kjim.2014.29.4.416">doi: 10.3904/kjim.2014.29.4.416&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC4101586&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chang Seong Kim and Soo Wan Kim&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) has been recognized as a significant global health problem because of the increased risk of total and cardiovascular morbidity and mortality. Vitamin D deficiency or insufficiency is common in patients with CKD, and serum levels of vitamin D appear to have an inverse correlation with kidney function. Growing evidence has indicated that vitamin D deficiency may contribute to deteriorating renal function, as well as increased morbidity and mortality in patients with CKD. Recent studies have suggested that treatment with active vitamin D or its analogues can ameliorate renal injury by reducing fibrosis, apoptosis, and inflammation in animal models; this treatment also decreases proteinuria and mortality in patients with CKD. These renoprotective effects of vitamin D treatment are far beyond its classical role in the maintenance of bone and mineral metabolism, in addition to its pleiotropic effects on extra-mineral metabolism. In this review, we discuss the altered metabolism of vitamin D in kidney disease, and the potential renoprotective mechanisms of vitamin D in experimental and clinical studies. In addition, issues regarding the effects of vitamin D treatment on clinical outcomes are discussed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Time-release form of active vitamin D granted a patent for chronic kidney disease</title><link>/posts/time-release-form-of-active-vitamin-d-granted-a-patent-for-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/time-release-form-of-active-vitamin-d-granted-a-patent-for-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Inflammatory diseases: review of vitamin D, with many tables</title><link>/posts/inflammatory-diseases-review-of-vitamin-d-with-many-tables.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inflammatory-diseases-review-of-vitamin-d-with-many-tables.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vitamin D insufficiency or deficiency has increased in the general population and become an important public health issue.1 Vitamin D is mainly known for its favorable effects in calcium and bone metabolism. However, increasing numbers of studies have established that vitamin D insufficiency contributes to a number of diseases, suggesting a range of physiological functions of vitamin D.M Several clinical studies have confirmed that vitamin D plays a crucial role in modulating innate immune responses toward various pathogens.5 Moreover, recent studies indicate that vitamin D can regulate the adaptive immune response in various inflammatory and autoimmune diseases.6,7 These results suggest the beneficial effects of vitamin D supplementation in decreasing the risk and adverse outcomes of inflammatory diseases, although the precise effect remains to be elucidated in large clinical trials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney Inflammation: both prevented and reduced by Vitamin D – review</title><link>/posts/kidney-inflammation-both-prevented-and-reduced-by-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-inflammation-both-prevented-and-reduced-by-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-the-immune-system-from-the-nephrologists-viewpoint">Vitamin D and the Immune System from the Nephrologist&amp;rsquo;s Viewpoint&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>ISRN Endocrinology; Volume 2014 (2014), Article ID 105456, 11 pages, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/105456">http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/105456&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cheng-Lin Lang,1 Min-Hui Wang,2 Chih-Kang Chiang,3 and Kuo-Cheng Lu2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Internal Medicine, Cardinal Tien Hospital, Yonghe Branch, New Taipei 23445, Taiwan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Cardinal Tien Hospital, School of Medicine, Fu-Jen Catholic University, 362 Chung-Cheng Road, Hsin-Tien District, New Taipei 23148, Taiwan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, National Taiwan University Hospital, College of Medicine, National Taiwan University, Taipei 10002, Taiwan&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less Pneumonia in those having more activated vitamin D (kidneys working)</title><link>/posts/less-pneumonia-in-those-having-more-activated-vitamin-d-kidneys-working.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-pneumonia-in-those-having-more-activated-vitamin-d-kidneys-working.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-community-acquired-pneumonia-low-levels-of-125oh2-d-are-associated-with-disease-severity">Vitamin D deficiency in community-acquired pneumonia: low levels of 1,25(OH)2 D are associated with disease severity&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Respiratory Research 2014, 15:53 doi:10.1186/1465-9921-15-53&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mathias W Pletz, Christoph Terkamp, Ulrike Schumacher, Gernot Rohde, Hartwig Schütte, Tobias Welte and Robert Bals&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We aimed to explore the association between vitamin D levels and the severity, mortality and microbiological etiology of community-acquired pneumonia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D levels (both, the reservoir form 25-OH and the activated form 1,25-OH2) of 300 randomly selected patients with community-acquired pneumonia due to pre-specified pathogens included in the German competence network (CAPNETZ) study were measured. Prior to statistical analysis, values of 25-OH and 1,25-OH2 were power-transformed to achieve parametric distribution. All further analyses were performed with seasonally and age adjusted values.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4X more Chronic Kidney disease patients are now using vitamin D</title><link>/posts/4x-more-chronic-kidney-disease-patients-are-now-using-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4x-more-chronic-kidney-disease-patients-are-now-using-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="kidney-disease-patient-use-of-vitamin-d-supplements-risinghttpwwwrenalandurologynewscomkidney-disease-patient-use-of-vitamin-d-supplements-risingarticle33826320-renal-and-urology-news">&lt;a href="http://www.renalandurologynews.com/kidney-disease-patient-use-of-vitamin-d-supplements-rising/article/338263/%20">Kidney Disease Patient Use of Vitamin D Supplements Rising&lt;/a> Renal and Urology News&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="clip">Clip&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>CRIC is a multicenter prospective observational cohort study that includes 3,939 participants with a mean age of 60 years and estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) of 42.1 mL/min/1.73 m2. The cohort was 54.9% male and 42.1% black, and 48.4% were diabetic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The proportion of participants reporting vitamin D supplement use increased from 10% at baseline to 44% at 7-year follow-up visits, according to Laura H. Mariani, MD, of the University of Michigan Medical School in Ann Arbor, and colleagues. Supplement use was greater among older, female, non-black, married participants with higher education and lower body mass index, the researchers noted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Immune system and vitamin D (from kidney doctor’s point of view)</title><link>/posts/immune-system-and-vitamin-d-from-kidney-doctors-point-of-view.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/immune-system-and-vitamin-d-from-kidney-doctors-point-of-view.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-the-immune-system-from-the-nephrologists-viewpoint">Vitamin D and the Immune System from the Nephrologist&amp;rsquo;s Viewpoint&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Immune system and vitamin D ( N viewpoint) – Feb 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ISRN Endocrinology, Volume 2014 (2014), Article ID 105456, 11 pages. &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/105456">http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/105456&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cheng-Lin Lang,1 Min-Hui Wang,2 Chih-Kang Chiang,3 and Kuo-Cheng Lu2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Internal Medicine, Cardinal Tien Hospital, Yonghe Branch, New Taipei 23445, Taiwan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Cardinal Tien Hospital, School of Medicine, Fu-Jen Catholic University, 362 Chung-Cheng Road, Hsin-Tien District, New Taipei 23148, Taiwan&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease patients need more vitamin D and phosphate</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-patients-need-more-vitamin-d-and-phosphate.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-patients-need-more-vitamin-d-and-phosphate.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="nutrition-prescription-to-achieve-positive-outcomes-in-chronic-kidney-disease-a-systematic-review">Nutrition prescription to achieve positive outcomes in chronic kidney disease: a systematic review.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nutrients. 2014 Jan 22;6(1):416-51. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/nu6010416.">doi: 10.3390/nu6010416.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ash S1, Campbell KL2, Bogard J3, Millichamp A4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Chronic Kidney Disease (CKD), management of diet is important in prevention of disease progression and symptom management, however evidence on nutrition prescription is limited. Recent international CKD guidelines and literature was reviewed to address the following question &amp;ldquo;What is the appropriate nutrition prescription to achieve positive outcomes in adult patients with chronic kidney disease?&amp;rdquo; Databases included in the search were Medline and CINAHL using EBSCOhost search engine, Embase and the Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews published from 2000 to 2009. International guidelines pertaining to nutrition prescription in CKD were also reviewed from 2000 to 2013. Three hundred and eleven papers and eight guidelines were reviewed by three reviewers. Evidence was graded as per the National Health and Medical Research Council of Australia criteria. The evidence from thirty six papers was tabulated under the following headings: protein, weight loss, enteral support, vitamin D, sodium, fat, fibre, oral nutrition supplements, nutrition counselling, including protein and phosphate, nutrients in peritoneal dialysis solution and intradialytic parenteral nutrition, and was compared to international guidelines. While more evidence based studies are warranted, the customary nutrition prescription remains satisfactory with the exception of Vitamin D and phosphate. In these two areas, additional research is urgently needed given the potential of adverse outcomes for the CKD patient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney not essential for Vitamin D3 activation – fungi can do it</title><link>/posts/kidney-not-essential-for-vitamin-d3-activation-fungi-can-do-it.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-not-essential-for-vitamin-d3-activation-fungi-can-do-it.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="microbial-production-of-1α-hydroxyvitamin-d3-from-vitamin-d3">Microbial production of 1α-hydroxyvitamin D3 from vitamin D3.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nat Prod Res. 2014 Jan 23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/14786419.2013.872104">doi: 10.1080/14786419.2013.872104&lt;/a> Publisher charges $46 for the PDF&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ahmed SA, Mesbah MK, Youssef DT, Khalifa SI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pharmacognosy , Faculty of Pharmacy, Suez Canal University , Ismailia , Egypt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The microbial transformation of vitamin D3 (1) by the fungi Candida maltosa R42 and Botrytis allii NRRL 2502 was investigated. Incubation of compound 1 with C. maltosa R42 and B. allii NRRL 2502 produced the same three more polar metabolites in small yields. The main metabolite was identified as 1α-hydroxyvitamin D3 (2). This biotransformation has utility as a possible tool for the production of 1α-hydroxyvitamin D3 from the readily available vitamin D3 for patients with compromised kidney function.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Most Chronic Kidney Disease patients restored their vitamin D levels with just 1,000 IU</title><link>/posts/most-chronic-kidney-disease-patients-restored-their-vitamin-d-levels-with-just-1000-iu.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/most-chronic-kidney-disease-patients-restored-their-vitamin-d-levels-with-just-1000-iu.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-effects-of-supplementation-with-cholecalciferol-in-patients-with-chronic-kidney-disease">Prevalence of Vitamin D Deficiency and Effects of Supplementation With Cholecalciferol in Patients With Chronic Kidney Disease&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Renal Nutrition&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sun Moon Kim, MD, PhD∗,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hyung Jin Choi, MD, PhD∗,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jung Pyo Lee, MD, PhD†, ‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dong Ki Kim, MD, PhD†,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yun Kyu Oh, MD, PhD†, ‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yon Su Kim, MD, PhD†,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chun Soo Lim, MD, PhD†, ‡, Corresponding author contact information, E-mail the corresponding author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∗ Department of Internal Medicine, Chungbuk National University Hospital, Cheongju, Republic of Korea&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Protective cardiovascular and renal actions of vitamin D and sex hormones</title><link>/posts/protective-cardiovascular-and-renal-actions-of-vitamin-d-and-sex-hormones.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/protective-cardiovascular-and-renal-actions-of-vitamin-d-and-sex-hormones.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#span-stylecolor00fthe-following-sections-are-clipped-from-the-pdf-is-attached-at-the-bottom-of-this-pagespan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">The following sections are clipped from the PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#4-sex-hormones-and-cardiovascular-disease">4. SEX HORMONES AND CARDIOVASCULAR DISEASE&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#5-sex-hormones-and-renal-disease">5. SEX HORMONES AND RENAL DISEASE&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#51-sex-hormones-and-the-glomerular-capillary-pressure">5.1. Sex hormones and the glomerular capillary pressure&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#52-estradiol-and-testosterone-effects-on-oxidative-stress">5.2. Estradiol and testosterone effects on oxidative stress&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#53-estradiol-and-the-endothelial-system">5.3. Estradiol and the endothelial system&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#6-sex-hormones-and-diabetes">6. SEX HORMONES AND DIABETES&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#7-replacement-strategies-and-outcomes">7. REPLACEMENT STRATEGIES AND OUTCOMES&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#71-vitamin-d-replacement-and-renal-disease">7.1. Vitamin D replacement and renal disease&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#72-estrogens-and-progestins">7.2. Estrogens and progestins&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#73-androgens-testosterone-and-dehydroepiandrosterone-dhea">7.3. Androgens: testosterone and dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#74-oxytocin">7.4. Oxytocin&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#8-perspective">8. PERSPECTIVE&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Protective cardiovascular and renal actions of vitamin D and estrogen.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease clinical trials of UV in Germany</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-clinical-trials-of-uv-in-germany.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-clinical-trials-of-uv-in-germany.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-and-uv-exposure-in-chronic-kidney-disease">Vitamin D and UV exposure in chronic kidney disease&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Rolfdieter Krause&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dermato-Endocrinology Vol 5 #1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With loss of renal function and decreasing glomerula filtration rate the serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> as well as 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[1,25 (OH)2 D]&lt;/span> often decrease simultaneously. In representative groups of German patients on renal replacement therapy (hemodialysis, peritoneal dialysis, kidney transplantation) our group retrospectively analyzed the vitamin D status over a period of 12 y (1995‒2006).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inflammation and Vitamin D in Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/inflammation-and-vitamin-d-in-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inflammation-and-vitamin-d-in-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="infection-inflammation-and-vitamin-d">Infection Inflammation and Vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Clin Microbial 2013, 2:4 &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.4172/2327-5073.1000116">http://dx.doi.org/10.4172/2327-5073.1000116&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yildirim I, Magden K and Hur E &lt;a href="mailto:hurender@hotmail.com">hurender@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bulent Ecevit University Medical School, Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Zonguldak, Turkey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>See also &lt;a href="/posts/kidney-inflammation-not-reduced-by-30-ng-vitamin-d-many-health-problems-need-50-ng" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Kidney Inflammation not reduced by 30 ng Vitamin D (many health problems need 50 ng) – Nov 2022">Kidney Inflammation not reduced by 30 ng Vitamin D (many health problems need 50 ng) – Nov 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney disease not helped much by vitamin D provided you ignore dose size – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-not-helped-much-by-vitamin-d-provided-you-ignore-dose-size-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-not-helped-much-by-vitamin-d-provided-you-ignore-dose-size-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-and-mortality-risk-in-chronic-kidney-disease-a-meta-analysis-of-20-observational-studies">Vitamin D supplementation and mortality risk in chronic kidney disease: a meta-analysis of 20 observational studies&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>BMC Nephrology 2013, 14:199&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhenfeng Zheng, Huilan Shi, Junya Jia, Dong Li and Shan Lin&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney patients need some form vitamin D – the question is, which form</title><link>/posts/kidney-patients-need-some-form-vitamin-d-the-question-is-which-form.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-patients-need-some-form-vitamin-d-the-question-is-which-form.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="which-vitamin-d-in-ckd-mbd-the-time-of-burning-questions">Which Vitamin D in CKD-MBD? The Time of Burning Questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>BioMed Research International, Volume 2013 (2013), Article ID 864012, 10 pages&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Antonio Bellasi,2,3 Sara Auricchio,1 Sergio Papagni,4 and Mario Cozzolino31Medical Department, Nephrology Unit, AO Desio Vimercate, Desio Hospital, 20832 Desio, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Nephrology, Sant’Anna Hospital, 22020 Como, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Health Sciences, University of Milan, 20142 Milan, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Division of Nephrology, Dialysis Center CBH-Città di Bisceglie, 70052 Bisceglie, Italy&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dialysis patients need real vitamin D – Editorial</title><link>/posts/dialysis-patients-need-real-vitamin-d-editorial.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dialysis-patients-need-real-vitamin-d-editorial.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-many-forms-and-functions-of-essential-vitamin-d-for-dialysis-patients">The Many Forms and Functions of Essential Vitamin D for Dialysis Patients&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Renal Nutrition, Volume 23, Issue 4 , Pages e87-e88, July 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Caroline Hamatake, MPH, RD &lt;a href="mailto:caroline.hamatake@fmc-na.com">caroline.hamatake@fmc-na.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liberty Dialysis–Hawaii, Honolulu, Hawaii&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feature Editor: Catherine M. Goeddeke-Merickel, MS, RD, LD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction/Overview&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The screening and treatment of vitamin D deficiency is now routinely done in most dialysis clinics. Many dialysis patients have suboptimal levels of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and require vitamin D supplementation even in clinics located in the tropics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Those Dialysis patients with low vitamin D were 75% more likely to die</title><link>/posts/those-dialysis-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-were-75-percent-more-likely-to-die.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/those-dialysis-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-were-75-percent-more-likely-to-die.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-mortality-in-patients-receiving-dialysis-the-comprehensive-dialysis-study">Vitamin D Deficiency and Mortality in Patients Receiving Dialysis: The Comprehensive Dialysis Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Renal Nutrition, Available online 19 July 2013, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1053/j.jrn.2013.05.003">http://dx.doi.org/10.1053/j.jrn.2013.05.003&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shuchi Anand, MD∗, Corresponding author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glenn M. Chertow, MD, MPH∗,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kirsten L. Johansen, MD†, ‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara Grimes, PhD§,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lorien S. Dalrymple, MD, MPH¶,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>George A. Kaysen, MD, PhD¶, ∗∗,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manjula Kurella Tamura, MD, MPH∗, ††&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∗ Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Palo Alto, California&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Postmenopausal vitamin D benefits to blood pressure and kidney – Review</title><link>/posts/postmenopausal-vitamin-d-benefits-to-blood-pressure-and-kidney-review.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/postmenopausal-vitamin-d-benefits-to-blood-pressure-and-kidney-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-blood-pressure-endothelial-and-renal-function-in-postmenopausal-women">The Role of Vitamin D in Blood Pressure, Endothelial and Renal Function in Postmenopausal Women&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(7), 2590-2610; doi:10.3390/nu5072590&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhao-Min Liu 1 &lt;a href="mailto:liuzhaomin@cuhk.edu.hk">liuzhaomin@cuhk.edu.hk&lt;/a> Jean Woo 1, Sheng-Hui Wu 2 and Suzanne C. Ho 3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Medicine &amp;amp; Therapeutics, the Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, 999077, China&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Division of Epidemiology, Department of Medicine, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville, TN 37203-1738, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Division of Epidemiology, The Jockey Club School of Public Health and Primary Care, the Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, 999077, China&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and bicarbonate perhaps synergistically reduce muscle loss</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-bicarbonate-perhaps-synergistically-reduce-muscle-loss.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-bicarbonate-perhaps-synergistically-reduce-muscle-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="could-vitamin-d-and-bicarbonate-supplementation-synergize-to-mitigate-age-related-loss-of-muscle">Could vitamin D and bicarbonate supplementation synergize to mitigate age-related loss of muscle?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocrine, DOI 10.1007/s12020-013-0011-2; EDITORIAL&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D. Travis Thomas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span>[This is an editorial on a rat experiment]&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In patients with kidney disease receiving hemodialysis, metabolic acidosis is closely tied to muscle pathology and is known to exacerbate age-related loss of muscle mass and function. To a lesser extent, the &amp;ldquo;Western&amp;rdquo; diet is thought to contribute to mild (sub-clinical) metabolic acidosis via the supply of acid precursors from foods &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>, but the clinical significance to chronic age-related muscle degeneration has received little attention. This may partly be due to equivocal data on the benefits of neutralizing diet-induced metabolic acidosis for improving muscle-related outcomes in patients without kidney disease &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>. Despite limited data, acidosis has been shown to stimulate muscle proteolysis and is associated with negative functional outcomes including reduced peak torque and lower gait speed &lt;sup>[3]&lt;/sup>. This is important to note because aged adults are less able to excrete excess H? ions and are more prone to develop mild, but slowly increasing metabolic acidosis that may be exacerbated by a &amp;ldquo;Western&amp;rdquo; diet &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. Furthermore, approximately one out of four adults older than 50 years of age have low serum bicarbonate levels to neutralize an acidogenic diet. Because of these factors, recommendations for future work include examining the effects of alkali therapy on functional outcomes, nitrogen balance, strength and other relevant measures of physical function, in aged healthy adults &lt;sup>[3]&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic kidney with low vitamin D: 90 percent of pediatric nephrologists now recommend more D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-with-low-vitamin-d-90-percent-of-pediatric-nephrologists-now-recommend-more-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-with-low-vitamin-d-90-percent-of-pediatric-nephrologists-now-recommend-more-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="nutritional-vitamin-d-use-in-chronic-kidney-disease-a-survey-of-pediatric-nephrologists">Nutritional vitamin D use in chronic kidney disease: a survey of pediatric nephrologists.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Pediatr Nephrol. 2013 Feb;28(2):265-75. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00467-012-2307-5.">doi: 10.1007/s00467-012-2307-5.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Oct 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Griffin LM, Denburg MR, Shults J, Furth SL, Salusky IB, Hwang W, Leonard MB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Philadelphia, 3535 Market Street, Room 868, Philadelphia, PA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D deficiency may contribute to risk of cardiovascular disease, diabetes, and infections, in addition to known effects on mineral metabolism. Controversy remains regarding the use of nutritional vitamin D supplementation in chronic kidney disease (CKD), and the supplementation practices of pediatric nephrologists are unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Comparing Vitamin D and analogs for kidney patients</title><link>/posts/comparing-vitamin-d-and-analogs-for-kidney-patients.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/comparing-vitamin-d-and-analogs-for-kidney-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-metabolites-andor-analogs-which-d-for-which-patient">Vitamin D Metabolites and/or Analogs: Which D for Which Patient?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Curr Vasc Pharmacol. 2013 May 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mazzaferro S, Goldsmith D, Larsson TE, Massy ZA, Cozzolino M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dept. of Cardiovascular, Respiratory, Nephrologic and Geriatric Sciences, Sapienza University of Rome, Viale del Policlinico 155 00161. Rome ITALY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Numerous drugs with vitamin D activity are available for clinical use and it may not be easy for the non-specialist to select the most suitable for the individual patient. In this paper we review the main characteristics of the available drugs and provide evidence about any potential specific clinical indications, with special emphasis on renal patients, in order to facilitate the optimal choice. Natural vitamin D products (i.e. those identical to natural metabolites) are first examined, followed by the most frequently used synthetic molecules (i.e. bioengineered molecules not-existing in nature), which are generally indicated as &amp;ldquo;analogs&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D tester falsely said half of hemodialysis patients had less than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-tester-falsely-said-half-of-hemodialysis-patients-had-less-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-tester-falsely-said-half-of-hemodialysis-patients-had-less-than-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="accuracy-of-three-automated-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-assays-in-hemodialysis-patients">Accuracy of three automated 25-hydroxyvitamin D assays in hemodialysis patients.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clin Chim Acta. 2013 Jan 16;415:255-60. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cca.2012.10.056.">doi: 10.1016/j.cca.2012.10.056.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Nov 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Depreter B, Heijboer AC, Langlois MR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Laboratory Medicine, AZ Sint-Jan Bruges-Ostend AV, 8000 Bruges, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: We evaluated the accuracy of three automated assays for 25(OH)D measurement in comparison to ID-XLC-MS/MS in hemodialysis patients, considering the importance of their vitamin D status and reported discrepant results obtained with automated assays.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Standard and artificial vitamin D both help Chronic Kidney Disease – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/standard-and-artificial-vitamin-d-both-help-chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/standard-and-artificial-vitamin-d-both-help-chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="impact-of-vitamin-d-on-chronic-kidney-diseases-in-non-dialysis-patients">Impact of Vitamin D on Chronic Kidney Diseases in Non-Dialysis Patients:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(4): e61387. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0061387&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lijuan Xu, Xuesi Wan, Zhimin Huang, Fangfang Zeng, Guohong Wei, Donghong Fang, Wanping Deng, Yanbing Li mail&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and Objectives: Recent studies have supported a role for both newer and more established vitamin D compounds in improving proteinuria, although systematic evaluation is lacking. Furthermore, concerns remain regarding the influence of vitamin D on the progression of renal function. We analyzed the efficacy and safety of vitamin D in non-dialysis patients and compared the use of newer versus established vitamin D compounds by performing a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CYP27B1 gene decreases kidney production of active vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cyp27b1-gene-decreases-kidney-production-of-active-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp27b1-gene-decreases-kidney-production-of-active-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="thyroid-hormones-decrease-plasma-1α25-dihydroxyvitamin-d-levels-through-transcriptional-repression-of-the-renal-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-1α-hydroxylase-gene-cyp27b1">Thyroid hormones decrease plasma 1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D levels through transcriptional repression of the renal 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 1α-hydroxylase gene (CYP27B1).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocrinology. 2013 Feb;154(2):609-22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1210/en.2012-1647.">doi: 10.1210/en.2012-1647.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kozai M, Yamamoto H, Ishiguro M, Harada N, Masuda M, Kagawa T, Takei Y, Otani A, Nakahashi O, Ikeda S, Taketani Y, Takeyama K, Kato S, Takeda E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Nutrition, Institute of Health Biosciences, University of Tokushima Graduate School, 3-18-15 Kuramoto-cho, Tokushima City, 770-8503, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary determinant of circulating 1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>(2)D) levels is the activity of 25-hydroxyvitamin D-1α-hydroxylase (cytochrome P450 27B1 &lt;span>[CYP27B1]&lt;/span>) in the kidney.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1700 IU of vitamin D not enough to help hemodialysis patients</title><link>/posts/1700-iu-of-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-help-hemodialysis-patients.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1700-iu-of-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-help-hemodialysis-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="effects-of-cholecalciferol-on-functional-biochemical-vascular-and-quality-of-life-outcomes-in-hemodialysis-patients">Effects of Cholecalciferol on Functional, Biochemical, Vascular, and Quality of Life Outcomes in Hemodialysis Patients.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2013 Mar 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hewitt NA, O&amp;rsquo;Connor AA, O&amp;rsquo;Shaughnessy DV, Elder GJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Postgraduate Medical School, University of Notre Dame, Sydney, Australia;, †Renal Resource Centre, Sydney Dialysis Centre, Royal North Shore Hospital, Sydney, Australia;, ‡Department of Renal Medicine, Westmead Hospital, Sydney, Australia, §Osteoporosis and Bone Biology Division, Garvan Institute of Medical Research, Sydney, Australia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D level can be high, but little benefit: due to kidney, genes, low Magnesium etc.</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduced risk of death of Chronic Kidney Disease by 30 percent: Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-risk-of-death-of-chronic-kidney-disease-by-30-percent-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-risk-of-death-of-chronic-kidney-disease-by-30-percent-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-treatment-and-mortality-in-chronic-kidney-disease">Vitamin D Treatment and Mortality in Chronic Kidney Disease:&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Nephrol. 2013 Mar 5;37(3):239-248.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Duranton F, Rodriguez-Ortiz ME, Duny Y, Rodriguez M, Daurès JP, Argilés A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RD-Néphrologie, Institut Universitaire de Recherche Clinique, Montpellier, France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aims: Hypovitaminosis D has been associated with an increased cardiovascular mortality in the general population and in patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD). Still, whether prescribing vitamin D reduces the risk of mortality in renal patients remains controversial.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death from acute kidney injury 84 percent more likely if have low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/death-from-acute-kidney-injury-84-percent-more-likely-if-have-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-from-acute-kidney-injury-84-percent-more-likely-if-have-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dysregulated-mineral-metabolism-in-patients-with-acute-kidney-injury-and-risk-of-adverse-outcomes">Dysregulated Mineral Metabolism in Patients with Acute Kidney Injury and Risk of Adverse Outcomes.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2013 Feb 18. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/cen.12172.">doi: 10.1111/cen.12172.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leaf DE, Waikar SS, Wolf M, Cremers S, Bhan I, Stern L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology, Columbia University Medical Center, New York, NY; Division of Renal Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Numerous studies have evaluated the prevalence and importance of vitamin D deficiency among patients with chronic kidney disease and end-stage renal disease, however, little is known about vitamin D levels in acute kidney injury (AKI). We evaluated the association between vitamin D metabolites and clinical outcomes among patients with AKI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney disease requires magnesium</title><link>/posts/kidney-disease-requires-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-disease-requires-magnesium.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="highlights-from-natural-newshttpwwwnaturalnewscom038713_kidney_disease_magnesium_nutritionhtml-dr-carol-dean-ms-magnesium">Highlights from &lt;a href="http://www.naturalnews.com/038713_kidney_disease_magnesium_nutrition.html">Natural News&lt;/a> Dr. Carol Dean (Ms Magnesium)&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>magnesium is required by about 1300 enzymes systems in the body,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Magnesium also has about 4,000 receptor sites on body proteins.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>One doctor said he couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand why there was 5X more cardiovascular hospitalization and cardiovascular events in people with lowered kidney filtration rates but normal blood chemistry..Low Magnesium!!&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Use ionized magnesium testing so you know what&amp;rsquo;s really going on with magnesium levels in the body.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Kidney Disease - 2009</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-kidney-disease-2009.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-kidney-disease-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-diseasehttpwwwncbinlmnihgovpubmed20077598-2009">&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20077598">Vitamin D and chronic kidney disease&lt;/a> 2009&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ethn Dis. 2009 Autumn;19(4 Suppl 5):S5-8-11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Williams S, Malatesta K, Norris K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charles Drew University of Medicine and Science, Los Angeles, California 90059, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is an emerging public health problem and one of the most powerful predictors of premature cardiovascular disease. Emerging evidence suggests that the progression of CKD and many of the cardiovascular complications may be linked to hypovitaminosis D. Patients with CKD have an exceptionally high rate of severe vitamin D deficiency that is further exacerbated by the reduced ability to convert 25-(OH)vitamin D into the active form, 1,25 dihydroxy-vitamin D. As new evidence has improved our understanding of classical, as well as the nonclassical, functions for vitamin D, it has become apparent that the autocrine role of vitamin D is an important modulator of several systems including the immune, renal and cardiovascular systems. In addition to the traditional supplementation of 1,25-vitamin D to CKD patients, by assessing and repleting 25-(OH)vitamin D deficiency, physicians will adequately fuel both the renal and extra-renal pathways of calcitriol synthesis maintaining the classical, as well as the non-classical, functions of vitamin D that ultimately influence clinical outcomes in this high-risk group of patients. Because of the high rates of hypovitaminosis D and progression of CKD to end-stage renal disease in minority populations, these findings are highly relevant to the national efforts to reduce health disparities. Healthcare providers are called to join the intensified efforts of public health officials to disseminate and implement updated guidelines and recommendations to halt the growing epidemic of vitamin D deficiency, particularly in high-risk populations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU vitamin D3 was not enough for children with chronic kidney disease</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d3-was-not-enough-for-children-with-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d3-was-not-enough-for-children-with-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-and-treatment-with-oral-vitamin-d3-in-children-with-chronic-kidney-disease">Vitamin D insufficiency and treatment with oral vitamin D3 in children with chronic kidney disease.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Saudi Med J. 2012 Jul;33(7):740-4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kari JA, Eldesoky SM, Bagdadi OT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, King Abdulaziz University Hospital, PO Box 80215, Jeddah 21589, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. &lt;a href="mailto:jkari@doctors.org.uk">jkari@doctors.org.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the effects of oral cholecalciferol on the levels of vitamin D3 and intact parathyroid hormone (iPTH) in children with chronic kidney disease (CKD).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: We conducted a prospective uncontrolled observational study at the Pediatric Nephrology Clinic of King Abdulaziz University Hospital, Jeddah, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia between January and October 2011 to assess serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) and iPTH in children with CKD stages 2-5. Children with low vitamin D3 levels were commenced on cholecalciferol, 2000 IU/day. Their 25(OH)D3 and iPTH levels were reassessed, first after 3 months, and then after 6 months. Data analysis was performed using the Statistical Package for Social Sciences. Paired t-test was used to compare results before and after treatment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease and Vitamin D Analogs – commentary</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d-analogs-commentary.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d-analogs-commentary.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="shining-light-on-vitamin-d-trials-in-chronic-kidney-disease">Shining light on vitamin D trials in chronic kidney disease&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Kidney International (2013) 83, 198–200; doi:10.1038/ki.2012.415&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sagar U Nigwekar1,2 and Ravi I Thadhani1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Nephrology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Scholars in Clinical Science Program, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Ravi I. Thadhani, Bulfinch 127, Massachusetts General Hospital, 55 Fruit Street, Boston, Massachusetts 02114, USA. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:rthadhani@partners.org">rthadhani@partners.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D compounds may have extraskeletal functions. Chronic kidney disease (CKD) offers an opportunity to investigate these actions, as vitamin D deficiency is prevalent in this population and actions of vitamin D such as those on the heart and glucose metabolism are highly relevant. However, recent randomized controlled trials have tempered enthusiasm. We appraise a trial by de Boer et al. that addresses effects of paricalcitol on glucose metabolism in CKD, and offer perspectives on future trials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For those with kidney disease, diabetes is strongly associated with low vitamin D – 2012</title><link>/posts/for-those-with-kidney-disease-diabetes-is-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-2012.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/for-those-with-kidney-disease-diabetes-is-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="risk-factors-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-chronic-kidney-disease">Risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in patients with chronic kidney disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Intern Med. 2012;51(8):845-50. Epub 2012 Apr 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Echida Y, Mochizuki T, Uchida K, Tsuchiya K, Nitta K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Kidney Center, Tokyo Women&amp;rsquo;s Medical University, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: We conducted a cohort study to identify the risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in predialyzed patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: An observational study of 135 outpatients with stage 3-5 CKD was undertaken. Clinical and biochemical parameters were analyzed in terms of nutritional status, inflammation, and mineral metabolism in relation to serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>. Levels of 25(OH)D lower than 15 ng/mL were considered to be deficient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mutations in CYP24A1 gene (vitamin D) associated with kidney problems</title><link>/posts/mutations-in-cyp24a1-gene-vitamin-d-associated-with-kidney-problems.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mutations-in-cyp24a1-gene-vitamin-d-associated-with-kidney-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="125-oh2d-24-hydroxylase-cyp24a1-deficiency-as-a-cause-of-nephrolithiasis">1,25-(OH)2D-24 Hydroxylase (CYP24A1) Deficiency as a Cause of Nephrolithiasis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2013 Jan 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nesterova G, Malicdan MC, Yasuda K, Sakaki T, Vilboux T, Ciccone C, Horst R, Huang Y, Golas G, Introne W, Huizing M, Adams D, Boerkoel CF, Collins MT, Gahl WA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical Genetics Branch, National Human Genome Research Institute, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland;,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>†Department of Biotechnology, Faculty of Engineering, Toyama Prefectural University, Toyama, Japan;,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney disease and low vitamin D in disadvantaged populations</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-low-vitamin-d-in-disadvantaged-populations.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-low-vitamin-d-in-disadvantaged-populations.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-neighborhood-poverty-and-progression-of-chronic-kidney-disease-in-disadvantaged-populations">Hypovitaminosis D, neighborhood poverty, and progression of chronic kidney disease in disadvantaged populations.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Nephrol. 2010 Nov;74 Suppl 1:S95-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mehrotra R, Norris K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology and Hypertension, Los Angeles Biomedical Research Center at Harbor-UCLA, Torrance, CA, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:rmehrotra@labiomed.org">rmehrotra@labiomed.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the United States, there are significant racial disparities in the incidence and prevalence of end-stage renal disease. The disparities are greatest for the Blacks and the magnitude of disparity is significantly greater than is evident from the incidence and prevalence data of end-stage renal disease - early stage chronic kidney disease is less common in Blacks and during that stage, mortality rate is significantly higher for that racial group. Recent studies have identified a genetic predisposition for non-diabetic renal disease among Blacks. However, genetic factors explain only part of the higher risk and the racial disparities are a result of a complex interplay of biology and sociology. Herein we focus on two factors and their role in explaining the higher risk for progression of chronic kidney disease among Blacks - one biologic (vitamin D deficiency) and one sociologic (neighborhood poverty). A greater Understanding of these factors is important in order to reduce the racial disparities in the United States.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney transplant patients advised to avoid the sun, then 90% have very low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/kidney-transplant-patients-advised-to-avoid-the-sun-then-90-percent-have-very-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-transplant-patients-advised-to-avoid-the-sun-then-90-percent-have-very-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="preserved-circannual-rhythm-of-vitamin-d-in-kidney-transplant-patients">Preserved circannual rhythm of vitamin D in kidney transplant patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Swiss Med Wkly. 2012 Sep 4;142:w13672. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4414/smw.2012.13672.">doi: 10.4414/smw.2012.13672.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burkhalter F, Schaub S, Dickenmann M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinic for Transplantation Immunology and Nephrology, University Hospital Basel, Switzerland. &lt;a href="mailto:fburkhalter@uhbs.ch">fburkhalter@uhbs.ch&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: A high prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency has been found in the general population, in patients with chronic kidney disease and in kidney transplant patients. During winter there is a higher prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency due to the lack of solar ultraviolet B (UVB) exposure. Kidney transplant patients are advised to avoid sun exposure because of their high risk of skin cancer. This is considered to be one of the main reasons for the very high prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency in these patients. Whether circannual rhythm of vitamin D is totally reversed in kidney transplant patients is not known.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rosuvastatin given for renal problem resulted in increased vitamin D levels – RCT</title><link>/posts/rosuvastatin-given-for-renal-problem-resulted-in-increased-vitamin-d-levels-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rosuvastatin-given-for-renal-problem-resulted-in-increased-vitamin-d-levels-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-insufficiency-is-associated-with-impaired-renal-endothelial-function-and-both-are-improved-with-rosuvastatin-treatment">25-Hydroxyvitamin D insufficiency is associated with impaired renal endothelial function and both are improved with rosuvastatin treatment.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clin Res Cardiol. 2012 Dec 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ott C, Raff U, Schneider MP, Titze SI, Schmieder RE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nephrology and Hypertension, University of Erlangen-Nuremberg, Ulmenweg 18, 91054, Erlangen, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is nowadays considered as a potential cardiovascular and renal risk factor. We tested the hypotheses that vitamin D deficiency impairs the endothelial function of renal vasculature and whether vitamin D levels and endothelial function can be improved by the treatment with statins.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>50 percent of Chronic Kidney Disease treatments in Germany include vitamin D</title><link>/posts/50-percent-of-chronic-kidney-disease-treatments-in-germany-include-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/50-percent-of-chronic-kidney-disease-treatments-in-germany-include-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="implementation-and-first-results-of-a-german-chronic-kidney-disease-registry">Implementation and first results of a German Chronic Kidney Disease Registry.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Nephrol. 2012 Dec 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kleophas W, Bieber B, Robinson BM, Duttlinger J, Fliser D, Lonnemann G, Rump LC, Pisoni RL, Port FK, Reichel H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Advanced chronic kidney disease (CKD) is gaining increasing medical and economical importance, but little information exists about treatment variation and the impact of routine clinical treatments on survival, quality of life, and cost. We demonstrate the first results of a national electronic registry of nephrology clinic data that will serve as a resource for the prospective observation of CKD patients in Germany. A large network of German nephrologist practices is currently joining the project. Routinely obtained clinical data for non-dialysis dependent CKD patients are documented in health records electronically, and elements from these data are extracted using QuaNT (Qualitätssicherung Nephrologie und Transplantation) to create a centralized database. Here, we report cross-sectional data from 59 participating nephrology clinics and 6,187 patients with CKD Stage 3 - 5 in 2011. Mean age ± standard deviation (SD) was 72 ± 12 years. The distribution of CKD 3, 4, and 5 (non-dialysis) was 60%, 33%, and 8%, respectively. The major renal diseases were hypertension/vascular nephropathy (47%) and diabetic nephropathy (26%).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active vitamin D treats Chronic Kidney Disease by stimulating Klotho production</title><link>/posts/active-vitamin-d-treats-chronic-kidney-disease-by-stimulating-klotho-production.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-vitamin-d-treats-chronic-kidney-disease-by-stimulating-klotho-production.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-secreted-klotho-a-long-awaited-panacea-for-vascular-calcification">Vitamin D and secreted Klotho: a long-awaited panacea for vascular calcification?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Kidney International (2012) 82, 1248–1250; doi:10.1038/ki.2012.338&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hirotaka Komaba1 and Masafumi Fukagawa1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Nephrology, Endocrinology and Metabolism, Tokai University School of Medicine, Isehara, Japan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Masafumi Fukagawa, Division of Nephrology, Endocrinology and Metabolism, Tokai University School of Medicine, 143 Shimo-Kasuya, Isehara 259-1193, Japan. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:fukagawa@tokai-u.jp">fukagawa@tokai-u.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is characterized by accelerated vascular calcification, which may in part be caused by deficiency of the anti-aging factor Klotho. Lau et al. demonstrate that administration of active vitamin D and its analog decreases aortic calcification in association with increases in two potent calcification inhibitors—the secreted form of Klotho and vascular osteopontin. These data might provide a new perspective on the association of active vitamin D with improved survival in patients with CKD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poor kidneys result in lower vitamin D level result in 7X more tooth loss</title><link>/posts/poor-kidneys-result-in-lower-vitamin-d-level-result-in-7x-more-tooth-loss.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poor-kidneys-result-in-lower-vitamin-d-level-result-in-7x-more-tooth-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="association-between-low-renal-function-and-tooth-loss-over-5-years">Association between low renal function and tooth loss over 5 years.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Gerodontology. 2012 Nov 26. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/ger.12015.">doi: 10.1111/ger.12015.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yoshihara A, Iwasaki M, Miyazaki H, Nakamura K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Oral Health and Welfare, Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences, Niigata University, Niigata, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This longitudinal study evaluated the relationship between low renal function and tooth loss in elderly subjects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MATERIAL AND METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Subjects comprised 406 female subjects (55-74 years old) who agreed to participate in a baseline examination and a follow-up examination after 5 years. Serum cystatin C levels were used to assess renal function. Multiple logistic regression analysis was used to evaluate the relationship between tooth loss and change in serum cystatin C levels over 5 years. Tooth loss over 5 years (0: no, 1: yes) was used as the dependent variable. Seven variables were used as independent variables, including change in serum cystatin C levels over 5 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When lupus affects the kidneys vitamin D levels drop even further</title><link>/posts/when-lupus-affects-the-kidneys-vitamin-d-levels-drop-even-further.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/when-lupus-affects-the-kidneys-vitamin-d-levels-drop-even-further.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-predictive-factors-of-low-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-systemic-lupus-erythematosus">The predictive factors of low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and vitamin D deficiency in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Rheumatol Int. 2012 Nov 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sumethkul K, Boonyaratavej S, Kitumnuaypong T, Angthararuk S, Cheewasat P, Manadee N, Sumethkul V.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatology Unit, Department of Medicine, Rajavithi Hospital, 2 Rajavithi Road, Bangkok, 10400, Thailand, &lt;a href="mailto:ckittiwan@hotmail.com">ckittiwan@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a steroid hormone with pleiotropic effects. The association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level &lt;span>[25(OH) D]&lt;/span> and lupus nephritis are not clearly known. We aim to determine serum 25(OH) D levels in patients with inactive SLE, active SLE without lupus nephritis (LN) and active SLE with LN and to identify clinical predictor of vitamin D deficiency. One hundred and eight SLE patients were included. Patients were classified as Group (Gr) 1, 2 and 3 if they had SLE disease activity index (SLEDAI) &amp;lt;3, ≥3 but no LN and ≥3 with LN. Important baseline characteristics were collected. 25(OH) D was measured by high performance liquid chromatography (HPLC). SLEDAI in Gr1, Gr2 and Gr3 was 0.7 (0.9), 5.6 (2.3) and 9.2 (5.2), respectively. 43.5 % had vitamin D insufficiency and 29.6 % had vitamin D deficiency. Mean 25(OH) D in each groups was 28.3 (8.0), 26.7 (9.5) and 19.9 (7.6) ng/ml (p &amp;lt; 0.001 comparing Gr1 and 3) (p = 0.003 comparing Gr2 and 3). Vitamin D deficiency was found in 11.1, 22.2 and 55.6 % of Gr1, 2 and 3. Linear regression analysis found that 25(OH) D was significantly correlated with serum albumin (r = 0.28, p = 0.004), inversely correlated with SLEDAI (r = -0.22, p = 0.03) and urinary protein creatinine index (UPCI) (r = -0.28, p = 0.005), but not with sun exposure score, body mass index and estimated GFR. Only UPCI was significantly inversely correlated with 25(OH) D (p = 0.02) from multiple linear regression. LN was a significant predictor of vitamin D deficiency from multivariate logistic regression (OR &lt;strong>5.97&lt;/strong> ; p = 0.006). Vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency was found in 93 and 86 % of LN with proteinuria ≥ and &amp;lt;500 mg/day. We conclude that SLE patients with LN have significantly lower vitamin D level than inactive SLE and active SLE without LN. Hence, nephritis is a significant predictor of vitamin D deficiency in SLE patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CYP24A1 gene, kidney disease, and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cyp24a1-and-kidney-disease">CYP24A1 and kidney disease&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens. 2011 May 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Petkovich M, Jones G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>aDivision of Cancer Biology and Genetics, Cancer Research Institute, Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, Canada bDepartment of Research and Development, Cytochroma Inc., Markham, Canada cDepartments of Biochemistry and Medicine, Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE OF REVIEW:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patients with chronic renal disease have elevated serum phosphate levels, elevated fibroblast-like growth factor 23 (FGF-23), and declining vitamin D status. These changes are related and may be responsible for elevated 25-hydroxyvitamin D-24-hydroxylase (CYP24A1) and dysfunctional vitamin D metabolism. This review focuses on the biochemistry and pathophysiology of CYP24A1 and the utility of blocking this enzyme with CYP24A1 inhibitors in chronic kidney disease (CKD) patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 far better than D2 for hemodialysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-far-better-than-d2-for-hemodialysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-far-better-than-d2-for-hemodialysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d2-versus-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-hemodialysis-patients">Vitamin D2 versus vitamin D3 supplementation in hemodialysis patients:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>a comparative pilot study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daroux M, Shenouda M, Bacri JL, Lemaitre V, Vanhille P, Bataille P&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nephrology, Doctor Duchenne Hospital, Boulogne-sur-Mer - France; and Department of Nephrology, Regional University Hospital of Lille, Lille - France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Nephrology &lt;span>[2012:0]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: In patients with chronic kidney disease, vitamin D insufficiency is highly prevalent. It can be corrected by supplementation with either vitamin D2 or vitamin D3. Recent studies in patients without impaired kidney function suggest that vitamin D3 is more efficient than vitamin D2 in correcting vitamin D insufficiency. However, no direct comparison has been made in hemodialysis (HD) patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney – only 1 in 3 doctors said kids need more than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-only-1-in-3-doctors-said-kids-need-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-only-1-in-3-doctors-said-kids-need-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kidney Dialysis clinics reluctant to add vitamin D treatment as they are not reimbursed</title><link>/posts/kidney-dialysis-clinics-reluctant-to-add-vitamin-d-treatment-as-they-are-not-reimbursed.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-dialysis-clinics-reluctant-to-add-vitamin-d-treatment-as-they-are-not-reimbursed.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>And, treating with vitamin D would decrease their number of patients thus and their income&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-cost-effective-complement-to-managing-the-vitamin-d-deficient-and-anemic-dialysis-patient-in-the-bundledworld">A cost effective complement to managing the vitamin D deficient and anemic dialysis patient in the bundled world.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsoweb">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="a-cost-effective-complement-to-managing-the-vitamin-d-deficient-and-anemic-dialysis-patient-in-the-bundledworld">A cost effective complement to managing the vitamin D deficient and anemic dialysis patient in the bundled world.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephrol News Issues. 2012 Jul;26(8):22-4, 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Larkin J, Bea L, Sharma A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pacific Renal Research Institute, Caldwell, Idaho, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4X fewer malignancies after kidney transplant if got active vitamin D – Prospective Score</title><link>/posts/4x-fewer-malignancies-after-kidney-transplant-if-got-active-vitamin-d-prospective-score.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4x-fewer-malignancies-after-kidney-transplant-if-got-active-vitamin-d-prospective-score.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="orally-active-vitamin-d-for-potential-chemoprevention-of-post-transplant-malignancy">Orally Active Vitamin D for Potential Chemoprevention of Post-transplant Malignancy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Yoshitsugu Obi1, Naotsugu Ichimaru2, Takayuki Hamano3,*, Kodo Tomida4, Isao Matsui1, Naohiko Fujii5, Masayoshi Okumi6, Jun-ya Kaimori7, Koji Yazawa6, Yukito Kokado8, Yoshiharu Tsubakihara9, Norio Nonomura10, Hiromi Rakugi11, Shiro Takahara12, and Yoshitaka Isaka11&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Geriatric Medicine &amp;amp; Nephrology, Osaka University Graduate School of Medicine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Urology, Osaka Central Hospital&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Comprehensive Kidney Disease Research, Osaka University Graduate School of Medicine&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omega 3 increases vitamin D in the blood – many studies</title><link>/posts/omega-3-increases-vitamin-d-in-the-blood-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-increases-vitamin-d-in-the-blood-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Many articles on this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omega-3 increases levels of active vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active vitamin D is the form which the body actually used&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active vitamin D is not measured by standard vitamin D tests&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omega-3 is thus especially useful to get vitamin D to the body if the kidney is not functioning properly&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-effects-of-omega-3-fatty-acid-on-vitamin-d-activation-in-hemodialysis-patients-a-pilot-study--2015">The Effects of Omega-3 Fatty Acid on Vitamin D Activation in Hemodialysis Patients: A Pilot Study- 2015&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/active-d-and-omega-3.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Mar. Drugs 2015, 13(2), 741-755; doi:10.3390/md13020741&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>With CKD should measure the active form of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/with-ckd-should-measure-the-active-form-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/with-ckd-should-measure-the-active-form-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="incident-isolated-125oh2d3-deficiency-is-more-common-than-25ohd-deficiency-in-ckd">Incident isolated 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) deficiency is more common than 25(OH)D deficiency in CKD.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Nephrol. 2012 Mar-Apr;25(2):204-10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5301/JN.2011.8429.">doi: 10.5301/JN.2011.8429.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Levin A, Le Barbier M, Er L, Andress D, Sigrist MK, Djurdjev O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BC Provincial Renal Agency, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada. &lt;a href="mailto:alevin@providencehealth.bc.ca">alevin@providencehealth.bc.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiencies are well described in general populations and in those with chronic kidney disease (CKD). Although serum 25(OH)D may be a good indicator of vitamin D status in healthy individuals, the hydroxylated product, 1,25(OH)(2)D, essential for important biological functions such as mineral metabolism, bone turnover, regulation of protein synthesis, cell differentiation and proliferation may be a more suitable indicator for individuals with CKD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>7100 IU (50000 weekly) restored vitamin D levels for those with Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/7100-iu-50000-weekly-restored-vitamin-d-levels-for-those-with-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7100-iu-50000-weekly-restored-vitamin-d-levels-for-those-with-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cholecalciferol-supplementation-in-chronic-kidney-disease-restoration-of-vitamin-d-status-and-impact-on-parathyroid-hormone">Cholecalciferol Supplementation in Chronic Kidney Disease: Restoration of Vitamin D Status and Impact on Parathyroid Hormone&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Nutr Metab 2012;61:74-82 (DOI: 10.1159/000339618)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Miriam G. Garcia-Lopesa, Roberta Pillarb, Maria Ayako Kamimuraa, b, Lillian A. Rochab, Maria Eugênia F. Canzianib, Aluízio B. Carvalhob, Lilian Cupparia, b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Nutrition Program and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Division of Nephrology, Federal University of São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aims: Hypovitaminosis D is highly prevalent among patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) and has been associated with poor outcome. We aimed to test the effect of a protocol of cholecalciferol supplementation on the restoration of vitamin D status and on parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels in patients with CKD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease reduced with 3600 IU vitamin D (50000 twice a month)– RCT</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-reduced-with-3600-iu-vitamin-d-50000-twice-a-month-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-reduced-with-3600-iu-vitamin-d-50000-twice-a-month-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chronic kidney disease associated with higher levels of vitamin K1</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-associated-with-higher-levels-of-vitamin-k1.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-associated-with-higher-levels-of-vitamin-k1.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="phylloquinone-and-vitamin-d-status-associations-with-incident-chronic-kidney-disease-in-the-framingham-offspring-cohort">Phylloquinone and vitamin d status: associations with incident chronic kidney disease in the framingham offspring cohort.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Nephrol. 2012;36(1):68-77. Epub 2012 Jun 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O&amp;rsquo;Seaghdha CM, Hwang SJ, Holden R, Booth SL, Fox CS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute&amp;rsquo;s Framingham Heart Study and the Center for Population Studies, Framingham, Mass., USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Cardiovascular risk factors are associated with the development of chronic kidney disease (CKD), and CKD and vascular disease are etiologically linked. Evidence suggests deficiencies of vitamins D and K may adversely affect the cardiovascular system, but data from longitudinal studies are lacking. We hypothesized that deficiencies of vitamins D and K may be associated with incident CKD and/or incident albuminuria amongst members of the general population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5700 IU of vitamin D helped half with chronic kidney disease if not having dialysis</title><link>/posts/5700-iu-of-vitamin-d-helped-half-with-chronic-kidney-disease-if-not-having-dialysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5700-iu-of-vitamin-d-helped-half-with-chronic-kidney-disease-if-not-having-dialysis.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>