<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kidney on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/kidney.html</link><description>Recent content in Kidney on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/kidney/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Death rate increased 3X for chronic kidney disease if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/death-rate-increased-3x-for-chronic-kidney-disease-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-rate-increased-3x-for-chronic-kidney-disease-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 becomes Calcidiol which becomes Calcitriol</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-becomes-calcidiol-which-becomes-calcitriol.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-becomes-calcidiol-which-becomes-calcitriol.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolorf00cholecalciferol-spanko-ler-cal-si-ferol--vitamin-d3--from-diet-or-your-skin-from-cholesterol-and-uv">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Cholecalciferol &lt;/span>(ko-ler-cal-&amp;lsquo;si ferol) = vitamin D3, from diet or your skin (from cholesterol and UV)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/getting-vitamin-d-into-your-blood-and-cells" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Getting Vitamin D into your blood and cells">{img fileId=&amp;ldquo;2696&amp;rdquo; width =&amp;ldquo;700&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>        &lt;strong>click on chart to see it larger, along with description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="liver-uses-enzymes-to-add-water--span-stylecolorf00calcidiol-span-kal-sĭ-dīol">Liver uses enzymes to add water ==&amp;gt; &lt;span style="color:#F00;">Calcidiol &lt;/span> (kal-sĭ-dī′ol)&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>25-hydroxy-vitamin-D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>25(OH)D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>what a blood test measures&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>stored all around the body, including in the blood&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>appears to last for weeks (&amp;gt; about 50 ng) to months (&amp;lt; about 30 ng)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D receptor activation and Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-activation-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-activation-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Some form of vitamin D may be the lowest cost treatment for CKD – Spanish</title><link>/posts/some-form-of-vitamin-d-may-be-the-lowest-cost-treatment-for-ckd-spanish.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-form-of-vitamin-d-may-be-the-lowest-cost-treatment-for-ckd-spanish.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="economic-impact-of-vitamin-d-treatment-on-chronic-kidney-disease-patients--sept-2011">Economic impact of vitamin D treatment on chronic kidney disease patients – Sept 2011&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nefrologia. 2011 Sep 20;31(5):528-536. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3265/Nefrologia.pre2011.Aug.11012.">doi: 10.3265/Nefrologia.pre2011.Aug.11012.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[Article in Spanish]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ramos R, Alcázar R, Otero A, de Francisco AL, Del Pino MD.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d3-becomes-calcidiol-which-becomes-calcitriol">Vitamin D3 becomes Calcidiol which becomes Calcitriol&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/application-to-fda-for-use-of-active-vitamin-d-for-hemodialysis-patients">Application to FDA for use of active Vitamin D for hemodialysis patients – July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/active-form-of-vitamin-d-appears-to-help-prevent-and-treat-some-cancers" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 923">Active form of vitamin D appears to help prevent and treat some cancers – Feb 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blacks have low vitamin D and have 50 percent more kidney failure</title><link>/posts/blacks-have-low-vitamin-d-and-have-50-percent-more-kidney-failure.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-have-low-vitamin-d-and-have-50-percent-more-kidney-failure.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-racial-disparity-in-albuminuria-nhanes-20012006">Vitamin D and Racial Disparity in Albuminuria: NHANES 2001–2006&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>American Journal of Hypertension 2011; 24 10, 1114–1120. doi:10.1038/ajh.2011.108&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kevin A. Fiscella1,2, Paul C. Winters1 and Gbenga Ogedegbe3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Family Medicine, University of Rochester School of Medicine, Rochester, New York, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Community &amp;amp; Preventive Medicine, University of Rochester School of Medicine, Rochester, New York, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Medicine, Division of General Internal Medicine, Center for Healthful Behavior Change, New York University School of Medicine, New York, New York, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-vitamin-d-axis-in-chronic-kidney-disease--state-of-the-art-and-future-perspectives">The Vitamin D Axis in Chronic Kidney Disease – State of the Art and Future Perspectives&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Marco Ruggiero, Stefania Pacini&lt;/p>
&lt;p>European Nephrology, 2011;5(1):15-19&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the components of the vitamin D axis participate in the pathogenesis of chronic kidney disease (CKD) and this knowledge can be exploited to devise targeted therapeutic strategies. The vitamin D axis includes vitamin D, vitamin D receptor and vitamin D-binding protein (VDBP), which is the precursor of a potent macrophage activating factor, group-specific component (Gc)-protein-derived macrophage activating factor (GcMAF), a protein that is being extensively studied after it was demonstrated that it eradicates advanced cancer and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. Thanks to its effects on the immune system and angiogenesis, it also appears to be a promising candidate for targeted therapy of CKD. In this article we shall summarise the state of the art on vitamin D and CKD, and then we shall focus on the perspectives opened by increasing knowledge of other components of the axis, in particular VDBP and GcMAF.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney aging-inevitable or preventable</title><link>/posts/kidney-aging-inevitable-or-preventable.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-aging-inevitable-or-preventable.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nat Rev Nephrol. 2011 Aug 9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneph.2011.104.">doi: 10.1038/nrneph.2011.104.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choudhury D, Levi M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dallas VA Medical Center, The University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX 75216, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aging process affects all organs, including the kidneys. As part of this process, progressive scarring and a measurable decline in renal function occur in most people over time. The improved understanding of the processes that can lead to and/or hasten scarring and loss of renal function over time parallels advances in our understanding of the aging process. Clinical factors, including hypertension, diabetes mellitus, obesity, abnormal lipid levels and vitamin D deficiency, have been associated with increasing renal sclerosis with age. In addition, tissue factors such as angiotensin II, advanced glycation end products, oxidative stress and Klotho are associated with renal aging. These associations and possible interventions, including the control of blood pressure, blood sugar, weight, diet and calorie restriction might make renal aging more preventable than inevitable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2.8X more likely to die of hemodialysis if low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/28x-more-likely-to-die-of-hemodialysis-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/28x-more-likely-to-die-of-hemodialysis-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-mortality-and-hospitalization-in-hemodialysis-patients-with-or-without-protein-energy-wasting--2011">Vitamin D Deficiency, Mortality, and Hospitalization in Hemodialysis Patients with or without Protein-Energy Wasting.- 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-and-mortality-of-german-hemodialysis-patients--2012">Vitamin D status and mortality of German hemodialysis patients.- 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-mortality-and-hospitalization-in-hemodialysis-patients-with-or-without-protein-energy-wasting--2011">Vitamin D Deficiency, Mortality, and Hospitalization in Hemodialysis Patients with or without Protein-Energy Wasting.- 2011&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephron Clin Pract. 2011 Aug 11;119(3):c220-c226.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fiedler R, Dorligjav O, Seibert E, Ulrich C, Markau S, Girndt M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine II, Martin Luther University Halle-Wittenberg, Halle/Saale, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:Vitamin D deficiency and protein-energy wasting (PEW) are highly prevalent in hemodialysis (HD) patients. The goal of our study was to investigate if a lack of vitamin D influences mortality and hospitalization of HD patients with or without PEW. Methods: In 81 chronic HD patients with different nutritional status assessed by the Malnutrition Inflammation Score (MIS), vitamin D deficiency (25-OH-vitamin D(3) levels ?30 nmol/l or &lt;strong>?12 ng/ml&lt;/strong> ) was prospectively investigated for its prognostic impact on mortality and hospitalization. Over a 3-year follow-up, all-cause mortality and hospitalization were determined. The predictive value of low vitamin D levels and PEW as well as their combined effect were evaluated using a multivariate Cox regression model.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>33 percent more likely to die of chronic kidney disease if less than 15 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/33-percent-more-likely-to-die-of-chronic-kidney-disease-if-less-than-15-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/33-percent-more-likely-to-die-of-chronic-kidney-disease-if-less-than-15-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>People with kidney disease moved faster after adding vitamin D</title><link>/posts/people-with-kidney-disease-moved-faster-after-adding-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-kidney-disease-moved-faster-after-adding-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-muscle-strength-functional-ability-and-balance-in-peritoneal-dialysis-patients-with-vitamin-d-deficiency">Vitamin D and muscle strength, functional ability and balance in peritoneal dialysis patients with vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Nephrol. 2011 Aug;76(2):110-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Taskapan H, Baysal O, Karahan D, Durmus B, Altay Z, Ulutas O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nephrology Department, and Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation Department, Turgut Ozal Medical Center of Inonu University, Medical Faculty, Malatya, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>25(OH)D deficiency has been associated with significantly worse physical performance in individuals with normal renal function. We examined the physical function, muscle strength and balance in age- and gender-matched 25 Stage 3 - 4 CKD patients and 47 Stage 5 CKD patients on peritoneal dialysis (PD) with vitamin D deficiency by objective methods and evaluated the effect of vitamin D replacement on physical performance tests: the &amp;ldquo;timed up and go&amp;rdquo; (TUG) test, gait velocity test, timed chair stand test, stair climb test, dynamic balance tests (TUG test, dynamic postural stability test), static balance test (functional reach test) and muscle strength in these two groups.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Application to FDA for use of active Vitamin D for hemodialysis patients</title><link>/posts/application-to-fda-for-use-of-active-vitamin-d-for-hemodialysis-patients.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/application-to-fda-for-use-of-active-vitamin-d-for-hemodialysis-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="rockwell-medical-announces-acquisition-of-generic-drug-vitamin-d-to-treat-secondary-hyperparathyroidism-in-esrd-patients">Rockwell Medical Announces Acquisition of Generic Drug Vitamin-D to Treat Secondary Hyperparathyroidism in ESRD Patients&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="injectable-calcitriol-will-address-estimated-350m-us-dialysis-market-press-release">Injectable Calcitriol Will Address Estimated $350M U.S. Dialysis Market; press release&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>WIXOM, Mich., Jul 26, 2011 (GlobeNewswire via COMTEX) &amp;ndash; Rockwell Medical , a fully-integrated biopharmaceutical company offering innovative products and services targeting end-stage renal disease (ESRD), chronic kidney disease (CKD), and iron deficiency anemia, announced today that it has acquired an &lt;strong>Abbreviated New Drug Application&lt;/strong> (ANDA) for injectable, active Vitamin-D (Calcitriol) for End Stage Renal Disease (ESRD) patients undergoing hemodialysis. Terms were not disclosed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hydroxylated vitamin D goes away faster than standard D in Kidney patents</title><link>/posts/hydroxylated-vitamin-d-goes-away-faster-than-standard-d-in-kidney-patents.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hydroxylated-vitamin-d-goes-away-faster-than-standard-d-in-kidney-patents.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="incident-isolated-125oh2d3-deficiency-is-more-common-than-25ohd-deficiency-in-ckd">Incident isolated 1,25(OH)2D3 deficiency is more common than 25(OH)D deficiency in CKD.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Nephrol. 2011 Jun 16. pii: 5403F0E0-161B-4C4F-96F9-2A4FAF4EB467. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5301/JN.2011.8429.">doi: 10.5301/JN.2011.8429.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Levin A, Le Barbier M, Er L, Andress D, Sigrist MK, Djurdjev O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BC Provincial Renal Agency, Vancouver, British Columbia - Canada and Division of Nephrology, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, British Columbia - Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Vitamin D deficiencies are well described in general populations and in those with chronic kidney disease (CKD). Although serum 25(OH)D may be a good indicator of vitamin D status in healthy individuals, &lt;strong>the hydroxylated product, 1,25(OH)2D,&lt;/strong> essential for important biological functions such as mineral metabolism, bone turnover, regulation of protein synthesis, cell differentiation and proliferation may be a more suitable indicator for individuals with CKD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cyclosporine etc. probably increase the need for vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cyclosporine-etc-probably-increase-the-need-for-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyclosporine-etc-probably-increase-the-need-for-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="effects-of-cyclosporine-tacrolimus-and-rapamycin-on-renal-calcium-transport-and-vitamin-d-metabolism">Effects of Cyclosporine, Tacrolimus and Rapamycin on Renal Calcium Transport and Vitamin D Metabolism.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Nephrol. 2011 Jun 20;34(1):87-94.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee CT, Ng HY, Lien YH, Lai LW, Wu MS, Lin CR, Chen HC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, Chang-Gung Memorial Hospital, Kaohsiung Medical Center, Chang-Gung University College of Medicine, Gueishan, Taiwan, ROC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Abnormalities in mineral metabolism are common complications of organ transplantation. The role of immunosuppressive agents in alteration of mineral metabolism is not clear.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Each 10 ng increase in vitamin D decreased kidney disease death by 14 percent</title><link>/posts/each-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-disease-death-by-14-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/each-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-disease-death-by-14-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-and-mortality-risk-in-ckd-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Vitamin D Status and Mortality Risk in CKD: A Meta-analysis of Prospective Studies.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Kidney Dis. 2011 May 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pilz S, Iodice S, Zittermann A, Grant WB, Gandini S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria; Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics and EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency, assessed as low 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) level, is highly prevalent in patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) and is associated with various adverse health outcomes. Whether low 25(OH)D levels in patients with CKD are an independent risk factor for mortality remains to be studied in detail, and this was the objective of our work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kids with new kidneys were both short and low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/kids-with-new-kidneys-were-both-short-and-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kids-with-new-kidneys-were-both-short-and-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-short-stature-and-may-influence-blood-pressure-control-in-paediatric-renal-transplant-recipients">Vitamin D deficiency is associated with short stature and may influence blood pressure control in paediatric renal transplant recipients.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pediatr Nephrol. 2011 Jun 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shroff R, Knott C, Gullett A, Wells D, Marks SD, Rees L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renal Unit, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children NHS Trust and Institute of Child Health London, London, WC1N 3JH, UK, &lt;a href="mailto:ShrofR@gosh.nhs.uk">ShrofR@gosh.nhs.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is common in adult renal transplant recipients, but data in children are scarce. Vitamin D is shown to have multiple effects on the cardiovascular system, renal function, and maintenance of bone health. We hypothesized that 25(OH)D deficiency is common in pediatric renal transplant recipients, and may be associated with hyperparathyroidism, short stature, renal function, and blood pressure control.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dialysis patients with higher levels of vitamin D were better</title><link>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-were-better.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-were-better.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-is-inversely-associated-with-serum-mmp-9-in-a-cross-sectional-study-of-african-american-esrd-patients">25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration is Inversely Associated with Serum MMP-9 in a cross-sectional study of African American ESRD Patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Nephrol. 2011 May 22;12(1):24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wasse H, Cardarelli F, De Staercke C, Hooper C, Veledar E, Guessous I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentration is inversely associated with peripheral arterial disease and hypertension. Vascular remodeling may play a role in this association, however, data relating vitamin D level to specific remodeling biomarkers among ESRD patients is sparse. We tested whether 25(OH)D concentration is associated with markers of vascular remodeling and inflammation in African American ESRD patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic kidney disease and PTH – Calcium – Phosphate – Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-pth-calcium-phosphate-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-pth-calcium-phosphate-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mineral-metabolism-and-vitamin-d-in-chronic-kidney-disease-more-questions-than-answers">Mineral metabolism and vitamin D in chronic kidney disease-more questions than answers.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Nephrol. 2011 May 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goldsmith DJ, Cunningham J; Medscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renal and Transplantation Department, 6th Floor, Borough Wing, Guy&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Great Maze Pond, London SE1 9RT, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) are at increased risk of total and cardiovascular morbidity and mortality. The underlying pathophysiology of this association remains largely unexplained and there is currently no clear interventional pathway. Emphasis has been placed on measuring serum levels of calcium, phosphate and parathyroid hormone (PTH) to monitor disease progression, driven by the assumption that achieving values within the &amp;rsquo;normal&amp;rsquo; range will translate into improved outcomes. Retrospective studies have provided a body of evidence that abnormal levels of mineral biomarkers, and phosphate in particular, are associated with clinical events. Disturbances in vitamin D metabolism are also likely to contribute to the pathophysiology of CKD. Designing studies that yield useful information has proved to be difficult, partly owing to conceptual and financial limitations, but also because of the tight interdependency of calcium, phosphate and PTH, and the potential impact of vitamin D on these mineral metabolites.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dialysis patients with less than 15 ng of vitamin D did not feel well</title><link>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d-did-not-feel-well.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d-did-not-feel-well.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Heart problems 5X worse for chronic kidney patients low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/heart-problems-5x-worse-for-chronic-kidney-patients-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-problems-5x-worse-for-chronic-kidney-patients-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wearable dialysis device being tested which also converts vitamin D</title><link>/posts/wearable-dialysis-device-being-tested-which-also-converts-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wearable-dialysis-device-being-tested-which-also-converts-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="being-developed-march-2011">Being Developed March 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="perhaps-1000--large-scale-trials-2011-2014-worn-like-a-belt">Perhaps $1000, large scale trials 2011-2014, worn like a belt&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="click-herehttptimesofindiaindiatimescomcitydelhidialysis-device-that-can-be-carried-aroundarticleshow7622329cms">&lt;a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/Dialysis-device-that-can-be-carried-around/articleshow/7622329.cms">CLICK HERE&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-of-vitamin-d-and-kidney" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 813">Overview of Vitamin D and Kidney&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Dialysis patients with low vitamin D were 2.7 X more likely to die of heart problems</title><link>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-were-27-x-more-likely-to-die-of-heart-problems.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-were-27-x-more-likely-to-die-of-heart-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-clinical-outcomes-in-incident-dialysis-patients-results-from-the-necosad-study">Vitamin D status and clinical outcomes in incident dialysis patients: results from the NECOSAD study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation, Volume26, Issue3, Pp. 1024-1032.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background. The majority of dialysis patients suffer from vitamin D deficiency, which might contribute to an adverse health outcome. We aimed to elucidate whether European dialysis patients with low 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels are at increased risk of mortality and specific fatal events.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods. This was a prospective cohort study of incident dialysis patients in the Netherlands (the NECOSAD). We selected all patients with measured 25(OH)D at 12 months after the start of dialysis, the baseline for our study. By Cox regression analyses, we assessed the impact of 25(OH)D levels on short-term (6 months of follow-up) as well as longer-term mortality (3 years of follow-up). Associations of 25(OH)D levels with cardiovascular and non-cardiovascular mortality were also determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney failure and vitamin D deficiency vicious cycle</title><link>/posts/kidney-failure-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-vicious-cycle.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-failure-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-vicious-cycle.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="defective-renal-maintenance-of-the-vitamin-d-endocrine-system-impairs-vitamin-d-renoprotection-a-downward-spiral-in-kidney-disease">Defective renal maintenance of the vitamin D endocrine system impairs vitamin D renoprotection: a downward spiral in kidney disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Kidney Int. 2011 Jan 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dusso AS, &lt;a href="mailto:adusso@im.wustl.edu">adusso@im.wustl.edu&lt;/a>; Tokumoto M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1] Renal Division, Department of Internal Medicine, Washington University School of Medicine, St Louis, Missouri, USA &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup> Experimental Nephrology Laboratory, IRB Lleida, Lleida, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In kidney disease, the progressive loss of renal capacity to produce calcitriol, the vitamin D hormone, is a key contributor to elevations in parathyroid hormone (PTH) and mineral and skeletal disorders predisposing to renal and cardiovascular damage, ectopic calcifications, and high mortality rates. Thus, the safe correction of calcitriol deficiency to suppress PTH has been the treatment of choice for decades. However, recent epidemiological and experimental data suggest that calcitriol replacement may improve outcomes through renal and cardioprotective actions unrelated to PTH suppression. Furthermore, a striking incidence of vitamin D deficiency occurs in kidney disease and associates more strongly than calcitriol deficiency with a higher risk for kidney disease progression and death. Despite the translational relevance of these findings, no prospective trials are currently available in support of the efficacy of vitamin D supplementation and/or calcitriol replacement to safely halt/moderate renal disease progression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease meta-analysis of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-chronic-kidney-disease-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-observational-studies-and-randomized-controlled-trials">Vitamin D Supplementation in Chronic Kidney Disease: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Observational Studies and Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>CJASN January 2011 vol. 6 no. 1 50-62 , published by American Society of Nephrology&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Praveen Kandula,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Mirela Dobre,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Jesse D. Schold,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Martin J. Schreiber ,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rajnish Mehrotra,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sankar D. Navaneethan&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Author Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> *Department of Nephrology, Indiana University, Indianapolis, Indiana;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Department of Internal Medicine, Huron Hospital, Cleveland, Ohio;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Department of Nephrology, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Department of Nephrology and Hypertension, Glickman Urological and Kidney Institute, and
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Quantitative Health Sciences, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Los Angeles Biomedical Research Institute at Harbor–University of California–Los Angeles Medical Center, Torrance, California; and
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> David Geffen School of Medicine at University of California–Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Correspondence:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney and Vitamin D – Heaney</title><link>/posts/kidney-and-vitamin-d-heaney.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-and-vitamin-d-heaney.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-the-iceberg-nutrient">Vitamin D: The Iceberg Nutrient.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Ren Nutr. 2011 Jan 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Armas LA, Heaney RP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creighton University Osteoporosis Research Center, Omaha, Nebraska.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The understanding of vitamin D&amp;rsquo;s role in human health has recently expanded. It is now recognized as more than a hormone activated in the kidney only for calcium homeostasis. It is metabolized and used by virtually every cell in the body. Patients with chronic kidney disease have a deficit in their kidney production of 1,25(OH)(2)D and have classically been treated with calcitriol or its active analogues. Despite often having lower systemic levels of 1,25(OH)(2)D, patients with chronic kidney disease retain the capability of extra renal production of 1,25(OH)(2)D. This has far reaching implications for their health. This review examines clinical trials and observations in 3 areas that impact chronic kidney disease patients. Cancer, cardiovascular disease and infections are responsible for much of the morbidity and mortality in this patient population. We will discuss vitamin D&amp;rsquo;s role in these disease states with a focus on the chronic kidney disease patient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney disease and vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-biology-from-the-discovery-to-its-significance-in-chronic-kidney-disease">Vitamin d biology: from the discovery to its significance in chronic kidney disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Ren Nutr. 2011 Jan;21(1):113-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cuppari L, Garcia Lopes MG, Kamimura MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology, Federal University of São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D was discovered and had its chemical structure described in the early years of the last century. Although classified as a nutrient because it was found in small quantities in butter, it soon became clear that exposure of skin to sunlight, supplies most of the vitamin D necessary for good health in human beings. Vitamin D (D3 or cholecalciferol) synthesis in the skin is extremely rapid and remarkably robust despite the complexity of the mechanisms involved. However, a number of factors related to latitude location, season, and skin characteristics can interfere with the photoproduction of vitamin D. The 2 forms of vitamin D (D3 or D2-ergocalciferol) are biologically inactive and require activation in the liver and kidney. The product of the first hydroxylation of vitamin D in the liver, 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D), is the marker of vitamin D status. Hypovitaminosis D (serum 25(OH)D, &amp;lt;30 ng/mL) is highly prevalent in the general population, and patients with chronic kidney disease seem to be at higher risk for the development of hypovitaminosis D. It is believed that, besides the traditional factors, protein losses, gastrointestinal malabsorption, and &lt;strong>defective skin synthesis&lt;/strong> of vitamin D might contribute to the elevated number of patients with suboptimal level of vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D helps organ transplant - many studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-organ-transplant-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-organ-transplant-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary-of-many-studies-of-vitamin-d-and-organ-transplantation">Summary of many studies of Vitamin D and organ transplantation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-in-organ-transplantation---2011">Vitamin D in organ transplantation - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#survive-heart-transplant-better-if-have-more-vitamin-d">Survive heart transplant better if have more vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#immune-system-is-often-supressed-so-that-a-new-organ-can-be-accepted-by-the-body">Immune system is often supressed so that a new organ can be accepted by the body&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="summary-of-many-studies-of-vitamin-d-and-organ-transplantation">Summary of many studies of Vitamin D and organ transplantation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>More vitamin D needed especially needed if organ = liver or kidney (low vitamin d ==&amp;gt; poor bones)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Even with vitamin D supplementation Kidney transplant patients were deficient</title><link>/posts/even-with-vitamin-d-supplementation-kidney-transplant-patients-were-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/even-with-vitamin-d-supplementation-kidney-transplant-patients-were-deficient.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Editorial on Vitamin D deficiency– Current Drug topics</title><link>/posts/editorial-on-vitamin-d-deficiency-current-drug-topics.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/editorial-on-vitamin-d-deficiency-current-drug-topics.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="editorial-hot-topic-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-cardiovascular-and-renal-disease">Editorial: Hot topic: Vitamin D Deficiency in Cardiovascular and Renal Disease:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="new-light-shed-on-an-old-enemy-guest-editor-martin-h-de-borst">New Light Shed on an Old Enemy (Guest Editor: Martin H. de Borst)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Current Drug Targets, Volume 12, Number 1, January 2011 , pp. 1-3(3)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fat-soluble secosteroid hormone vitamin D is best known for its role in bone metabolism. From a historical perspective, the study of vitamin D deficiency has been intimately related to the study of (possible treatment of) rickets. Although diseases characterized by bone deformations have been described in ancient medical writings from the 1st and 2nd centuries, it was Galen who described the classic bone deformities noted in rickets &lt;sup>[1, 2]&lt;/sup>. More clear descriptions originate from the 17th century, reporting rickets to be endemic in England &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. In the early 20th century, observations that artificial UV light or sunlight provides protection against rickets coincided with results suggesting that rickets may be the consequence of a nutritional deficiency &lt;sup>[3, 4]&lt;/sup>. The responsible vitamin was identified by McCollum et al., who stated in their paper in the Journal of Biological Chemistry in 1922: “These experiments clearly demonstrate the existence of a fourth vitamin whose specific property, as far as we can tell at present, is to regulate the metabolism of the bones” &lt;sup>[5]&lt;/sup>. This “fourth vitamin” was named vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Vitamin D decreased kidney deaths by 4x</title><link>/posts/adding-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-deaths-by-4x.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adding-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-deaths-by-4x.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>End stage kidney disease almost 3X more likely for blacks – 2009</title><link>/posts/end-stage-kidney-disease-almost-3x-more-likely-for-blacks-2009.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/end-stage-kidney-disease-almost-3x-more-likely-for-blacks-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-race-and-the-progression-of-kidney-disease">25-hydroxyvitamin D levels, race, and the progression of kidney disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Am Soc Nephrol. 2009 Dec;20(12):2631-9. Epub 2009 Oct 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Melamed ML, Astor B, Michos ED, Hostetter TH, Powe NR, Muntner P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Albert Einstein College of Medicine, 1300 Morris Park Avenue, Bronx, NY 10461, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:mmelamed@aecom.yu.edu">mmelamed@aecom.yu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Black individuals have lower 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and experience a disproportionate burden of ESRD compared with white individuals. Animal studies suggest that vitamin D has renoprotective effects. We evaluated the contribution of low 25(OH)D levels on incidence of ESRD using data from the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey-linked Medicare claims files (n = 13,328). We included baseline (1988 through 1994) measurements of 25(OH)D and assessed the incidence of ESRD through July 31, 2001.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>