<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kidney on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/kidney.html</link><description>Recent content in Kidney on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/kidney/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dialysis patients need real vitamin D – Editorial</title><link>/posts/dialysis-patients-need-real-vitamin-d-editorial.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dialysis-patients-need-real-vitamin-d-editorial.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-many-forms-and-functions-of-essential-vitamin-d-for-dialysis-patients">The Many Forms and Functions of Essential Vitamin D for Dialysis Patients&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Renal Nutrition, Volume 23, Issue 4 , Pages e87-e88, July 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Caroline Hamatake, MPH, RD &lt;a href="mailto:caroline.hamatake@fmc-na.com">caroline.hamatake@fmc-na.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liberty Dialysis–Hawaii, Honolulu, Hawaii&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feature Editor: Catherine M. Goeddeke-Merickel, MS, RD, LD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction/Overview&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The screening and treatment of vitamin D deficiency is now routinely done in most dialysis clinics. Many dialysis patients have suboptimal levels of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and require vitamin D supplementation even in clinics located in the tropics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Those Dialysis patients with low vitamin D were 75% more likely to die</title><link>/posts/those-dialysis-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-were-75-percent-more-likely-to-die.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/those-dialysis-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-were-75-percent-more-likely-to-die.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-mortality-in-patients-receiving-dialysis-the-comprehensive-dialysis-study">Vitamin D Deficiency and Mortality in Patients Receiving Dialysis: The Comprehensive Dialysis Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Renal Nutrition, Available online 19 July 2013, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1053/j.jrn.2013.05.003">http://dx.doi.org/10.1053/j.jrn.2013.05.003&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shuchi Anand, MD∗, Corresponding author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glenn M. Chertow, MD, MPH∗,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kirsten L. Johansen, MD†, ‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara Grimes, PhD§,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lorien S. Dalrymple, MD, MPH¶,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>George A. Kaysen, MD, PhD¶, ∗∗,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manjula Kurella Tamura, MD, MPH∗, ††&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∗ Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Palo Alto, California&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Postmenopausal vitamin D benefits to blood pressure and kidney – Review</title><link>/posts/postmenopausal-vitamin-d-benefits-to-blood-pressure-and-kidney-review.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/postmenopausal-vitamin-d-benefits-to-blood-pressure-and-kidney-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-blood-pressure-endothelial-and-renal-function-in-postmenopausal-women">The Role of Vitamin D in Blood Pressure, Endothelial and Renal Function in Postmenopausal Women&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(7), 2590-2610; doi:10.3390/nu5072590&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhao-Min Liu 1 &lt;a href="mailto:liuzhaomin@cuhk.edu.hk">liuzhaomin@cuhk.edu.hk&lt;/a> Jean Woo 1, Sheng-Hui Wu 2 and Suzanne C. Ho 3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Medicine &amp;amp; Therapeutics, the Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, 999077, China&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Division of Epidemiology, Department of Medicine, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville, TN 37203-1738, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Division of Epidemiology, The Jockey Club School of Public Health and Primary Care, the Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, 999077, China&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and bicarbonate perhaps synergistically reduce muscle loss</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-bicarbonate-perhaps-synergistically-reduce-muscle-loss.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-bicarbonate-perhaps-synergistically-reduce-muscle-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="could-vitamin-d-and-bicarbonate-supplementation-synergize-to-mitigate-age-related-loss-of-muscle">Could vitamin D and bicarbonate supplementation synergize to mitigate age-related loss of muscle?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocrine, DOI 10.1007/s12020-013-0011-2; EDITORIAL&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D. Travis Thomas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span>[This is an editorial on a rat experiment]&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In patients with kidney disease receiving hemodialysis, metabolic acidosis is closely tied to muscle pathology and is known to exacerbate age-related loss of muscle mass and function. To a lesser extent, the &amp;ldquo;Western&amp;rdquo; diet is thought to contribute to mild (sub-clinical) metabolic acidosis via the supply of acid precursors from foods &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>, but the clinical significance to chronic age-related muscle degeneration has received little attention. This may partly be due to equivocal data on the benefits of neutralizing diet-induced metabolic acidosis for improving muscle-related outcomes in patients without kidney disease &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>. Despite limited data, acidosis has been shown to stimulate muscle proteolysis and is associated with negative functional outcomes including reduced peak torque and lower gait speed &lt;sup>[3]&lt;/sup>. This is important to note because aged adults are less able to excrete excess H? ions and are more prone to develop mild, but slowly increasing metabolic acidosis that may be exacerbated by a &amp;ldquo;Western&amp;rdquo; diet &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. Furthermore, approximately one out of four adults older than 50 years of age have low serum bicarbonate levels to neutralize an acidogenic diet. Because of these factors, recommendations for future work include examining the effects of alkali therapy on functional outcomes, nitrogen balance, strength and other relevant measures of physical function, in aged healthy adults &lt;sup>[3]&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic kidney with low vitamin D: 90 percent of pediatric nephrologists now recommend more D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-with-low-vitamin-d-90-percent-of-pediatric-nephrologists-now-recommend-more-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-with-low-vitamin-d-90-percent-of-pediatric-nephrologists-now-recommend-more-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="nutritional-vitamin-d-use-in-chronic-kidney-disease-a-survey-of-pediatric-nephrologists">Nutritional vitamin D use in chronic kidney disease: a survey of pediatric nephrologists.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Pediatr Nephrol. 2013 Feb;28(2):265-75. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00467-012-2307-5.">doi: 10.1007/s00467-012-2307-5.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Oct 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Griffin LM, Denburg MR, Shults J, Furth SL, Salusky IB, Hwang W, Leonard MB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Philadelphia, 3535 Market Street, Room 868, Philadelphia, PA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D deficiency may contribute to risk of cardiovascular disease, diabetes, and infections, in addition to known effects on mineral metabolism. Controversy remains regarding the use of nutritional vitamin D supplementation in chronic kidney disease (CKD), and the supplementation practices of pediatric nephrologists are unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Comparing Vitamin D and analogs for kidney patients</title><link>/posts/comparing-vitamin-d-and-analogs-for-kidney-patients.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/comparing-vitamin-d-and-analogs-for-kidney-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-metabolites-andor-analogs-which-d-for-which-patient">Vitamin D Metabolites and/or Analogs: Which D for Which Patient?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Curr Vasc Pharmacol. 2013 May 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mazzaferro S, Goldsmith D, Larsson TE, Massy ZA, Cozzolino M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dept. of Cardiovascular, Respiratory, Nephrologic and Geriatric Sciences, Sapienza University of Rome, Viale del Policlinico 155 00161. Rome ITALY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Numerous drugs with vitamin D activity are available for clinical use and it may not be easy for the non-specialist to select the most suitable for the individual patient. In this paper we review the main characteristics of the available drugs and provide evidence about any potential specific clinical indications, with special emphasis on renal patients, in order to facilitate the optimal choice. Natural vitamin D products (i.e. those identical to natural metabolites) are first examined, followed by the most frequently used synthetic molecules (i.e. bioengineered molecules not-existing in nature), which are generally indicated as &amp;ldquo;analogs&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D tester falsely said half of hemodialysis patients had less than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-tester-falsely-said-half-of-hemodialysis-patients-had-less-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-tester-falsely-said-half-of-hemodialysis-patients-had-less-than-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="accuracy-of-three-automated-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-assays-in-hemodialysis-patients">Accuracy of three automated 25-hydroxyvitamin D assays in hemodialysis patients.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clin Chim Acta. 2013 Jan 16;415:255-60. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cca.2012.10.056.">doi: 10.1016/j.cca.2012.10.056.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Nov 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Depreter B, Heijboer AC, Langlois MR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Laboratory Medicine, AZ Sint-Jan Bruges-Ostend AV, 8000 Bruges, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: We evaluated the accuracy of three automated assays for 25(OH)D measurement in comparison to ID-XLC-MS/MS in hemodialysis patients, considering the importance of their vitamin D status and reported discrepant results obtained with automated assays.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Standard and artificial vitamin D both help Chronic Kidney Disease – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/standard-and-artificial-vitamin-d-both-help-chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/standard-and-artificial-vitamin-d-both-help-chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="impact-of-vitamin-d-on-chronic-kidney-diseases-in-non-dialysis-patients">Impact of Vitamin D on Chronic Kidney Diseases in Non-Dialysis Patients:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(4): e61387. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0061387&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lijuan Xu, Xuesi Wan, Zhimin Huang, Fangfang Zeng, Guohong Wei, Donghong Fang, Wanping Deng, Yanbing Li mail&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and Objectives: Recent studies have supported a role for both newer and more established vitamin D compounds in improving proteinuria, although systematic evaluation is lacking. Furthermore, concerns remain regarding the influence of vitamin D on the progression of renal function. We analyzed the efficacy and safety of vitamin D in non-dialysis patients and compared the use of newer versus established vitamin D compounds by performing a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CYP27B1 gene decreases kidney production of active vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cyp27b1-gene-decreases-kidney-production-of-active-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp27b1-gene-decreases-kidney-production-of-active-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="thyroid-hormones-decrease-plasma-1α25-dihydroxyvitamin-d-levels-through-transcriptional-repression-of-the-renal-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-1α-hydroxylase-gene-cyp27b1">Thyroid hormones decrease plasma 1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D levels through transcriptional repression of the renal 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 1α-hydroxylase gene (CYP27B1).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocrinology. 2013 Feb;154(2):609-22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1210/en.2012-1647.">doi: 10.1210/en.2012-1647.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kozai M, Yamamoto H, Ishiguro M, Harada N, Masuda M, Kagawa T, Takei Y, Otani A, Nakahashi O, Ikeda S, Taketani Y, Takeyama K, Kato S, Takeda E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Nutrition, Institute of Health Biosciences, University of Tokushima Graduate School, 3-18-15 Kuramoto-cho, Tokushima City, 770-8503, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary determinant of circulating 1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>(2)D) levels is the activity of 25-hydroxyvitamin D-1α-hydroxylase (cytochrome P450 27B1 &lt;span>[CYP27B1]&lt;/span>) in the kidney.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1700 IU of vitamin D not enough to help hemodialysis patients</title><link>/posts/1700-iu-of-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-help-hemodialysis-patients.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1700-iu-of-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-help-hemodialysis-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="effects-of-cholecalciferol-on-functional-biochemical-vascular-and-quality-of-life-outcomes-in-hemodialysis-patients">Effects of Cholecalciferol on Functional, Biochemical, Vascular, and Quality of Life Outcomes in Hemodialysis Patients.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2013 Mar 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hewitt NA, O&amp;rsquo;Connor AA, O&amp;rsquo;Shaughnessy DV, Elder GJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Postgraduate Medical School, University of Notre Dame, Sydney, Australia;, †Renal Resource Centre, Sydney Dialysis Centre, Royal North Shore Hospital, Sydney, Australia;, ‡Department of Renal Medicine, Westmead Hospital, Sydney, Australia, §Osteoporosis and Bone Biology Division, Garvan Institute of Medical Research, Sydney, Australia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D level can be high, but little benefit: due to kidney, genes, low Magnesium etc.</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduced risk of death of Chronic Kidney Disease by 30 percent: Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-risk-of-death-of-chronic-kidney-disease-by-30-percent-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-risk-of-death-of-chronic-kidney-disease-by-30-percent-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-treatment-and-mortality-in-chronic-kidney-disease">Vitamin D Treatment and Mortality in Chronic Kidney Disease:&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Nephrol. 2013 Mar 5;37(3):239-248.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Duranton F, Rodriguez-Ortiz ME, Duny Y, Rodriguez M, Daurès JP, Argilés A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RD-Néphrologie, Institut Universitaire de Recherche Clinique, Montpellier, France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aims: Hypovitaminosis D has been associated with an increased cardiovascular mortality in the general population and in patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD). Still, whether prescribing vitamin D reduces the risk of mortality in renal patients remains controversial.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death from acute kidney injury 84 percent more likely if have low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/death-from-acute-kidney-injury-84-percent-more-likely-if-have-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-from-acute-kidney-injury-84-percent-more-likely-if-have-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dysregulated-mineral-metabolism-in-patients-with-acute-kidney-injury-and-risk-of-adverse-outcomes">Dysregulated Mineral Metabolism in Patients with Acute Kidney Injury and Risk of Adverse Outcomes.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2013 Feb 18. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/cen.12172.">doi: 10.1111/cen.12172.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leaf DE, Waikar SS, Wolf M, Cremers S, Bhan I, Stern L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology, Columbia University Medical Center, New York, NY; Division of Renal Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Numerous studies have evaluated the prevalence and importance of vitamin D deficiency among patients with chronic kidney disease and end-stage renal disease, however, little is known about vitamin D levels in acute kidney injury (AKI). We evaluated the association between vitamin D metabolites and clinical outcomes among patients with AKI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney disease requires magnesium</title><link>/posts/kidney-disease-requires-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-disease-requires-magnesium.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="highlights-from-natural-newshttpwwwnaturalnewscom038713_kidney_disease_magnesium_nutritionhtml-dr-carol-dean-ms-magnesium">Highlights from &lt;a href="http://www.naturalnews.com/038713_kidney_disease_magnesium_nutrition.html">Natural News&lt;/a> Dr. Carol Dean (Ms Magnesium)&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>magnesium is required by about 1300 enzymes systems in the body,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Magnesium also has about 4,000 receptor sites on body proteins.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>One doctor said he couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand why there was 5X more cardiovascular hospitalization and cardiovascular events in people with lowered kidney filtration rates but normal blood chemistry..Low Magnesium!!&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Use ionized magnesium testing so you know what&amp;rsquo;s really going on with magnesium levels in the body.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Kidney Disease - 2009</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-kidney-disease-2009.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-kidney-disease-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-diseasehttpwwwncbinlmnihgovpubmed20077598-2009">&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20077598">Vitamin D and chronic kidney disease&lt;/a> 2009&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ethn Dis. 2009 Autumn;19(4 Suppl 5):S5-8-11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Williams S, Malatesta K, Norris K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charles Drew University of Medicine and Science, Los Angeles, California 90059, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is an emerging public health problem and one of the most powerful predictors of premature cardiovascular disease. Emerging evidence suggests that the progression of CKD and many of the cardiovascular complications may be linked to hypovitaminosis D. Patients with CKD have an exceptionally high rate of severe vitamin D deficiency that is further exacerbated by the reduced ability to convert 25-(OH)vitamin D into the active form, 1,25 dihydroxy-vitamin D. As new evidence has improved our understanding of classical, as well as the nonclassical, functions for vitamin D, it has become apparent that the autocrine role of vitamin D is an important modulator of several systems including the immune, renal and cardiovascular systems. In addition to the traditional supplementation of 1,25-vitamin D to CKD patients, by assessing and repleting 25-(OH)vitamin D deficiency, physicians will adequately fuel both the renal and extra-renal pathways of calcitriol synthesis maintaining the classical, as well as the non-classical, functions of vitamin D that ultimately influence clinical outcomes in this high-risk group of patients. Because of the high rates of hypovitaminosis D and progression of CKD to end-stage renal disease in minority populations, these findings are highly relevant to the national efforts to reduce health disparities. Healthcare providers are called to join the intensified efforts of public health officials to disseminate and implement updated guidelines and recommendations to halt the growing epidemic of vitamin D deficiency, particularly in high-risk populations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU vitamin D3 was not enough for children with chronic kidney disease</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d3-was-not-enough-for-children-with-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d3-was-not-enough-for-children-with-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-and-treatment-with-oral-vitamin-d3-in-children-with-chronic-kidney-disease">Vitamin D insufficiency and treatment with oral vitamin D3 in children with chronic kidney disease.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Saudi Med J. 2012 Jul;33(7):740-4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kari JA, Eldesoky SM, Bagdadi OT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, King Abdulaziz University Hospital, PO Box 80215, Jeddah 21589, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. &lt;a href="mailto:jkari@doctors.org.uk">jkari@doctors.org.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the effects of oral cholecalciferol on the levels of vitamin D3 and intact parathyroid hormone (iPTH) in children with chronic kidney disease (CKD).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: We conducted a prospective uncontrolled observational study at the Pediatric Nephrology Clinic of King Abdulaziz University Hospital, Jeddah, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia between January and October 2011 to assess serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) and iPTH in children with CKD stages 2-5. Children with low vitamin D3 levels were commenced on cholecalciferol, 2000 IU/day. Their 25(OH)D3 and iPTH levels were reassessed, first after 3 months, and then after 6 months. Data analysis was performed using the Statistical Package for Social Sciences. Paired t-test was used to compare results before and after treatment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease and Vitamin D Analogs – commentary</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d-analogs-commentary.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d-analogs-commentary.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="shining-light-on-vitamin-d-trials-in-chronic-kidney-disease">Shining light on vitamin D trials in chronic kidney disease&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Kidney International (2013) 83, 198–200; doi:10.1038/ki.2012.415&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sagar U Nigwekar1,2 and Ravi I Thadhani1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Nephrology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Scholars in Clinical Science Program, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Ravi I. Thadhani, Bulfinch 127, Massachusetts General Hospital, 55 Fruit Street, Boston, Massachusetts 02114, USA. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:rthadhani@partners.org">rthadhani@partners.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D compounds may have extraskeletal functions. Chronic kidney disease (CKD) offers an opportunity to investigate these actions, as vitamin D deficiency is prevalent in this population and actions of vitamin D such as those on the heart and glucose metabolism are highly relevant. However, recent randomized controlled trials have tempered enthusiasm. We appraise a trial by de Boer et al. that addresses effects of paricalcitol on glucose metabolism in CKD, and offer perspectives on future trials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For those with kidney disease, diabetes is strongly associated with low vitamin D – 2012</title><link>/posts/for-those-with-kidney-disease-diabetes-is-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-2012.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/for-those-with-kidney-disease-diabetes-is-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="risk-factors-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-chronic-kidney-disease">Risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in patients with chronic kidney disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Intern Med. 2012;51(8):845-50. Epub 2012 Apr 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Echida Y, Mochizuki T, Uchida K, Tsuchiya K, Nitta K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Kidney Center, Tokyo Women&amp;rsquo;s Medical University, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: We conducted a cohort study to identify the risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in predialyzed patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: An observational study of 135 outpatients with stage 3-5 CKD was undertaken. Clinical and biochemical parameters were analyzed in terms of nutritional status, inflammation, and mineral metabolism in relation to serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>. Levels of 25(OH)D lower than 15 ng/mL were considered to be deficient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mutations in CYP24A1 gene (vitamin D) associated with kidney problems</title><link>/posts/mutations-in-cyp24a1-gene-vitamin-d-associated-with-kidney-problems.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mutations-in-cyp24a1-gene-vitamin-d-associated-with-kidney-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="125-oh2d-24-hydroxylase-cyp24a1-deficiency-as-a-cause-of-nephrolithiasis">1,25-(OH)2D-24 Hydroxylase (CYP24A1) Deficiency as a Cause of Nephrolithiasis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2013 Jan 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nesterova G, Malicdan MC, Yasuda K, Sakaki T, Vilboux T, Ciccone C, Horst R, Huang Y, Golas G, Introne W, Huizing M, Adams D, Boerkoel CF, Collins MT, Gahl WA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical Genetics Branch, National Human Genome Research Institute, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland;,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>†Department of Biotechnology, Faculty of Engineering, Toyama Prefectural University, Toyama, Japan;,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney disease and low vitamin D in disadvantaged populations</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-low-vitamin-d-in-disadvantaged-populations.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-low-vitamin-d-in-disadvantaged-populations.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-neighborhood-poverty-and-progression-of-chronic-kidney-disease-in-disadvantaged-populations">Hypovitaminosis D, neighborhood poverty, and progression of chronic kidney disease in disadvantaged populations.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Nephrol. 2010 Nov;74 Suppl 1:S95-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mehrotra R, Norris K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology and Hypertension, Los Angeles Biomedical Research Center at Harbor-UCLA, Torrance, CA, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:rmehrotra@labiomed.org">rmehrotra@labiomed.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the United States, there are significant racial disparities in the incidence and prevalence of end-stage renal disease. The disparities are greatest for the Blacks and the magnitude of disparity is significantly greater than is evident from the incidence and prevalence data of end-stage renal disease - early stage chronic kidney disease is less common in Blacks and during that stage, mortality rate is significantly higher for that racial group. Recent studies have identified a genetic predisposition for non-diabetic renal disease among Blacks. However, genetic factors explain only part of the higher risk and the racial disparities are a result of a complex interplay of biology and sociology. Herein we focus on two factors and their role in explaining the higher risk for progression of chronic kidney disease among Blacks - one biologic (vitamin D deficiency) and one sociologic (neighborhood poverty). A greater Understanding of these factors is important in order to reduce the racial disparities in the United States.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney transplant patients advised to avoid the sun, then 90% have very low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/kidney-transplant-patients-advised-to-avoid-the-sun-then-90-percent-have-very-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-transplant-patients-advised-to-avoid-the-sun-then-90-percent-have-very-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="preserved-circannual-rhythm-of-vitamin-d-in-kidney-transplant-patients">Preserved circannual rhythm of vitamin D in kidney transplant patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Swiss Med Wkly. 2012 Sep 4;142:w13672. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4414/smw.2012.13672.">doi: 10.4414/smw.2012.13672.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burkhalter F, Schaub S, Dickenmann M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinic for Transplantation Immunology and Nephrology, University Hospital Basel, Switzerland. &lt;a href="mailto:fburkhalter@uhbs.ch">fburkhalter@uhbs.ch&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: A high prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency has been found in the general population, in patients with chronic kidney disease and in kidney transplant patients. During winter there is a higher prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency due to the lack of solar ultraviolet B (UVB) exposure. Kidney transplant patients are advised to avoid sun exposure because of their high risk of skin cancer. This is considered to be one of the main reasons for the very high prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency in these patients. Whether circannual rhythm of vitamin D is totally reversed in kidney transplant patients is not known.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rosuvastatin given for renal problem resulted in increased vitamin D levels – RCT</title><link>/posts/rosuvastatin-given-for-renal-problem-resulted-in-increased-vitamin-d-levels-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rosuvastatin-given-for-renal-problem-resulted-in-increased-vitamin-d-levels-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-insufficiency-is-associated-with-impaired-renal-endothelial-function-and-both-are-improved-with-rosuvastatin-treatment">25-Hydroxyvitamin D insufficiency is associated with impaired renal endothelial function and both are improved with rosuvastatin treatment.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clin Res Cardiol. 2012 Dec 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ott C, Raff U, Schneider MP, Titze SI, Schmieder RE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nephrology and Hypertension, University of Erlangen-Nuremberg, Ulmenweg 18, 91054, Erlangen, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is nowadays considered as a potential cardiovascular and renal risk factor. We tested the hypotheses that vitamin D deficiency impairs the endothelial function of renal vasculature and whether vitamin D levels and endothelial function can be improved by the treatment with statins.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>50 percent of Chronic Kidney Disease treatments in Germany include vitamin D</title><link>/posts/50-percent-of-chronic-kidney-disease-treatments-in-germany-include-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/50-percent-of-chronic-kidney-disease-treatments-in-germany-include-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="implementation-and-first-results-of-a-german-chronic-kidney-disease-registry">Implementation and first results of a German Chronic Kidney Disease Registry.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Nephrol. 2012 Dec 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kleophas W, Bieber B, Robinson BM, Duttlinger J, Fliser D, Lonnemann G, Rump LC, Pisoni RL, Port FK, Reichel H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Advanced chronic kidney disease (CKD) is gaining increasing medical and economical importance, but little information exists about treatment variation and the impact of routine clinical treatments on survival, quality of life, and cost. We demonstrate the first results of a national electronic registry of nephrology clinic data that will serve as a resource for the prospective observation of CKD patients in Germany. A large network of German nephrologist practices is currently joining the project. Routinely obtained clinical data for non-dialysis dependent CKD patients are documented in health records electronically, and elements from these data are extracted using QuaNT (Qualitätssicherung Nephrologie und Transplantation) to create a centralized database. Here, we report cross-sectional data from 59 participating nephrology clinics and 6,187 patients with CKD Stage 3 - 5 in 2011. Mean age ± standard deviation (SD) was 72 ± 12 years. The distribution of CKD 3, 4, and 5 (non-dialysis) was 60%, 33%, and 8%, respectively. The major renal diseases were hypertension/vascular nephropathy (47%) and diabetic nephropathy (26%).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active vitamin D treats Chronic Kidney Disease by stimulating Klotho production</title><link>/posts/active-vitamin-d-treats-chronic-kidney-disease-by-stimulating-klotho-production.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-vitamin-d-treats-chronic-kidney-disease-by-stimulating-klotho-production.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-secreted-klotho-a-long-awaited-panacea-for-vascular-calcification">Vitamin D and secreted Klotho: a long-awaited panacea for vascular calcification?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Kidney International (2012) 82, 1248–1250; doi:10.1038/ki.2012.338&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hirotaka Komaba1 and Masafumi Fukagawa1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Nephrology, Endocrinology and Metabolism, Tokai University School of Medicine, Isehara, Japan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Masafumi Fukagawa, Division of Nephrology, Endocrinology and Metabolism, Tokai University School of Medicine, 143 Shimo-Kasuya, Isehara 259-1193, Japan. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:fukagawa@tokai-u.jp">fukagawa@tokai-u.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is characterized by accelerated vascular calcification, which may in part be caused by deficiency of the anti-aging factor Klotho. Lau et al. demonstrate that administration of active vitamin D and its analog decreases aortic calcification in association with increases in two potent calcification inhibitors—the secreted form of Klotho and vascular osteopontin. These data might provide a new perspective on the association of active vitamin D with improved survival in patients with CKD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poor kidneys result in lower vitamin D level result in 7X more tooth loss</title><link>/posts/poor-kidneys-result-in-lower-vitamin-d-level-result-in-7x-more-tooth-loss.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poor-kidneys-result-in-lower-vitamin-d-level-result-in-7x-more-tooth-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="association-between-low-renal-function-and-tooth-loss-over-5-years">Association between low renal function and tooth loss over 5 years.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Gerodontology. 2012 Nov 26. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/ger.12015.">doi: 10.1111/ger.12015.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yoshihara A, Iwasaki M, Miyazaki H, Nakamura K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Oral Health and Welfare, Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences, Niigata University, Niigata, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This longitudinal study evaluated the relationship between low renal function and tooth loss in elderly subjects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MATERIAL AND METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Subjects comprised 406 female subjects (55-74 years old) who agreed to participate in a baseline examination and a follow-up examination after 5 years. Serum cystatin C levels were used to assess renal function. Multiple logistic regression analysis was used to evaluate the relationship between tooth loss and change in serum cystatin C levels over 5 years. Tooth loss over 5 years (0: no, 1: yes) was used as the dependent variable. Seven variables were used as independent variables, including change in serum cystatin C levels over 5 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When lupus affects the kidneys vitamin D levels drop even further</title><link>/posts/when-lupus-affects-the-kidneys-vitamin-d-levels-drop-even-further.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/when-lupus-affects-the-kidneys-vitamin-d-levels-drop-even-further.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-predictive-factors-of-low-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-systemic-lupus-erythematosus">The predictive factors of low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and vitamin D deficiency in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Rheumatol Int. 2012 Nov 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sumethkul K, Boonyaratavej S, Kitumnuaypong T, Angthararuk S, Cheewasat P, Manadee N, Sumethkul V.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatology Unit, Department of Medicine, Rajavithi Hospital, 2 Rajavithi Road, Bangkok, 10400, Thailand, &lt;a href="mailto:ckittiwan@hotmail.com">ckittiwan@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a steroid hormone with pleiotropic effects. The association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level &lt;span>[25(OH) D]&lt;/span> and lupus nephritis are not clearly known. We aim to determine serum 25(OH) D levels in patients with inactive SLE, active SLE without lupus nephritis (LN) and active SLE with LN and to identify clinical predictor of vitamin D deficiency. One hundred and eight SLE patients were included. Patients were classified as Group (Gr) 1, 2 and 3 if they had SLE disease activity index (SLEDAI) &amp;lt;3, ≥3 but no LN and ≥3 with LN. Important baseline characteristics were collected. 25(OH) D was measured by high performance liquid chromatography (HPLC). SLEDAI in Gr1, Gr2 and Gr3 was 0.7 (0.9), 5.6 (2.3) and 9.2 (5.2), respectively. 43.5 % had vitamin D insufficiency and 29.6 % had vitamin D deficiency. Mean 25(OH) D in each groups was 28.3 (8.0), 26.7 (9.5) and 19.9 (7.6) ng/ml (p &amp;lt; 0.001 comparing Gr1 and 3) (p = 0.003 comparing Gr2 and 3). Vitamin D deficiency was found in 11.1, 22.2 and 55.6 % of Gr1, 2 and 3. Linear regression analysis found that 25(OH) D was significantly correlated with serum albumin (r = 0.28, p = 0.004), inversely correlated with SLEDAI (r = -0.22, p = 0.03) and urinary protein creatinine index (UPCI) (r = -0.28, p = 0.005), but not with sun exposure score, body mass index and estimated GFR. Only UPCI was significantly inversely correlated with 25(OH) D (p = 0.02) from multiple linear regression. LN was a significant predictor of vitamin D deficiency from multivariate logistic regression (OR &lt;strong>5.97&lt;/strong> ; p = 0.006). Vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency was found in 93 and 86 % of LN with proteinuria ≥ and &amp;lt;500 mg/day. We conclude that SLE patients with LN have significantly lower vitamin D level than inactive SLE and active SLE without LN. Hence, nephritis is a significant predictor of vitamin D deficiency in SLE patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CYP24A1 gene, kidney disease, and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cyp24a1-and-kidney-disease">CYP24A1 and kidney disease&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens. 2011 May 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Petkovich M, Jones G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>aDivision of Cancer Biology and Genetics, Cancer Research Institute, Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, Canada bDepartment of Research and Development, Cytochroma Inc., Markham, Canada cDepartments of Biochemistry and Medicine, Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE OF REVIEW:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patients with chronic renal disease have elevated serum phosphate levels, elevated fibroblast-like growth factor 23 (FGF-23), and declining vitamin D status. These changes are related and may be responsible for elevated 25-hydroxyvitamin D-24-hydroxylase (CYP24A1) and dysfunctional vitamin D metabolism. This review focuses on the biochemistry and pathophysiology of CYP24A1 and the utility of blocking this enzyme with CYP24A1 inhibitors in chronic kidney disease (CKD) patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 far better than D2 for hemodialysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-far-better-than-d2-for-hemodialysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-far-better-than-d2-for-hemodialysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d2-versus-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-hemodialysis-patients">Vitamin D2 versus vitamin D3 supplementation in hemodialysis patients:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>a comparative pilot study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daroux M, Shenouda M, Bacri JL, Lemaitre V, Vanhille P, Bataille P&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nephrology, Doctor Duchenne Hospital, Boulogne-sur-Mer - France; and Department of Nephrology, Regional University Hospital of Lille, Lille - France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Nephrology &lt;span>[2012:0]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: In patients with chronic kidney disease, vitamin D insufficiency is highly prevalent. It can be corrected by supplementation with either vitamin D2 or vitamin D3. Recent studies in patients without impaired kidney function suggest that vitamin D3 is more efficient than vitamin D2 in correcting vitamin D insufficiency. However, no direct comparison has been made in hemodialysis (HD) patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney – only 1 in 3 doctors said kids need more than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-only-1-in-3-doctors-said-kids-need-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-only-1-in-3-doctors-said-kids-need-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kidney Dialysis clinics reluctant to add vitamin D treatment as they are not reimbursed</title><link>/posts/kidney-dialysis-clinics-reluctant-to-add-vitamin-d-treatment-as-they-are-not-reimbursed.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-dialysis-clinics-reluctant-to-add-vitamin-d-treatment-as-they-are-not-reimbursed.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>And, treating with vitamin D would decrease their number of patients thus and their income&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-cost-effective-complement-to-managing-the-vitamin-d-deficient-and-anemic-dialysis-patient-in-the-bundledworld">A cost effective complement to managing the vitamin D deficient and anemic dialysis patient in the bundled world.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsoweb">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="a-cost-effective-complement-to-managing-the-vitamin-d-deficient-and-anemic-dialysis-patient-in-the-bundledworld">A cost effective complement to managing the vitamin D deficient and anemic dialysis patient in the bundled world.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephrol News Issues. 2012 Jul;26(8):22-4, 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Larkin J, Bea L, Sharma A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pacific Renal Research Institute, Caldwell, Idaho, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4X fewer malignancies after kidney transplant if got active vitamin D – Prospective Score</title><link>/posts/4x-fewer-malignancies-after-kidney-transplant-if-got-active-vitamin-d-prospective-score.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4x-fewer-malignancies-after-kidney-transplant-if-got-active-vitamin-d-prospective-score.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="orally-active-vitamin-d-for-potential-chemoprevention-of-post-transplant-malignancy">Orally Active Vitamin D for Potential Chemoprevention of Post-transplant Malignancy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Yoshitsugu Obi1, Naotsugu Ichimaru2, Takayuki Hamano3,*, Kodo Tomida4, Isao Matsui1, Naohiko Fujii5, Masayoshi Okumi6, Jun-ya Kaimori7, Koji Yazawa6, Yukito Kokado8, Yoshiharu Tsubakihara9, Norio Nonomura10, Hiromi Rakugi11, Shiro Takahara12, and Yoshitaka Isaka11&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Geriatric Medicine &amp;amp; Nephrology, Osaka University Graduate School of Medicine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Urology, Osaka Central Hospital&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Comprehensive Kidney Disease Research, Osaka University Graduate School of Medicine&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omega 3 increases vitamin D in the blood – many studies</title><link>/posts/omega-3-increases-vitamin-d-in-the-blood-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-increases-vitamin-d-in-the-blood-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Many articles on this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omega-3 increases levels of active vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active vitamin D is the form which the body actually used&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active vitamin D is not measured by standard vitamin D tests&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omega-3 is thus especially useful to get vitamin D to the body if the kidney is not functioning properly&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-effects-of-omega-3-fatty-acid-on-vitamin-d-activation-in-hemodialysis-patients-a-pilot-study--2015">The Effects of Omega-3 Fatty Acid on Vitamin D Activation in Hemodialysis Patients: A Pilot Study- 2015&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/active-d-and-omega-3.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Mar. Drugs 2015, 13(2), 741-755; doi:10.3390/md13020741&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>With CKD should measure the active form of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/with-ckd-should-measure-the-active-form-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/with-ckd-should-measure-the-active-form-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="incident-isolated-125oh2d3-deficiency-is-more-common-than-25ohd-deficiency-in-ckd">Incident isolated 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) deficiency is more common than 25(OH)D deficiency in CKD.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Nephrol. 2012 Mar-Apr;25(2):204-10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5301/JN.2011.8429.">doi: 10.5301/JN.2011.8429.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Levin A, Le Barbier M, Er L, Andress D, Sigrist MK, Djurdjev O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BC Provincial Renal Agency, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada. &lt;a href="mailto:alevin@providencehealth.bc.ca">alevin@providencehealth.bc.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiencies are well described in general populations and in those with chronic kidney disease (CKD). Although serum 25(OH)D may be a good indicator of vitamin D status in healthy individuals, the hydroxylated product, 1,25(OH)(2)D, essential for important biological functions such as mineral metabolism, bone turnover, regulation of protein synthesis, cell differentiation and proliferation may be a more suitable indicator for individuals with CKD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>7100 IU (50000 weekly) restored vitamin D levels for those with Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/7100-iu-50000-weekly-restored-vitamin-d-levels-for-those-with-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7100-iu-50000-weekly-restored-vitamin-d-levels-for-those-with-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cholecalciferol-supplementation-in-chronic-kidney-disease-restoration-of-vitamin-d-status-and-impact-on-parathyroid-hormone">Cholecalciferol Supplementation in Chronic Kidney Disease: Restoration of Vitamin D Status and Impact on Parathyroid Hormone&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Nutr Metab 2012;61:74-82 (DOI: 10.1159/000339618)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Miriam G. Garcia-Lopesa, Roberta Pillarb, Maria Ayako Kamimuraa, b, Lillian A. Rochab, Maria Eugênia F. Canzianib, Aluízio B. Carvalhob, Lilian Cupparia, b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Nutrition Program and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Division of Nephrology, Federal University of São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aims: Hypovitaminosis D is highly prevalent among patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) and has been associated with poor outcome. We aimed to test the effect of a protocol of cholecalciferol supplementation on the restoration of vitamin D status and on parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels in patients with CKD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease reduced with 3600 IU vitamin D (50000 twice a month)– RCT</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-reduced-with-3600-iu-vitamin-d-50000-twice-a-month-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-reduced-with-3600-iu-vitamin-d-50000-twice-a-month-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chronic kidney disease associated with higher levels of vitamin K1</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-associated-with-higher-levels-of-vitamin-k1.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-associated-with-higher-levels-of-vitamin-k1.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="phylloquinone-and-vitamin-d-status-associations-with-incident-chronic-kidney-disease-in-the-framingham-offspring-cohort">Phylloquinone and vitamin d status: associations with incident chronic kidney disease in the framingham offspring cohort.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Nephrol. 2012;36(1):68-77. Epub 2012 Jun 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O&amp;rsquo;Seaghdha CM, Hwang SJ, Holden R, Booth SL, Fox CS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute&amp;rsquo;s Framingham Heart Study and the Center for Population Studies, Framingham, Mass., USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Cardiovascular risk factors are associated with the development of chronic kidney disease (CKD), and CKD and vascular disease are etiologically linked. Evidence suggests deficiencies of vitamins D and K may adversely affect the cardiovascular system, but data from longitudinal studies are lacking. We hypothesized that deficiencies of vitamins D and K may be associated with incident CKD and/or incident albuminuria amongst members of the general population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5700 IU of vitamin D helped half with chronic kidney disease if not having dialysis</title><link>/posts/5700-iu-of-vitamin-d-helped-half-with-chronic-kidney-disease-if-not-having-dialysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5700-iu-of-vitamin-d-helped-half-with-chronic-kidney-disease-if-not-having-dialysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kidney Conference had many Vitamin D papers</title><link>/posts/kidney-conference-had-many-vitamin-d-papers.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-conference-had-many-vitamin-d-papers.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Need at least 80 ng of vitamin D if have chronic kidney disease</title><link>/posts/need-at-least-80-ng-of-vitamin-d-if-have-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/need-at-least-80-ng-of-vitamin-d-if-have-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="ckd-patients-may-need-higher-25d-levelshttpwwwrenalandurologynewscomckd-patients-may-need-higher-25d-levelsarticle24070620">&lt;a href="http://www.renalandurologynews.com/ckd-patients-may-need-higher-25d-levels/article/240706/%20">CKD Patients May Need Higher 25D Levels&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Jody A. Charnow May 11, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NATIONAL HARBOR, Md.—Levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25D) higher than 20 ng/mL would be required to normalize intact parathyroid hormone (iPTH) in patients with stages 3 and 4 chronic kidney disease (CKD) with vitamin D insufficiency and secondary hyperparathyroidism, researchers concluded in a study presented at the National Kidney Foundation 2012 Spring Clinical Meetings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Researchers noted that the Institute of Medicine recently suggested 20 ng/mL as the lower limit of the normal range for 25D, but this limit may be significantly higher among individuals with reduced kidney function.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perhaps Vitamin D3 is better than D2 for Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/perhaps-vitamin-d3-is-better-than-d2-for-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/perhaps-vitamin-d3-is-better-than-d2-for-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="ergocalciferol-and-cholecalciferol-in-ckd">Ergocalciferol and Cholecalciferol in CKD.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Kidney Dis. 2012 May 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nigwekar SU, Bhan I, Thadhani R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA; Scholars in Clinical Science Program, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The development of chronic kidney disease (CKD) is accompanied by a progressive decrease in the ability to produce 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D. Pharmacological replacement with active vitamin D therefore has been a cornerstone of secondary hyperparathyroidism therapy in the end-stage renal disease population treated by long-term dialysis. Recent evidence suggests that extrarenal conversion of 25-hydroxyvitamin D to 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D may have significant biological roles beyond those traditionally ascribed to vitamin D. Furthermore, low 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels are common in patients with all stages of CKD. This article focuses on the role of nutritional vitamin D replacement in CKD and aims to review vitamin D biology and summarize the existing literature regarding nutritional vitamin D replacement in these populations. Based on the current state of the evidence, we provide suggestions for clinical practice and address areas of uncertainty that need further research.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D testing typically not needed, but in 9 cases it is</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-testing-typically-not-needed-but-in-9-cases-it-is.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-testing-typically-not-needed-but-in-9-cases-it-is.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/many-ways-to-get-2x-increased-response-from-the-same-dose" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1918">Many ways to get 2X increased response from the same dose&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>this study does not appear to have tried any of the ways - such as use of co-factors like Magnesium, Vitamin K2, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This study does not seem to consider use of &lt;a href="/posts/loading-bolusstoss-doses" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 326">loading /bolus/Stoss doses&lt;/a>, only maintenance doses&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/no-vitamin-d-test-needed-before-supplementing-typically" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: No vitamin D test needed before supplementing (typically) – April 2014">No vitamin D test needed before supplementing (typically) – April 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney transplant worked better if initially have high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/kidney-transplant-worked-better-if-initially-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-transplant-worked-better-if-initially-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney disease with low vitamin D causes health problems</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-with-low-vitamin-d-causes-health-problems.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-with-low-vitamin-d-causes-health-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="risk-factors-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-chronic-kidney-disease">Risk factors for vitamin d deficiency in patients with chronic kidney disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Intern Med. 2012;51(8):845-50. Epub 2012 Apr 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Echida Y, Mochizuki T, Uchida K, Tsuchiya K, Nitta K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Kidney Center, Tokyo Women&amp;rsquo;s Medical University, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective We conducted a cohort study to identify the risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in predialyzed patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods An observational study of 135 outpatients with stage 3-5 CKD was undertaken. Clinical and biochemical parameters were analyzed in terms of nutritional status, inflammation, and mineral metabolism in relation to serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fructose reduces blood levels of active vitamin D</title><link>/posts/fructose-reduces-blood-levels-of-active-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fructose-reduces-blood-levels-of-active-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#chronic-high-fructose-intake-reduces-serum-125-oh2d3-levels-in-calcium-sufficient-rodents---2014">Chronic high fructose intake reduces serum 1,25 (OH)2D3 levels in calcium-sufficient rodents - 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="chronic-high-fructose-intake-reduces-serum-125-oh2d3-levels-in-calcium-sufficient-rodents---2014">Chronic high fructose intake reduces serum 1,25 (OH)2D3 levels in calcium-sufficient rodents - 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2014 Apr 9;9(4):e93611. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0093611">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0093611&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Douard V1, Patel C1, Lee J1, Tharabenjasin P1, Williams E2, Fritton JC3, Sabbagh Y4, Ferraris RP1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/fructose-2014a.jpg" alt="image" width="300">&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/fructose-2014b.jpg" alt="image" width="100">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Excessive fructose consumption inhibits adaptive increases in intestinal Ca2+ transport in lactating and weanling rats with increased Ca2+ requirements by preventing the increase in serum levels of 1,25(OH)2D3. Here we tested the hypothesis that chronic fructose intake decreases 1,25(OH)2D3 levels independent of increases in Ca2+ requirements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 vs serum D3 (Calcitriol, HyD)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-vs-serum-d3-calcitriol-hyd.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-vs-serum-d3-calcitriol-hyd.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Junk&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#oral-supplementation-with-25ohd3-versus-vitamin-d3-effects-on-25ohd-levels-lower-extremity-function-blood-pressure-and-markers-of-innate-immunity">Oral supplementation with 25(OH)D3 versus vitamin D3: Effects on 25(OH)D levels, lower extremity function, blood pressure, and markers of innate immunity&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#abstract">Abstract&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#patients-and-methods">Patients and Methods&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clinical-trial-protocol">Clinical trial protocol&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clinical-visits">Clinical visits&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biomarker-assays">Biomarker assays&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#compliance-and-safety">Compliance and safety&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#statistical-analysis">Statistical analysis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#results">Results&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#markers-of-immunity">Markers of immunity&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#discussion">Discussion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#in-conclusion">In conclusion,&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="oral-supplementation-with-25ohd3-versus-vitamin-d3-effects-on-25ohd-levels-lower-extremity-function-blood-pressure-and-markers-of-innate-immunity">Oral supplementation with 25(OH)D3 versus vitamin D3: Effects on 25(OH)D levels, lower extremity function, blood pressure, and markers of innate immunity&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Bone and Mineral Research, Volume 27, Issue 1, pages 160–169, January 2012&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HFCS or fructose decreases Calcium and vitamin D if have CKD</title><link>/posts/hfcs-or-fructose-decreases-calcium-and-vitamin-d-if-have-ckd.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hfcs-or-fructose-decreases-calcium-and-vitamin-d-if-have-ckd.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="dietary-fructose-inhibits-intestinal-calcium-absorption-and-induces-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-ckd">Dietary fructose inhibits intestinal calcium absorption and induces vitamin D insufficiency in CKD.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Am Soc Nephrol. 2010 Feb;21(2):261-71. Epub 2009 Dec 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Douard V, Asgerally A, Sabbagh Y, Sugiura S, Shapses SA, Casirola D, Ferraris RP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pharmacology and Physiology, UMDNJ-New Jersey Medical School, Newark, NJ 07101-1709, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renal disease leads to perturbations in calcium and phosphate homeostasis and vitamin D metabolism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dietary fructose aggravates chronic kidney disease (CKD), but whether it also worsens CKD-induced derangements in calcium and phosphate homeostasis is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors with poorly functioning kidneys had lower levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/seniors-with-poorly-functioning-kidneys-had-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-with-poorly-functioning-kidneys-had-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-elderly-women-in-nursing-homes">Vitamin D deficiency in elderly women in nursing homes:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="investigation-with-consideration-of-decreased-activation-function-from-the-kidneys">investigation with consideration of decreased activation function from the kidneys.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Am Geriatr Soc. 2012 Feb;60(2):251-5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-5415.2011.03826.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2011.03826.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jan 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Terabe Y, Harada A, Tokuda H, Okuizumi H, Nagaya M, Shimokata H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, National Center for Geriatrics and Gerontology, Obu City, Aichi, Japan. &lt;a href="mailto:yst-trb@ncgg.go.jp">yst-trb@ncgg.go.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine the approximate percentage of women in nursing homes who have vitamin D deficiency and to investigate whether, in assessing vitamin D status in elderly women, there are problems with measuring only 25 hydroxy-vitamin D(3) (25(OH)D(3) ) and whether decreased vitamin D activation as a result of poor renal function needs to be considered.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease stage not associated with vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-stage-not-associated-with-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-stage-not-associated-with-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-insufficiency-in-patients-with-chronic-kidney-disease">Vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency in patients with chronic kidney disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Bras Nefrol. 2012 Mar;34(1):58-63.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[Article in English, Portuguese]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diniz HF, Romão MF, Elias RM, Romão Júnior JE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de São Paulo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is common among patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD). A higher level of serum vitamin D is expected in residents of the tropics in relation to inhabitants of non-tropical regions, due to greater sun exposure and increased production of vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Telomeres longer for dialysis patients having higher levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/telomeres-longer-for-dialysis-patients-having-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/telomeres-longer-for-dialysis-patients-having-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kidney dysfunction associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/kidney-dysfunction-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-dysfunction-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-threshold-value-of-estimated-glomerular-filtration-rate-that-predicts-changes-in-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-4th-korean-national-health-and-nutritional-examination-survey-2008">A threshold value of estimated glomerular filtration rate that predicts changes in serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels: 4th Korean National Health and Nutritional Examination Survey 2008.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="a-threshold-value-of-estimated-glomerular-filtration-rate-that-predicts-changes-in-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-4th-korean-national-health-and-nutritional-examination-survey-2008">A threshold value of estimated glomerular filtration rate that predicts changes in serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels: 4th Korean National Health and Nutritional Examination Survey 2008.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2012 Jan 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh YJ, Kim M, Lee H, Lee JP, Kim H, Kim S, Oh KH, Joo KW, Lim CS, Kim S, Kim YS, Kim DK.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hemodialysis low vitamin D status was normalized with 28500 IU avg daily</title><link>/posts/hemodialysis-low-vitamin-d-status-was-normalized-with-28500-iu-avg-daily.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hemodialysis-low-vitamin-d-status-was-normalized-with-28500-iu-avg-daily.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="efficacy-and-safety-of-a-short-course-of-very-high-dose-cholecalciferol-in-hemodialysis">Efficacy and safety of a short course of very-high-dose cholecalciferol in hemodialysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2012 Jan 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wasse H, Huang R, Long Q, Singapuri S, Raggi P, Tangpricha V.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Divisions of Nephrology and Cardiology, Emory University, Atlanta, GA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D deficiency is highly prevalent among hemodialysis patients, but little data exist in support of an optimal repletion regimen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: The objective was to ascertain the efficacy of weekly very-high-dose cholecalciferol (vitamin D(3)) in correcting vitamin D insufficiency and deficiency in patients with stage 5D chronic kidney disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death rate increased 3X for chronic kidney disease if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/death-rate-increased-3x-for-chronic-kidney-disease-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-rate-increased-3x-for-chronic-kidney-disease-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 becomes Calcidiol which becomes Calcitriol</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-becomes-calcidiol-which-becomes-calcitriol.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-becomes-calcidiol-which-becomes-calcitriol.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolorf00cholecalciferol-spanko-ler-cal-si-ferol--vitamin-d3--from-diet-or-your-skin-from-cholesterol-and-uv">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Cholecalciferol &lt;/span>(ko-ler-cal-&amp;lsquo;si ferol) = vitamin D3, from diet or your skin (from cholesterol and UV)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/getting-vitamin-d-into-your-blood-and-cells" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Getting Vitamin D into your blood and cells">{img fileId=&amp;ldquo;2696&amp;rdquo; width =&amp;ldquo;700&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>        &lt;strong>click on chart to see it larger, along with description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="liver-uses-enzymes-to-add-water--span-stylecolorf00calcidiol-span-kal-sĭ-dīol">Liver uses enzymes to add water ==&amp;gt; &lt;span style="color:#F00;">Calcidiol &lt;/span> (kal-sĭ-dī′ol)&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>25-hydroxy-vitamin-D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>25(OH)D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>what a blood test measures&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>stored all around the body, including in the blood&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>appears to last for weeks (&amp;gt; about 50 ng) to months (&amp;lt; about 30 ng)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D receptor activation and Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-activation-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-activation-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Some form of vitamin D may be the lowest cost treatment for CKD – Spanish</title><link>/posts/some-form-of-vitamin-d-may-be-the-lowest-cost-treatment-for-ckd-spanish.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-form-of-vitamin-d-may-be-the-lowest-cost-treatment-for-ckd-spanish.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="economic-impact-of-vitamin-d-treatment-on-chronic-kidney-disease-patients--sept-2011">Economic impact of vitamin D treatment on chronic kidney disease patients – Sept 2011&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nefrologia. 2011 Sep 20;31(5):528-536. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3265/Nefrologia.pre2011.Aug.11012.">doi: 10.3265/Nefrologia.pre2011.Aug.11012.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[Article in Spanish]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ramos R, Alcázar R, Otero A, de Francisco AL, Del Pino MD.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d3-becomes-calcidiol-which-becomes-calcitriol">Vitamin D3 becomes Calcidiol which becomes Calcitriol&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/application-to-fda-for-use-of-active-vitamin-d-for-hemodialysis-patients">Application to FDA for use of active Vitamin D for hemodialysis patients – July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/active-form-of-vitamin-d-appears-to-help-prevent-and-treat-some-cancers" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 923">Active form of vitamin D appears to help prevent and treat some cancers – Feb 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blacks have low vitamin D and have 50 percent more kidney failure</title><link>/posts/blacks-have-low-vitamin-d-and-have-50-percent-more-kidney-failure.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-have-low-vitamin-d-and-have-50-percent-more-kidney-failure.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-racial-disparity-in-albuminuria-nhanes-20012006">Vitamin D and Racial Disparity in Albuminuria: NHANES 2001–2006&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>American Journal of Hypertension 2011; 24 10, 1114–1120. doi:10.1038/ajh.2011.108&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kevin A. Fiscella1,2, Paul C. Winters1 and Gbenga Ogedegbe3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Family Medicine, University of Rochester School of Medicine, Rochester, New York, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Community &amp;amp; Preventive Medicine, University of Rochester School of Medicine, Rochester, New York, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Medicine, Division of General Internal Medicine, Center for Healthful Behavior Change, New York University School of Medicine, New York, New York, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-vitamin-d-axis-in-chronic-kidney-disease--state-of-the-art-and-future-perspectives">The Vitamin D Axis in Chronic Kidney Disease – State of the Art and Future Perspectives&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Marco Ruggiero, Stefania Pacini&lt;/p>
&lt;p>European Nephrology, 2011;5(1):15-19&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the components of the vitamin D axis participate in the pathogenesis of chronic kidney disease (CKD) and this knowledge can be exploited to devise targeted therapeutic strategies. The vitamin D axis includes vitamin D, vitamin D receptor and vitamin D-binding protein (VDBP), which is the precursor of a potent macrophage activating factor, group-specific component (Gc)-protein-derived macrophage activating factor (GcMAF), a protein that is being extensively studied after it was demonstrated that it eradicates advanced cancer and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. Thanks to its effects on the immune system and angiogenesis, it also appears to be a promising candidate for targeted therapy of CKD. In this article we shall summarise the state of the art on vitamin D and CKD, and then we shall focus on the perspectives opened by increasing knowledge of other components of the axis, in particular VDBP and GcMAF.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney aging-inevitable or preventable</title><link>/posts/kidney-aging-inevitable-or-preventable.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-aging-inevitable-or-preventable.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nat Rev Nephrol. 2011 Aug 9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneph.2011.104.">doi: 10.1038/nrneph.2011.104.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choudhury D, Levi M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dallas VA Medical Center, The University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX 75216, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aging process affects all organs, including the kidneys. As part of this process, progressive scarring and a measurable decline in renal function occur in most people over time. The improved understanding of the processes that can lead to and/or hasten scarring and loss of renal function over time parallels advances in our understanding of the aging process. Clinical factors, including hypertension, diabetes mellitus, obesity, abnormal lipid levels and vitamin D deficiency, have been associated with increasing renal sclerosis with age. In addition, tissue factors such as angiotensin II, advanced glycation end products, oxidative stress and Klotho are associated with renal aging. These associations and possible interventions, including the control of blood pressure, blood sugar, weight, diet and calorie restriction might make renal aging more preventable than inevitable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2.8X more likely to die of hemodialysis if low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/28x-more-likely-to-die-of-hemodialysis-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/28x-more-likely-to-die-of-hemodialysis-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-mortality-and-hospitalization-in-hemodialysis-patients-with-or-without-protein-energy-wasting--2011">Vitamin D Deficiency, Mortality, and Hospitalization in Hemodialysis Patients with or without Protein-Energy Wasting.- 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-and-mortality-of-german-hemodialysis-patients--2012">Vitamin D status and mortality of German hemodialysis patients.- 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-mortality-and-hospitalization-in-hemodialysis-patients-with-or-without-protein-energy-wasting--2011">Vitamin D Deficiency, Mortality, and Hospitalization in Hemodialysis Patients with or without Protein-Energy Wasting.- 2011&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephron Clin Pract. 2011 Aug 11;119(3):c220-c226.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fiedler R, Dorligjav O, Seibert E, Ulrich C, Markau S, Girndt M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine II, Martin Luther University Halle-Wittenberg, Halle/Saale, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:Vitamin D deficiency and protein-energy wasting (PEW) are highly prevalent in hemodialysis (HD) patients. The goal of our study was to investigate if a lack of vitamin D influences mortality and hospitalization of HD patients with or without PEW. Methods: In 81 chronic HD patients with different nutritional status assessed by the Malnutrition Inflammation Score (MIS), vitamin D deficiency (25-OH-vitamin D(3) levels ?30 nmol/l or &lt;strong>?12 ng/ml&lt;/strong> ) was prospectively investigated for its prognostic impact on mortality and hospitalization. Over a 3-year follow-up, all-cause mortality and hospitalization were determined. The predictive value of low vitamin D levels and PEW as well as their combined effect were evaluated using a multivariate Cox regression model.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>33 percent more likely to die of chronic kidney disease if less than 15 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/33-percent-more-likely-to-die-of-chronic-kidney-disease-if-less-than-15-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/33-percent-more-likely-to-die-of-chronic-kidney-disease-if-less-than-15-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>People with kidney disease moved faster after adding vitamin D</title><link>/posts/people-with-kidney-disease-moved-faster-after-adding-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-kidney-disease-moved-faster-after-adding-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-muscle-strength-functional-ability-and-balance-in-peritoneal-dialysis-patients-with-vitamin-d-deficiency">Vitamin D and muscle strength, functional ability and balance in peritoneal dialysis patients with vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Nephrol. 2011 Aug;76(2):110-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Taskapan H, Baysal O, Karahan D, Durmus B, Altay Z, Ulutas O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nephrology Department, and Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation Department, Turgut Ozal Medical Center of Inonu University, Medical Faculty, Malatya, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>25(OH)D deficiency has been associated with significantly worse physical performance in individuals with normal renal function. We examined the physical function, muscle strength and balance in age- and gender-matched 25 Stage 3 - 4 CKD patients and 47 Stage 5 CKD patients on peritoneal dialysis (PD) with vitamin D deficiency by objective methods and evaluated the effect of vitamin D replacement on physical performance tests: the &amp;ldquo;timed up and go&amp;rdquo; (TUG) test, gait velocity test, timed chair stand test, stair climb test, dynamic balance tests (TUG test, dynamic postural stability test), static balance test (functional reach test) and muscle strength in these two groups.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Application to FDA for use of active Vitamin D for hemodialysis patients</title><link>/posts/application-to-fda-for-use-of-active-vitamin-d-for-hemodialysis-patients.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/application-to-fda-for-use-of-active-vitamin-d-for-hemodialysis-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="rockwell-medical-announces-acquisition-of-generic-drug-vitamin-d-to-treat-secondary-hyperparathyroidism-in-esrd-patients">Rockwell Medical Announces Acquisition of Generic Drug Vitamin-D to Treat Secondary Hyperparathyroidism in ESRD Patients&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="injectable-calcitriol-will-address-estimated-350m-us-dialysis-market-press-release">Injectable Calcitriol Will Address Estimated $350M U.S. Dialysis Market; press release&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>WIXOM, Mich., Jul 26, 2011 (GlobeNewswire via COMTEX) &amp;ndash; Rockwell Medical , a fully-integrated biopharmaceutical company offering innovative products and services targeting end-stage renal disease (ESRD), chronic kidney disease (CKD), and iron deficiency anemia, announced today that it has acquired an &lt;strong>Abbreviated New Drug Application&lt;/strong> (ANDA) for injectable, active Vitamin-D (Calcitriol) for End Stage Renal Disease (ESRD) patients undergoing hemodialysis. Terms were not disclosed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hydroxylated vitamin D goes away faster than standard D in Kidney patents</title><link>/posts/hydroxylated-vitamin-d-goes-away-faster-than-standard-d-in-kidney-patents.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hydroxylated-vitamin-d-goes-away-faster-than-standard-d-in-kidney-patents.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="incident-isolated-125oh2d3-deficiency-is-more-common-than-25ohd-deficiency-in-ckd">Incident isolated 1,25(OH)2D3 deficiency is more common than 25(OH)D deficiency in CKD.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Nephrol. 2011 Jun 16. pii: 5403F0E0-161B-4C4F-96F9-2A4FAF4EB467. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5301/JN.2011.8429.">doi: 10.5301/JN.2011.8429.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Levin A, Le Barbier M, Er L, Andress D, Sigrist MK, Djurdjev O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BC Provincial Renal Agency, Vancouver, British Columbia - Canada and Division of Nephrology, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, British Columbia - Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Vitamin D deficiencies are well described in general populations and in those with chronic kidney disease (CKD). Although serum 25(OH)D may be a good indicator of vitamin D status in healthy individuals, &lt;strong>the hydroxylated product, 1,25(OH)2D,&lt;/strong> essential for important biological functions such as mineral metabolism, bone turnover, regulation of protein synthesis, cell differentiation and proliferation may be a more suitable indicator for individuals with CKD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cyclosporine etc. probably increase the need for vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cyclosporine-etc-probably-increase-the-need-for-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyclosporine-etc-probably-increase-the-need-for-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="effects-of-cyclosporine-tacrolimus-and-rapamycin-on-renal-calcium-transport-and-vitamin-d-metabolism">Effects of Cyclosporine, Tacrolimus and Rapamycin on Renal Calcium Transport and Vitamin D Metabolism.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Nephrol. 2011 Jun 20;34(1):87-94.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee CT, Ng HY, Lien YH, Lai LW, Wu MS, Lin CR, Chen HC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, Chang-Gung Memorial Hospital, Kaohsiung Medical Center, Chang-Gung University College of Medicine, Gueishan, Taiwan, ROC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Abnormalities in mineral metabolism are common complications of organ transplantation. The role of immunosuppressive agents in alteration of mineral metabolism is not clear.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Each 10 ng increase in vitamin D decreased kidney disease death by 14 percent</title><link>/posts/each-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-disease-death-by-14-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/each-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-disease-death-by-14-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-and-mortality-risk-in-ckd-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Vitamin D Status and Mortality Risk in CKD: A Meta-analysis of Prospective Studies.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Kidney Dis. 2011 May 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pilz S, Iodice S, Zittermann A, Grant WB, Gandini S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria; Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics and EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency, assessed as low 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) level, is highly prevalent in patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) and is associated with various adverse health outcomes. Whether low 25(OH)D levels in patients with CKD are an independent risk factor for mortality remains to be studied in detail, and this was the objective of our work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kids with new kidneys were both short and low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/kids-with-new-kidneys-were-both-short-and-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kids-with-new-kidneys-were-both-short-and-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-short-stature-and-may-influence-blood-pressure-control-in-paediatric-renal-transplant-recipients">Vitamin D deficiency is associated with short stature and may influence blood pressure control in paediatric renal transplant recipients.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pediatr Nephrol. 2011 Jun 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shroff R, Knott C, Gullett A, Wells D, Marks SD, Rees L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renal Unit, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children NHS Trust and Institute of Child Health London, London, WC1N 3JH, UK, &lt;a href="mailto:ShrofR@gosh.nhs.uk">ShrofR@gosh.nhs.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is common in adult renal transplant recipients, but data in children are scarce. Vitamin D is shown to have multiple effects on the cardiovascular system, renal function, and maintenance of bone health. We hypothesized that 25(OH)D deficiency is common in pediatric renal transplant recipients, and may be associated with hyperparathyroidism, short stature, renal function, and blood pressure control.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dialysis patients with higher levels of vitamin D were better</title><link>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-were-better.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-were-better.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-is-inversely-associated-with-serum-mmp-9-in-a-cross-sectional-study-of-african-american-esrd-patients">25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration is Inversely Associated with Serum MMP-9 in a cross-sectional study of African American ESRD Patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Nephrol. 2011 May 22;12(1):24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wasse H, Cardarelli F, De Staercke C, Hooper C, Veledar E, Guessous I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentration is inversely associated with peripheral arterial disease and hypertension. Vascular remodeling may play a role in this association, however, data relating vitamin D level to specific remodeling biomarkers among ESRD patients is sparse. We tested whether 25(OH)D concentration is associated with markers of vascular remodeling and inflammation in African American ESRD patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic kidney disease and PTH – Calcium – Phosphate – Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-pth-calcium-phosphate-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-pth-calcium-phosphate-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mineral-metabolism-and-vitamin-d-in-chronic-kidney-disease-more-questions-than-answers">Mineral metabolism and vitamin D in chronic kidney disease-more questions than answers.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Nephrol. 2011 May 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goldsmith DJ, Cunningham J; Medscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renal and Transplantation Department, 6th Floor, Borough Wing, Guy&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Great Maze Pond, London SE1 9RT, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) are at increased risk of total and cardiovascular morbidity and mortality. The underlying pathophysiology of this association remains largely unexplained and there is currently no clear interventional pathway. Emphasis has been placed on measuring serum levels of calcium, phosphate and parathyroid hormone (PTH) to monitor disease progression, driven by the assumption that achieving values within the &amp;rsquo;normal&amp;rsquo; range will translate into improved outcomes. Retrospective studies have provided a body of evidence that abnormal levels of mineral biomarkers, and phosphate in particular, are associated with clinical events. Disturbances in vitamin D metabolism are also likely to contribute to the pathophysiology of CKD. Designing studies that yield useful information has proved to be difficult, partly owing to conceptual and financial limitations, but also because of the tight interdependency of calcium, phosphate and PTH, and the potential impact of vitamin D on these mineral metabolites.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dialysis patients with less than 15 ng of vitamin D did not feel well</title><link>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d-did-not-feel-well.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d-did-not-feel-well.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Heart problems 5X worse for chronic kidney patients low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/heart-problems-5x-worse-for-chronic-kidney-patients-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-problems-5x-worse-for-chronic-kidney-patients-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wearable dialysis device being tested which also converts vitamin D</title><link>/posts/wearable-dialysis-device-being-tested-which-also-converts-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wearable-dialysis-device-being-tested-which-also-converts-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="being-developed-march-2011">Being Developed March 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="perhaps-1000--large-scale-trials-2011-2014-worn-like-a-belt">Perhaps $1000, large scale trials 2011-2014, worn like a belt&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="click-herehttptimesofindiaindiatimescomcitydelhidialysis-device-that-can-be-carried-aroundarticleshow7622329cms">&lt;a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/Dialysis-device-that-can-be-carried-around/articleshow/7622329.cms">CLICK HERE&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-of-vitamin-d-and-kidney" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 813">Overview of Vitamin D and Kidney&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Dialysis patients with low vitamin D were 2.7 X more likely to die of heart problems</title><link>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-were-27-x-more-likely-to-die-of-heart-problems.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dialysis-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-were-27-x-more-likely-to-die-of-heart-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-clinical-outcomes-in-incident-dialysis-patients-results-from-the-necosad-study">Vitamin D status and clinical outcomes in incident dialysis patients: results from the NECOSAD study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation, Volume26, Issue3, Pp. 1024-1032.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background. The majority of dialysis patients suffer from vitamin D deficiency, which might contribute to an adverse health outcome. We aimed to elucidate whether European dialysis patients with low 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels are at increased risk of mortality and specific fatal events.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods. This was a prospective cohort study of incident dialysis patients in the Netherlands (the NECOSAD). We selected all patients with measured 25(OH)D at 12 months after the start of dialysis, the baseline for our study. By Cox regression analyses, we assessed the impact of 25(OH)D levels on short-term (6 months of follow-up) as well as longer-term mortality (3 years of follow-up). Associations of 25(OH)D levels with cardiovascular and non-cardiovascular mortality were also determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney failure and vitamin D deficiency vicious cycle</title><link>/posts/kidney-failure-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-vicious-cycle.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-failure-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-vicious-cycle.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="defective-renal-maintenance-of-the-vitamin-d-endocrine-system-impairs-vitamin-d-renoprotection-a-downward-spiral-in-kidney-disease">Defective renal maintenance of the vitamin D endocrine system impairs vitamin D renoprotection: a downward spiral in kidney disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Kidney Int. 2011 Jan 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dusso AS, &lt;a href="mailto:adusso@im.wustl.edu">adusso@im.wustl.edu&lt;/a>; Tokumoto M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1] Renal Division, Department of Internal Medicine, Washington University School of Medicine, St Louis, Missouri, USA &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup> Experimental Nephrology Laboratory, IRB Lleida, Lleida, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In kidney disease, the progressive loss of renal capacity to produce calcitriol, the vitamin D hormone, is a key contributor to elevations in parathyroid hormone (PTH) and mineral and skeletal disorders predisposing to renal and cardiovascular damage, ectopic calcifications, and high mortality rates. Thus, the safe correction of calcitriol deficiency to suppress PTH has been the treatment of choice for decades. However, recent epidemiological and experimental data suggest that calcitriol replacement may improve outcomes through renal and cardioprotective actions unrelated to PTH suppression. Furthermore, a striking incidence of vitamin D deficiency occurs in kidney disease and associates more strongly than calcitriol deficiency with a higher risk for kidney disease progression and death. Despite the translational relevance of these findings, no prospective trials are currently available in support of the efficacy of vitamin D supplementation and/or calcitriol replacement to safely halt/moderate renal disease progression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease meta-analysis of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-chronic-kidney-disease-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-observational-studies-and-randomized-controlled-trials">Vitamin D Supplementation in Chronic Kidney Disease: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Observational Studies and Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>CJASN January 2011 vol. 6 no. 1 50-62 , published by American Society of Nephrology&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Praveen Kandula,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Mirela Dobre,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Jesse D. Schold,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Martin J. Schreiber ,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rajnish Mehrotra,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sankar D. Navaneethan&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Author Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> *Department of Nephrology, Indiana University, Indianapolis, Indiana;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Department of Internal Medicine, Huron Hospital, Cleveland, Ohio;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Department of Nephrology, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Department of Nephrology and Hypertension, Glickman Urological and Kidney Institute, and
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Quantitative Health Sciences, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Los Angeles Biomedical Research Institute at Harbor–University of California–Los Angeles Medical Center, Torrance, California; and
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> David Geffen School of Medicine at University of California–Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Correspondence:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney and Vitamin D – Heaney</title><link>/posts/kidney-and-vitamin-d-heaney.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-and-vitamin-d-heaney.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-the-iceberg-nutrient">Vitamin D: The Iceberg Nutrient.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Ren Nutr. 2011 Jan 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Armas LA, Heaney RP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creighton University Osteoporosis Research Center, Omaha, Nebraska.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The understanding of vitamin D&amp;rsquo;s role in human health has recently expanded. It is now recognized as more than a hormone activated in the kidney only for calcium homeostasis. It is metabolized and used by virtually every cell in the body. Patients with chronic kidney disease have a deficit in their kidney production of 1,25(OH)(2)D and have classically been treated with calcitriol or its active analogues. Despite often having lower systemic levels of 1,25(OH)(2)D, patients with chronic kidney disease retain the capability of extra renal production of 1,25(OH)(2)D. This has far reaching implications for their health. This review examines clinical trials and observations in 3 areas that impact chronic kidney disease patients. Cancer, cardiovascular disease and infections are responsible for much of the morbidity and mortality in this patient population. We will discuss vitamin D&amp;rsquo;s role in these disease states with a focus on the chronic kidney disease patient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney disease and vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-biology-from-the-discovery-to-its-significance-in-chronic-kidney-disease">Vitamin d biology: from the discovery to its significance in chronic kidney disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Ren Nutr. 2011 Jan;21(1):113-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cuppari L, Garcia Lopes MG, Kamimura MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology, Federal University of São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D was discovered and had its chemical structure described in the early years of the last century. Although classified as a nutrient because it was found in small quantities in butter, it soon became clear that exposure of skin to sunlight, supplies most of the vitamin D necessary for good health in human beings. Vitamin D (D3 or cholecalciferol) synthesis in the skin is extremely rapid and remarkably robust despite the complexity of the mechanisms involved. However, a number of factors related to latitude location, season, and skin characteristics can interfere with the photoproduction of vitamin D. The 2 forms of vitamin D (D3 or D2-ergocalciferol) are biologically inactive and require activation in the liver and kidney. The product of the first hydroxylation of vitamin D in the liver, 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D), is the marker of vitamin D status. Hypovitaminosis D (serum 25(OH)D, &amp;lt;30 ng/mL) is highly prevalent in the general population, and patients with chronic kidney disease seem to be at higher risk for the development of hypovitaminosis D. It is believed that, besides the traditional factors, protein losses, gastrointestinal malabsorption, and &lt;strong>defective skin synthesis&lt;/strong> of vitamin D might contribute to the elevated number of patients with suboptimal level of vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D helps organ transplant - many studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-organ-transplant-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-organ-transplant-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary-of-many-studies-of-vitamin-d-and-organ-transplantation">Summary of many studies of Vitamin D and organ transplantation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-in-organ-transplantation---2011">Vitamin D in organ transplantation - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#survive-heart-transplant-better-if-have-more-vitamin-d">Survive heart transplant better if have more vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#immune-system-is-often-supressed-so-that-a-new-organ-can-be-accepted-by-the-body">Immune system is often supressed so that a new organ can be accepted by the body&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="summary-of-many-studies-of-vitamin-d-and-organ-transplantation">Summary of many studies of Vitamin D and organ transplantation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>More vitamin D needed especially needed if organ = liver or kidney (low vitamin d ==&amp;gt; poor bones)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Even with vitamin D supplementation Kidney transplant patients were deficient</title><link>/posts/even-with-vitamin-d-supplementation-kidney-transplant-patients-were-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/even-with-vitamin-d-supplementation-kidney-transplant-patients-were-deficient.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Editorial on Vitamin D deficiency– Current Drug topics</title><link>/posts/editorial-on-vitamin-d-deficiency-current-drug-topics.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/editorial-on-vitamin-d-deficiency-current-drug-topics.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="editorial-hot-topic-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-cardiovascular-and-renal-disease">Editorial: Hot topic: Vitamin D Deficiency in Cardiovascular and Renal Disease:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="new-light-shed-on-an-old-enemy-guest-editor-martin-h-de-borst">New Light Shed on an Old Enemy (Guest Editor: Martin H. de Borst)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Current Drug Targets, Volume 12, Number 1, January 2011 , pp. 1-3(3)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fat-soluble secosteroid hormone vitamin D is best known for its role in bone metabolism. From a historical perspective, the study of vitamin D deficiency has been intimately related to the study of (possible treatment of) rickets. Although diseases characterized by bone deformations have been described in ancient medical writings from the 1st and 2nd centuries, it was Galen who described the classic bone deformities noted in rickets &lt;sup>[1, 2]&lt;/sup>. More clear descriptions originate from the 17th century, reporting rickets to be endemic in England &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. In the early 20th century, observations that artificial UV light or sunlight provides protection against rickets coincided with results suggesting that rickets may be the consequence of a nutritional deficiency &lt;sup>[3, 4]&lt;/sup>. The responsible vitamin was identified by McCollum et al., who stated in their paper in the Journal of Biological Chemistry in 1922: “These experiments clearly demonstrate the existence of a fourth vitamin whose specific property, as far as we can tell at present, is to regulate the metabolism of the bones” &lt;sup>[5]&lt;/sup>. This “fourth vitamin” was named vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Vitamin D decreased kidney deaths by 4x</title><link>/posts/adding-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-deaths-by-4x.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adding-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-deaths-by-4x.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>End stage kidney disease almost 3X more likely for blacks – 2009</title><link>/posts/end-stage-kidney-disease-almost-3x-more-likely-for-blacks-2009.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/end-stage-kidney-disease-almost-3x-more-likely-for-blacks-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-race-and-the-progression-of-kidney-disease">25-hydroxyvitamin D levels, race, and the progression of kidney disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Am Soc Nephrol. 2009 Dec;20(12):2631-9. Epub 2009 Oct 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Melamed ML, Astor B, Michos ED, Hostetter TH, Powe NR, Muntner P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Albert Einstein College of Medicine, 1300 Morris Park Avenue, Bronx, NY 10461, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:mmelamed@aecom.yu.edu">mmelamed@aecom.yu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Black individuals have lower 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and experience a disproportionate burden of ESRD compared with white individuals. Animal studies suggest that vitamin D has renoprotective effects. We evaluated the contribution of low 25(OH)D levels on incidence of ESRD using data from the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey-linked Medicare claims files (n = 13,328). We included baseline (1988 through 1994) measurements of 25(OH)D and assessed the incidence of ESRD through July 31, 2001.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>