<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kidney on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/kidney/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kidney on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/kidney/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The potential role of vitamin D binding protein in kidney disease: a comprehensive review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-potential-role-of-vitamin-d-binding-protein-in-kidney-disease-a-comprehensive-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-potential-role-of-vitamin-d-binding-protein-in-kidney-disease-a-comprehensive-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;jan-2024-study&#34;&gt;Jan 2024 study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;International Journal of Clinical and Laboratory Medicine &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/17843286.2023.2301278&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/17843286.2023.2301278&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Joris R. Delanghe,Charlotte Delrue,Reinhart Speeckaert &amp;amp;Marijn M. Speeckaert ORCID&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is a growing health concern with a complex etiological landscape. Among the numerous factors implicated, vitamin D binding protein (VDBP) has emerged as a focal point of scientific studies because of its critical role in vitamin D metabolism and immune modulation. The relationship between VDBP and CKD reveals a complex web of molecular and biochemical details that have great potential for improving diagnostic understanding and treatment strategies for CKD. This review summarizes the multifaceted roles of VDBP, including its molecular dynamics, interactions with vitamin D, and subsequent implications for kidney function.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Kidney not helped much by little vitamin D (none got to a 75 nmol level) – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-kidney-not-helped-much-by-little-vitamin-d-none-got-to-a-75-nmol-level-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-kidney-not-helped-much-by-little-vitamin-d-none-got-to-a-75-nmol-level-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-regulated-vitamin-d-increase-on-vascular-markers-in-patients-with-chronic-kidney-disease-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials&#34;&gt;Effect of regulated vitamin D increase on vascular markers in patients with chronic kidney disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrition, Metabolism &amp;amp; Cardiovascular Diseases, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.numecd.2023.09.015&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.numecd.2023.09.015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aim&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The effect of increased vitamin D levels on vascular function in patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) is controversial. This meta-analysis aimed to assess the effect of regulated vitamin D increase on vascular markers in patients with CKD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Kidney disease 15 X more likely if Vitamin D deficient (Chinese males)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-15-x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficient-chinese-males/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-15-x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficient-chinese-males/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;sex-differences-in-the-association-between-vitamin-d-and-early-stage-chronic-kidney-disease-a-population-based-study&#34;&gt;Sex differences in the association between vitamin D and early-stage chronic kidney disease: A population-based study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrition Research Volume 117, September 2023, Pages 48-55 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nutres.2023.05.004&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nutres.2023.05.004&lt;/a&gt; PDF behind Paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ting-An Yang a b, Jau-Yuan Chen a c, Chieh-An Lin a, Yi-Chuan Chen a c, Wei Yu d, Hsiung Ying Huang e, Xue-Jie Xiong f, Wen-Cheng Li a c d&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D deficiency (VDD) is commonly observed in people with late-stage chronic kidney disease (CKD) and end-stage renal disease; it has also been associated with the progression of kidney disease. We hypothesized that VDD played a role in early-stage chronic kidney disease as well. Thus, this cross-sectional study aimed to evaluate the association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration and CKD stages 1 through 3 (early-stage CKD) in a relatively healthy population in China. A total of 3142 Chinese individuals were included in this cross-sectional study. VDD was observed in 108  &lt;strong&gt;(5.6%) males&lt;/strong&gt;  and 307  &lt;strong&gt;(25.33%) females&lt;/strong&gt; . We found a significant inverse association between serum 25(OH)D concentration with CKD stages in both sexes. Furthermore, VDD was associated with CKD stages 1 through 3 in males (adjusted odds ratio,  &lt;strong&gt;15.84&lt;/strong&gt; ; 95% confidence interval, 7.85-31.98; P &amp;lt; .001), but not in females. Vitamin D status should be evaluated in people who are newly diagnosed with CKD stages 1 through 3 or decreased estimated glomerular filtration rate, especially in males.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Kidney Disease needs Vitamin D: how much, what kind - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-needs-vitamin-d-how-much-what-kind-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-needs-vitamin-d-how-much-what-kind-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-decreases-vitamin-d-in-4-ways-nov-2017chronic-kidney-dise-level-in-4-ways&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Chronic Kidney Disease decreases Vitamin D in 4 ways – Nov 2017|Chronic Kidney Disease decreases Vitamin D level in 4 ways&#34;&gt;Chronic Kidney Disease decreases Vitamin D in 4 ways – Nov 2017|Chronic Kidney Disease decreases Vitamin D level in 4 ways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/4x-more-chronic-kidney-disease-patients-are-now-using-vitamin-d&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: 4X more Chronic Kidney disease patients are now using vitamin D – March 2014&#34;&gt;4X more Chronic Kidney disease patients are now using vitamin D – March 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All children with Chronic Kidney Disease had low Vitamin D (Pakistan hospital)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-children-with-chronic-kidney-disease-had-low-vitamin-d-pakistan-hospital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-children-with-chronic-kidney-disease-had-low-vitamin-d-pakistan-hospital/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;25-hydroxyvitamin-d-deficiency-in-chronic-kidney-disease-stages-iii-iv-and-v-in-south-asian-population-a-retrospective-cohort&#34;&gt;25-Hydroxyvitamin-D deficiency in chronic kidney disease stages III, IV, and V in South Asian population: a retrospective cohort&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SAGE Open Med  2023 Jan 19;11:20503121221148613. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/20503121221148613&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1177/20503121221148613&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muhammad Raheel Abdul Razzaque 1, Sameer Saleem Tebha 2, Alaa Tukruna 3, Aabiya Arif 4, Lucas Marian Kogut 5, Nasir Ali Afsar 6, Dania Shabbir 7, Zain Ali Zaidi 8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objective: Vitamin D deficiency in Chronic Kidney Disease is a known fact, but the data regarding the prevalence and extent of vitamin D deficiency in different stages of Chronic Kidney Disease is scarce. This leads to a delay in addressing this issue. We conducted this study to assess vitamin-D deficiency in different stages of Chronic Kidney Disease to improve the evidence available to Physicians and Nephrologists which can help them better address this common finding in Chronic Kidney Disease.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fracture 4X less likely following kidney transplant if high-dose Vitamin D (100,000 every 2 weeks) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fracture-4x-less-likely-following-kidney-transplant-if-high-dose-vitamin-d-100000-every-2-weeks-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fracture-4x-less-likely-following-kidney-transplant-if-high-dose-vitamin-d-100000-every-2-weeks-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;nonskeletal-and-skeletal-effects-of-high-doses-versus-low-doses-of-vitamin-d3-in-renal-transplant-recipients-results-of-the-vitale-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-renal-transplant-recipients-study-a-randomized-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;Nonskeletal and skeletal effects of high doses versus low doses of vitamin D3 in renal transplant recipients: Results of the VITALE (VITamin D supplementation in renAL transplant recipients) study, a randomized clinical trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Am J Transplant . 2023 Jan 9;S1600-6135(22)29286-7. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajt.2022.12.007&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.ajt.2022.12.007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Marie Courbebaisse 1, Aurelie Bourmaud 2, Jean-Claude Souberbielle 3, Rebecca Sberro-Soussan 4, Valérie Moal 5, Yannick Le Meur 6, Nassim Kamar 7, Laetitia Albano 8, Antoine Thierry 9, Jacques Dantal 10, Clément Danthu 11, Karine Moreau 12, Emmanuel Morelon 13, Anne-Elisabeth Heng 14, Dominique Bertrand 15, Nadia Arzouk 16, Peggy Perrin 17, Marie-Pascale Morin 18, Philippe Rieu 19, Claire Presne 20, Philippe Grimbert 21, Didier Ducloux 22, Matthias Büchler 23, Moglie Le Quintrec 24, Nacéra Ouali 25, Vincent Pernin 26, Nicolas Bouvier 27, Antoine Durrbach 28, Eric Alamartine 29, Christine Randoux 30, Virginie Besson 31, Marc Hazzan 32, Justine Pages 33, Sandra Colas 34, Marie-Liesse Piketty 3, Gérard Friedlander 35, Dominique Prié 36, Corinne Alberti 2, Eric Thervet 37&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hemodialysis and Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hemodialysis-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hemodialysis-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;hemodialysis-patients-reduced-dementia-chance-by-60-if-take-40000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly--aug-2023&#34;&gt;Hemodialysis patients reduced dementia chance by 60% if take 40,000 IU of vitamin D weekly – Aug 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Protective Effect of Vitamin D on Dementia Risk in Hemodialysis Patients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Life 2023, 13(8), 1741; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/life13081741&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/life13081741&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Chih-Lang Lin 1,2,3,†,Wan-Ming Chen 4,5,†,An-Tzu Jao 6,Ben-Chang Shia 4,5ORCID andSzu-Yuan Wu 4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,*ORCID&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simple Summary&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study investigated the effect of vitamin D supplementation on the risk of dementia in patients with end-stage renal disease on hemodialysis, which is a novel contribution to the literature. To our knowledge, this is the first study to examine the relationship between vitamin D supplementation and the risk of dementia in this patient population. The use of a 1:1 propensity score-matched cohort design adds robustness and reliability to the study findings. The results demonstrated that vitamin D supplementation at doses of ≥70 μg/week significantly reduced the risk of dementia in a dose-dependent manner, regardless of age. These findings add new and important information to the existing literature on the relationship between vitamin D and cognitive health in ESRD patients on hemodialysis, and suggest that vitamin D supplementation may be an effective preventive strategy for cognitive impairment in this vulnerable patient population.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
