<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Forms on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/forms.html</link><description>Recent content in Forms on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/forms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Standard oral vitamin D is not a good way to supplement if have Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/standard-oral-vitamin-d-is-not-a-good-way-to-supplement-if-have-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/standard-oral-vitamin-d-is-not-a-good-way-to-supplement-if-have-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lung cells activate Vitamin D, without liver or kidney</title><link>/posts/lung-cells-activate-vitamin-d-without-liver-or-kidney.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lung-cells-activate-vitamin-d-without-liver-or-kidney.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calcifediol-loaded-liposomes-for-local-treatment-of-pulmonary-bacterial-infections">Calcifediol-loaded liposomes for local treatment of pulmonary bacterial infections&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Pharmaceutics and Biopharmaceutics, online 22 Nov 2016 &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ejpb.2016.11.026">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ejpb.2016.11.026&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arianna Castoldi a, Christian Herr b, Julia Niederstraßer b, Hagar Ibrahim Labouta a, c, d, Ana Melero a, e, Sarah Gordon a, Nicole Schneider-Dauma , Robert Bals b, Claus-Michael Lehr a, f, &lt;a href="mailto:Claus-Michael.Lehr@helmholtz-hzi.de">Claus-Michael.Lehr@helmholtz-hzi.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Helmholtz-Institute for Pharmaceutical Research Saarland (HIPS), Helmholtz-Institute for Infection Research (HZI), Saarbrücken, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Internal Medicine V – Pulmonology, Allergology, Critical Care Medicine, Saarland University, Homburg, Germany&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D injection lasts longer and has bigger response than weekly oral</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-injection-lasts-longer-and-has-bigger-response-than-weekly-oral.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-injection-lasts-longer-and-has-bigger-response-than-weekly-oral.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Inhaled vitamin D help lungs - many studies</title><link>/posts/inhaled-vitamin-d-help-lungs-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inhaled-vitamin-d-help-lungs-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Inhaled Vitamin D has treated my breathing problems from pollen, forest fire smoke, mold, dust, and my exercise-induced asthma for 8 years now.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It might also help with other breathing problems proven to be helped by oral Vitamin D:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/pneumonia-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Pneumonia and low vitamin D - many studies">pneumonia&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="/posts/respiratory-infection-children-and-vitamin-d-many-studies" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Respiratory infection, children and Vitamin D - many studies">RTI&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="/posts/cystic-fibrosis-hay-fever-allergic-rhinitis-and-vitamin-d-many-studies" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Cystic Fibrosis)), ((Hay fever (Allergic Rhinitis) and Vitamin D - many studies">Hay Fever&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="/posts/recurrent-wheezing-in-children-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-several-studies" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Recurrent Wheezing in children is associated with low Vitamin D – several studies">Wheezing&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="/posts/overview-tuberculosis-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Tuberculosis and Vitamin D">TB&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="/posts/overview-colds-and-flu-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Colds and flu and Vitamin D">Respiratory Virus&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="/posts/copd-fought-by-vitamin-d-many-studies">COPD&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D – water-soluble is far more absorbable than fat-soluble</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-water-soluble-is-far-more-absorbable-than-fat-soluble.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-water-soluble-is-far-more-absorbable-than-fat-soluble.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="efficacy-of-micellized-vs-fat-soluble-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-healthy-school-children-from-northern-india">Efficacy of micellized vs. fat-soluble vitamin D3 supplementation in healthy school children from Northern India.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab. 2016 Nov 16. pii: /j/jpem.ahead-of-print/jpem-2016-0191/jpem-2016-0191.xml. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2016-0191.">doi: 10.1515/jpem-2016-0191.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marwaha RK, Yenamandra VK, Ganie MA, Sethuraman G, Sreenivas V, Ramakrishnan L, Mathur SK, Sharma VK, Mithal A.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>| | | |
| &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; |
| 60,000 IU Vitamin D &lt;br>monthly for 6 months | Increased &lt;br>     by | Became &lt;br>sufficient |
| Water-soluble in water | 32 ng | 100% |
| Fat-soluble in 4% milk | 24 ng | 83% |&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inhaled vitamin D helped lungs of new-born (rats)</title><link>/posts/inhaled-vitamin-d-helped-lungs-of-new-born-rats.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inhaled-vitamin-d-helped-lungs-of-new-born-rats.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="inhaled-vitamin-d-a-novel-strategy-to-enhance-neonatal-lung-maturation">Inhaled Vitamin D: A Novel Strategy to Enhance Neonatal Lung Maturation.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Lung. 2016 Dec;194(6):931-943. Epub 2016 Sep 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Taylor SK1, Sakurai R1, Sakurai T1, Rehan VK2.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I had wondered if inhaled Vit. D would help some &lt;a href="/categories/breathing">breathing&lt;/a> problems&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Examples: Asthma, pneumonia, RTI, COPD, &lt;a href="/posts/tuberculosis" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Tuberculosis ">Tuberculosis &lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Being able to apply any treatment locally is typically better than treating the entire body&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Topical vitamin D can be applied topically to skin problems, for example&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some olive oils decrease vitamin D absorption by 25 percent</title><link>/posts/some-olive-oils-decrease-vitamin-d-absorption-by-25-percent.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-olive-oils-decrease-vitamin-d-absorption-by-25-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pinoresinol-of-olive-oil-decreases-vitamin-d-intestinal-absorption">Pinoresinol of olive oil decreases vitamin D intestinal absorption&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Food Chemistry doi:10.1016/j.foodchem.2016.03.048&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aurélie Goncalvesa, b, c, Marielle Margiera, b, c, Camille Tagliaferrid, Patrice Lebecqued, Stéphane Georgée, Yohann Wittrantd, Véronique Coxamd, Marie-Josèphe Amiota, b, c, Emmanuelle Reboula, b, c, &lt;a href="mailto:Emmanuelle.Reboul@univ-amu.fr">Emmanuelle.Reboul@univ-amu.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>There had been many indications that some Vitamin D supplements using olive oil were not as as good as supplements. This may be the reason why – some have more Pinoresinol. Not all olive oil is the same. Until we find out otherwise, I would suggest not supplementing with Vitamin D which is in olive oil,&lt;/strong> I think that I will also avoid having vitamin D supplements with olive oil salads&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D sprayed inside cheeks (buccal spray) - several studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-sprayed-inside-cheeks-buccal-spray-several-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-sprayed-inside-cheeks-buccal-spray-several-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Buccal and sublingual gets vitamin D into the body about day faster then oral&lt;br>
   and gets MORE vitamin D into the blood for those with poor guts&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d3-buccal-spray-review-of-rcts-not-help-much---march-2020">Vitamin D3 Buccal Spray review of RCTs (not help much) - March 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#rct-buccal-spray-for-poor-gut---oct-2015">RCT buccal spray for poor gut - Oct 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#new-buccal-spray-review-proposed-dec-2018">New buccal spray review proposed Dec 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-sprays-and-alternatives">Vitamin D sprays and alternatives&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see--also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-buccal-spray-review-of-rcts-not-help-much---march-2020">Vitamin D3 Buccal Spray review of RCTs (not help much) - March 2020&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Efficacy of Vitamin D3 Buccal Spray Supplementation Compared to Other Delivery Methods: A Systematic Review of Superiority Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Topical vitamin D might be more bio-available than oral</title><link>/posts/topical-vitamin-d-might-be-more-bio-available-than-oral.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/topical-vitamin-d-might-be-more-bio-available-than-oral.html</guid><description>&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>Yet another group feels that topical vitamin D is better than oral&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both of their references are on VitaminDWiki&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is not the current consensus opinion, but may be correct&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/topical-vitamin-d">Topical Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/topical-vitamin-d-provides-more-benefits-than-oral-sometimes-many-studies" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Topical Vitamin D provides more benefits than oral sometimes - many studies">Topical Vitamin D provides more benefits than oral sometimes - many studies&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/Search+Results?hl=en&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search&amp;amp;googles.x=0&amp;amp;googles.y=0&amp;amp;q=topical&amp;amp;domains=VitaminDWiki.com&amp;amp;sitesearch=VitaminDWiki.com">Search VitaminDWiki for TOPICAL&lt;/a> 404 items as of Oct 2015&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nanoparticles could be used to increase vitamin D getting to the gut</title><link>/posts/nanoparticles-could-be-used-to-increase-vitamin-d-getting-to-the-gut.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nanoparticles-could-be-used-to-increase-vitamin-d-getting-to-the-gut.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="novel-starch-based-nanocarrier-for-vitamin-d-fortification-of-milk-production-and-characterization">Novel starch based nanocarrier for vitamin D fortification of milk: Production and characterization&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Food and Bioproducts Processing, Volume 96, October 2015, Pages 264–277, doi:10.1016/j.fbp.2015.09.007&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elham Hasanvanda, Milad Fathib, , , Alireza Bassiric, Majid Javanmarda, Rouzbeh Abbaszadeha&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Novel high amylose starch based nanoparticles were developed for entrapment of Vitamin D3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Release of encapsulant can be postponed in gastric media.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Vitamin loaded nanocarriers can be used to produce functional food.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pill taking is not a problem with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pill-taking-is-not-a-problem-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pill-taking-is-not-a-problem-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="some-vitamin-d-capsules-can-be-twisted-open-and-put-the-tastless-powder-on-food-in-drinks-or-directly-on-your-tongue">Some vitamin D capsules can be twisted open and put the tastless powder on food, in drinks, or directly on your tongue&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Example &lt;a href="http://www.biotechpharmacal.com/">Bio-Tech Pharmacal&lt;/a> tiny 5,000 IU and 50,000 IU capsules contain water-soluble powder&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="some-vitamin-d-is-available-as-liquid-spray-topical-injection-monthly-etc">Some vitamin D is available as liquid, spray, topical, injection (monthly), etc&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/low-cost-vitamin-d-including-liquid-and-bulk" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Low Cost vitamin D - including liquid and bulk">Low Cost vitamin D - including liquid and bulk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D in powder (Bio-Tech) better than in oil (Thesis with Cystic Fibrosis patients)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-in-powder-bio-tech-better-than-in-oil-thesis-with-cystic-fibrosis-patients.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-in-powder-bio-tech-better-than-in-oil-thesis-with-cystic-fibrosis-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vehicles-for-the-absorption-of-vitamin-d-in-cystic-fibrosis-comparison-of-powder-vs-oil">Vehicles for the Absorption of Vitamin D In Cystic Fibrosis: Comparison of Powder Vs. Oil&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Wendy A. Hermes, Georgia State University&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Date of Award Summer 7-2-2015, Degree Type Thesis, Degree Name Master of Science (MS), Department Nutrition&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Despite the high prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in cystic fibrosis (CF) populations, there is little consensus on the most efficacious vehicle substance for vitamin D supplements. Given the high prevalence of pancreatic insufficiency in CF, it is possible that resulting fat malabsorption may impede the ability of patients with CF to absorb vitamin D in an oil vehicle. Further investigation is needed to determine the optimal vehicle substance for use in vitamin D supplements. The objective of this pilot study was to compare the absorption of vitamin D3 and to evaluate the rise in serum cholecalciferol (D3) concentrations in response to vitamin D supplements contained in power or oil vehicles. We hypothesized that vitamin D contained in a powder vehicle would be absorbed more efficiently than vitamin D contained in an oil vehicle in patients with CF.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Transdermal vitamin D aided by dodecylamine with pretreatment by ethanol</title><link>/posts/transdermal-vitamin-d-aided-by-dodecylamine-with-pretreatment-by-ethanol.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/transdermal-vitamin-d-aided-by-dodecylamine-with-pretreatment-by-ethanol.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="investigating-transdermal-delivery-of-vitamin-d3">Investigating Transdermal Delivery of Vitamin D3.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>AAPS PharmSciTech. 2015 Jan 22. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alsaqr A1, Rasoully M, Musteata FM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Transdermal delivery of therapeutic amounts of vitamin D3 is proposed to overcome its variable oral bioavailability, especially for people who suffer from fat malabsorption. The main challenge for this delivery route is to overcome the barrier properties of skin, especially for very lipophilic compounds such as vitamin D3. In this study, the effect of different penetration enhancers, such as oleic acid, dodecylamine, ethanol, oleic acid in propylene glycol, isopropyl myristate, octyldodecanol, and oleyl alcohol in propylene glycol were evaluated in vitro for their effectiveness in delivering vitamin D3 through polyamide filter, polydimethylsiloxane membrane, and porcine skin. A diffusion cell was used to study the transdermal permeability of vitamin D3. Ointment formulations of vitamin D3 were prepared containing the most widely used penetration enhancers, oleic acid, and dodecylamine. The ointment containing oleic acid as chemical penetration enhancer did not improve delivery compared to control. On the other hand, the formulation containing dodecylamine as a penetration enhancer did improve the transdermal delivery of vitamin D3. However, statistical significance and an amount high enough for nutritional supplementation purposes were reached only when the skin was pretreated with 50% ethanol. In these conditions, the ointment delivered an amount of 760-ng vitamin D3 per cm2 of skin. The research shows promise that transdermal delivery could be an effective administration route for vitamin D3 when ethanol and dodecylamine are used as penetration enhancers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D bioavailability: State of the art</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-bioavailability-state-of-the-art.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-bioavailability-state-of-the-art.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2013 Oct 2. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Borel P 1, Caillaud D, Cano NJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1a INSERM, UMR1062, Nutrition, Obesity and Risk of Thrombosis , F-13385 , Marseille , France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been renewed interest in vitamin D since numerous recent studies have suggested that besides its well-established roles in bone metabolism and immunity, vitamin D status is inversely associated with the incidence of several diseases, e.g. cancers, cardio-vascular diseases and neurodegenerative diseases. Surprisingly, there is very little data on factors that affect absorption of this fat-soluble vitamin, although it is acknowledged that dietary vitamin D could help to fight against the sub-deficient vitamin D status that is common in several populations. This review describes the state of the art concerning the fate of vitamin D in the human upper gastrointestinal tract and on the factors assumed to affect its absorption efficiency. The main conclusions are:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>800 IU vitamin D in capsule form (but not drops) helped nursing home residents</title><link>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-in-capsule-form-but-not-drops-helped-nursing-home-residents.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-in-capsule-form-but-not-drops-helped-nursing-home-residents.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="efficacy-of-daily-800-iu-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-reaching-vitamin-d-sufficiency-in-nursing-home-residents-cross-sectional-patient-file-study">Efficacy of daily 800 IU vitamin D supplementation in reaching vitamin D sufficiency in nursing home residents: cross-sectional patient file study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Geriatr. 2014 Sep 19;14(1):103. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Veleva BI, Chel VG, Achterberg WP.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:>60%">
&lt;p>Nursing Home: Average age 82&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Capsule (powder or solid?): mean vitamin D = 36 ng, 0% &amp;lt; 12 ng&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drop : mean vitamin D = 16 ng, 32 % &amp;lt; 12 ng&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drop users were 35 X more likely to be insufficient at the end of the study&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Another country with poor Vitamin D quality control – New Zealand content varies from 8 to 200 percent</title><link>/posts/another-country-with-poor-vitamin-d-quality-control-new-zealand-content-varies-from-8-to-200-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/another-country-with-poor-vitamin-d-quality-control-new-zealand-content-varies-from-8-to-200-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="evaluation-of-vitamin-d-medicines-and-dietary-supplements-and-the-physicochemical-analysis-of-selected-formulations">Evaluation of vitamin D medicines and dietary supplements and the physicochemical analysis of selected formulations.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Nutr Health Aging. 2013 Feb;17(2):158-61. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s12603-012-0090-4.">doi: 10.1007/s12603-012-0090-4.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Garg S1, Sabri D, Kanji J, Rakkar PS, Lee Y, Naidoo N, Svirskis D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1School of Pharmacy, University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand. &lt;a href="mailto:sanjay.garg@unisa.edu.au">sanjay.garg@unisa.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CONTEXT:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is purported to offer wide ranging and numerous health benefits leading to increased interest from manufacturers of medicines and dietary supplements. Elderly patients frequently require vitamin D supplementation due to reduced sun exposure and dietary intake. There are ever increasing numbers of vitamin D formulations in the global market. However, due to a lack of regulatory restrictions for some of these products the quality of these dosage forms can be of some concern.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Infants do not tolerate some brands of Vitamin D – additives, color, etc</title><link>/posts/infants-do-not-tolerate-some-brands-of-vitamin-d-additives-color-etc.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/infants-do-not-tolerate-some-brands-of-vitamin-d-additives-color-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="di-vi-solhttpwwwamazoncomenfamil-d-vi-sol-vitamin-supplement-dropsproduct-reviewsb005zic55krefdpx_acr_txtshowviewpoints1-amazon">&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Enfamil-D-Vi-Sol-Vitamin-Supplement-Drops/product-reviews/B005ZIC55K/ref=dpx_acr_txt?showViewpoints=1">Di-Vi-Sol&lt;/a> Amazon&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>about half of the comments were negative (=1 star)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-baby-amazon-sorted-by-highest-recommendationhttpwwwamazoncomsrefnb_sb_nossurlsearch-alias3dhpcfield-keywords22vitamind22babyrhn3a37609012ck3a22vitamind22babyajr0">&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss?url=search-alias%3Dhpc&amp;amp;field-keywords=%22vitamin+d%22+baby&amp;amp;rh=n%3A3760901%2Ck%3A%22vitamin+d%22+baby&amp;amp;ajr=0">Vitamin D and baby Amazon sorted by highest recommendation&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>DDrops, VitaCost, Carlson get high recommendations and are tasteless.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="see-also---lots-of-vitamin-d-virtually-always-necessary-for-infant-health">See also - Lots of vitamin D virtually always necessary for infant health&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/third-study-found-that-infants-needed-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-jama-rct">Third study found that Infants needed 1600 IU of vitamin D – JAMA RCT May 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/fewer-pre-infants-were-vitamin-d-deficient-when-they-got-800-iu-rct">Fewer pre-infants were vitamin D deficient when they got 800 IU – RCT Feb 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Vitamin D into your blood and cells</title><link>/posts/getting-vitamin-d-into-your-blood-and-cells.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/getting-vitamin-d-into-your-blood-and-cells.html</guid><description>&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="550">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Summary by Claude Sonnet AI - Feb 2025&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This image shows a comprehensive flow chart explaining how Vitamin D is processed and utilized in the human body.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me break it down systematically:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The chart starts at the top by identifying the main sources and products of Vitamin D, which come through three primary pathways:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Direct absorption through sun exposure&lt;/strong> (UVB rays), topical application, or sublingual supplements that enter through the skin or mouth&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium intestinal absorption increased with active, but not tested level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/calcium-intestinal-absorption-increased-with-active-but-not-tested-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-intestinal-absorption-increased-with-active-but-not-tested-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-does-not-reflect-intestinal-calcium-absorption-an-assay-using-strontium-as-a-surrogate-marker">25-Hydroxyvitamin D level does not reflect intestinal calcium absorption: an assay using strontium as a surrogate marker.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Metab. 2014 May 24. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Camargo MB1, Vilaça T, Hayashi LF, Rocha OG, Lazaretti-Castro M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Endocrinology, School of Medicine, Federal University of São Paulo/UNIFESP, Avenida Nove de Julho, 5581, Apto. 30, Jardim Paulista, São Paulo, SP, CEP 01407-200, Brazil, &lt;a href="mailto:lilacamargo@uol.com.br">lilacamargo@uol.com.br&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is conflicting evidence as to the optimal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentration for intestinal calcium absorption (Abs-Ca). Our purpose was to assess the relationship between vitamin D status and Abs-Ca in postmenopausal women. Fifty volunteers with low bone mass were grouped according to their serum 25(OH)D concentration as follows: mild deficient, &amp;lt;50 nmol/L (DEF) and sufficient, ≥75 nmol/L (SUF). The subjects were submitted to an oral strontium overload test to assess their Abs-Ca. Fasting blood samples were obtained to perform the relevant hormonal and biochemical tests. After the subjects received the test solution, blood samples were drawn at 30, 60, 120, and 240 min to determine the strontium concentrations. Abs-Ca was indirectly expressed as the area under the serum strontium concentration curve (AUC). A repeated measures ANOVA was performed to determine the differences among the groups. Pearson&amp;rsquo;s correlation and multiple linear regression analysis were used to study the associations between the variables. The mean 25(OH)D and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[1,25(OH)2D]&lt;/span> concentrations differed between the groups (SUF vs. DEF) as follows: 98.7 ± 18.2 vs. 38.4 ± 8.5 nmol/L (p &amp;lt; 0.001) and 36.2 ± 10.2 vs. 24.9 ± 4.6 pg/mL (p &amp;lt; 0.001), respectively. There was no statistically significant difference between the groups for parathyroid hormone and AUC.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oil-based Vitamin D3 has the worst bioavailability</title><link>/posts/oil-based-vitamin-d3-has-the-worst-bioavailability.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/oil-based-vitamin-d3-has-the-worst-bioavailability.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Topical vitamin D raised blood level to 38 ng (used Aloe Vera gel) – RCT</title><link>/posts/topical-vitamin-d-raised-blood-level-to-38-ng-used-aloe-vera-gel-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/topical-vitamin-d-raised-blood-level-to-38-ng-used-aloe-vera-gel-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#topical-delivery-of-vitamin-d3-a-randomized-controlled-pilot-study---2014">Topical Delivery of Vitamin D3: A Randomized Controlled Pilot Study - 2014&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction">introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#methods">Methods&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#results">Results&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#discussion">discussion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#comment-by-vitamindwiki-neat">Comment by VitaminDWiki: Neat&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#topical-vitamin-d3-a-randomized-controlled-trial-rct---june-2018-same-authors">Topical vitamin D3: A randomized controlled trial (RCT) - June 2018 (same authors?)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#many-companies-sell-vitamin-d-creams---patent-expired">Many companies sell Vitamin D creams - patent expired?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="topical-delivery-of-vitamin-d3-a-randomized-controlled-pilot-study---2014">Topical Delivery of Vitamin D3: A Randomized Controlled Pilot Study - 2014&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>(Int J Biomed Sci 2014; 10 (1): 21-24)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mir Sadat-Ali &lt;a href="mailto:drsadat@hotmail.com">drsadat@hotmail.com&lt;/a>, Dalal A. Bubshait, Haifa A. Al-Turki, Dakheel A. Al-Dakheel, Wissam S. Al-Olayani&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D prices</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-prices.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-prices.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="leanituphttpwwwleanitupcomproducts-whats-vitamin-d-ultimate-vitamin-d-buyers-guide-24-top-products-uncappedutm_sourcerssutm_mediumrssutm_campaignproducts-whats-vitamin-d-ultimate-vitamin-d-buyers-guide-24-top-products-uncapped">&lt;a href="http://www.leanitup.com/products-whats-vitamin-d-ultimate-vitamin-d-buyers-guide-24-top-products-uncapped/?utm_source=rss&amp;amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;amp;utm_campaign=products-whats-vitamin-d-ultimate-vitamin-d-buyers-guide-24-top-products-uncapped">LeanItUp&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/buyers-guide-01.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/buyers-guide-02.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note: He is mainly reviewing 2000 IU D3 gel caps, not pills, liquid, emulsion, spray, bulk, sublingual, vaginal, D3 for vegans, etc.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>| | | |
| &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; |
| | &lt;a href="http://www.biotechpharmacal.com/catalog/d3-5-5000-iu/">Bio-Tech&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Bio-Tech-D3-50-000-100-caps/dp/B000A0F2B2/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1395889745&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=bio-tech+50%2C000">Bio-Tech&lt;/a> |
| Rating VitaminDWiki | * | * * |
| Total IU | 5,000 | 50,000 |
| Servings | 100 | 100 |
| Price | $7.30 | $20.40 (Amazon) |
| &lt;span style="color:#06F;">Cost/1,000 IU&lt;/span> | &lt;span style="color:#06F;">$0.015&lt;/span> | &lt;span style="color:#06F;">$.0041&lt;/span> |
| Cost per serving | $0.07 | $0.20 |&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Topical Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/topical-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/topical-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="off-label-uses-of-topical-vitamin-d-in-dermatology-a-systematic-review---2014">Off-label uses of topical vitamin d in dermatology: a systematic review - 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Cutan Med Surg. 2014 Mar 1;18(2):91-108.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wat H, Dytoc M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:Topical vitamin D is approved by the US Food and Drug Administration for the treatment of psoriasis but is also used off-label in the treatment of a variety of cutaneous diseases despite a lack of evidence-based guidelines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective:The objective of this study was to provide evidence-based clinical guidelines for the off-label use of topical vitamin D in the treatment of dermatologic disease.Methods:A systematic literature review was conducted via the MEDLINE, Embase, and CENTRAL databases for off-label uses of topical vitamin D analogues in the treatment of dermatologic disease other than psoriasis. The data were synthesized, and evidence-based recommendations were rendered according to the highest level of evidence available.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Forms of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/forms-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/forms-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vaginal Vitamin D reduced vaginal infections</title><link>/posts/vaginal-vitamin-d-reduced-vaginal-infections.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vaginal-vitamin-d-reduced-vaginal-infections.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D sachets in India – fewer than a third had the stated amount</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-sachets-in-india-fewer-than-a-third-had-the-stated-amount.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-sachets-in-india-fewer-than-a-third-had-the-stated-amount.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="disparity-in-cholecalciferol-content-of-commercial-preparations-available-in-india">Disparity in cholecalciferol content of commercial preparations available in India.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Indian J Endocrinol Metab. 2013 Nov;17(6):1100-3. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4103/2230-8210.122638.">doi: 10.4103/2230-8210.122638.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Khadgawat R1, Ramot R1, Chacko KM2, Marwaha RK2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: High prevalence of vitamin D deficiency (VDD) has been reported throughout the India for all age groups. Increased awareness about VDD among treating physicians has led to increased prescriptions of vitamin D preparations. Based on our experience of varied clinical and radiological response with different vitamin D formulations, we decided to assess cholecalciferol content of commonly available vitamin D formulations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nanoemulsions of vitamin D help reduce asthma markers in mice</title><link>/posts/nanoemulsions-of-vitamin-d-help-reduce-asthma-markers-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nanoemulsions-of-vitamin-d-help-reduce-asthma-markers-in-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="pharmacological-and-pharmacokinetic-studies-with-vitamin-d-loaded-nanoemulsions-in-asthma-model">Pharmacological and Pharmacokinetic Studies with Vitamin D-loaded Nanoemulsions in Asthma Model.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Inflammation. 2013 Dec 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wei-Hong T, Min-Chang G, Zhen X, Jie S. &lt;a href="mailto:sunjiehuzhou@yeah.net">sunjiehuzhou@yeah.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Taizhou Enze Medical Center Zhejiang Hospital, Zhejiang, 318050, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D (VD) was studied for its anti-inflammatory activities with prepared VD-loaded nanoemulsions (VDNM) in ovalbumin-induced asthmatic mice in this paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this study, we prepared VDNM for the delivery of VD from the established composition of solid self-emulsifying drug delivery systems (sSEDDS) by spray-drying technique and evaluated its bioavailability (BA) and anti-inflammatory activities in experimental allergic asthma. After the mice were treated orally with VD or VDNM, the plasma 25(OH) D levels, polymorphonuclear cells, tumor necrosis factor alpha (TNF-α), interleukin 1 beta (IL-1β), total antioxidant activity, and C3 and C4 complement protein levels were studied, respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Patent application for a skin cream which enhances production of vitamin D – Holick</title><link>/posts/patent-application-for-a-skin-cream-which-enhances-production-of-vitamin-d-holick.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/patent-application-for-a-skin-cream-which-enhances-production-of-vitamin-d-holick.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="compositions-for-providing-vitamin-d-year-round-and-uses-thereofhttpappftusptogovnetacginph-parsersect1pto2sect2hitoffu2fnetahtml2fpto2fsearch-advhtmlr12p1fgl50dpg01s12822vitamind22ttl29osttl22vitamind22rsttl22vitamind22">&lt;a href="http://appft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO2&amp;amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsearch-adv.html&amp;amp;r=12&amp;amp;p=1&amp;amp;f=G&amp;amp;l=50&amp;amp;d=PG01&amp;amp;S1=%28%22vitamin+d%22.TTL.%29&amp;amp;OS=ttl/%22vitamin+d%22&amp;amp;RS=TTL/%22vitamin+d%22">Compositions for Providing Vitamin D Year Round and Uses Thereof&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Methods for enhancing the ability of an individual, exposed to sunlight, to produce vitamin D via the skin. Pharmaceutical compositions comprising provitamin D and at least one of &lt;strong>lumisterol and tachysterol&lt;/strong> and analogs and derivatives thereof are also disclosed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Claim 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A composition comprising a pharmaceutically acceptable carrier and an effective amount of (a) provitamin D or a derivative or analog thereof; (b) at least one of lumisterol and tachysterol or analogs and/or esters thereof, and (c) a pharmaceutically effective carrier, wherein (a) and (b) are present in amounts effective to provide vitamin D or derivatives or analogs and/or esters thereof to an individual at a particular latitude and/or time of the year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spray vitamin D inside cheek in case of emergency</title><link>/posts/spray-vitamin-d-inside-cheek-in-case-of-emergency.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spray-vitamin-d-inside-cheek-in-case-of-emergency.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="in-case-of-emergency-you-probably--want-to-get-vitamin-d-into-the-bloodstream-as-quickly-as-possible">In case of emergency you probably want to get vitamin D into the bloodstream as quickly as possible.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/fat-soluable-vitamins-decrease-quickly-after-trauma" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Fat soluable vitamins decrease quickly after trauma">Fat soluable vitamins decrease quickly after trauma&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without getting an injection, it appears that a vitamin D spray is the fastest way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following study indicates that spraying the vitamin D on the cheeks is faster than sublinqual.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>