<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thyroid and Parathyroid on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/thyroid-and-parathyroid.html</link><description>Recent content in Thyroid and Parathyroid on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/thyroid-and-parathyroid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ischemic Stroke risk best predicted by Vitamin D, including PTH improves the prediction</title><link>/posts/ischemic-stroke-risk-best-predicted-by-vitamin-d-including-pth-improves-the-prediction.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ischemic-stroke-risk-best-predicted-by-vitamin-d-including-pth-improves-the-prediction.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="parathyroid-hormone-levels-in-the-prediction-of-ischemic-stroke-risk">Parathyroid Hormone Levels in the Prediction of Ischemic Stroke Risk.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dis Markers. 2017;2017:4343171. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/4343171.">doi: 10.1155/2017/4343171.&lt;/a> Epub 2017 Jan 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Çelik G1, Doğan A2, Dener Ş3, Öztürk Ş4, Kulaksızoğlu S5, Ekmekçi H4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Beyhekim State Hospital, Department of Neurology, Konya, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Bandırma State Hospital, Department of Neurology, Balıkesir, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Neurology, Başkent University, Konya Training and Research Hospital, Konya, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4Department of Neurology, Selçuk Medical Faculty, Selçuk University, Konya, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>5Department of Biochemistry, Başkent University, Konya Training and Research Hospital, Konya, Turkey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunshine vitamin and thyroid</title><link>/posts/sunshine-vitamin-and-thyroid.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunshine-vitamin-and-thyroid.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Thyroid diseases and vitamin D – review 2015</title><link>/posts/thyroid-diseases-and-vitamin-d-review-2015.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/thyroid-diseases-and-vitamin-d-review-2015.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-thyroid-diseases">Vitamin D and thyroid diseases.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Physiol Res. 2015;64 Suppl 2:S95-S100.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vondra K1, Stárka L, Hampl R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Institute of Endocrinology, Prague, Czech Republic. &lt;a href="mailto:kvondra@endo.cz">kvondra@endo.cz&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this review we summarize recent opinions on the possible role of vitamin D in the risk of thyroid diseases development. It may be concluded from the available data that vitamin D deficiency, &lt;strong>particularly levels below 12.5 ng/ml&lt;/strong> should be considered as an additional, but important risk factor for development of thyroid autoimmunity, both chronic autoimmune thyroiditis and Graves´ disease. A higher risk of Graves´ disease development is also associated with several polymorphisms in the gene encoding for vitamin D binding protein and for the specific receptor of active form of vitamin D - 1,25-(OH)(2)D(3) in the respective target cells. Important for development of thyroid cancer appeared polymorphisms of genes encoding for vitamin D receptors and of genes encoding for the participating hydroxylating enzymes in thyroid tissue, leading to a diminished local 1,25-(OH)(2)D(3) formation capacity with following alteration of antiproliferatory, antiapoptotic and prodifferentiating efficacy of the latter. Whether supplementation with high doses of vitamin D or its analogues possesses preventive or therapeutic effect is an object of intensive studies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lots of vitamin D supplementation by those with Primary Hyperparathyroidism</title><link>/posts/lots-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-by-those-with-primary-hyperparathyroidism.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lots-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-by-those-with-primary-hyperparathyroidism.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="seasonal-variability-in-vitamin-d-levels-no-longer-detectable-in-primary-hyperparathyroidism">Seasonal Variability in Vitamin D Levels No Longer Detectable in Primary Hyperparathyroidism.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2015 Sep;100(9):3452-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1210/JC.2015-2105.">doi: 10.1210/JC.2015-2105.&lt;/a> Epub 2015 Jun 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cong E1, Walker MD1, Kepley A1, Zhang C1, McMahon DJ1, Silverberg SJ1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>.1Department of Medicine, Columbia University, College of Physicians and Surgeons, New York City, New York 10032.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:500px">
&lt;p>100 patients with Primary Hyperparathyroidism in NE US&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No seasonal difference in % with &amp;lt; 30 ng of Vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Graves' disease and Hashimoto's thyroiditis 1.5X less likely for each 2 ng more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/graves-disease-and-hashimotos-thyroiditis-15x-less-likely-for-each-2-ng-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/graves-disease-and-hashimotos-thyroiditis-15x-less-likely-for-each-2-ng-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="lower-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-is-associated-with-3-types-of-autoimmune-thyroid-diseases">Lower Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Level is Associated With 3 Types of Autoimmune Thyroid Diseases.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Medicine (Baltimore). 2015 Sep;94(39):e1639.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ma J1, Wu D, Li C, Fan C, Chao N, Liu J, Li Y, Wang R, Miao W, Guan H, Shan Z, Teng W.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1From the Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, The Endocrine Institute and The Liaoning Provincial Key Laboratory of Endocrine Diseases (JM, DW, CF, NC, JL, YL, RW, WM, HG, ZS, WT), The First Affiliated Hospital of China Medical University; and Department of Gynecology and Obstetrics (CL), Shenyang Women&amp;rsquo;s and Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Shenyang, Liaoning, PR China.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3000 IU of vitamin D minimum to reduce parathyroid hormone (PTH) – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/3000-iu-of-vitamin-d-minimum-to-reduce-parathyroid-hormone-pth-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3000-iu-of-vitamin-d-minimum-to-reduce-parathyroid-hormone-pth-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="determinants-of-parathyroid-hormone-response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-randomised-controlled-trials">Determinants of parathyroid hormone response to vitamin D supplementation: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2015 Sep 4:1-15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moslehi N1, Shab-Bidar S2, Mirmiran P3, Hosseinpanah F4, Azizi F5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PTH response to Vitamin D intervention&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/pth-response-meta.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>This systematic review aimed to assess the determinants of the parathyroid hormone (PTH) level response to vitamin D supplementation. We searched Medline, Google Scholar and the reference lists of previous reviews. All randomised controlled trials (RCT) on vitamin D supplementation that involved apparently healthy human subjects with a report of PTH were selected. Potential studies were screened independently and in duplicate. Results are summarised as mean differences with 95 % confidence intervals. Quality assessment, subgroup analysis, meta-analysis and meta-regression analysis were carried out. Thirty-three vitamin D supplementation RCT were included. Vitamin D supplementation significantly raised circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) with significant heterogeneity among studies with a pooled mean difference (PMD) of 15.5 ng/ml (test for heterogeneity: P&amp;lt;0·001 and I 2=97·3 %). Vitamin D supplementation significantly reduced PTH level with PMD of -8·0 pg/ml, with significant heterogeneity ( (test for heterogeneity: P&amp;lt;0·001) and the I 2 value was 97·3 %). In the subgroup analyses, the optimum treatment effect for PTH was observed with Ca doses of 600-1200 mg/d (-22·48 pg/ml), after the duration of a &amp;gt;12-month trial (-18·36 pg/ml), with low baseline 25(OH)D concentration of &amp;lt;20 ng/ml (-16·70 pg/ml) and in those who were overweight and obese (-18·11 pg/ml).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis Vitamin D receptor controls PTH without needing Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-receptor-controls-pth-without-needing-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-receptor-controls-pth-without-needing-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-vitamin-d-receptor-functions-as-a-transcription-regulator-in-the-absence-of-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3">The vitamin D receptor functions as a transcription regulator in the absence of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, doi:10.1016/j.jsbmb.2015.08.018&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seong Min Lee, , J. Wesley Pike&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Biochemistry, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI 53706, United States&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• The VDR de-represses PTH secretion in the absence of 1,25(OH)2D3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• The VDR is involved in bone metabolism in the absence of 1,25(OH)2D3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• The VDR modulates expression of its target genes in the absence of 1,25(OH)2D3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Critically ill injected with 300,000 IU of vitamin D, 3X more likely to die if PTH did not respond - RCT</title><link>/posts/critically-ill-injected-with-300000-iu-of-vitamin-d-3x-more-likely-to-die-if-pth-did-not-respond-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/critically-ill-injected-with-300000-iu-of-vitamin-d-3x-more-likely-to-die-if-pth-did-not-respond-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-randomized-study-of-a-single-dose-of-intramuscular-cholecalciferol-in-critically-ill-adults">A Randomized Study of a Single Dose of Intramuscular Cholecalciferol in Critically Ill Adults.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Crit Care Med. 2015 Jul 16.&lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note: 40% of the high-dose group was having Renal Replacement Therapy,&lt;br>
    which indicates that 40% were probably not able to process Vitamin D&lt;br>
Vitamin D is not the appropriate form to give to those patients,&lt;br>
    they needed &lt;a href="/categories/calcitriol">Calcitriol&lt;/a> injection - which does not require kidney processing&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>They did not check for adverse reaction to a small dose before giving 300,000 IU injection&lt;br>
Overall, there was no statistially significant difference in mortality between the 150,000 and 300,000 groups&lt;br>
Strangely. the PDF fails to say the number of people who did not change PTH, nor the number of deaths.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Graves Disease is 2.2X more likely with low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/graves-disease-is-22x-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/graves-disease-is-22x-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-graves-disease-a-meta-analysis-update---2015">Vitamin D and Graves’ Disease: A Meta-Analysis Update - 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#graves-disease-recurrence-32-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d--aug-2017">Graves disease recurrence 3.2 X more likely if low vitamin D – Aug 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#wikipedia">WikiPedia&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-graves-disease-a-meta-analysis-update---2015">Vitamin D and Graves’ Disease: A Meta-Analysis Update - 2015&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2015, 7(5), 3813-3827; doi:10.3390/nu7053813 (registering DOI)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mei-Yan Xu 1,* Bing Cao 2, Jian Yin 1, Dong-Fang Wang 2 Kai-Li Chen 3 and Qing-Bin Lu 2, &lt;a href="mailto:qingbinlu@bjmu.edu.cn">qingbinlu@bjmu.edu.cn&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Nutrition, Aerospace Center Hospital, Beijing 100049, China&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autoimmune Thyroid Disease 3X more likely if low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/autoimmune-thyroid-disease-3x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/autoimmune-thyroid-disease-3x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="meta-analysis-of-the-association-between-vitamin-d-and-autoimmune-thyroid-disease">Meta-Analysis of the Association between Vitamin D and Autoimmune Thyroid Disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients. 2015 Apr 3;7(4):2485-2498.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wang J1, Lv S2, Chen G3, Gao C4, He J5, Zhong H6, Xu Y7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Affiliated Hospital of Luzhou Medical College, Luzhou 646000, China. &lt;a href="mailto:wangjiying90@aliyun.com">wangjiying90@aliyun.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Affiliated Hospital of Luzhou Medical College, Luzhou 646000, China. &lt;a href="mailto:lss219219@163.com">lss219219@163.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Affiliated Hospital of Luzhou Medical College, Luzhou 646000, China. &lt;a href="mailto:terry1210@aliyun.com">terry1210@aliyun.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Following primary hyperparathyroidism surgery 1600 IU vitamin D was not enough to help - RCT</title><link>/posts/following-primary-hyperparathyroidism-surgery-1600-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-help-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/following-primary-hyperparathyroidism-surgery-1600-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-help-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="health-related-quality-of-life-after-successful-surgery-for-primary-hyperparathyroidism-no-additive-effect-from-vitamin-d-supplementation-results-of-a-double-blind-randomized-study">Health-related quality of life after successful surgery for primary hyperparathyroidism: no additive effect from vitamin D supplementation: results of a double-blind randomized study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Endocrinol. 2015 Feb;172(2):181-7. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1530/EJE-14-0757.">doi: 10.1530/EJE-14-0757.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Nov 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Åberg V1, Norenstedt S1, Zedenius J1, Sääf M1, Nordenström J1, Pernow Y1, Nilsson IL2.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:300px">
&lt;p>1t600 IU for 1 year&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Raised average blood level to 30 ng&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not enough to help&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D insufficiency is common in primary hyperparathyroidism (pHPT). Patients with pHPT frequently have a reduced health-related quality of life (HRQoL). Our objectives were to evaluate whether HRQoL in pHPT is associated with vitamin D insufficiency and whether vitamin D supplementation after parathyroidectomy (PTX) could improve HRQoL.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PTH reduced 3.5 pmol by vitamin D intervention which added 22 ng – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/pth-reduced-35-pmol-by-vitamin-d-intervention-which-added-22-ng-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pth-reduced-35-pmol-by-vitamin-d-intervention-which-added-22-ng-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-25-oh-d-replacements-in-patients-with-primary-hyperparathyroidism-phpt-and-coexistent-vitamin-d-deficiency-on-serum-25oh-d-calcium-and-pth-levels-a-meta-analysis-and-review-of-literature">Effect of 25 (OH) D replacements in patients with primary hyperparathyroidism (PHPT) and coexistent vitamin D deficiency on serum 25(OH) D, calcium and PTH levels: a meta-analysis and review of literature.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2014 Jun;80(6):797-803. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/cen.12398.">doi: 10.1111/cen.12398.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Jan 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shah VN1, Shah CS, Bhadada SK, Rao DS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Barbara Davis Center for Diabetes, University of Colorado, Denver, CO, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CONTEXT:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The safety of vitamin D replacement in subjects with primary hyperparathyroidism (PHPT) and coexistent vitamin D deficiency is not well established.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D helps with T2 Diabetes, hyperparathyroidism, PCOS, and some other endocinological diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-with-t2-diabetes-hyperparathyroidism-pcos-and-some-other-endocinological-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-with-t2-diabetes-hyperparathyroidism-pcos-and-some-other-endocinological-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mechanisms-in-endocrinology-vitamin-d-as-a-potential-contributor-in-endocrine-health-and-disease">Mechanisms in endocrinology: vitamin D as a potential contributor in endocrine health and disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Endocrinol. 2014 Sep;171(3):R101-10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1530/EJE-14-0158.">doi: 10.1530/EJE-14-0158.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 May 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Muscogiuri G1, Mitri J2, Mathieu C2, Badenhoop K2, Tamer G2, Orio F3, Mezza T2, Vieth R3, Colao A2, Pittas A2.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/endocrine-table-1.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been suggested that vitamin D may play a role in the pathogenesis of several endocrine diseases, such as hyperparathyroidism, type 1 diabetes (T1DM), type 2 diabetes (T2DM), autoimmune thyroid diseases, Addison&amp;rsquo;s disease and polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS). In this review, we debate the role of vitamin D in the pathogenesis of endocrine diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes after giving birth was associated with low vitamin D combined with high PTH</title><link>/posts/diabetes-after-giving-birth-was-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-combined-with-high-pth.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-after-giving-birth-was-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-combined-with-high-pth.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prospective-associations-of-vitamin-d-status-with-beta-cell-function-insulin-sensitivity-and-glycemia-the-impact-of-parathyroid-hormone-status">Prospective Associations of Vitamin D Status with Beta-cell function, Insulin Sensitivity and Glycemia: The Impact of Parathyroid Hormone Status.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Diabetes. 2014 May 29. pii: DB_140489. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kramer CK1, Swaminathan B2, Hanley AJ3, Connelly PW4, Sermer M5, Zinman B6, Retnakaran R7.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1Leadership Sinai Centre for Diabetes, Mount Sinai Hospital, Toronto, Canada Division of Endocrinology, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>2Leadership Sinai Centre for Diabetes, Mount Sinai Hospital, Toronto, Canada.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hyperparathyroidism – still not absolutely, positively sure that vitamin D should be used to treat it</title><link>/posts/hyperparathyroidism-still-not-absolutely-positively-sure-that-vitamin-d-should-be-used-to-treat-it.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hyperparathyroidism-still-not-absolutely-positively-sure-that-vitamin-d-should-be-used-to-treat-it.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-primary-hyperparathyroidism-to-treat-or-not-to-treat-that-is-the-question">Hypovitaminosis D in primary hyperparathyroidism: to treat or not to treat? That is the question&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Endocrinological Investigation, March 2014 - Editorial&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Salvatore Minisola, Elisabetta Romagnoli, Alfredo Scillitani, Sudhakar D. Rao&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/hyperparathyroidism.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-hyperparathyroidism-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Hyperparathyroidism and vitamin D">Overview Hyperparathyroidism and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/graves-disease-is-22x-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis">Graves Disease is 2.2X more likely with low vitamin D – meta-analysis May 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2800 IU of vitamin D before and after parathyroid surgery helped a lot – RCT</title><link>/posts/2800-iu-of-vitamin-d-before-and-after-parathyroid-surgery-helped-a-lot-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2800-iu-of-vitamin-d-before-and-after-parathyroid-surgery-helped-a-lot-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-treatment-in-primary-hyperparathyroidism-a-randomized-placebo-controlled-trial">Vitamin D Treatment in Primary Hyperparathyroidism: a Randomized Placebo Controlled Trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014 Jan 13:jc20133978.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rolighed L, Rejnmark L, Sikjaer T, Heickendorff L, Vestergaard P, Mosekilde L, Christiansen P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Surgery P, Breast and Endocrine Section, THG, Aarhus University Hospital, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Context: Low 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25OHD) levels are common in patients with primary hyperparathyroidism (PHPT) and associated with higher PTH levels and hungry bone syndrome following parathyroidectomy (PTX). However, concerns have been raised on safety of vitamin D supplementation in PHPT.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autoimmune Thyroid Disease 2X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/autoimmune-thyroid-disease-2x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/autoimmune-thyroid-disease-2x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-levels-of-serum-vitamin-d3-are-associated-with-autoimmune-thyroid-disease-in-pre-menopausal-women">Low Levels of Serum Vitamin D3 are Associated with Autoimmune Thyroid Disease in Pre-Menopausal Women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Thyroid. 2013 Dec 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choi YM, Kim WG, Kim TY, Bae SJ, Kim HK, Jang EK, Jeon M, Han JM, Lee SH, Baek JH, Shong Y, Kim WB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Backgroud: Low serum vitamin D level has been associated with several autoimmune diseases, but its association with thyroid autoimmunity is unclear. We evaluated the association of serum vitamin D level with the prevalence of autoimmune thyroid disease (AITD).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Long term Hashimoto's Thyroiditis has lower level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/long-term-hashimotos-thyroiditis-has-lower-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/long-term-hashimotos-thyroiditis-has-lower-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-association-between-severity-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-hashimotos-thyroiditis">The Association Between Severity of Vitamin D Deficiency and Hashimoto&amp;rsquo;s Thyroiditis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Journal	Endocrine Practice, Online Jan 21 2013, Pages	1-14&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nujen Colak Bozkurt, MD1, Basak Karbek, MD1, Bekir Ucan, MD1, Mustafa Sahin, MD2, Erman Cakal, MD1, Mustafa Ozbek, MD1, Tuncay Delibasi, MD1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Diskapi Yildirim Beyazit Training and Research Hospital&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Ankara University School of Medicine, Ankara, Turkey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: The relation between vitamin-D and autoimmune disorders has long been investigated regarding to important roles of this hormone in immune regulation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>50,000 IU vitamin D weekly is safe and effective for Primary Hyperparathyroidism</title><link>/posts/50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-is-safe-and-effective-for-primary-hyperparathyroidism.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-is-safe-and-effective-for-primary-hyperparathyroidism.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="safety-of-vitamin-d-replacement-in-patients-with-primary-hyperparathyroidism-and-concomitant-vitamin-d-deficiency">Safety of Vitamin D Replacement in Patients with Primary Hyperparathyroidism and Concomitant Vitamin D Deficiency.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2013 Jan 21:1-20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wagner D, Xia Y, Hou R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, University of Rochester Medical Center, Rochester, New York.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To evaluate the safety of vitamin D replacement in patients with vitamin D deficiency and primary hyperparathyroidism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: Retrospective chart review on 35 patients from our Endocrine clinic, age 22-89, diagnosed with primary hyperparathyroidism and vitamin D deficiency and treated with either 1000-2000 IU of vitamin D daily or 50,000 IU of Vitamin D weekly for 5 months. Data were collected on serum calcium, 25-OH vitamin D, iPTH, PO4, alkaline phosphatase, nephrolithiasis, fractures and osteoporosis before and after treatment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thyroid and parathyroid</title><link>/posts/thyroid-and-parathyroid.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/thyroid-and-parathyroid.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#what-is-the-difference-between-the-intact-parathyroid-hormone-and-the-parathyroid-hormone-asked-ai">What is the difference between the Intact Parathyroid Hormone and the Parathyroid Hormone (asked AI)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="what-is-the-difference-between-the-intact-parathyroid-hormone-and-the-parathyroid-hormone-asked-ai">What is the difference between the Intact Parathyroid Hormone and the Parathyroid Hormone (asked AI)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The difference between Intact Parathyroid Hormone (iPTH) and Parathyroid Hormone (PTH) primarily lies in the specific forms of the hormone that each assay measures and their clinical utility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Intact Parathyroid Hormone (iPTH)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The iPTH assay measures the level of 1-84 PTH, which is the full, active form of the hormone, along with large truncated fragments of non-1-84 PTH, including 7-84 PTH. This assay is widely used, especially in the context of managing patients with chronic kidney disease, including those on dialysis, to assess parathyroid function and secondary hyperparathyroidism. The iPTH assay is considered the standard measurement for PTH in clinical practice and is used for approximately 90% of Japanese dialysis patients 1.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Worse diabetic vision is associated with low vitamin D or high PTH</title><link>/posts/worse-diabetic-vision-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-or-high-pth.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/worse-diabetic-vision-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-or-high-pth.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="diabetic-retinopathy-severity-serum-vitamin-d-and-parathormone-pth-concentrations-as-predictors-of-the-development-and-severity-of-diabetic-retinopathy">Diabetic Retinopathy severity Serum vitamin D and parathormone (PTH) concentrations as predictors of the development and severity of diabetic retinopathy&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="alexandria-journal-of-medicine--nov-2012httpwwwajmeorgarticles2090-50681200079-6abstract">&lt;a href="http://www.ajme.org/article/S2090-5068(12)00079-6/abstract">Alexandria Journal of Medicine Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Rania Naguib Abdel Mouteleb Abdel Reheem &lt;a href="mailto:ranianaguib2000@yahoo.com">ranianaguib2000@yahoo.com&lt;/a>, Maaly Abdel Halim Mohamed Abdel Fattah &lt;a href="mailto:mola_73@hotmail.com">mola_73@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 14 April 2012; accepted 24 August 2012. published online 08 October 2012.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D is suggested to be an inhibitor of angiogenesis. The degree of severity of diabetic retinopathy (DR) may be related to serum vitamin D concentration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>African-Americans need only 20 ng of vitamin, not 30 ng, based on iPTH</title><link>/posts/african-americans-need-only-20-ng-of-vitamin-not-30-ng-based-on-ipth.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/african-americans-need-only-20-ng-of-vitamin-not-30-ng-based-on-ipth.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">2nd study on this page disagrees - finding NO iPTH plateau&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="defining-physiologically-normal-vitamin-d-in-african-americans">Defining physiologically “normal” vitamin D in African Americans&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>OSTEOPOROSIS INTERNATIONAL; Volume 23, Number 9 (2012), 2283-2291,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N. C. Wright (1), L. Chen (2), J. Niu (3), T. Neogi (3), K. Javiad (4), M. A. Nevitt (5). C. E. Lewis (6), J. R. Curtis (2)jcurtis@uab.edu&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology, University of Alabama at Birmingham, RPHB 523, 1665 University Blvd, Birmingham, AL 35294, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PTH does not plateau with increasing vitamin D, but does decrease with patient age</title><link>/posts/pth-does-not-plateau-with-increasing-vitamin-d-but-does-decrease-with-patient-age.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pth-does-not-plateau-with-increasing-vitamin-d-but-does-decrease-with-patient-age.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-age-and-serum-25-oh-vitamin-d-on-serum-parathyroid-hormone-levels">Effects of Age and Serum 25-OH-Vitamin D on Serum Parathyroid Hormone Levels&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism August 29, 2012 jc.2012-2276&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. Valcour, F. Blocki, D. M. Hawkins and Sudhaker D. Rao&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Esoteric Testing (A.V.), Lab Corp., Burlington, North Carolina 27216; DiaSorin (F.B.), Stillwater, Minnesota 55082; School of Statistics (D.M.H.), University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota 55455; and Bone and Mineral Research Laboratory (S.D.R.), Henry Ford Hospital, Detroit, Michigan 48202&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium and bone disorders in pregnancy</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-bone-disorders-in-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-bone-disorders-in-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Indian J Endocrinol Metab. 2012 May-Jun; 16(3): 358–363, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4103/2230-8210.95665">doi: 10.4103/2230-8210.95665&lt;/a>, PMCID: PMC3354840&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shriraam Mahadevan, V. Kumaravel,1 and R. Bharath2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Endocrinology, Dr. E. V. Kalyani Medical Centre, Chennai, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Clinical Endocrinology, Alpha Hospital and Research Centre, Madurai, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Endocrinology, Chettinad Medical College and Research Institute, Chennai, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corresponding Author: Dr. Shriraam Mahadevan, Department of Clinical Endocrinology, Dr. E. V. Kalyani Medical Centre, 4, Radhakrishnan Salai, Mylapore, Chennai 600004, India. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:mshriraam@gmail.com">mshriraam@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Primary hyperparathyroidism might increase when vitamin D levels increase</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-primary-hyperparathyroidism-might-increase-when-vitamin-d-levels-increase.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-primary-hyperparathyroidism-might-increase-when-vitamin-d-levels-increase.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-or-wait-and-see">Vitamin D, or wait and see?&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="letter-to-the-editor">LETTER TO THE EDITOR,&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="the-netherlands-journal-of-medicine-august-2-012-vol-70-no-6-292">The Netherlands Journal of Medicine AUGUST 2 012, VOL. 70, NO 6 292&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I.M.E. Wentholt 1*, J. Bras 2, F.H.M. Kroon 3, E.J.M. Nieveen van Dijkum 4, E. Fliers 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of &amp;lsquo;Endocrinology and Metabolism, 2 Pathology, 3 Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery, 4 Surgery, Academic Medical Center of the University of Amsterdam, Meibergdreef 9, 1105 AZ Amsterdam the Netherlands,*corresponding author: tel: +31 (0)6-14399031, e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:I.M.Wentholt@amc.nl">I.M.Wentholt@amc.nl&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X more Thyroid Cancer malignancy if less than 15 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/2x-more-thyroid-cancer-malignancy-if-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-thyroid-cancer-malignancy-if-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-potentially-modifiable-risk-factor-for-thyroid-cancer">Vitamin d deficiency as a potentially modifiable risk factor for thyroid cancer.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-receptor-and-medullary-thyroid-cancer---july-2016">Vitamin D Receptor and medullary thyroid cancer - July 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2000-studies-contain-thyroid-cancer-and-vitamin-d-receptor">2,000+ studies contain &amp;ldquo;Thyroid Cancer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;vitamin D Receptor&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-potentially-modifiable-risk-factor-for-thyroid-cancer">Vitamin d deficiency as a potentially modifiable risk factor for thyroid cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2012 Jun 1;41(3):160-3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roskies M, Dolev Y, Caglar D, Hier MP, Mlynarek A, Majdan A, Payne RJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:Vitamin D, classically involved in calcium homeostasis, has garnered recent interest for its potential role in cancer prevention and therapy. Although few risk factors have been established in the development of well-differentiated thyroid carcinoma, some would argue that no clear modifiable risk factor exists. Our study is one of the first to explore the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and thyroid cancer.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>