<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vitamin D and Vitamin K on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vitamin D and Vitamin K on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin K can reduce aging</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-k-can-reduce-aging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-k-can-reduce-aging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-role-of-vitamin-k-in-humans-implication-in-aging-and-age-associated-diseases&#34;&gt;The Role of Vitamin K in Humans: Implication in Aging and Age-Associated Diseases&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Antioxidants 2021, 10(4), 566; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox10040566&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox10040566&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Daniela-Saveta Popa 1,*ORCID,Galya Bigman 2ORCID and Marius Emil Rusu 3ORCID&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As human life expectancy is rising, the incidence of age-associated diseases will also increase. Scientific evidence has revealed that healthy diets, including good fats, vitamins, minerals, or polyphenolics, could have antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities, with antiaging effects. Recent studies demonstrated that vitamin K is a vital cofactor in activating several proteins, which act against age-related syndromes. Thus, vitamin K can carboxylate osteocalcin (a protein capable of transporting and fixing calcium in bone), activate matrix Gla protein (an inhibitor of vascular calcification and cardiovascular events) and carboxylate Gas6 protein (involved in brain physiology and a cognitive decline and neurodegenerative disease inhibitor). By improving insulin sensitivity, vitamin K lowers diabetes risk. It also exerts antiproliferative, proapoptotic, autophagic effects and has been associated with a reduced risk of cancer. Recent research shows that protein S, another vitamin K-dependent protein, can prevent the cytokine storm observed in COVID-19 cases. The reduced activation of protein S due to the pneumonia-induced vitamin K depletion was correlated with higher thrombogenicity and possibly fatal outcomes in COVID-19 patients. Our review aimed to present the latest scientific evidence about vitamin K and its role in preventing age-associated diseases and/or improving the effectiveness of medical treatments in mature adults ˃50 years old.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID associated with less Vitamin K2-7 - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-associated-with-less-vitamin-k2-7-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-associated-with-less-vitamin-k2-7-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;dramatic-decrease-of-vitamin-k2-subtype-menaquinone-7-in-covid-19-patients---june-2022&#34;&gt;Dramatic Decrease of Vitamin K2 Subtype Menaquinone-7 in COVID-19 Patients - June 2022&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Antioxidants 2022, 11(7), 1235; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox11071235&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox11071235&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Harald Mangge 1,*ORCID,Florian Prueller 1ORCID,Christine Dawczynski 2ORCID,Pero Curcic 1,Zdenka Sloup&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) Background: Vitamin K (VK) is a fat-soluble compound with a common chemical structure, a 2-methyl-1,4-naphthoquinone ring, and a variable aliphatic side-chain. VK is involved in the synthesis of blood-clotting proteins, bone stability, anti-oxidative, and immune inflammatory-modulatory functions. Vitamin K also activates protein S, which acts as an antioxidant and anti-inflammatory. The fact that cytokine overproduction, oxidative stress, and disturbed microcirculation by thrombogenicity play a central role in severe COVID-19 prompted us to analyze this vitamin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>T2 Diabetes is also fought by Vitamin K2 – several studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/t2-diabetes-is-also-fought-by-vitamin-k2-several-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/t2-diabetes-is-also-fought-by-vitamin-k2-several-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-vitamin-k2-on-type-2-diabetes-mellitus-a-review--2018&#34;&gt;Effect of vitamin K2 on type 2 diabetes mellitus: A review – 2018&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice - Vol 136, Feb 2018, Pages 39-51 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2017.11.020&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2017.11.020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yan Li a, Jie peng Chen b, Lili Duan b, Shuzhuang Li a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) continue to be a major public health problem around the world that frequently presents with microvascular and macrovascular complications. Individuals with T2DM are not only suffering from significant emotional and physical misery, but also at increased risk of dying from severe complications. In recent years, evidence from prospective observational studies and clinical trials has shown T2DM risk reduction with vitamin K2 supplementation. We thus did an overview of currently available studies to assess the effect of vitamin K2 supplementation on insulin sensitivity, glycaemic control and reviewed the underlying mechanisms. We proposed that vitamin K2 improved insulin sensitivity through involvement of vitamin K-dependent-protein osteocalcin, anti-inflammatory properties, and lipid-lowering effects. Vitamin K2 had a better effect than vitamin K1 on T2DM. The interpretation of this review will increase comprehension of the development of a therapeutic strategy to prevent and treat T2DM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supplements taken by the founder of VitaminDWiki</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/supplements-taken-by-the-founder-of-vitamindwiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/supplements-taken-by-the-founder-of-vitamindwiki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;supplements-taken-daily-thru-once-a-week&#34;&gt;Supplements: taken daily thru once a week&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Manufacturer - rarely important, typically popular on Amazon)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magnesium  &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;Co-Factor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;VDR activate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;**   400 mg in water&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;need &amp;gt;100 mg average daily MgCl (bulk crystal, disolved in water)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Omega-3  &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;Co-Factor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;*  - tend to take it the in morning,  (Coromega - tastes great)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Must also decrease Omega-6 to get the benefit from Omega-3: See &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/omega-3-index-many-studiesomega-3-index-home-test&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Omega-3 index - many studies|Omega-3 index home test&#34;&gt;Omega-3 index - many studies|Omega-3 index home test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every 2 days&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin K, cardiovascular health, and stroke - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-k-cardiovascular-health-and-stroke-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-k-cardiovascular-health-and-stroke-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-k-intake-in-chronic-stroke-implications-for-dietary-recommendations---oct-2020&#34;&gt;Vitamin K Intake in Chronic Stroke: Implications for Dietary Recommendations - Oct 2020&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2020, 12(10), 3059; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu12103059&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu12103059&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Chad Wessinger,Charlene Hafer-Macko andAlice S. Ryan *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VA Research Service, Department of Medicine, Division of Gerontology and Geriatric Medicine at the University of Maryland School of Medicine, and the Baltimore VA Medical Center Geriatric Research, Education and Clinical Center (GRECC), VA Maryland Health Care System, Baltimore, MD 21201, USA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Previous research has identified a possible association between vitamin K intake and cardiometabolic disease. This could mean that the assessment of vitamin K intake is a meaningful tool when monitoring individuals with preexisting cardiovascular disease. Sixty chronic stroke survivors (men and women, body mass index (BMI) 30.36 ± 6.61 kg/m2, age 61.7 ± 7.2 years) completed food records which were analyzed for energy, macronutrient, micronutrient, and food group servings. Participants were divided into two groups: below vitamin K recommendation (BEL, n = 49) and met vitamin K recommendation (MET, n = 11). Energy and macronutrient intake did not differ between groups (all p &amp;gt; 0.127). Vegetable intake was higher in the MET group (p = 0.0001). Vitamin K intake was higher in the MET group (p = 0.0001). Calcium (p = 0.003), vitamin A (p = 0.007), and vitamin E (p = 0.005) intakes were higher in the MET group. There were no differences in sodium, potassium, vitamin D, vitamin C, and iron intakes between groups (all p &amp;gt; 0.212). In this sample of chronic stroke survivors, 82% reported consuming below the Dietary Reference Intake (DRI) for vitamin K. Given that the majority of this study population did not reach the DRI for vitamin K, it is advisable to promote the adequate intake of food rich in vitamin K. Further work is needed to determine the significance of low vitamin K intake in this population.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calcium and Vitamin K2 - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-k2-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-k2-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-options-to-reduce-excess-calcium-in-the-arteries-if-take-high-dose-vitamin-d&#34;&gt;2 options to reduce excess Calcium in the arteries if take high-dose Vitamin D&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reduce Calcium intake (so that the same amout of Calcium gets into the body)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Note: Might only need to reduce the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vitamindwiki.com/tiki-index.php?page_id=12996&#34;&gt;rock-calcium, not natural Calcium (plants, dairy)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take Vitamin K2 - at least once every 3 days while taking high-dose vitamin D&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamindwiki--&#34;&gt;VitaminDWiki -&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {SQL(db=&gt;vitamind)}SELECT COUNT(*) FROM (SELECT catObjectId, COUNT(*) FROM `tiki_category_objects` WHERE categId = 53  OR categId = 106 GROUP BY catObjectId HAVING COUNT(*) &gt; 1) AS categs INNER JOIN tiki_objects ON tiki_objects.objectId = categs.catObjectId WHERE type = &#34;wiki page&#34;{SQL} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;studies in both categories Calcium and Vitamin K2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin K2 fights Breast and some other cancers - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-k2-fights-breast-and-some-other-cancers-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-k2-fights-breast-and-some-other-cancers-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;17-x-less-likely-to-get-breast-cancer-if-have-high-vitamin-k2-intake---may-2021&#34;&gt;1.7 X less likely to get breast cancer if have high Vitamin K2 intake - May 2021&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vitamin K intake and breast cancer incidence and death: results from a prospective cohort study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clinical Nutrition, Volume 40, Issue 5, May 2021, Pages 3370-3378. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnu.2020.11.009&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnu.2020.11.009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kang Wang a b g, Qianxue Wu a, Zhuyue Li c, Michael K. Reger d, Yongfu Xiong e, Guochao Zhong f, Qing Li a, Xiang Zhang a, Hongyuan Li a, Theodoros Foukakis g h, Tingxiu Xiang b, Jianjun Zhang i, Guosheng Ren a b&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-factors increase Vitamin D response for the GRH cohort</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/co-factors-increase-vitamin-d-response-for-the-grh-cohort/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/co-factors-increase-vitamin-d-response-for-the-grh-cohort/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;important-nutrients-to-make-sure-you-are-getting-along-with-vitamin-d&#34;&gt;Important Nutrients to Make Sure You Are Getting Along with Vitamin D&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://myemail.constantcontact.com/Important-Nutrients-to-Make-Sure-You-Are-Getting-Along-with-Vitamin-D.html?soid=1102722411090&amp;amp;aid=1o3gmmf_klw&#34;&gt;Grassrootshealth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The calculations below show how much more supplemental vitamin D was needed, on average, for participants to achieve a vitamin D level of at least  &lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;40 ng/ml &lt;/span&gt;(100 nmol/L), for those not taking each nutrient in supplement form compared to those taking each nutrient.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;244%  more D needed if not taking both magnesium and K2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
