<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vitamin D and Vitamin K on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k.html</link><description>Recent content in Vitamin D and Vitamin K on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin K-2 (180 ug MK-7) helped both bone density and strength – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k-2-180-ug-mk-7-helped-both-bone-density-and-strength-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k-2-180-ug-mk-7-helped-both-bone-density-and-strength-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="three-year-low-dose-menaquinone-7-supplementation-helps-decrease-bone-loss-in-healthy-postmenopausal-women">Three-year low-dose menaquinone-7 supplementation helps decrease bone loss in healthy postmenopausal women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis International March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. H. J. Knapen, N. E. Drummen, E. Smit, C. Vermeer, E. Theuwissen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have investigated whether low-dose vitamin K2 supplements (menaquinone-7, MK-7) could beneficially affect bone health. Next to an improved vitamin K status, MK-7 supplementation significantly decreased the age-related decline in bone mineral density and bone strength. Low-dose MK-7 supplements may therefore help postmenopausal women prevent bone loss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D monotherapy reduces colorectal cancer but has calcemic side effects</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-monotherapy-reduces-colorectal-cancer-but-has-calcemic-side-effects.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-monotherapy-reduces-colorectal-cancer-but-has-calcemic-side-effects.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="antineoplastic-effects-of-125oh2d3-and-its-analogs-in-breast-prostate-and-colorectal-cancer">Antineoplastic effects of 1,25(OH)2D3 and its analogs in breast, prostate and colorectal cancer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Endocr Relat Cancer April 1, 2013 20 R31-R47&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carlien Leyssens,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lieve Verlinden and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annemieke Verstuyf, &lt;a href="mailto:mieke.verstuyf@med.kuleuven.be">mieke.verstuyf@med.kuleuven.be&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical and Experimental Endocrinology, KU Leuven, Herestraat 49, bus 902, 3000 Leuven, Belgium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The active form of vitamin D3, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3), is mostly known for its importance in the maintenance of calcium and phosphate homeostasis. However, next to its classical effects on bone, kidney and intestine, 1,25(OH)2D3 also exerts antineoplastic effects on various types of cancer. The use of 1,25(OH)2D3 itself as treatment against neoplasia is hampered by its calcemic side effects. Therefore, 1,25(OH)2D3-derived analogs were developed that are characterized by lower calcemic side effects and stronger antineoplastic effects. This review mainly focuses on the role of 1,25(OH)2D3 in breast, prostate and colorectal cancer (CRC) and the underlying signaling pathways. 1,25(OH)2D3 and its analogs inhibit proliferation, angiogenesis, migration/invasion and induce differentiation and apoptosis in malignant cell lines. Moreover, prostaglandin synthesis and Wnt/b-catenin signaling are also influenced by 1,25(OH)2D3 and its analogs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cholesterol, Vitamins D3 and K2, heart disease, sulfates, LDL, – Masterjohn Interview</title><link>/posts/cholesterol-vitamins-d3-and-k2-heart-disease-sulfates-ldl-masterjohn-interview.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cholesterol-vitamins-d3-and-k2-heart-disease-sulfates-ldl-masterjohn-interview.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="mercola-interviewed-dr-chris-masterohnhttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20130116cholesterol-regulates-cell-signalingaspxe_cid20130116_dnl_art_220">&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2013/01/16/cholesterol-regulates-cell-signaling.aspx?e_cid=20130116_DNL_art_2%20">Mercola interviewed Dr. Chris Masterohn&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Video is 15 minutes long&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Transcript follows&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="update-nutritional-adjuncts-to-the-fat-soluble-vitamins-a-d-and-k-httparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20130318fat-soluble-vitaminsaspxe_cid20130318_dnl_art_2utm_sourcednlutm_mediumemailutm_contentart2utm_campaign20130318_edn4-mercola-march-2013">Update &lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2013/03/18/fat-soluble-vitamins.aspx?e_cid=20130318_DNL_art_2&amp;amp;utm_source=dnl&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=art2&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20130318#_edn4">Nutritional Adjuncts to the Fat-Soluble Vitamins A, D, and K &lt;/a> Mercola March 2013&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eventually earning a reputation as “the most toxic of all the vitamins. still in textbooks in 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Zinc added to vitamin A greatly reduced conjunctiva of the eye&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="here-is-the-73-minute-transcript">Here is the 73+ minute transcript&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-special-interview-with-chris-masterjohn-jan-2013">A Special Interview with Chris Masterjohn Jan 2013&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By Dr. Joseph Mercola&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Healthy bones need Ca, Silicon, Vitamins B, C, D, and K</title><link>/posts/healthy-bones-need-ca-silicon-vitamins-b-c-d-and-k.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/healthy-bones-need-ca-silicon-vitamins-b-c-d-and-k.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Update on nutrients involved in maintaining healthy bone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinol Nutr. 2012 Dec 27. pii: S1575-0922(12)00294-X. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.endonu.2012.09.006.">doi: 10.1016/j.endonu.2012.09.006.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Article in English, Spanish]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rondanelli M, Opizzi A, Perna S, Faliva MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Applied Health Sciences, Section of Human Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Medicine, University of Pavia, Endocrinology and Nutrition Unit, Azienda di Servizi alla Persona di Pavia, Pavia, Italy. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:mariangela.rondanelli@unipv.it">mariangela.rondanelli@unipv.it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis is a leading cause of morbidity and mortality in the elderly and influences quality of life, as well as life expectancy. Currently, there is a growing interest among the medical scientists in search of specific nutrients and/or bioactive compounds of natural origin for the prevention of disease and maintenance of bone health. Although calcium and vitamin D have been the primary focus of nutritional prevention of osteoporosis, a recent research has clarified the importance of several additional nutrients and food constituents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview of Vitamin K2 and Calcium Paradox author by Dr. Mercola</title><link>/posts/interview-of-vitamin-k2-and-calcium-paradox-author-by-dr-mercola.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/interview-of-vitamin-k2-and-calcium-paradox-author-by-dr-mercola.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="youtube-2012httpwwwyoutubecomwatchvfymexqnostq-1-hour---concerning-ca-k2-and-ostoeporosis">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fYMExQNosTQ">YouTube, 2012&lt;/a> 1 hour - concerning Ca, K2 and Ostoeporosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="interview-of-author-by-mercolahttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20121216vitamin-k2aspxe_cid20121216_snl_art_1-dec-2012">&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2012/12/16/vitamin-k2.aspx?e_cid=20121216_SNL_Art_1">Interview of author by Mercola&lt;/a> Dec 2012&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox--2012-bookpostsvitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book-review--and-table-of-contents-on-vitamindwiki">&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book">Vitamin K2 and the Calcium Paradox – 2012 book&lt;/a> Review and table of contents on VitaminDWiki&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/kate.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostsoverview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-765overview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-da">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 765">Overview Vitamin K and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights in BLUE added by VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolor00fbullet-points-by-vitamindwikispan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Bullet points by VitaminDWiki&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>100 micrograms of Vitamin K2 (MK-7) per 1,000 IU of vitamin D (example: 1,000 micrograms if taking 10,000 IU)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Vitamin D or Vitamin K2 may be a cause of Hypertension and Osteoporosis</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-or-vitamin-k2-may-be-a-cause-of-hypertension-and-osteoporosis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-or-vitamin-k2-may-be-a-cause-of-hypertension-and-osteoporosis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hip fractures greatly reduced by sunshine, vitamin D, and vitamin K – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-greatly-reduced-by-sunshine-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-greatly-reduced-by-sunshine-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="strategy-for-prevention-of-hip-fractures-in-patients-with-parkinsons-disease">Strategy for prevention of hip fractures in patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>World J Orthop. 2012 Sep 18;3(9):137-41. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5312/wjo.v3.i9.137.">doi: 10.5312/wjo.v3.i9.137.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Iwamoto J, Sato Y, Takeda T, Matsumoto H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jun Iwamoto, Tsuyoshi Takeda, Hideo Matsumoto, Institute for Integrated Sports Medicine, Keio University School of Medicine, Tokyo 160-8582, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypovitaminosis D and K due to malnutrition or sunlight deprivation, increased bone resorption due to immobilization, low bone mineral density (BMD) and an increased risk of falls may contribute to an increased risk of hip fractures in patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease. The purpose of the present study was to clarify the efficacy of interventions intended to prevent hip fractures in elderly patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease. PubMed was used to search the literature for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) regarding Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease and hip fractures. The inclusion criteria were 50 or more subjects per group and a study period of 1 year or longer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soft Bones, Hard Arteries, Vitamin D, Vitamin K2 and antibiotics</title><link>/posts/soft-bones-hard-arteries-vitamin-d-vitamin-k2-and-antibiotics.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/soft-bones-hard-arteries-vitamin-d-vitamin-k2-and-antibiotics.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>A balanced diet is no longer enough – supplements needed - VitaminDWiki</title><link>/posts/a-balanced-diet-is-no-longer-enough-supplements-needed-vitamindwiki.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-balanced-diet-is-no-longer-enough-supplements-needed-vitamindwiki.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Increasing bone mineral density increases breast cancer by at least 2X</title><link>/posts/increasing-bone-mineral-density-increases-breast-cancer-by-at-least-2x.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increasing-bone-mineral-density-increases-breast-cancer-by-at-least-2x.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="osteoporosis-myth-the-dangers-of-high-bone-mineral-densityhttpwwwgreenmedinfocomblogosteoporosis-myth-dangers-high-bone-mineral-densityutm_sourcewwwgreenmedinfocomutm_campaignb739c633e3-greenmedinfoutm_mediumemail-green-med-info">&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/osteoporosis-myth-dangers-high-bone-mineral-density?utm_source=www.GreenMedInfo.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=b739c633e3-Greenmedinfo&amp;amp;utm_medium=email">Osteoporosis Myth: The Dangers of High Bone Mineral Density&lt;/a> Green Med Info&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="the-following-was-clipped-from-the-above-item">The following was clipped from the above item&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of the most important facts about bone mineral density, conspicuously absent from discussion, is that having higher-than-normal bone density in middle-aged and older women actually &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">INCREASES their risk of breast cancer by 200-300%&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> , and this is according to research published in some of the world&amp;rsquo;s most well-respected and authoritative journals, e.g. Lancet, JAMA, NCI. (see citations below).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin K2 and the Calcium Paradox – 2012 book</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Healthy bones need: Calcium, Vitamin D, Magnesium, Silicon, Vitamin K, and Boron – 2012</title><link>/posts/healthy-bones-need-calcium-vitamin-d-magnesium-silicon-vitamin-k-and-boron-2012.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/healthy-bones-need-calcium-vitamin-d-magnesium-silicon-vitamin-k-and-boron-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Essential Nutrients for Bone Health and a Review of their Availability in the Average North American Diet.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open Orthop J. 2012;6:143-9&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price CT, Langford JR, Liporace FA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Orlando Health, 1222 Orange Avenue, 5 Floor, Orlando, Florida 32806, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis and low bone mineral density affect millions of Americans. The majority of adults in North America have insufficient intake of vitamin D and calcium along with inadequate exercise. Physicians are aware that vitamin D, calcium and exercise are essential for maintenance of bone health. Physicians are less likely to be aware that dietary insufficiencies of magnesium, silicon, Vitamin K, and boron are also widely prevalent, and each of these essential nutrients is an important contributor to bone health. In addition, specific nutritional factors may improve calcium metabolism and bone formation. It is the authors&amp;rsquo; opinion that nutritional supplements should attempt to provide ample, but not excessive, amounts of factors that are frequently insufficient in the typical American diet.In contrast to dietary insufficiencies, several nutrients that support bone health are readily available in the average American diet. These include zinc, manganese, and copper which may have adverse effects at higher levels of intake. Some multivitamins and bone support products provide additional quantities of nutrients that may be unnecessary or potentially harmful.The purpose of this paper is to identify specific nutritional components of bone health, the effects on bone, the level of availability in the average American diet, and the implications of supplementation for each nutritional component. A summary of recommended dietary supplementation is included.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased growth factors with vitamin D and Vitamin K2</title><link>/posts/increased-growth-factors-with-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k2.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-growth-factors-with-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k2.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="note-wikipedia-igf-1httpenwikipediaorgwikiinsulin-like_growth_factor_120-insulin-like-growth-factor-1">Note: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insulin-like_growth_factor_1%20">Wikipedia IGF-1&lt;/a> Insulin-like growth factor 1&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="email-to-dr-cannell-at-the-vitamin-d-council">Email to Dr. Cannell at the Vitamin D Council&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Dr Cannell, in response your suggestion in your April 30 Vitamin D Newsletter, I have&lt;/p>
&lt;p>had my IGF-1 measured, with a result of 83 ng/ml, reference level of 55-166. I should&lt;/p>
&lt;p>have mentioned that I am a 91.5 year old male in reasonably good health. I have been&lt;/p>
&lt;p>taking vitamin D since I read your article about vitamin D and influenza in an 2007&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin K helps vitamin D build bone</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k-helps-vitamin-d-build-bone.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k-helps-vitamin-d-build-bone.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="changes-in-parameters-of-bone-metabolism-in-postmenopausal-women-following-a-12-month-intervention-period-using-dairy-products-enriched-with-calcium-vitamin-d-and-phylloquinone-vitamin-k1-or-menaquinone-7-vitamin-k2-the-postmenopausal-health-study-ii">Changes in Parameters of Bone Metabolism in Postmenopausal Women Following a 12-Month Intervention Period Using Dairy Products Enriched with Calcium, Vitamin D, and Phylloquinone (Vitamin K1) or Menaquinone-7 (Vitamin K2): The Postmenopausal Health Study II&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>CALCIFIED TISSUE INTERNATIONAL&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 90, Number 4 (2012), 251-262, DOI: 10.1007/s00223-012-9571-z&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International Osteoporosis Foundation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spyridon Kanellakis, George Moschonis, Roxane Tenta, Anne Schaafsma, Ellen G. H. M. van den Heuvel, Nikolaos Papaioannou, George Lyritis and Yannis Manios&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Osteoporotic fractures marginally reduced with 800 IU of vitamin D and some vitamin K2</title><link>/posts/osteoporotic-fractures-marginally-reduced-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-some-vitamin-k2.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/osteoporotic-fractures-marginally-reduced-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-some-vitamin-k2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-k-supplementation-for-the-primary-prevention-of-osteoporotic-fractures-is-it-cost-effective-and-is-future-research-warranted">Vitamin K supplementation for the primary prevention of osteoporotic fractures: is it cost-effective and is future research warranted?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>O Gajic-Veljanoski, A M Bayoumi, G Tomlinson, K Khan and A M Cheung&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int 2012 Mar 8 PMID 22398856&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lifetime supplementation with vitamin K, vitamin D(3), and calcium is likely to reduce fractures and increase survival in postmenopausal women. It would be a cost-effective intervention at commonly used thresholds, but high uncertainty around the cost-effectiveness estimates persists. Further research on the effect of vitamin K on fractures is warranted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, K2, Magnesium, etc increase bone density when taking together</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-k2-magnesium-etc-increase-bone-density-when-taking-together.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-k2-magnesium-etc-increase-bone-density-when-taking-together.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reasons for low response to vitamin D</title><link>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#detailed-reasons-for-poor-response">Detailed Reasons for poor response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reasons-for-not-getting-benefits---span-stylecolorf00even-if-blood-tests-are-okspan">Reasons for not getting benefits - &lt;span style="color:#F00;">even if blood tests are OK&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsuv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual--2010big-differences-in-uvb-responsesa-20-to-36-ng-after-6-weeks">&lt;a href="/posts/uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: UV production of Vitamin D varies with the individual – 2010">Big differences in UVB responses&lt;/a>: 20 to 36 ng after 6 weeks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#alternate-sources-of-vitamin-d">Alternate sources of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/h4>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>~ 50% of all people have a low response to vitamin D3&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: bags under eyes are due to lack of vitamin D and vitamin K</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-bags-under-eyes-are-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-bags-under-eyes-are-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="winter-ages-a-womans-eyes-by-four-years-and-eight-months-experts-have-claimedhttpwwwtelegraphcoukhealthhealthnews8937939winter-makes-womens-eyes-look-olderhtml-uk-telegraph-dec-2011">&lt;a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/health/healthnews/8937939/Winter-makes-womens-eyes-look-older.html">Winter ages a woman&amp;rsquo;s eyes by four years and eight months, experts have claimed.&lt;/a> UK Telegraph Dec 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The thin skin under the eyes allows fluid to build up and dark circles and puffy eyes to appear Photo: ALAMY&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;921&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A team of beauty scientists studied the eyes of 5,000 women throughout the seasons and found bags under the eyes were significantly darker during the colder months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They concluded the ageing process is caused by a lack of sunlight which brings paler skin and emphasises the bags.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BONE SPURS not produced if have enough Vitamin D3, Vitamin K2, etc.</title><link>/posts/bone-spurs-not-produced-if-have-enough-vitamin-d3-vitamin-k2-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-spurs-not-produced-if-have-enough-vitamin-d3-vitamin-k2-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-toxicity--bone-spurs-httpwwwlivestrongcomarticle550949-vitamin-d-toxicity-bone-spurs20-at-livestrong">&lt;a href="http://www.livestrong.com/article/550949-vitamin-d-toxicity-bone-spurs/%20">VITAMIN D TOXICITY &amp;amp; BONE SPURS &lt;/a> at Livestrong&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nov 8, 2011 | By Sirah Dubois&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clips from the page&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bone-spurs">BONE SPURS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Bone spurs are abnormal calcifications that occur in places beyond the boundaries of normal bone. Bone spurs commonly form on the heel and around joints such as your knee, shoulder, spine and fingers. Bone spurs cause problems because they interfere with the motion of joints and often physically irritate surrounding connective tissue such as ligaments and tendons. Reduced range of motion, inflammation and pain are common symptoms of bone spurs. Conventional treatment for bone spurs involves surgical removal, but natural remedies attempt to reverse the biochemical or hormonal conditions that caused the spur in hopes your body will naturally dissolve it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Age-related diseases due to lack of nutrients like vitamin K – Ames Triage Theory</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-age-related-diseases-due-to-lack-of-nutrients-like-vitamin-k-ames-triage-theory.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-age-related-diseases-due-to-lack-of-nutrients-like-vitamin-k-ames-triage-theory.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="summary-body-does-the-best-it-can-when-lacking-nutrients-while-in-the-reproduction-years">Summary: body does the best it can when lacking nutrients while in the reproduction years.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="body-is-low-on-nutrients-such-as-vitamin-k-magnesium-and-selenium">Body is low on Nutrients such as Vitamin K, Magnesium, and Selenium&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Several items on this page&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="the-triage-theory-of-aginghttpwwwbiosyntrxcomarticlesphpid112820-june-10-2011-biosyntrx">&lt;a href="http://www.biosyntrx.com/articles.php?id=1128%20">The Triage Theory of Aging&lt;/a> June 10, 2011 BioSyntrx&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of our favorite nutrition researchers, Bruce Ames, PhD and his colleague, Joyce McCann, PhD, at The Nutrition and Metabolism Center, Children Hospital of Oakland, California continue to discoverer how vitamins and minerals may prevent age-related diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin K1 reduced hip fracture but Vitamin K2 did not</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k1-reduced-hip-fracture-but-vitamin-k2-did-not.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k1-reduced-hip-fracture-but-vitamin-k2-did-not.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="intake-of-vitamin-k1-and-k2-and-risk-of-hip-fractures-the-hordaland-health-study">Intake of vitamin K1 and K2 and risk of hip fractures: The Hordaland Health Study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ellen M. Apalset a,b &lt;a href="mailto:ellen.apalset@isf.uib.no">ellen.apalset@isf.uib.no&lt;/a>; Clara G. Gjesdal b, c, Geir E. Eide a, d, and Grethe S. Tell a,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Public Health and Primary Health Care, University of Bergen, Kalfarveien 31, N-5018 Bergen, Norway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Rheumatology, Haukeland University Hospital, N-5021 Bergen, Norway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c Section of Rheumatology, Institute of Medicine, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of synergy between vitamins D and K2 – 2010</title><link>/posts/review-of-synergy-between-vitamins-d-and-k2-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-synergy-between-vitamins-d-and-k2-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamins-d-and-k-as-pleiotropic-nutrients-clinical-importance-to-the-skeletal-and-cardiovascular-systems-and-preliminary-evidence-for-synergy">Vitamins D and K as pleiotropic nutrients: clinical importance to the skeletal and cardiovascular systems and preliminary evidence for synergy.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Altern Med Rev. 2010 Sep;15(3):199-222.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kidd PM, University of California, Berkeley, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:dockidd@dockidd.com">dockidd@dockidd.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamins D and K are lipid-phase nutrients that are pleiotropic - endowed with versatile homeostatic capacities at the organ, tissue, and cellular levels. Their metabolic and physiologic roles overlap considerably, as evidenced in the bone and cardiovascular systems. Vitamin D? (cholecalciferol, D?) is the prehormone for the vitamin D endocrine system. Vitamin D? undergoes initial enzymatic conversion to 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25D, calcidiol), then to the seco-steroid hormone 1alpha, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25D, calcitriol). Beyond its endocrine roles in calcium homeostasis, 1,25D likely has autocrine, paracrine, and intracrine effects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Do not reduce vitamin K if taking warfarin</title><link>/posts/do-not-reduce-vitamin-k-if-taking-warfarin.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/do-not-reduce-vitamin-k-if-taking-warfarin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="often-people-taking-warfarin-are-told-to-reduce-vitamin-k-intake">Often people taking warfarin are told to reduce vitamin K intake&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>!It appears that it exactly the opposite of what should be done&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/518758">Medscape&lt;/a> 2000&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>100 ug of vitamin D appeared to stabilize warfarin use&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.coumadin.com/vitamin_k.aspx">Counadin.com on Vitamin K&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Lots of details of how much vitamin K in different food types&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.clotcare.com/vitaminkandwarfarin.aspx">ClotCare 2004&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Should not reduce vitamin K when taking warfarin – doing so causes problems&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://lpi.oregonstate.edu/infocenter/vitamins/vitaminK/">Linus Pauling Institute&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“Warfarin prevents the recycling of vitamin K by inhibiting two important reactions and creating a functional vitamin K deficiency”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Vitamin D and Vitamin K: brittle bones and hardened arteries – LEF</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-brittle-bones-and-hardened-arteries-lef.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-brittle-bones-and-hardened-arteries-lef.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin K2 from natto improved bone mineral density</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k2-from-natto-improved-bone-mineral-density.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k2-from-natto-improved-bone-mineral-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="association-between-vitamin-k-intake-from-fermented-soybeans-natto-and-bone-mineral-density-in-elderly-japanese-men-the-fujiwara-kyo-osteoporosis-risk-in-men-formen-study">Association between vitamin K intake from fermented soybeans, natto, and bone mineral density in elderly Japanese men: the Fujiwara-kyo Osteoporosis Risk in Men (FORMEN) study&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis International; DOI: 10.1007/s00198-011-1594-1Online First™&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Y. Fujita, M. Iki, J. Tamaki, K. Kouda, A. Yura, E. Kadowaki, Y. Sato, J.-S. Moon, K. Tomioka and N. Okamoto, et al.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summary&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A cross-sectional analysis of 1,662 community dwelling elderly Japanese men suggested that habitual natto intake was significantly associated with higher bone mineral density (BMD). When adjustment was made for undercarboxylated osteocalcin levels, this association was insignificant, showing the natto–bone association to be primarily mediated by vitamin K.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Women with hip fractures very low on vitamins D3 and K</title><link>/posts/women-with-hip-fractures-very-low-on-vitamins-d3-and-k.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-with-hip-fractures-very-low-on-vitamins-d3-and-k.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-prevalence-of-hypovitaminosis-d-and-k-in-patients-with-hip-fracture">High prevalence of hypovitaminosis D and K in patients with hip fracture.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Asia Pac J Clin Nutr. 2011;20(1):56-61.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nakano T, Tsugawa N, Kuwabara A, Kamao M, Tanaka K, Okano T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Health and Nutrition, Osaka Shoin Women&amp;rsquo;s University, 4-2-26 Hishiyanishi, Higashiosaka-shi, Osaka 577-8550 Japan. &lt;a href="mailto:kuwabara.akiko@osaka-shoin.ac.jp">kuwabara.akiko@osaka-shoin.ac.jp&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although hip fracture is considered to be associated with hypovitaminosis D and K, few reports have previously studied both of them. We have studied the vitamin D- and K-status as well as the general nutritional status in ninety-nine patients with hip fracture. Mean serum concentration of 25hydroxy-vitamin D (25OH-D) in female fractured patients was only approximately &lt;strong>9 ng/mL&lt;/strong> , suggesting severe vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low cost cofactors for vitamin D</title><link>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-for-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-for-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="it-is-important-to-have-cofactors-when-taking-more-than-2000-iu-vitamin-d-average">It is IMPORTANT to have cofactors when taking more than 2000 IU vitamin D average&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/decrease-calcium-and-increase-magnesium-when-increasing-vitamin-d">Decrease Calcium and Increase Magnesium when increasing vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There is a lack of evidence of the interactions - the following are guesses based on incomplete information&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most studies are monotheraputic: e.g. supply Vitamin D, and rarely use any of the cofactors&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="update-2022-taking-most-of-my-supplements-as-pills---average-of-about-3day">Update 2022 taking most of my supplements as pills - average of about 3/day&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/herny-s-weekly-pills.jpg" alt="image" width="800">
&lt;p>Also take Magnesium Chloride as a liquid and Omega-3 as a cream&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Price and Masterjohn on Vitamin A Vitamin D and Vitamin K – 2010</title><link>/posts/price-and-masterjohn-on-vitamin-a-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/price-and-masterjohn-on-vitamin-a-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-2010.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>