<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Veterinary on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/veterinary-.html</link><description>Recent content in Veterinary on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/veterinary-/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Senior laying hens were fed super-doses of Vitamin D daily (human equiv. of 144,000 IU)</title><link>/posts/senior-laying-hens-were-fed-super-doses-of-vitamin-d-daily-human-equiv-of-144000-iu.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/senior-laying-hens-were-fed-super-doses-of-vitamin-d-daily-human-equiv-of-144000-iu.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dietary-super-doses-of-cholecalciferol-fed-to-aged-laying-hens-illustrates-limitation-of-2425-dihydroxycholecalciferol-conversion">Dietary Super-Doses of Cholecalciferol Fed to Aged Laying Hens Illustrates Limitation of 24,25-Dihydroxycholecalciferol Conversion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#iu-computations-by-vitamindwiki">IU Computations by VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="dietary-super-doses-of-cholecalciferol-fed-to-aged-laying-hens-illustrates-limitation-of-2425-dihydroxycholecalciferol-conversion">Dietary Super-Doses of Cholecalciferol Fed to Aged Laying Hens Illustrates Limitation of 24,25-Dihydroxycholecalciferol Conversion&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Developments in Nutrition Volume 8, Issue 5, May 2024, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cdnut.2024.102156">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cdnut.2024.102156&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matthew F Warren 1, Pete M Pitman 2, Dellila D Hodgson 1, Nicholas C Thompson 3, Kimberly A Livingston 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Older humans taking high concentrations of vitamin D3 supplementation for a prolonged time may be at risk of vitamin D toxicity. It is unclear how dietary super-doses (10,000 times greater than the requirement) can affect vitamin D3 status in aged animals. Aged laying hens could be a model to compare vitamin D3 supplementation effects with women in peri- or postmenopausal stages of life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cats often have similar range of Vitamin D as humans - 10 to 30 ng</title><link>/posts/cats-often-have-similar-range-of-vitamin-d-as-humans-10-to-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cats-often-have-similar-range-of-vitamin-d-as-humans-10-to-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#serum-concentration-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-apparently-healthy-cats-regarding-age-gender-breed-diet-type-reproductive-status-and-housing-condition">Serum concentration of 25-hydroxyvitamin D in apparently healthy cats regarding age, gender, breed, diet type, reproductive status, and housing condition&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="serum-concentration-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-apparently-healthy-cats-regarding-age-gender-breed-diet-type-reproductive-status-and-housing-condition">Serum concentration of 25-hydroxyvitamin D in apparently healthy cats regarding age, gender, breed, diet type, reproductive status, and housing condition&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Iran J Vet Res 2023;24(3):265-269. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.22099/IJVR.2023.46793.6721.">doi: 10.22099/IJVR.2023.46793.6721.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S Amirnezhad 1, S Ahmadi Sheikhsarmast 2, J Khoshnegah 3, M Mohri 3&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/png/cats.png" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;h5 id="span-stylecolor00fcommercial-cat-food-has-a-lot-of-vitamin-dspan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Commercial cat food has a lot of Vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Background: Optimal vitamin D levels for an effective role in immune function and rickets prevention are thought to vary, but have not yet been definitively determined. Reports on reference values of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) in cats are limited.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Feed Additives as Antiviral Agents: Probiotics, Vitamin D, Zn, Se, etc.</title><link>/posts/feed-additives-as-antiviral-agents-probiotics-vitamin-d-zn-se-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/feed-additives-as-antiviral-agents-probiotics-vitamin-d-zn-se-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#feed-additives-as-antiviral-agents-book-chapter">Feed Additives as Antiviral Agents (book chapter)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="feed-additives-as-antiviral-agents-book-chapter">Feed Additives as Antiviral Agents (book chapter)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-42855-5_12">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-42855-5_12&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. R. Yasmin, M. N. Sohaimi, S. N. A. Azaman, S. H. Nur-Fazila &amp;amp; F. M. A. Amirul&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Viral infection is a major devastating challenge in the livestock industry. Hardy to completely eradicate the virus, the emergence of new variants accompanied by high morbidity and mortality further substantiates the problems in poultry, ruminant, and swine farms. Notifiable diseases caused by virus infection such as avian influenza (AI), infectious bursal disease (IBD), Newtle disease (ND), foot and mouth disease (FMD), Aujeszky’s disease, classical swine fever (CSF), and other viral diseases are controlled by vaccination, proper husbandry, and strict biosecurity. The nutritional factors also play a pivotal role in ensuring optimum growth and immunity of the livestock as well as safeguarding sustainable food security as a protein source to human. Continuous global demand requires crucial maintenance of the good quality and value of livestock-based protein.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB not help chickens much (no surprise – shined on feathers, not legs)</title><link>/posts/uvb-not-help-chickens-much-no-surprise-shined-on-feathers-not-legs.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-not-help-chickens-much-no-surprise-shined-on-feathers-not-legs.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#minimal-effects-of-ultraviolet-light-supplementation-on-egg-production-egg-and-bone-quality-and-health-during-early-lay-of-laying-hens">Minimal effects of ultraviolet light supplementation on egg production, egg and bone quality, and health during early lay of laying hens&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="minimal-effects-of-ultraviolet-light-supplementation-on-egg-production-egg-and-bone-quality-and-health-during-early-lay-of-laying-hens">Minimal effects of ultraviolet light supplementation on egg production, egg and bone quality, and health during early lay of laying hens&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PeerJ . 2023 Mar 15;11:e14997. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.14997">doi: 10.7717/peerj.14997&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Md Sohel Rana 1 2 3, Jonathon Clay 1, Prafulla Regmi 4, Dana L M Campbell 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chicken vision is sensitive to ultraviolet (UV) light containing the UVA spectrum, while UVB plays a key role in the endogenous production of vitamin D3. However, commercially available light sources are typically deficient in the UV spectrum and thus may not adequately fulfill the lighting requirements of indoor-housed laying hens. We hypothesized that supplementary UVB light may improve egg production and egg quality, and bone health during early lay relative to UVA supplementation or standard control lighting. To investigate the effects of UV light supplementation, an experiment was conducted on 252 ISA Brown hens during 16 to 27 weeks of age. Birds were housed in eighteen pens (14 hens/pen) under three different light treatment groups each with six replications: (i) UVO: standard control lighting with LED white light, (ii) UVA: control lighting plus supplemental daylight with an avian bulb, and (iii) UVA/B: control lighting plus a supplemental full spectrum reptile bulb containing both UVA and UVB wavelengths. Hen-day egg production and egg quality, blood parameters including plasma Ca and P, and serum 25(OH)D3, and hen body weight and external health scoring were measured at different age points; while bone quality was assessed at the end of the experiment at 27 weeks. Data were analyzed in JMP® 16.0 using general linear mixed models with a level set at 0.05. Results showed that UVA and UVA/B supplemented birds reached sexual maturity (50% production) 3 and 1 day earlier, respectively, than control birds. There was a trend for UV lights to increase hen-day egg production (P = 0.06). Among egg quality traits, only eggshell reflectivity and yolk index were affected by UV lights (P = 0.02 and 0.01, respectively); however, most of the egg quality traits changed over age (all P &amp;lt; 0.01). Post-hoc tests showed higher serum 25(OH)D3 in the UVA/B group relative to control hens (P &amp;lt; 0.05); but there was no treatment effect on plasma Ca and P or on bone quality parameters (all P &amp;gt; 0.05). A significant interaction was observed between light treatment and age for the number of comb wounds (P = 0.0004), with the UV supplemented hens showing more comb wounds after 24 weeks. These results demonstrated that supplemental UVA/B light had minimal effects on egg production and egg quality, whereas, UVA/B exposure may increase vitamin D3 synthesis during the early laying period. The optimum duration of exposure and level of intensity needs to be determined to ensure these benefits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2,000 IU of Vitamin D per kg of food – best growth, bone strength, etc. (pig trial)</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-of-food-best-growth-bone-strength-etc-pig-trial.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-of-food-best-growth-bone-strength-etc-pig-trial.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effects-of-25ohvd3-on-growth-performance-pork-quality-and-calcium-deposit-in-growing-finishing-pigs">Effects of 25(OH)VD3 on Growth Performance, Pork Quality and Calcium Deposit in Growing-Finishing Pigs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="effects-of-25ohvd3-on-growth-performance-pork-quality-and-calcium-deposit-in-growing-finishing-pigs">Effects of 25(OH)VD3 on Growth Performance, Pork Quality and Calcium Deposit in Growing-Finishing Pigs&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Animals (Basel) . 2022 Dec 26;13(1):86. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ani13010086.">doi: 10.3390/ani13010086.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zeyu Zhang 1, Gang Zhang 1, Jindang Cao 2, Baoqin Qiu 2, Xiaoyu Qin 2, Jinbiao Zhao 1&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/pig-tibia.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>The study was conducted to evaluate the effects of 25(OH)VD3 with different inclusion levels of &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">0, 25, 50 and 75 µg/kg in the diet&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> on growth performance, nutrient digestibility, bone properties and pork quality in growing-finishing pigs. The results showed that the average daily gain (p &amp;lt; 0.05) and body weight (p &amp;lt; 0.10) of pigs showed a trend of increasing quadratically as inclusion levels of 25(OH)VD3 increased.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More UVB results in more Vitamin D (chimps in zoos in this case)</title><link>/posts/more-uvb-results-in-more-vitamin-d-chimps-in-zoos-in-this-case.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-uvb-results-in-more-vitamin-d-chimps-in-zoos-in-this-case.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-in-chimpanzees-in-human-care-a-europe-wide-study">Vitamin D status in chimpanzees in human care: a Europe wide study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-related-in-vitamindwiki">See related in VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-chimpanzees-in-human-care-a-europe-wide-study">Vitamin D status in chimpanzees in human care: a Europe wide study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Scientific Reports volume 12, Article number: 17625 (2022)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sophie Moittié, Rachel Jarvis, Stephan Bandelow, Sarah Byrne, Phillipa Dobbs, Melissa Grant, Christopher Reeves, Kate White, Mátyás Liptovszky &amp;amp; Kerstin Baiker&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/chimps.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/chimpanzees-low-d-compresspdf.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki &lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While vitamin D deficiency is a public health concern in humans, comparatively little is known about vitamin D levels in non-human primates. Vitamin D plays a crucial role in overall health and its deficiency is associated with a range of disorders, including cardiovascular disease, which is a leading cause of death in great apes. Serum samples (n = 245) from chimpanzees (Pan troglodytes) housed at 32 European zoos were measured for 25-hydroxyvitamin D2, 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 and total 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) using liquid chromatography and tandem mass spectrometry. Of these samples, 33.1% indicated inadequate vitamin D status, using the human reference interval (25-OHD &amp;lt; 50 nmol/L). The season of the year, health status of the animal, and the provision of daily outdoor access had a significant effect on vitamin D status. This is the first large-scale study on vitamin D status of non-human great apes in human care. Inadequate 25-OHD serum concentrations are widespread in the chimpanzee population in Europe and could be a risk factor for the development of idiopathic myocardial fibrosis, a major cause of mortality in this species, as well as other diseases. A review of husbandry and nutrition practices is recommended to ensure optimal vitamin D supply for these endangered animals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is important for pregnancies (pigs as well as people)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-important-for-pregnancies-pigs-as-well-as-people.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-important-for-pregnancies-pigs-as-well-as-people.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#associations-between-maternal-vitamin-d-status-and-porcine-litter-characteristics-throughout-gestation">Associations between maternal vitamin D status and porcine litter characteristics throughout gestation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="associations-between-maternal-vitamin-d-status-and-porcine-litter-characteristics-throughout-gestation">Associations between maternal vitamin D status and porcine litter characteristics throughout gestation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Anim Sci Biotechnol. 2022 Sep 20;13(1):106. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/s40104-022-00760-w.">doi: 10.1186/s40104-022-00760-w.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Claire Stenhouse 1 2 , Emma Hurst 3 , Richard J Mellanby 3 , Cheryl J Ashworth 4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emerging evidence suggests an important role of vitamin D in the establishment and maintenance of pregnancy, and the regulation of foetal growth across mammalian species. However, the temporal changes in maternal vitamin D status throughout gestation in the pig and the relationship between maternal vitamin D status and litter characteristics of interest across gestation remain poorly understood and under-investigated. The abundance of 25(OH)D in maternal plasma was quantified by HPLC-MS/MS at gestational days (GD) 18, 30, 45, 60 and 90 (n = 5-11 gilsts/GD).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doggie dementia 6.5X more likely if not get exercise (probably low vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/doggie-dementia-65x-more-likely-if-not-get-exercise-probably-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/doggie-dementia-65x-more-likely-if-not-get-exercise-probably-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cats-and-dogs-get-dementia-heres-how-to-spot-signs-and-support-pets---aug2023">Cats and dogs get dementia. Here’s how to spot signs and support pets - Aug 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#will-your-dog-get-dementia-a-large-new-study-offersclues">Will Your Dog Get Dementia? A Large New Study Offers Clues.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also">See also&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="cats-and-dogs-get-dementia-heres-how-to-spot-signs-and-support-pets---aug2023">Cats and dogs get dementia. Here’s how to spot signs and support pets - Aug 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2023/08/31/cats-dogs-dementia-signs-support-treatment/?utm_campaign=wp_post_most&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;amp;wpisrc=nl_most">Washington Post&lt;/a> Vitamin D is NOT mentioned&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Experts aren’t sure how many companion animals suffer from dementia. Estimates range from 14 to 35 percent of the pet dog population age 8 and older, according to one &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0195561619300233?via=ihub">study&lt;/a>. Another &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S1938973611000079">study&lt;/a> suggests nearly one-third of cats ages 11 to 14 and 50 percent of cats 15 and older are affected. Many experts believe these numbers are probably conservative.&amp;quot;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="will-your-dog-get-dementia-a-large-new-study-offersclues">Will Your Dog Get Dementia? A Large New Study Offers Clues.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/25/health/dog-dementia-causes.html">New York Times Aug 26, 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcidiol (bacterial fermentation-derived vitamin D) OK with pigs (perhaps lower cost)</title><link>/posts/calcidiol-bacterial-fermentation-derived-vitamin-d-ok-with-pigs-perhaps-lower-cost.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcidiol-bacterial-fermentation-derived-vitamin-d-ok-with-pigs-perhaps-lower-cost.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#efficacy-and-safety-of-a-novel-source-of-dietary-25-hydroxycholecalciferol-in-growing-pigs">Efficacy and safety of a novel source of dietary 25-hydroxycholecalciferol in growing pigs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="efficacy-and-safety-of-a-novel-source-of-dietary-25-hydroxycholecalciferol-in-growing-pigs">Efficacy and safety of a novel source of dietary 25-hydroxycholecalciferol in growing pigs&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Anim Sci . 2022 Aug 12;skac260. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/skac260.">doi: 10.1093/jas/skac260.&lt;/a> PDF behind $39 paywall&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorge L Sandoval 1 , Diego E Ventura 1 , Orlando B Fiallos 1 , Brian L Anderson 2 , J Chris Sparks 3 , Jessica D Starkey 1 , Charles W Starkey 1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many Vitamin D similarities: people and cows</title><link>/posts/many-vitamin-d-similarities-people-and-cows.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-vitamin-d-similarities-people-and-cows.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-few-of-the-many-vitamin-d-similarities-in-the-study">A few of the many Vitamin D similarities in the study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-in-dairy-cows-metabolism-status-and-functions-in-the-immune-system">Vitamin D in dairy cows: metabolism, status and functions in the immune system&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#abstract">ABSTRACT&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#metabolism-of-vitamin-d">Metabolism of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#assessment-of-the-vitamin-d-status-of-dairy-cows">Assessment of the vitamin D status of dairy cows&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#functions-of-vitamin-d">Functions of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-the-immune-system">The role of vitamin D in the immune system&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#conclusion-and-future-directions">Conclusion and future directions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-related-items-in-vitamindwiki">Some related items in VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#gene-charts-this-study-and-vitamindwikitagsvitamindwikihtml">Gene charts: this study and &lt;a href="/tags/vitamindwiki.html">VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="a-few-of-the-many-vitamin-d-similarities-in-the-study">A few of the many Vitamin D similarities in the study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If less time in the sun, more vitamin D supplementation (or UVB) is needed&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No tuberculosis if more than 80 ng of vitamin D (cattle)</title><link>/posts/no-tuberculosis-if-more-than-80-ng-of-vitamin-d-cattle.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-tuberculosis-if-more-than-80-ng-of-vitamin-d-cattle.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reduced-levels-of-serum-25ohd-3-are-associated-with-tuberculosis-positive-cattle-under-conditions-of-high-natural-exposure-to-mycobacterium-bovis">Reduced levels of serum 25(OH)D 3 are associated with tuberculosis positive cattle under conditions of high natural exposure to Mycobacterium bovis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#other-references">Other references&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="reduced-levels-of-serum-25ohd-3-are-associated-with-tuberculosis-positive-cattle-under-conditions-of-high-natural-exposure-to-mycobacterium-bovis">Reduced levels of serum 25(OH)D 3 are associated with tuberculosis positive cattle under conditions of high natural exposure to Mycobacterium bovis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Comp Immunol Microbiol Infect Dis&amp;hellip; 2022 Jan 10;81:101746. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cimid.2022.101746">doi: 10.1016/j.cimid.2022.101746&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sofía López-Constantino 1, Evaristo A Barragan 2, Edgar Alfonseca-Silva 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum vitamin D (25(OH)D3) concentrations of &amp;lt; 30 ng/mL in cattle are insufficient to induce an adequate immune response against intracellular pathogens, which suggests that the efficacy of the immune response may be highly dependent on the bioavailability of 25(OH)D3. This study shows an overview of both in vitro and in vivo 25(OH)D3-mediated immune modulation amongst dairy cattle naturally exposed to M. bovis. Tuberculin status was confirmed by interferon gamma release assay (IGRA), and natural exposure was demonstrated by polymerase chain reaction (PCR). Tuberculin (-) cattle have a higher serum concentration of 25(OH)D3 (X¯= 87.12 ng/mL) when compared to tuberculin (+) cattle (X¯ = 45.86 ng/mL). Reduced serum 25(OH)D3 levels are associated with the presence of bovine TB, and &lt;strong>serum 25(OH)D3 levels of &amp;gt; 80 ng/mL are necessary to counteract infection by M. bovis&lt;/strong> . Kill assays were performed to evaluate in vitro 25(OH)D3 modulation of intracellular M. bovis growth in bovine macrophages, which showed that reduced serum 25(OH)D3 levels are associated with diminished mycobactericidal capacity in this experimental model. On the other hand, increased 25(OH)D3 in culture media enhances phagocytosis and nitric oxide production, which in turn improves capacity to combat M. bovis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>450,000 IU of Vitamin D daily too much for a cat</title><link>/posts/450000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-too-much-for-a-cat.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/450000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-too-much-for-a-cat.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="case-report-a-case-series-linked-to-vitamin-d-excess-in-pet-food-cholecalciferol-vitamin-d3-toxicity-observed-in-five-cats">Case Report: A Case Series Linked to Vitamin D Excess in Pet Food: Cholecalciferol (Vitamin D3) Toxicity Observed in Five Cats&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Front. Vet. Sci. 8:707741. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2021.707741">doi: 10.3389/fvets.2021.707741&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carla G. Vecchiato1*, Costanza Delsante1, Giorgia Galiazzo1, Simone Perfetti1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carlo Pinna1, Maria C. Sabetti1, Laura Zagnoli2, Giacomo Biagi1f and Marco Pietra1f&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Veterinary Medical Sciences, University of Bologna, Ozzano dell’Emilia, Italy,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Clinica Veterinaria dell’ Orologio - AniCura, Sasso Marconi, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>The unactivated vitamin D in the kitten food was, for some reason, 40X higher than it should have been&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Several advanced-maternal-age problems reduced if given Vitamin D during pregnancy (mice in this case)</title><link>/posts/several-advanced-maternal-age-problems-reduced-if-given-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-mice-in-this-case.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/several-advanced-maternal-age-problems-reduced-if-given-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-mice-in-this-case.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-mice-with-advanced-maternal-age-and-cognitive-function-of-the-offspring">Vitamin D supplementation in mice with advanced maternal age and cognitive function of the offspring&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Transl Res. 2021 Jul 15;13(7):7641-7653. eCollection 2021.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dao Li 1 2, Kai Wang 1, Zhuanhong Yang 3, Hui Li 4, Suqing Wang 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/advanced-maternal-age-compressed.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the effects of vitamin D supplementation before pregnancy on the offspring&amp;rsquo;s cognitive function in mice with advanced maternal age (AMA). Thirty-two-week-old female mice were randomly allocated into two groups: the 32 W+VD group (receiving 10 IU/g body weight vitamin D3 dissolved in 200 μl corn oil per day), and the 32 W group (receiving 200 μl corn oil per day) for one week before mating with ten-week-old male mice. Another group of eight-week-old female mice was given 200 μl corn oil for the same period of time and set as normal childbearing age controls (8 W group). The pregnancy outcomes were recorded and the offspring at the age of 6 weeks were subjected to behavioral tests. Finally, the expression level and distribution of neural cell markers in the offspring&amp;rsquo;s hippocampus were detected by immunofluorescence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcidiol increased blood levels of Vitamin D in one month (dogs)</title><link>/posts/calcidiol-increased-blood-levels-of-vitamin-d-in-one-month-dogs.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcidiol-increased-blood-levels-of-vitamin-d-in-one-month-dogs.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cows gave more milk after pregnancy if given Calcidiol (semi-activated Vitamin D) – RCT</title><link>/posts/cows-gave-more-milk-after-pregnancy-if-given-calcidiol-semi-activated-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cows-gave-more-milk-after-pregnancy-if-given-calcidiol-semi-activated-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effect-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-during-prepartum-transition-and-lactation-on-production-reproduction-and-health-of-lactating-dairy-cows">Effect of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 during prepartum transition and lactation on production, reproduction, and health of lactating dairy cows&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#treatment-plan-i-could-not-figure-it-out">Treatment plan (I could not figure it out)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="effect-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-during-prepartum-transition-and-lactation-on-production-reproduction-and-health-of-lactating-dairy-cows">Effect of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 during prepartum transition and lactation on production, reproduction, and health of lactating dairy cows&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Dairy Science. online 2 March 2021, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3168/jds.2020-18901">https://doi.org/10.3168/jds.2020-18901&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>H.M.Golder1J.McGrath2I.J.Lean1&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4 sample herds     CON = no vitamin D     TRT = 2 mg of calcdiol daily&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Immune system is improved by Vitamin D, A, C, and E (chickens)</title><link>/posts/immune-system-is-improved-by-vitamin-d-a-c-and-e-chickens.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/immune-system-is-improved-by-vitamin-d-a-c-and-e-chickens.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="centennial-review-effects-of-vitamins-a-d-e-and-c-on-the-chicken-immune-system">Centennial Review: Effects of vitamins A, D, E, and C on the chicken immune system&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>2021 Poultry Science 100:100930 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016Zj.psj.2020.12.027">https://doi.org/10.1016Zj.psj.2020.12.027&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bahram Shojadoost, Alexander Yitbarek, Mohammadali Alizadeh, Raveendra R. Kulkarni. Jake Astill, Nitish Boodhoo, and Shayan Sharif &lt;a href="mailto:shayan@uoguelph.ca">shayan@uoguelph.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pathobiology, Ontario Veterinary College, University of Guelph, Guelph, N1G 2W1, Ontario, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
#### Various bird flus have infected Humans, but 
 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; they have not yet mutated to allow transmission between humans
&lt;p>&lt;strong>VitaminDWiki became aware that such a mutation could result in a pandemic far worse that COVID-19&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D types and amounts vary widely between humans and animals</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-types-and-amounts-vary-widely-between-humans-and-animals.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-types-and-amounts-vary-widely-between-humans-and-animals.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Poor immune system associated with low Vitamin D (dogs in this case)</title><link>/posts/poor-immune-system-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-dogs-in-this-case.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poor-immune-system-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-dogs-in-this-case.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>3 proven ways to increase Vitamin D in eggs</title><link>/posts/3-proven-ways-to-increase-vitamin-d-in-eggs.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-proven-ways-to-increase-vitamin-d-in-eggs.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chicken bones, eggs, and activated vitamin D in eggs increased with 2 hours of daily UVB</title><link>/posts/chicken-bones-eggs-and-activated-vitamin-d-in-eggs-increased-with-2-hours-of-daily-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chicken-bones-eggs-and-activated-vitamin-d-in-eggs-increased-with-2-hours-of-daily-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/hens-with-vitamin-d-were-better-in-at-least-5-ways-rct">Hens with Vitamin D were better in at least 5 ways – RCT Aug 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/in-less-than-3-weeks-chickens-have-problems-if-they-do-not-have-vitamin-d">In less than 3 weeks chickens have problems if they do not have vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reminder: Before the 1940&amp;rsquo;s all hens had access to the sunshine.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/outdoor-chickens.jpg" alt="image" style="max-width: 600px;">
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/eggs.pdf">Download the PDF from Sci-Hub via VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Caged laying hens are prone to calcium deficiencies, resulting in osteoporosis and egg quality deterioration during the later phase of the laying cycle. Fluorescent light and light-emitting diodes (LEDs), which are widely used in poultry houses now, are both deficient in ultraviolet (UV) light, the lack of which is detrimental to chickens&amp;rsquo; welfare and health. This study was conducted to investigate the effects of UVB light supplementation using LEDs on the bone traits, blood parameters, laying performance, and egg quality for caged laying hens at 68-75 weeks. In total, 120 Jingfen laying hens were randomly assigned to four different groups, with three replicates in each group (10 hens in each cage as a replicate). UVB-LED lamps installed under the feed troughs were used to provide UVB light (296-316 nm) for the birds in the three treatment groups (1 h, 2 h, and 3 h UVB supplementation per day, respectively), while the control group was not exposed to UVB-LED light. Bone traits, egg quality, and amounts of calcium (Ca), phosphorus (P), 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25(OH)D3), 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3), and 7-dehydrocholesterol (7-DHC) in both the serum and egg yolks were tested during the experiment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many non-bone diseases associated with low Vitamin D (dog and cats in this study)</title><link>/posts/many-non-bone-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-dog-and-cats-in-this-study.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-non-bone-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-dog-and-cats-in-this-study.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-metabolism-in-dogs-and-cats-and-its-relation-to-diseases-not-associated-with-bone-metabolism">Vitamin D metabolism in dogs and cats and its relation to diseases not associated with bone metabolism.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr (Berl). 2019 Dec 5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/jpn.13259">doi: 10.1111/jpn.13259&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zafalon RVA1, Risolia LW1, Pedrinelli V1, Vendramini THA1, Rodrigues RBA1, Amaral AR1, Kogika MM1, Brunetto MA1.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/tags/human-health-problems-were-proven-to-be-fought-by-vitamin-d.html">Human Health Problems were proven to be fought by Vitamin D&lt;/a> by Nov 2018&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/dogs-and-cats-non-bone-vitamin-d-problems.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="a-few-of-the-columns-from-table">A few of the columns from table&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/dc1.jpg" alt="image" width="450">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/dc2.jpg" alt="image" width="450">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/dc3.jpg" alt="image" width="450">
&lt;p>Due to the presence of receptors in the cells of numerous body tissues, vitamin D is associated with several physiological functions that go beyond calcium and phosphorus homoeostasis and control of bone metabolism in the body. In humans, several studies have associated lower vitamin D concentrations with numerous diseases, such as cancer, heart disease, autoimmune diseases and infectious diseases, and also with an increase in the total mortality rate of the population. Recently, this nutrient started to gain importance in veterinary medicine, and several articles have shown a correlation between low vitamin D status and diseases unrelated to bone metabolism. The present review aims to highlight the recent publications that investigated this relationship, bringing the evidence that exists so far in dogs and cats.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon cancer increased in mice fed a western diet (low vitamin D, low fiber, etc)</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-increased-in-mice-fed-a-western-diet-low-vitamin-d-low-fiber-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-increased-in-mice-fed-a-western-diet-low-vitamin-d-low-fiber-etc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fat-soluble vitamins critical for conception, pregnancy and breast feeding (pigs)</title><link>/posts/fat-soluble-vitamins-critical-for-conception-pregnancy-and-breast-feeding-pigs.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fat-soluble-vitamins-critical-for-conception-pregnancy-and-breast-feeding-pigs.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="critical-times-for-fat-soluble-vitamin-intake-for-todays-swinehttpswwwnationalhogfarmercomnutritioncritical-times-fat-soluble-vitamin-intake-todays-swine-national-hog-farmer">&lt;a href="https://www.nationalhogfarmer.com/nutrition/critical-times-fat-soluble-vitamin-intake-todays-swine">Critical times for fat-soluble vitamin intake for today&amp;rsquo;s swine&lt;/a> National Hog Farmer&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>“The 2012 NRC Nutrient Requirements of Swine has the most recent requirements for fat-soluble vitamins. Requirements for vitamin A and vitamin E were not increased from the 1998 NRC publication, but the &lt;strong>vitamin D requirement was increased four-fold from 200 to 800 I.U. per kg diet.&lt;/strong> ”&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Thus Pigs eating 1 kilogram of food per day should get at least 800 IU of vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chicken meat with lots of Omega-3 – available, US patent applied for</title><link>/posts/chicken-meat-with-lots-of-omega-3-available-us-patent-applied-for.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chicken-meat-with-lots-of-omega-3-available-us-patent-applied-for.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="many-chicken-breeders-are-addiing-omega-3-to-the-feed">Many chicken breeders are addiing Omega-3 to the feed&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.texasgrassfedbeef.com/faq/omega-3-chicken-information">Example -Slanker&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/slanker-chicken.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://iqchicken.com/about-iqchicken/nutritional-information/good-bad-fats-nutrition-charts/">Example - IQChicken&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/iq-chicken.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="patent-application-add-omega-3-to-chicken-feed-so-as-to-increase-human-blood-levels-of-omega-3">Patent application: Add Omega-3 to chicken feed so as to increase human blood levels of Omega-3&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>METHODS OF INCREASING THE OMEGA -3 POLYUNSATURATED FATTY ACIDS LEVELS IN HUMAN PLASMA - Patent Application July 2019&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/patent-application-omega-3-chicken.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="omega-3-in-other-human-food">Omega-3 in other human food&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/omega-3-added-to-cattle-feed-increases-the-level-in-milk">Omega-3 added to cattle feed increases the level in milk – Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D in eggs increased 4X after UV lighting near legs was added</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-in-eggs-increased-4x-after-uv-lighting-near-legs-was-added.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-in-eggs-increased-4x-after-uv-lighting-near-legs-was-added.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Domesticated animals vary in amount and causes of bone diseases</title><link>/posts/domesticated-animals-vary-in-amount-and-causes-of-bone-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/domesticated-animals-vary-in-amount-and-causes-of-bone-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>The pathology of vitamin D deficiency in domesticated animals: An evolutionary and comparative overview)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International Journal of Paleopathology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elizabeth W. Uhl&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pathology, College of Veterinary Medicine, 501 DW Brooks Drive, The University of Georgia, Athens, GA, 30602-7388, United States&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although &lt;strong>vitamin D&lt;/strong> is critical to calcium/phosphorus homeostasis, bone formation and remodeling, there is evolution-based variation between species in &lt;strong>vitamin D&lt;/strong> metabolism and susceptibility to rickets and osteomalacia. Most herbivores produce &lt;strong>vitamin D&lt;/strong> 3 in response to sunlight, but dogs and cats have generally lost the ability as carnivore diets are rich in &lt;strong>vitamin D&lt;/strong> . Nutritional deficiencies and/or poor exposure to sunlight can induce rickets in birds, swine, cattle and sheep, but horses are less susceptible as they have evolved a calcium homeostasis that is quite different than other animals. Adaptations to specific environments also affect disease incidence: llamas/alpacas out of their natural high altitude intense solar radiation environments are highly susceptible to &lt;strong>vitamin D&lt;/strong> deficiency. The pathology of rickets/osteomalacia is similar across species, however fibrous osteodystrophy is more common and may also be present. Rickets/osteomalacia were likely more common in animals before the advent of commercial diets, but can be difficult to definitively diagnose especially in single archeological specimens. Consideration of species susceptibility, location - especially in terms of latitude, and any available information on diet, season of occurrence, husbandry practices or descriptions of affected animals can support the diagnosis of metabolic bone disease in animals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – dinosaur extinction due to low vitamin D (fewer eggs hatched)</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-dinosaur-extinction-due-to-low-vitamin-d-fewer-eggs-hatched.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-dinosaur-extinction-due-to-low-vitamin-d-fewer-eggs-hatched.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="why-did-the-dinosaurs-become-extinct-could-cholecalciferol-vitamin-d3-deficiency-be-the-answer">Why did the dinosaurs become extinct? Could cholecalciferol (vitamin D3) deficiency be the answer?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Nutritional Science (2019), vol. 8, e9, page 1 of 5 doi:10.1017/jns.2019.7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D. R. Fraser&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sydney School of Veterinary Science, Faculty of Science, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW 2006, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/hens-with-vitamin-d-were-better-in-at-least-5-ways-rct">Hens with Vitamin D were better in at least 5 ways – RCT Aug 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/hens-fed-a-form-of-vitamin-d-had-more-hatchable-eggs-and-more-immune-chicks">Hens fed a form of vitamin D had more hatchable eggs and more immune chicks – March 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heavier offspring if mothers had more sunlight (sheep in this case)</title><link>/posts/heavier-offspring-if-mothers-had-more-sunlight-sheep-in-this-case.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heavier-offspring-if-mothers-had-more-sunlight-sheep-in-this-case.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="investigation-of-relationship-between-vitamin-d-status-and-reproductive-fitness-in-scottish-hill-sheep">Investigation of relationship between vitamin D status and reproductive fitness in Scottish hill sheep.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Sci Rep. 2019 Feb 4;9(1):1162. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-37843-6.">doi: 10.1038/s41598-018-37843-6.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhou P1,2, McEvoy TG2, Gill AC1,3, Lambe NR2, Morgan-Davies CR2, Hurst E1, Sargison ND1, Mellanby RJ4.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-animal-laboratory-more-twins-if-more-vitamin-d-sheep">Vitamin D Animal Laboratory - more twins if more vitamin D (sheep) &lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/more-surviving-offspring-if-mother-had-high-vitamin-d-sheep-in-this-case">More surviving offspring if mother had high vitamin D (sheep in this case) – Jan 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/lambs-get-10x-more-vitamin-d3-in-their-milk-formula-than-humans">Lambs get 10X more vitamin D3 in their milk formula than humans&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some Dog food had excess vitamin D, first dry food, then canned – Speculation</title><link>/posts/some-dog-food-had-excess-vitamin-d-first-dry-food-then-canned-speculation.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-dog-food-had-excess-vitamin-d-first-dry-food-then-canned-speculation.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="update-on-hills-may-2019">Update on Hill&amp;rsquo;s May 2019&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://news.vin.com/VINNews.aspx?articleId=53544">https://news.vin.com/VINNews.aspx?articleId=53544&lt;/a>|Hill’s adds lot of vitamin D-laden dog food to recall list]&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>25 class action suits so far&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hill&amp;rsquo; is able to put the recall costs on the as yet unamed supplier&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="why-so-many-excess-vitamin-d-recallshttpstruthaboutpetfoodcomwhy-so-many-excess-vitamin-d-recalls-truth-about-pet-foodcom">&lt;a href="https://truthaboutpetfood.com/why-so-many-excess-vitamin-d-recalls/">Why so many excess Vitamin D Recalls?&lt;/a> truth about pet food.com&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“After the first two initial dog food recalls, seven more dry dog food recalls occurred up to December 5, 2018. For 8 weeks we saw no new excess Vitamin D recalls, and then on January 31, 2019 we learned of a Hill’s Pet Nutrition recall for 25 different varieties of canned dog foods.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Animal Laboratory - more twins if more vitamin D (sheep)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-animal-laboratory-more-twins-if-more-vitamin-d-sheep.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-animal-laboratory-more-twins-if-more-vitamin-d-sheep.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitdalhttpmellanbylaborgabout-scotland">&lt;a href="http://mellanbylab.org/about/">VitDal&lt;/a> Scotland&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dHRVM4gbE8U&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be">YouTube Video- last 40 minutes has some vitamin D items&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor00fmore-twins-if-more-vitamin-dspan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">More Twins if more vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/lambs-born.jpg" alt="image" width="350">
&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor00fmore-protein-losing-enteropathy-ple-if-lower-vitamin-dspan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">More Protein-Losing Enteropathy (PLE) if lower vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/dogs-ple.jpg" alt="image" width="350">
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-veterinary-and-vitamin-d">Overview Veterinary and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-increased-phosphorus-absorption-chickens-rct">Vitamin D increased Phosphorus absorption (chickens) – RCT Oct 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/critically-ill-dogs-with-good-levels-of-vitamin-d-have-much-better-outcomes-humans-too">Critically ill dogs with good levels of vitamin D have much better outcomes (humans too) – March 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/half-of-dogs-now-get-cancer-it-used-to-be-just-1-percent-probably-low-vitamin-d">Half of dogs now get cancer, it used to be just 1 percent (probably low Vitamin D) &lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pigs used to get the flu only in the winter ( had got Vitamin D in the summer)</title><link>/posts/pigs-used-to-get-the-flu-only-in-the-winter-had-got-vitamin-d-in-the-summer.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pigs-used-to-get-the-flu-only-in-the-winter-had-got-vitamin-d-in-the-summer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="russ-daly-is-it-flu-season-for-animals-toohttpswwwfarmforumnetfarm_forumruss-daly-is-it-flu-season-for-animals-tooarticle_7e6a4f0a-801b-55b1-aecb-4104e7d7ee81html">&lt;a href="https://www.farmforum.net/farm_forum/russ-daly-is-it-flu-season-for-animals-too/article_7e6a4f0a-801b-55b1-aecb-4104e7d7ee81.html">Russ Daly: Is it flu season for animals too?&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Of our domestic animals, it’s pigs that most often encounter influenza — something we’ve recognized for decades. For much of that history, we considered swine influenza to be very much a seasonal disease. I remember being called out to examine groups of pigs in late fall and winter that suddenly went off feed and began coughing. The “barking” cough characteristic of a swine influenza outbreak made you wonder if the barn was filled with dogs instead of pigs! In most cases, these outbreaks would resolve themselves after a few days.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D increased Phosphorus absorption (chickens) – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-increased-phosphorus-absorption-chickens-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-increased-phosphorus-absorption-chickens-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dietary-supplemental-vitamin-d3-enhances-phosphorus-absorption-and-utilisation-by-regulating-gene-expression-of-related-phosphate-transporters-in-the-small-intestine-of-broilers">Dietary supplemental vitamin D3 enhances phosphorus absorption and utilisation by regulating gene expression of related phosphate transporters in the small intestine of broilers.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2018 Oct 29:1-13. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0007114518002763.">doi: 10.1017/S0007114518002763.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shao Y1, Wen Q1, Zhang S1, Lu L1, Zhang L1, Liao X1, Luo X1.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Started with 1 day old chicks&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the trial half of the chicks got 3,500 IU of vitamin D per kg (of feed?)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Boron is vital for animal (and human) health</title><link>/posts/boron-is-vital-for-animal-and-human-health.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/boron-is-vital-for-animal-and-human-health.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Acute pancreatitis in dogs is associated with low vitamin D (lowest D equals death)</title><link>/posts/acute-pancreatitis-in-dogs-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-lowest-d-equals-death.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/acute-pancreatitis-in-dogs-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-lowest-d-equals-death.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Restoring Vitamin D levels to health cows did not change immune biomarkers in 30 days</title><link>/posts/restoring-vitamin-d-levels-to-health-cows-did-not-change-immune-biomarkers-in-30-days.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/restoring-vitamin-d-levels-to-health-cows-did-not-change-immune-biomarkers-in-30-days.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-treatments-on-plasma-metabolism-and-immune-parameters-of-healthy-dairy-cows">Effect of vitamin D treatments on plasma metabolism and immune parameters of healthy dairy cows.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arch Anim Nutr. 2018 Jun;72(3):205-220. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/1745039X.2018.1448564.">doi: 10.1080/1745039X.2018.1448564.&lt;/a> Epub 2018 Mar 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yue Y1,2, Hymøller L2, Jensen SK2, Lauridsen C2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 College of Veterinary Medicine , China Agricultural University , Beijing , China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Animal Science , Aarhus University , Tjele , Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The study&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Deprived cows of Vitamin D for 4 months&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Supplemented healthy cows with Vitamin D in 5 ways for just 1 month&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hens with Vitamin D were better in at least 5 ways – RCT</title><link>/posts/hens-with-vitamin-d-were-better-in-at-least-5-ways-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hens-with-vitamin-d-were-better-in-at-least-5-ways-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>More pregnancies and fewer abortions when Omega-3 was added (cows in this case)</title><link>/posts/more-pregnancies-and-fewer-abortions-when-omega-3-was-added-cows-in-this-case.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-pregnancies-and-fewer-abortions-when-omega-3-was-added-cows-in-this-case.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="evaluation-of-a-rumen-protected-omega-3-supplement-for-reproduction-in-dairy-cows-as-determined-in-three-large-herd-field-trials">Evaluation of a Rumen Protected Omega 3 Supplement for Reproduction in Dairy Cows as Determined in Three Large Herd Field Trials&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>OJAS&amp;gt; Vol.8 No.3, July 2018. DOI: 10.4236/ojas.2018.83026&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Malcolm Ballard1*, Anthony T. Byrd2 Affiliation(s)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 The Ballard Group, Inc. 6075 Miami Rd., Cincinnati, OH, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Anthony T. Byrd ATB Specialty Products, Inc. 5813 Greencrest Drive, Hamilton, OH, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/pregnancy-and-infants-healthier-with-omega-3-supplementation-many-studies">Pregnancy and infants healthier with Omega-3 supplementation - many studies&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Insects create Vitamin D from light (similar to most animals)</title><link>/posts/insects-create-vitamin-d-from-light-similar-to-most-animals.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/insects-create-vitamin-d-from-light-similar-to-most-animals.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="evidence-of-vitamin-d-synthesis-in-insects-exposed-to-uvb-light">Evidence of vitamin D synthesis in insects exposed to UVb light.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Sci Rep. 2018 Jul 17;8(1):10807. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-29232-w.">doi: 10.1038/s41598-018-29232-w.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oonincx DGAB1, van Keulen P2, Finke MD3, Baines FM4, Vermeulen M5,6, Bosch G2.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-veterinary-and-vitamin-d">Overview Veterinary and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/dogs-cats-rabbits-guinea-pigs-pet-birds-etc-need-vitamin-d">Dogs, cats, rabbits, guinea pigs, pet birds, etc need Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/animals-get-a-lot-more-vitamin-d-than-minimum-recommended-for-humans-2016">Animals get a lot more vitamin D than minimum recommended for humans – 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/history-of-vitamin-d-from-500-million-years-ago-to-orthopaedic-practice-today-2019">History of Vitamin D from 500 million years ago to orthopaedic practice today – 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Critically ill dogs with good levels of vitamin D have much better outcomes (humans too)</title><link>/posts/critically-ill-dogs-with-good-levels-of-vitamin-d-have-much-better-outcomes-humans-too.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/critically-ill-dogs-with-good-levels-of-vitamin-d-have-much-better-outcomes-humans-too.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Serum vitamin D concentrations in hospitalized critically ill dogs&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 13(3): e0194062. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/iournal">https://doi.org/10.1371/iournal&lt;/a>. pone.0194062&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jared A. Jaffey &lt;a href="mailto:jaffeyj@missouri.edu">jaffeyj@missouri.edu&lt;/a>, Robert C. Backus, Kaylyn M. McDaniel, Amy E. DeClue&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Veterinary Medicine and Surgery, Veterinary Health Center, University of Missouri, Columbia, Missouri, United States of America&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:750px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Study of 99 dogs with a wide variety of critical illnesses are compared to 17 healthy dogs&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Observations by Henry Lahore, founder of VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Some places give Vitamin D to humans as they enter the ICU&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half of dogs now get cancer, it used to be just 1 percent (probably low Vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/half-of-dogs-now-get-cancer-it-used-to-be-just-1-percent-probably-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-of-dogs-now-get-cancer-it-used-to-be-just-1-percent-probably-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-web">See web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>GreenMed Info March 2018 (link broken)&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Just 50 years ago, 1 in 100 dogs got cancer. Today it is a staggering 1 in 1.65 dogs.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Dogs have the highest rates of cancer of any mammal on the planet. “&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Cats aren’t far behind. About 1 in 3 cats will get cancer.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://thetruthaboutpetcancer.com/">The Truth About PET Cancer&lt;/a> 7 part documentar,y April 2018&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.fetchacure.org/resource-library/facts/">Fetch A Cure &lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Dogs are affected by more forms of cancer compared to other companion animals. According to The Veterinary Cancer Society, cancer is the leading cause of death in 47% of dogs, especially dogs over age ten, and 32% of cats. Dogs get cancer at about the same rate as humans, while cats get fewer cancers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets in domesticated animals</title><link>/posts/rickets-in-domesticated-animals.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-in-domesticated-animals.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Healthy pigs get at least 2 X more vitamin D than the govt recommends</title><link>/posts/healthy-pigs-get-at-least-2-x-more-vitamin-d-than-the-govt-recommends.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/healthy-pigs-get-at-least-2-x-more-vitamin-d-than-the-govt-recommends.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="12-questions-to-ask-to-avoid-sow-mortalityhttpwwwpigprogressnetsowsarticles2018212-questions-to-ask-to-avoid-sow-mortality-250614e-feb-2018--pigprogress">&lt;a href="http://www.pigprogress.net/Sows/Articles/2018/2/12-questions-to-ask-to-avoid-sow-mortality-250614E/">12 questions to ask to avoid sow mortality&lt;/a> Feb 2018 – PigProgress&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>7 Are vitamin D levels adequate?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Additionally, it is well known that vitamin D plays a crucial role in calcium absorption, homeostasis, and bone formation, but it is also involved in the immune system. Within human literature, it is suggested that higher vitamin D levels are associated with a decreased risk of pelvic floor disorders. A 2014 survey by the USA swine industry reported a range of 1,100-2,222 IU/kg in gestation and lactation diets fed, while NRC (2012) recommends 800 IU/kg”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogs, cats, rabbits, guinea pigs, pet birds, etc need Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dogs-cats-rabbits-guinea-pigs-pet-birds-etc-need-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dogs-cats-rabbits-guinea-pigs-pet-birds-etc-need-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-sampling-from-the-web">A sampling from the web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#be-aware">Be Aware&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="a-sampling-from-the-web">A sampling from the web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://healthypets.mercola.com/sites/healthypets/archive/2014/06/20/vitamin-d-deficiency-rabbits.aspx">Rabbits Kept Indoors Could Be Vitamin D Deficient&lt;/a> June 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.dogsnaturallymagazine.com/new-study-shows-dogs-with-low-vitamin-d-are-at-risk-for-cancer/">New Study Shows Dogs with Low Vitamin D Are At Risk For Cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.2ndchance.info/vitaminD.htm">Vitamin D (Cholecalciferol) How Much Should My Pet Receive?&lt;/a> lots of detail&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.petcha.com/vitamin-d-deficiency-in-parrots/">Vitamin-D Deficiency In Parrots&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://healthypets.mercola.com/sites/healthypets/archive/2010/01/27/why-pet-birds-seriously-need-ultraviolet-light.aspx">Vitamin D: The Essential Nutrient Your Pet Bird is Likely Seriously Lacking&lt;/a> Jan 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://studentswithbirds.wordpress.com/2014/03/09/the-importance-of-sun-to-parrots/">The Importance of Sun to Parrots&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic dermatitis treated by Vitamin D (in dogs too) - RCT</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-treated-by-vitamin-d-in-dogs-too-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-treated-by-vitamin-d-in-dogs-too-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-shows-in-vivo-efficacy-in-a-placebo-controlled-double-blinded-randomised-clinical-trial-on-canine-atopic-dermatitis">Vitamin D shows in vivo efficacy in a placebo-controlled, double-blinded, randomised clinical trial on canine atopic dermatitis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>VetRecord – BMJ, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1136/vr.104492">http://dx.doi.org/10.1136/vr.104492&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christoph J Klinger1 &lt;a href="mailto:klingerchristoph@icloud.com">klingerchristoph@icloud.com&lt;/a>, Stefan Hobi1, Cornelia Johansen1, Hans-Joachim Koch2, Karin Weber1 and Ralf S Mueller1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 – Clinic of Small Animal Medicine, Ludwig Maximilian University, Munich, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 – Tierärztliche Klinik Birkenfeld, Birkenfeld, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>Veterinary was the very first category made in VitaminDWiki 8 years ago&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Farm animal doctors are paid to keep their patients healthy, vs human doctors are paid to treat sick patients&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogs, like humans, need vitamin D for many reasons</title><link>/posts/dogs-like-humans-need-vitamin-d-for-many-reasons.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dogs-like-humans-need-vitamin-d-for-many-reasons.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-importance-of-vitamin-d-in-canine-health">The Importance of Vitamin D in Canine Health&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>An exploration of current knowledge on a primary nutrient, including dietary recommendations and directions for future research.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By Natalie Stilwell, DVM, MS, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/companion-animals-dog-cats-need-vitamin-d-too">Companion animals (dog, cats) need vitamin D too – March 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-veterinary-and-vitamin-d">Overview Veterinary and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/dogs-with-cancer-have-low-vitamin-d-same-as-humans">Dogs with Cancer have low vitamin D, same as humans – Sept 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/dog-cancer-4x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d">Dog Cancer 4X more likely if low Vitamin D – Nov 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogs with Cancer have low vitamin D, same as humans</title><link>/posts/dogs-with-cancer-have-low-vitamin-d-same-as-humans.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dogs-with-cancer-have-low-vitamin-d-same-as-humans.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="influence-of-various-factors-on-circulating-25oh-vitamin-d-concentrations-in-dogs-with-cancer-and-healthy-dogs">Influence of Various Factors on Circulating 25(OH) Vitamin D Concentrations in Dogs with Cancer and Healthy Dogs.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Vet Intern Med. 2017 Sep 23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/jvim.14834.">doi: 10.1111/jvim.14834.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weidner N1, Woods JP1, Conlon P2, Meckling KA3, Atkinson JL4, Bayle J5, Makowski AJ6, Horst RL6, Verbrugghe A1.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:720px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>| | | |
| &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; |
| | Dogs | Humans |
| Diagnosed with Cancer in lifetime | 25% | 38% |
| Other diseases also associated with low D | Yes | Yes |
| Diseases associated with CYP24A1 gene | Yes | Yes |
| Decreased Vitamin D in food/supplements associated with Cancer | Yes | Yes |
| Vitamin D reduces pain of arthritis, etc. | Yes | Yes |&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beef was more tender and contained more vitamin D when finishing diet included 4,000 IU of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/beef-was-more-tender-and-contained-more-vitamin-d-when-finishing-diet-included-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/beef-was-more-tender-and-contained-more-vitamin-d-when-finishing-diet-included-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cholecalciferol-supplementation-of-heifer-diets-increases-beef-vitamin-d-concentration-and-improves-beef-tenderness">Cholecalciferol supplementation of heifer diets increases beef vitamin D concentration and improves beef tenderness&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Meat Science, Volume 134, December 2017, Pages 103–110, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.meatsci.2017.07.024">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.meatsci.2017.07.024&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Supplementation probably also increased semi-activated vitamin D – which benefits the human, but it rarely tested&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Previous studies gave 10X more vitamin D to cattle&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/cattle-need-66-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-pound">Cattle need 66 IU of vitamin D per pound&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>700 lbs X 66 IU/lb = 46,000 IU&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/national-requirement-of-vitamin-d-for-pigs-increased-by-4x-4x-more-than-for-humans">National requirement of vitamin D for pigs increased by 4X, (4X more than for humans) - Jan 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D binding protein restricts Vitamin D in blood getting to horses (as well as humans)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-binding-protein-restricts-vitamin-d-in-blood-getting-to-horses-as-well-as-humans.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-binding-protein-restricts-vitamin-d-in-blood-getting-to-horses-as-well-as-humans.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="characterization-of-equine-vitamin-d-binding-protein-development-of-an-assay-and-assessment-of-plasma-concentrations-of-the-protein-in-healthy-horses-and-horses-with-gastrointestinal-disease">Characterization of equine vitamin D-binding protein, development of an assay, and assessment of plasma concentrations of the protein in healthy horses and horses with gastrointestinal disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/blood-tests-can-be-a-poor-measure-of-actual-vitamin-d-due-to-d-binding-protein-dbp">Blood tests can be a poor measure of actual vitamin D due to D Binding Protein (DBP) – May 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/5x-less-risk-of-kidney-cancer-if-good-ratio-of-vitamin-d-binding-protein-to-circulating-vitamin-d">5X less risk of Kidney cancer if good ratio of Vitamin D binding protein to circulating vitamin D – Nov 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/benefits-of-vitamin-d-often-limited-by-genes">Benefits of Vitamin D often limited by genes&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dairy cattle have 70 ng of vitamin D if supplementation equal to 5,000 IU for human</title><link>/posts/dairy-cattle-have-70-ng-of-vitamin-d-if-supplementation-equal-to-5000-iu-for-human.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dairy-cattle-have-70-ng-of-vitamin-d-if-supplementation-equal-to-5000-iu-for-human.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Obese baboons consume 73 percent more vitamin D – keeping blood level the same</title><link>/posts/obese-baboons-consume-73-percent-more-vitamin-d-keeping-blood-level-the-same.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-baboons-consume-73-percent-more-vitamin-d-keeping-blood-level-the-same.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-vitamin-d-concentrations-in-baboons-papio-spp-during-pregnancy-and-obesity">Serum Vitamin D Concentrations in Baboons (Papio spp.) during Pregnancy and Obesity.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Comp Med. 2016;66(2):137-42.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schlabritz-Loutsevitch NE1, Comuzzie AG2, Mahaney MM3, Hubbard GB4, Dick EJ5, Kocak M6, Gupta S7, Carrillo M8, Schenone M7, Postlethwaite A9, Slominski A10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Texas Tech University HSC School of Medicine at the Permian Basin, Odessa, Texas, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:Natalia.schlabritz-lutsevich@ttuhsc.edu">Natalia.schlabritz-lutsevich@ttuhsc.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Departments of Genetics, Texas Biomedical Research Institute, San Antonio, Texas, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3The University of Texas Rio Grande Valley, Brownsville, Texas, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Animals get a lot more vitamin D than minimum recommended for humans – 2016</title><link>/posts/animals-get-a-lot-more-vitamin-d-than-minimum-recommended-for-humans-2016.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/animals-get-a-lot-more-vitamin-d-than-minimum-recommended-for-humans-2016.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="dsm-vitamin-supplementation-guidelines-2016-for-animal-nutrition">DSM Vitamin Supplementation Guidelines 2016 for animal nutrition&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="the-goal-of-a-vet-is-to-keep-animals-healthy">The goal of a Vet is to keep animals healthy.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The goal of a goverment is to avoid any possible risk to the recomenders in the govt.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolorf00humans-need-more-vitamin-dspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Humans need more vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>IU is typically per kilogram of feed&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It seems that a human adult eats about 2 kg of dry food/day, so might multiply by 2X for adult&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>They often also use HyD – a semi-activated form of Vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Companion animals (dog, cats) need vitamin D too</title><link>/posts/companion-animals-dog-cats-need-vitamin-d-too.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/companion-animals-dog-cats-need-vitamin-d-too.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#beyond-the-skeleton-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-companion-animal-health---2016">Beyond the skeleton: the role of vitamin D in companion animal health - 2016&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-metabolism">Vitamin D metabolism&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-gastrointestinal-diseases">Vitamin D and gastrointestinal diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-kidney-diseases">Vitamin D and kidney diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-cardiac-diseases">Vitamin D and cardiac diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-infectious-diseases">Vitamin D and infectious diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-cancer">Vitamin D and cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-inflammation">Vitamin D and inflammation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-mortality">Vitamin D and mortality&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#future-directions">FUTURE DIRECTIONS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="beyond-the-skeleton-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-companion-animal-health---2016">Beyond the skeleton: the role of vitamin D in companion animal health - 2016&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Small Animal Practice (2016) 57, 175-180 DOI: 10.1111/jsap.12458&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More surviving offspring if mother had high vitamin D (sheep in this case)</title><link>/posts/more-surviving-offspring-if-mother-had-high-vitamin-d-sheep-in-this-case.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-surviving-offspring-if-mother-had-high-vitamin-d-sheep-in-this-case.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-predicts-reproductive-fitness-in-a-wild-sheep-population">Vitamin D status predicts reproductive fitness in a wild sheep population&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 18986 (2016), doi:10.1038/srep18986&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ian Handel, Kathryn A. Watt, Jill G. Pilkington, Josephine M. Pemberton, Alastair Macrae, Philip Scott, Tom N. McNeilly, Jacqueline L. Berry, Dylan N. Clements, Daniel H. Nussey &amp;amp; Richard J. Mellanby&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with the development of many human diseases, and with poor reproductive performance in laboratory rodents. We currently have no idea how natural selection directly acts on variation in vitamin D metabolism due to a total lack of studies in wild animals. Here, we measured serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentrations in female Soay sheep that were part of a long-term field study on St Kilda. We found that total 25(OH)D was strongly influenced by age, and that light coloured sheep had higher 25(OH)D3 (but not 25(OH)D2) concentrations than dark sheep. The coat colour polymorphism in Soay sheep is controlled by a single locus, suggesting vitamin D status is heritable in this population. &lt;strong>We also observed a very strong relationship between total 25(OH)D concentrations in summer and a ewe’s fecundity the following spring.&lt;/strong> This resulted in a positive association between total 25(OH)D and the number of lambs produced that survived their first year of life, an important component of female reproductive fitness. Our study provides the first insight into naturally-occurring variation in vitamin D metabolites, and offers the first evidence that vitamin D status is both heritable and under natural selection in the wild.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pigs have about 2X less variation in response to calcidiol as humans do to vitamin D – 2015</title><link>/posts/pigs-have-about-2x-less-variation-in-response-to-calcidiol-as-humans-do-to-vitamin-d-2015.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pigs-have-about-2x-less-variation-in-response-to-calcidiol-as-humans-do-to-vitamin-d-2015.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cats with feline HIV and hospitalized cats have low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cats-with-feline-hiv-and-hospitalized-cats-have-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cats-with-feline-hiv-and-hospitalized-cats-have-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-cats-with-feline-immunodeficiency-virus">Vitamin D status in cats with feline immunodeficiency virus&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Veterinary Medicine and Science, Volume 1, Issue 2, pages 72–78, Oct2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Helen F. Titmarsh1,*, Stephanie M. Lalor1, Severine Tasker2, Emily N. Barker2, Jacqueline Berry3, Danielle Gunn-More1 and Richard J Mellanby1&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/feline-hiv.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Feline immunodeficiency virus (FIV) is a lentivirus that can lead to a syndrome of acquired immune dysfunction. Infected cats often remain asymptomatic for several years before immune dysfunction leads to an increased risk for the development of systemic diseases, neoplasia and opportunistic infections. FIV is structurally related to human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and the pathogenesis of FIV-related disease is similar to that seen in HIV-infected patients. Observational studies have documented an association between low plasma vitamin D and HIV infection. Vitamin D status has been shown to be associated with HIV-related disease progression, morbidity and mortality. The objective of this study was to examine the hypothesis that vitamin D status, as assessed by serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations, are lower in cats with FIV infection compared to healthy control cats. Serum 25(OH)D concentrations were measured in 20 healthy cats, 39 hospitalized ill cats and 59 cats infected with FIV. Cats which were FIV infected had significantly lower 25(OH)D concentrations compared to healthy control cats. Serum 25(OH)D concentrations were not significantly different between FIV-infected cats and hospitalized ill cats. Further investigations are warranted to determine whether vitamin D status influences the prognosis of cats infected with FIV.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Behavior changes due to low vitamin D – in rodents</title><link>/posts/behavior-changes-due-to-low-vitamin-d-in-rodents.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/behavior-changes-due-to-low-vitamin-d-in-rodents.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-impact-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-on-behavior-and-brain-function-in-rodents">The impact of vitamin D deficiency on behavior and brain function in rodents&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Current Opinion in Behavioral Sciences, Available online 26 November 2015, doi:10.1016/j.cobeha.2015.11.012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K Overeem1, DW Eyles1, 2, JJ McGrath1, 2, THJ Burne1, 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•We review studies using rodent models of vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•Prenatal vitamin D deficiency alters brain development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•Adult vitamin D deficiency alters behaviour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been proposed as an environmental risk factor for several neurological disorders. To investigate the biological plausibility of this risk factor, vitamin D (DVD) deficiency rodent models have been used to examine the impact of DVD deficiency on neurobiology and behaviour. The majority of these studies have taken a developmental stance and examined the impact of vitamin D deficiency during gestation on the adult behaviour of the &lt;strong>offspring&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dog Cancer 4X more likely if low Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dog-cancer-4x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dog-cancer-4x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="new-study-shows-dogs-with-low-vitamin-d-are-at-risk-for-cancerhttpwwwdogsnaturallymagazinecomnew-study-shows-dogs-with-low-vitamin-d-are-at-risk-for-cancer-dogsnaturally">&lt;a href="http://www.dogsnaturallymagazine.com/new-study-shows-dogs-with-low-vitamin-d-are-at-risk-for-cancer/">New Study Shows Dogs with Low Vitamin D Are At Risk For Cancer&lt;/a> DogsNaturally&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/cancer-in-dogs---low-vitamin-d.jpg" alt="image" width="300">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Some other factors that are known to decrease the ability to convert dietary vitamin D to 25-VitD:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Polyunsaturated fats can decrease the bioavailability of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fluoride (which is present in many pet foods and water supplies)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>decreases magnesium, which is an essential cofactor for vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Strong magnetic fields can reduce vitamin D levels&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>PCBs increase the risk of deficiency by 3%&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is great for dogs and cats too</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-great-for-dogs-and-cats-too.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-great-for-dogs-and-cats-too.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#50-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-pound-of-dog-helps-blood-in-this-study---may2024">50 IU of Vitamin D per pound of dog (helps blood in this study) - May 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#might-vitamin-d-improve-the-health-and-life-of-pet-cats---asked-perplexity-ai-june2024">Might vitamin D improve the health and life of pet cats? - asked Perplexity AI June 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cats-and-dogs-can-generate-vitamin-d-in-their-fur-and-then-lick-if-off---2012">Cats and dogs can generate Vitamin D in their fur, and then lick if off - 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-in-health-and-disease-in-dogs-and-cats-nov2020">Vitamin D in Health and Disease in Dogs and Cats Nov 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#web">Web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#examples-of-vitamin-d-suppliers-fordogs">Examples of Vitamin D suppliers for dogs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="50-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-pound-of-dog-helps-blood-in-this-study---may2024">50 IU of Vitamin D per pound of dog (helps blood in this study) - May 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A study on the effects of vitamin D supplementation on hematological parameters and serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D in healthy dogs&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Receptor and immune differences between mice and men</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-and-immune-differences-between-mice-and-men.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-and-immune-differences-between-mice-and-men.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="species-specific-regulation-of-innate-immunity-by-vitamin-d-signaling">Species-specific regulation of innate immunity by vitamin D signaling&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, doi:10.1016/j.jsbmb.2015.09.016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vassil Dimitrov, John H. White,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•The hormonal form of vitamin D, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D, is a key regulator of innate immunity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•In humans, the activated vitamin D receptor (VDR) is a direct regulator of transcription of genes encoding antimicrobial peptides, pattern recognition receptors, and innate immune cytokines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•While regulation of VDR target genes implicated in innate immunity in humans appears to be widely conserved in primates, the regulation is not conserved in mice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High dose vitamin D (20,000 IU per kg of feed) safe for pigs</title><link>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-d-20000-iu-per-kg-of-feed-safe-for-pigs.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-d-20000-iu-per-kg-of-feed-safe-for-pigs.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="tolerance-evaluation-of-overdosed-dietary-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-in-growing-piglets">Tolerance evaluation of overdosed dietary levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 in growing piglets.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr (Berl). 2015 Aug 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/jpn.12355">doi: 10.1111/jpn.12355&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>von Rosenberg SJ1, Weber GM2, Erhardt A1, Höller U2, Wehr UA1, Rambeck WA1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forty-eight, cross-bred (GL × LW × P) piglets were used in a 42-day tolerance trial to assess the effects of feeding diets supplemented with vitamin D or increasing levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25-OH-D3 ). Six-week-old piglets (24 castrate males, 24 females) were used. Two replicate groups of 6 piglets were randomized by weight and allocated to four dietary treatments. The control group (T1) was supplemented with 50 μg vitamin D3 /kg feed. The experimental groups received 25-OH-D3 at the recommended dose (T2: 50 μg/kg = 1x), at 250 μg/kg (T3: 5x) or at 500 μg/kg (T4: 10x) respectively. Feed intake and daily weight gain were measured weekly, and the animals were examined by a veterinarian daily. After 42 days, body mass, blood, urine, bone and tissue samples were analysed and a pathology examination conducted. Dietary treatments had no significant effect on final body mass or daily weight gain. The 25-OH-D3 plasma concentration in T1 was 17 ± 3 ng/ml (mean ± SD) while the respective values of the experimental groups were significantly increased in T2, T3 and T4. Tissue concentrations of 25-OH-D3 were higher in liver and muscle for T3 and T4 and in skin for T4 than in T1. However, neither gross pathology nor histology, nor blood and urine characteristics, nor bone parameters were affected by dietary treatments. Weight of organs as well as dry matter, ash and calcium content of kidneys remained unaffected by dietary 25-OH-D3 intake. Furthermore, no changes were observed for general indicators of health. The results of this study demonstrated that feeding piglets with 25-OH-D3 at 5 or 10 times the recommended level had no adverse effects on any of the biological parameters measured. It was concluded that 25-OH-D3 can be regarded as a supplement with a very high safety margin when used at the recommended level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultraviolet B needed for indoor cows to have enough vitamin D in milk</title><link>/posts/ultraviolet-b-needed-for-indoor-cows-to-have-enough-vitamin-d-in-milk.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ultraviolet-b-needed-for-indoor-cows-to-have-enough-vitamin-d-in-milk.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="short-communication-artificial-ultraviolet-b-light-exposure-increases-vitamin-d-levels-in-cow-plasma-and-milk">Short communication: Artificial ultraviolet B light exposure increases vitamin D levels in cow plasma and milk.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Dairy Sci. 2015 Jun 24. pii: S0022-0302(15)00433-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3168/jds.2014-9277.">doi: 10.3168/jds.2014-9277.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jakobsen J1, Jensen SK2, Hymøller L2, Andersen EW3, Kaas P4, Burild A5, Jäpelt RB5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1National Food Institute, Technical University of Denmark, 2860 Søborg, Denmark. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:jeja@food.dtu.dk">jeja@food.dtu.dk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Animal Science, Aarhus University, 8830 Tjele, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Applied Mathematics and Computer Science, Technical University of Denmark, 2800 Lyngby, Denmark.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Neonate horses (as well as neonate humans) having low vitamin D are more likely to die.</title><link>/posts/neonate-horses-as-well-as-neonate-humans-having-low-vitamin-d-are-more-likely-to-die.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/neonate-horses-as-well-as-neonate-humans-having-low-vitamin-d-are-more-likely-to-die.html</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="vitamin-d-metabolites-and-their-association-with-calcium-phosphorus-and-pth-concentrations-severity-of-illness-and-mortality-in-hospitalized-equine-neonates">Vitamin D Metabolites and Their Association with Calcium, Phosphorus, and PTH Concentrations, Severity of Illness, and Mortality in Hospitalized Equine Neonates&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>PLOS ONE doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0127684.g003&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ahmed M. Kamr1,4, Katarzyna A. Dembek1, Stephen M. Reed2, Nathan M. Slovis3, Ahmed A. Zaghawa4, Thomas J. Rosol1, Ramiro E. Toribio1 toribio.1 @osu.edu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>College of Veterinary Medicine, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, United States of America,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rood and Riddle Equine Hospital, Lexington, Kentucky, United States of America, 3 Hagyard Equine Medical Institute, Lexington, Kentucky, United States of America, 4 Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, University of Sadat City, Sadat City, Egypt&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hospitalized cats 8X more likely to die if low vitamin D (Vit. D helps humans too)</title><link>/posts/hospitalized-cats-8x-more-likely-to-die-if-low-vitamin-d-vit-d-helps-humans-too.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hospitalized-cats-8x-more-likely-to-die-if-low-vitamin-d-vit-d-helps-humans-too.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-predicts-30-day-mortality-in-hospitalised-cats">Vitamin d status predicts 30 day mortality in hospitalised cats.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2015 May 13;10(5):e0125997. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0125997.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0125997.&lt;/a> eCollection 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Titmarsh H1, Kilpatrick S1, Sinclair J1, Boag A1, Bode EF1, Lalor SM1, Gaylor D1, Berry J2, Bommer NX1, Gunn-Moore D1, Reed N1, Handel I1, Mellanby RJ1.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/cat-mortality.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/webp/cat-mortality.webp" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;p>Vitamin D insufficiency, defined as low serum concentrations of the major circulating form of vitamin D, 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D), has been associated with the development of numerous infectious, inflammatory, and neoplastic disorders in humans. In addition, vitamin D insufficiency has been found to be predictive of mortality for many disorders. However, interpretation of human studies is difficult since vitamin D status is influenced by many factors, including diet, season, latitude, and exposure to UV radiation. In contrast, domesticated cats do not produce vitamin D cutaneously, and most cats are fed a commercial diet containing a relatively standard amount of vitamin D. Consequently, domesticated cats are an attractive model system in which to examine the relationship between serum 25(OH)D and health outcomes. The hypothesis of this study was that vitamin D status would predict short term, all-cause mortality in domesticated cats. Serum concentrations of 25(OH)D, together with a wide range of other clinical, hematological, and biochemical parameters, were measured in 99 consecutively hospitalised cats. Cats which died within 30 days of initial assessment had significantly lower serum 25(OH)D concentrations than cats which survived. In a linear regression model including 12 clinical variables, serum 25(OH)D concentration in the lower tertile was significantly predictive of mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 primates have higher levels of vitamin D than clothed humans, level varies between individuals</title><link>/posts/3-primates-have-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-than-clothed-humans-level-varies-between-individuals.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-primates-have-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-than-clothed-humans-level-varies-between-individuals.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="measurement-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d23-and-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d23-by-tandem-mass-spectrometry-a-primate-multispecies-comparison">Measurement of 25-hydroxyvitamin D2&amp;amp;3 and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D2&amp;amp;3 by tandem mass spectrometry: A primate multispecies comparison&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Primatology, 2 APR 2015, DOI: 10.1002/ajp.22403&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Toni E. Ziegler 1,2,*, Amita Kapoor 1,2, Curtis J. Hedman 1,2,3, Neil Binkley 4 and Joseph W. Kemnitz 1,2,5&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/3-primates.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>Vitamin D metabolites are widely studied for their roles in bone health, immune functions, and other potential physiologic roles in humans. However, the optimal blood levels of vitamin D metabolites are still unclear. Various methods for measuring vitamin D metabolites have been used and recently liquid chromatography tandem mass spectroscopy (LC-MS/MS) has been adopted as the gold standard for vitamin D metabolite measurement. Here, we report the use of LC-MS/MS to measure 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D2&amp;amp;3), and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)2D2&amp;amp;3), in three laboratory nonhuman primate species:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone strength increased when sow and piglets had enough Vitamin D and Phosphorus</title><link>/posts/bone-strength-increased-when-sow-and-piglets-had-enough-vitamin-d-and-phosphorus.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-strength-increased-when-sow-and-piglets-had-enough-vitamin-d-and-phosphorus.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="neonatal-pig-femur-integrity-responses-to-dietary-vitamin-d-and-p-depend-on-maternal-dietary-vitamin-d">Neonatal Pig Femur Integrity Responses to Dietary Vitamin D and P Depend on Maternal Dietary Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>L Amundson1 and T Crenshaw1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Dept Anim Sci Univ of Wisconsin Madison Wisconsin United States&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/bone-strength.jpg" alt="image" width="650">
&lt;p>Kyphosis, an idiopathic disease, occurs in swine and humans. We induced kyphosis by altering maternal dietary vitamin D (D) and pig dietary D, Ca and P. The objective was to characterize bone traits and gene expression in the kyphosis model and assess maternal carryover effects. Traits from mechanical tests to characterize femur integrity are reported herein. Sows were fed diets with 0, 325 or 1750 IU D/kg (n = 6, 8, or 9/diet). At weaning (23 ± 2 d) pigs were fed diets with 0 (-D) or 280 (+D) IU D/kg, each with 95% (95P) or 120% (120P) of the P requirement. Pigs were killed at birth (n = 23), weaning (n = 22), and at the end of nursery (n = 185) for bone and tissue analysis. Excised femurs were subjected to a 4-point bending test to determine bending moment (BM), stress, strain, and modulus of elasticity (ME) at the yield point of load deformation curves. Mass moment of inertia (MOI) was derived from CT scans. ME encompasses of BM, stress, strain and MOI and is assumed to be a constant property of a material. No differences in ME were detected at birth. At weaning ME increased in pigs produced by sows fed 1750 (P &amp;lt; 0.05). At the end of nursery ME depended on maternal diets (interaction, P &amp;lt; 0.05). ME increased in pigs fed +D95P if produced by sows fed 0 or 325 but decreased if produced by sows fed 1750. As previously reported, DXA whole body bone mineral density also indicated maternal carryover effects, but the pattern differed among diets. Therefore whole body bone and femur integrity traits differ, but provide unique characterization of the model. As previously reported, the kyphosis model was further characterized by molecular analysis of bone and D homeostatic cell signaling mechanisms. All traits contribute to the characterization of the kyphosis model but a specific mechanism by which the deformity is induced has yet to be determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active vitamin D increased fractional rate of protein synthesis in chickens by 3X</title><link>/posts/active-vitamin-d-increased-fractional-rate-of-protein-synthesis-in-chickens-by-3x.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-vitamin-d-increased-fractional-rate-of-protein-synthesis-in-chickens-by-3x.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="25-hydroxycholecalciferol-enhances-male-broiler-breast-meat-yield-through-the-mtor-pathway">25-Hydroxycholecalciferol Enhances Male Broiler Breast Meat Yield through the mTOR Pathway.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2015 Mar 18. pii: jn207936. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vignale K1, Greene ES1, Caldas JV1, England JA1, Boonsinchai N1, Sodsee P1, Pollock ED2, Dridi S3, Coon CN3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In recent years, there has been a growing body of evidence indicating that replacing cholecalciferol (vitamin D3) with 25-hydroxycholecalciferol &lt;span>[25(OH)D3]&lt;/span> through dietary supplementation &lt;strong>enhances breast meat yield in broiler chickens&lt;/strong> . However, the underlying molecular mechanisms are still unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cows in pastures need vitamin D for milk production</title><link>/posts/cows-in-pastures-need-vitamin-d-for-milk-production.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cows-in-pastures-need-vitamin-d-for-milk-production.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="invited-the-role-and-potential-advantages-of-vitamin-d-metabolites-in-maintaining-calcium-status-in-high-producing-dairy-herds">INVITED: The role and potential advantages of Vitamin D metabolites in maintaining calcium status in high producing dairy herds.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Animal Production Science, AN14450 Accepted 06 March 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joseph McGrath, Darryl Savage, Ian Godwin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Long-term, declining fertility is a reported trend in high production dairy herds. Nutrition management is identified as a key area where improvement is required. Most published literature relating to nutrition management of dairy cow fertility examines energy and protein status and peri-parturient Ca homeostasis availability. This article examines the current understanding of calcium homeostasis relevant to improving performance in the high production dairy herd.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hens fed a form of vitamin D had more hatchable eggs and more immune chicks</title><link>/posts/hens-fed-a-form-of-vitamin-d-had-more-hatchable-eggs-and-more-immune-chicks.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hens-fed-a-form-of-vitamin-d-had-more-hatchable-eggs-and-more-immune-chicks.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-hen-age-and-maternal-vitamin-d-source-on-performance-hatchability-bone-mineral-density-and-progeny-in-vitro-early-innate-immune-function">Effect of hen age and maternal vitamin D source on performance, hatchability, bone mineral density, and progeny in vitro early innate immune function.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Poult Sci. 2015 Mar 5. pii: pev002. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saunders-Blades JL1, Korver DR2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Agricultural, Food, and Nutritional Science, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada T6G 2P5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Agricultural, Food, and Nutritional Science, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada T6G 2P5 &lt;a href="mailto:doug.korver@ualberta.ca">doug.korver@ualberta.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The metabolite 25-hydroxy vitamin D3 (25-OHD) can complement or replace vitamin D3 in poultry rations, and may influence broiler production and immune function traits. The effect of broiler breeder dietary 25-OHD on egg production, hatchability, and chick early innate immune function was studied. We hypothesized that maternal dietary 25-OHD would support normal broiler breeder production and a more mature innate immune system of young chicks. Twenty-three-week-old Ross 308 hens (n = 98) were placed in 4 floor pens and fed either&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dog Cancer (hemangiosarcoma) is rare if more than 100 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dog-cancer-hemangiosarcoma-is-rare-if-more-than-100-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dog-cancer-hemangiosarcoma-is-rare-if-more-than-100-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-dogs---correlation-with-health-and-cancer-risk">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations in dogs - correlation with health and cancer risk&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Veterinary and Comparative Oncology,DOI:10.1111/vco.12101&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K. A. Selting1,C. R. Sharp2,R. Ringold3,D. H. Thamm4 and R. Backus1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Veterinary Medical Teaching Hospital, University of Missouri, Columbia, MO, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Cummings School of Veterinary Medicine, Tufts University, North Grafton, MA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Veterinary Diagnostics Institute, Simi Valley, CA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Department of Clinical Sciences, Animal Cancer Center, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less weight gain in mice getting lots of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/less-weight-gain-in-mice-getting-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-weight-gain-in-mice-getting-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-protects-against-diet-induced-obesity-by-enhancing-fatty-acid-oxidation">Vitamin D protects against diet-induced obesity by enhancing fatty acid oxidation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cited-146-times-as-of-dec-2023">Cited 146 times as of Dec 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-protects-against-diet-induced-obesity-by-enhancing-fatty-acid-oxidation">Vitamin D protects against diet-induced obesity by enhancing fatty acid oxidation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Nutritional Biochemistry. Available online 21 June 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Julie Marcotorchinoa, b, c, Franck Tourniairea, b, c, Julien Astiera, b, c, Esma Karkenia, b, c, Matthias Canaulta, b, c, Marie-Josèphe Amiota, b, c, David Bendahanc, d, Monique Bernardc, d, Jean-Charles Martina, b, c, Benoit Giannesinic, d, Jean-François Landriera, b, c, &lt;a href="mailto:jean-francois.landrier@univ-amu.fr">jean-francois.landrier@univ-amu.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rotovarious virus less of a problem for pigs with enough vitamin D – CT</title><link>/posts/rotovarious-virus-less-of-a-problem-for-pigs-with-enough-vitamin-d-ct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rotovarious-virus-less-of-a-problem-for-pigs-with-enough-vitamin-d-ct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dietary-vitamin-d-supplementation-attenuates-immune-responses-of-pigs-challenged-with-rotavirus-potentially-through-the-retinoic-acid-inducible-gene-i-signalling-pathway">Dietary vitamin D supplementation attenuates immune responses of pigs challenged with rotavirus potentially through the retinoic acid-inducible gene I signalling pathway.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2014 May 15:1-9. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhao Y, Yu B, Mao X, He J, Huang Z, Zheng P, Yu J, Han G, Liang X, Chen D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Animal Nutrition, Sichuan Agricultural University,Xinkang Road 46#,Ya&amp;rsquo;an Sichuan Province 625014, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the present study, twenty-four Duroc × Landrance × Yorkshire (initial body weight (BW) of 21·82 (sem 2·06) kg) cross-bred pigs were used to determine whether dietary vitamin D supplementation could confer protection against viral infections through the retinoic acid-inducible gene I (RIG-I) signalling pathway in pigs. Experimental treatments were arranged in a 2 × 2 factorial manner with the main effects of immune challenge (control v. porcine rotavirus (PRV) challenge) and dietary concentrations of vitamin D (200 and 5000 IU; where 1 IU of vitamin D is defined as the biological activity of 0.025 mg of cholecalciferol). The pigs were fed a diet containing 200 or 5000 IU vitamin D in the first week of the study period. On day 8, the pigs were orally dosed with 4 ml of Dulbecco&amp;rsquo;s modified Eagle&amp;rsquo;s medium/Ham&amp;rsquo;s F-12 medium containing PRV or essential medium (control). Serum samples were collected on day 8 (pre-challenge), and 6 d after the PRV challenge, the pigs were killed to evaluate intestinal morphology and tissue gene expression following the last blood collection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chinchillas are another furry animal which makes vitamin D from UVB</title><link>/posts/chinchillas-are-another-furry-animal-which-makes-vitamin-d-from-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chinchillas-are-another-furry-animal-which-makes-vitamin-d-from-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-ultraviolet-radiation-on-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-captive-chinchillas-chinchilla-laniger">Effects of ultraviolet radiation on serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D Concentrations in captive Chinchillas (chinchilla laniger)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Exotic Pet Medicine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anne E. Rivas, DVM, Mark A. Mitchell, DVM, MS, PhD, Dip. ECZM (Herpetology)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mark A. Mitchell, DVM, MS, PhD, Dip. ECZM (Herpetology), College of Veterinary Medicine, University of Illinois, 1108W. Hazelwood Dr., Urbana, IL 61802 USA.Tel.: 217-244-9386. &lt;a href="mailto:mmitch@illinois.edu">mmitch@illinois.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DVM, Kenneth R. Welle, DVM, Dip. ABVP (Avian), Julia K. Whittington, DVM&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is an important hormone in vertebrates, and most animals acquire this hormone through their diet and/or exposure to ultraviolet B (UVB) radiation. To date, no study has determined how chinchillas (Chinchilla laniger) acquire vitamin D. The objective of this study was to determine whether exposure to UVB radiation had an effect on serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in captive chinchillas.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D recommended for all animals (FEEDAP does not say how much)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-recommended-for-all-animals-feedap-does-not-say-how-much.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-recommended-for-all-animals-feedap-does-not-say-how-much.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="scientific-opinion-on-the-safety-and-efficacy-of-vitamin-d3-cholecalciferol-as-a-feed-additive-for-all-animal-species-or-categories-based-on-a-dossier-submitted-by-lohmann-animal-health-gmbh">Scientific Opinion on the safety and efficacy of vitamin D3 (cholecalciferol) as a feed additive for all animal species or categories based on a dossier submitted by Lohmann Animal Health GmbH&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>EFSA Journal 2014;12(2):3568 &lt;span>[2 pp.]&lt;/span>. doi:10.2903/j.efsa.2014.3568&lt;/p>
&lt;p>EFSA Panel on Additives and Products or Substances used in Animal Feed (FEEDAP)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Type: Opinion of the Scientific Committee/Scientific Panel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On request from: European Commission, Question number: EFSA-Q-2011-00952&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adopted: 30 January 2014, Published: 20 February 2014&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inflammatory Bowel Disease and Lymphoma – associated with low vitamin D in cats too</title><link>/posts/inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-lymphoma-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-cats-too.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-lymphoma-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-cats-too.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cats-with-inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-intestinal-small-cell-lymphoma-have-low-serum-concentrations-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d">Cats with Inflammatory Bowel Disease and Intestinal Small Cell Lymphoma Have Low Serum Concentrations of 25-Hydroxyvitamin D.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Vet Intern Med. 2014 Jan 16. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/jvim.12294.">doi: 10.1111/jvim.12294.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lalor S, Schwartz AM, Titmarsh H, Reed N, Tasker S, Boland L, Berry J, Gunn-Moore D, Mellanby RJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Royal (Dick) School of Veterinary Studies, Division of Clinical Veterinary Sciences, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) and intestinal small cell lymphoma (ISCL) are common diseases in cats. The prevalence of alterations in the serum concentrations of fat soluble vitamins, such as vitamin D, in cats with IBD and ISCL is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is HyD (25(OH)D) a better form of vitamin D for some animals and maybe humans with liver problems</title><link>/posts/is-hyd-25ohd-a-better-form-of-vitamin-d-for-some-animals-and-maybe-humans-with-liver-problems.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-hyd-25ohd-a-better-form-of-vitamin-d-for-some-animals-and-maybe-humans-with-liver-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dsm-recommendations-of-vitamin-d-andor-their-hyd-product">DSM recommendations of Vitamin D AND/OR their HyD product&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note the IUs are per of dry FEED, not WEIGHT&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">It seems that a human adult eats about 2 kg of dry food per day, so might multiply by 2X for human adult&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">2011 PDF is attached at the bottom of this page has all of the recommended nutrients&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="updated-animals-get-a-lot-more-vitamin-d-than-minimum-recommended-for-humans--2016postsanimals-get-a-lot-more-vitamin-d-than-minimum-recommended-for-humans-2016">Updated &lt;a href="/posts/animals-get-a-lot-more-vitamin-d-than-minimum-recommended-for-humans-2016">Animals get a lot more vitamin D than minimum recommended for humans – 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-poultry.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-turkey.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-swine.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-ruminants.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-fish-and-shrimp.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-horses-and-others.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ocn-dogs-and-cats.jpg" alt="image"></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D: calcium and bone homeostasis during evolution</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-calcium-and-bone-homeostasis-during-evolution.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-calcium-and-bone-homeostasis-during-evolution.html</guid><description>&lt;p>BoneKEy Reports 3, Article number: 480 (2014) | doi:10.1038/bonekey.2013.214&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roger Bouillon &lt;a href="mailto:roger.bouillon@med.kuleuven.be">roger.bouillon@med.kuleuven.be&lt;/a> 1 and Tatsuo Suda2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Clinical and Experimental Endocrinology, KU Leuven; Department of Endocrinology, University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium. 2Research Center for Genomic Medicine, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D3 is already found early in the evolution of life but essentially as inactive end products of the photochemical reaction of 7-dehydrocholestol with ultraviolet light B. A full vitamin D (refers to vitamin D2 and D3) endocrine system, characterized by a specific VDR (vitamin D receptor, member of the nuclear receptor family), specific vitamin D metabolizing CYP450 enzymes regulated by calciotropic hormones and a dedicated plasma transport-protein is only found in vertebrates. In the earliest vertebrates (lamprey), vitamin D metabolism and VDR may well have originated from a duplication of a common PRX/VDR ancestor gene as part of a xenobiotic detoxification pathway. The vitamin D endocrine system, however, subsequently became an important regulator of calcium supply for an extensive calcified skeleton. Vitamin D is essential for normal calcium and bone homeostasis as shown by rickets in vitamin D-deficient growing amphibians, reptiles, birds and mammals. From amphibians onward, bone is gradually more dynamic with regulated bone resorption, mainly by combined action of PTH and 1 a,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3) on the generation and function of multinucleated osteoclasts. Therefore, bone functions as a large internal calcium reservoir, under the control of osteoclasts. Osteocytes also display a remarkable spectrum of activities, including mechanical sensing and regulating mineral homeostasis, but also have an important role in global nutritional and energy homeostasis. Mineralization from reptiles onward is under the control of well-regulated SIBLING proteins and associated enzymes, nearly all under the control of 1,25(OH)2D3. The vitamin D story thus started as inert molecule but gained an essential role for calcium and bone homeostasis in terrestrial animals to cope with the challenge of higher gravity and calcium-poor environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>National requirement of vitamin D for pigs increased by 4X, (4X more than for humans)</title><link>/posts/national-requirement-of-vitamin-d-for-pigs-increased-by-4x-4x-more-than-for-humans.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/national-requirement-of-vitamin-d-for-pigs-increased-by-4x-4x-more-than-for-humans.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="establishment-of-the-2012-vitamin-d-requirements-in-swine-with-focus-on-dietary-forms-and-levels-of-vitamin-d">Establishment of the 2012 vitamin D requirements in swine with focus on dietary forms and levels of vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J ANIM SCI January 7, 2014 jas.2013-7201&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C. Lauridsen &lt;a href="mailto:charlotte.lauridsen@agrsci.dk">charlotte.lauridsen@agrsci.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Animal Science, Aarhus University, 8830 Tjele, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In swine nutrition, little is known about vitamin requirements for reproductive processes and bone health, especially vitamin D. Supplemental vitamin D is usually added to animal feed as cholecalciferol (vitamin D3), which is transported to the liver and hydroxylated to 25-hydroxycholecalciferol &lt;span>[25(OH)D3]&lt;/span>, and this metabolite has become commercially available for swine nutrition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lizard (brown sagrei) seeks more UVB if less Vitamin D in diet</title><link>/posts/lizard-brown-sagrei-seeks-more-uvb-if-less-vitamin-d-in-diet.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lizard-brown-sagrei-seeks-more-uvb-if-less-vitamin-d-in-diet.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="ultraviolet-light-exposure-and-response-to-dietary-vitamin-d3-in-two-jamaican-anoles">Ultraviolet Light Exposure and Response to Dietary Vitamin D3 in Two Jamaican Anoles&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Herpetology 47(4):524-529. 2013, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/http">doi: http&lt;/a>://dx.doi.org/10.1670/12-020&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gary W. Ferguson &lt;a href="mailto:g.ferguson@tcu.edu">g.ferguson@tcu.edu&lt;/a>, Adam J. Kingeter 2, and William H. Gehrmann&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Biology, Texas Christian University, Fort Worth, Texas 76129 USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Present address: Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Department of Anesthesiology, Nashville, Tennessee 37232 USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Jamaica, free-living male and female-sized Anolis sagrei are exposed to more natural ultraviolet-B (UVB) from sunlight than male and female-sized Anolis lineatopus. In the laboratory, &lt;strong>we tested predictions derived from the hypothesis that Anolis possess a mechanism for behaviorally photo-regulating their exposure to UVB depending on their dietary intake of vitamin D3&lt;/strong> . Anolis sagrei voluntarily exposed themselves more frequently to visible and UVB light and received higher doses of UVB in an artificial light gradient when fed a low vitamin D3 diet for 6 weeks than when subsequently fed a high dietary vitamin D3 diet for 6 weeks. When we returned the anole&amp;rsquo;s diet to the low vitamin D3 regimen for a third 6-week period, UVB exposure remained lower than in the first 6-week period. This suggests an initial UV photo-regulatory adjustment to high dietary vitamin-D3 but a slow return to greater reliance on UVB-induced endogenous vitamin D3 production.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Feed chicken lots of vitamin D, get 6000 IU per egg with no change in production</title><link>/posts/feed-chicken-lots-of-vitamin-d-get-6000-iu-per-egg-with-no-change-in-production.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/feed-chicken-lots-of-vitamin-d-get-6000-iu-per-egg-with-no-change-in-production.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="effects-of-long-term-supplementation-of-laying-hens-with-high-concentrations-of-cholecalciferol-on-performance-and-egg-quality">Effects of long-term supplementation of laying hens with high concentrations of cholecalciferol on performance and egg quality&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Poult. Sci. November 2013 vol. 92 no. 11 2930-2937&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. E. Persia*, &lt;a href="mailto:mpersia@iastate.edu">mpersia@iastate.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. Higgins†,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>T. Wang‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D. Trample‡ and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E. A. Bobeck*&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Department of Animal Science,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>†Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡Veterinary Diagnostic and Production Animal Medicine, Iowa State University, Ames 50011&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/egg.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>There is current interest in increasing human vitamin D dietary intake without having to modify human eating habits. One method to increase human dietary vitamin D intake is to generate eggs with increased concentrations of vitamin D through high-concentration vitamin D feeding in the diets of laying hens. Although eggs can be produced with high concentrations of vitamin D, the consequences of these diets on hen performance and egg quality have not been validated. The objective of this research is to quantify the effects of high concentrations of cholecalciferol (D3) on laying hen performance and egg quality. Hy-Line W36 laying hens were placed on 1 of 5 experimental diets for 40 wk:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>During brown bear hibernation Vitamin D3 decreases but D2 increases (surprise)</title><link>/posts/during-brown-bear-hibernation-vitamin-d3-decreases-but-d2-increases-surprise.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/during-brown-bear-hibernation-vitamin-d3-decreases-but-d2-increases-surprise.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-and-bone-and-connective-tissue-turnover-in-brown-bears-ursus-arctos-during-hibernation-and-the-active-state">Vitamin D Status and Bone and Connective Tissue Turnover in Brown Bears (Ursus arctos) during Hibernation and the Active State&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 6(6): e21483. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0021483&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter Vestergaard mail, Ole-Gunnar Støen, Jon E. Swenson, Leif Mosekilde, Lene Heickendorff, Ole Fröbert&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Extended physical inactivity causes disuse osteoporosis in humans. In contrast, brown bears (Ursus arctos) are highly immobilised for half of the year during hibernation without signs of bone loss and therefore may serve as a model for prevention of osteoporosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduced bacterial infection in cows – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-bacterial-infection-in-cows-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-bacterial-infection-in-cows-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="treatment-of-an-intramammary-bacterial-infection-with-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3">Treatment of an Intramammary Bacterial Infection with 25-Hydroxyvitamin D3&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PLOS One PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John D. Lippolis &lt;a href="mailto:john.lippolis@ars.usda.gov">john.lippolis@ars.usda.gov&lt;/a>, Timothy A. Reinhardt, Randy A. Sacco, Brian J. Nonnecke, Corwin D. Nelson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deficiency of serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 has been correlated with increased risk of infectious diseases such as tuberculosis and influenza. A plausible reason for this association is that expression of genes encoding important antimicrobial proteins depends on concentrations of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 produced by activated immune cells at sites of infection, and that synthesis of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 is dependent on the availability of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3. Thus, increasing the availability of 25(OH)D3 for immune cell synthesis of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 at sites of infection has been hypothesized to aid in clearance of the infection. This report details the treatment of an acute intramammary infection with infusion of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 to the site of infection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breed cows based on vitamin D production</title><link>/posts/breed-cows-based-on-vitamin-d-production.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breed-cows-based-on-vitamin-d-production.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="variation-of-vitamin-d-in-cows-milk-and-interaction-with-p-lactoglobulin">Variation of Vitamin D in Cow&amp;rsquo;s Milk and Interaction with P-Lactoglobulin&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Molecules 2013, 18, 10122-10131; doi:10.3390/moleculesl80910122&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omar Bulgari 1, Anna Maria Caroli Stefania Chessa 2, Rita Rizzi 3 and Carmen Gigliotti 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Molecular and Translational Medicine, University of Brescia, Brescia 25123, Italy; E-Mails: &lt;a href="mailto:bulgari.omar@libero.it">bulgari.omar@libero.it&lt;/a> (O.B.); &lt;a href="mailto:giglio@med.unibs.it">giglio@med.unibs.it&lt;/a> (C.G.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Institute of Agricultural Biology and Biotechnology—National Research Council, Milano 20133, Italy; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:chessa@ibba.cnr.it">chessa@ibba.cnr.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Veterinary Science and Public Health (DIVET), Milano 20133, Italy; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:rita.rizzi@unimi.it">rita.rizzi@unimi.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Piglets helped a lot with 40,000 IU on day 1, provided they did not have diarrhea</title><link>/posts/piglets-helped-a-lot-with-40000-iu-on-day-1-provided-they-did-not-have-diarrhea.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/piglets-helped-a-lot-with-40000-iu-on-day-1-provided-they-did-not-have-diarrhea.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-what-is-all-the-fuss-abouthttpnationalhogfarmercomnutritionvitamin-d-deficiency-what-all-fuss-about20">&lt;a href="http://nationalhogfarmer.com/nutrition/vitamin-d-deficiency-what-all-fuss-about%20">Vitamin D Deficiency: What Is All the Fuss About?&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>nice story in National Hog Farmer. Before many piglets raised indoors were dying&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-levels-indoor-pigs--10ngml-outdoor-pigs-50-ngml">Vitamin D levels: indoor pigs &amp;lt; 10ng/ml, outdoor pigs &amp;gt;50 ng/ml&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/pig-farm.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/rickets-in-humans-and-domestic-animals">Rickets in Humans and domestic animals - March 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/piglets-getting-single-dose-of-40000-iu-of-vitamin-d-gained-more-weight">Piglets getting single dose of 40,000 IU of vitamin D gained more weight – March 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/swine-with-extra-vitamin-d-more-likely-to-get-pregnant-and-have-more-and-larger-piglets">Swine with extra vitamin D more likely to get pregnant and have more and larger piglets – June 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB on legs of chickens resulted in 70 IU vitamin D per egg yoke</title><link>/posts/uvb-on-legs-of-chickens-resulted-in-70-iu-vitamin-d-per-egg-yoke.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-on-legs-of-chickens-resulted-in-70-iu-vitamin-d-per-egg-yoke.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="uvb-exposure-of-farm-animals-study-on-a-food-based-strategy-to-bridge-the-gap-between-current-vitamin-d-intakes-and-dietary-targets">UVB Exposure of Farm Animals: Study on a Food-Based Strategy to Bridge the Gap between Current Vitamin D Intakes and Dietary Targets&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLOS ONE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alexandra Schutkowski, Julia Krämer, Holger Kluge, Frank Hirche, Andreas Krombholz, Torsten Theumer, Gabriele I. Stangl &lt;a href="mailto:gabriele.stangl@landw.uni-halle.de">gabriele.stangl@landw.uni-halle.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is a global health problem. This study aimed to investigate the efficacy of ultraviolet (UV) B radiation for improving vitamin D3 content of eggs and meat. In a two-factorial design hens that received diets with 0 (-D3) or 3,000 IU (+D3) vitamin D3/kg were non-exposed (-UVB) or exposed to UVB radiation (+UVB) for 3 h daily over 4 weeks. Data show that UVB radiation was very effective in raising the vitamin D3 content of egg yolk and meat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vets getting excited about vitamin D</title><link>/posts/vets-getting-excited-about-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vets-getting-excited-about-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 class="svTitle">
&lt;p>&lt;span style="font-size:22px;">It’s not just bones anymore: The new and exciting world of vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/h1>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="publicationHead">
&lt;div class="title">
&lt;p>&lt;a class="cLink" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/journal/10900233" title="Go to The Veterinary Journal on SciVerse ScienceDirect">&lt;span>The Veterinary Journal,&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/journal/10900233/194/1" title="Go to table of contents for this volume/issue"> Volume 194, Issue 1&lt;/a>, October 2012, Pages 5–6&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul class="authorGroup noCollab">&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="authorName" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1090023312003280#" id="authname_N4255ecc0N4251ac88">Keren Dittmer&lt;/a> &lt;a href="mailto:K.E.Dittmer@massey.ac.nz">K.E.Dittmer@massey.ac.nz&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;/ul>&lt;ul class="affiliation">&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;span>Institute of Veterinary, Animal and Biomedical Sciences, Massey University, Palmerston North 4472, New Zealand&lt;/span>&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;/ul>&lt;ul class="articleDoi">&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tvjl.2012.07.025" id="ddDoi">&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tvjl.2012.07.025">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tvjl.2012.07.025&lt;/a>&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/help/doi.htm">How to Cite or Link Using DOI&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;/ul>&lt;ul class="articleInfo">&lt;li class="permissions" id="permissions">
&lt;div class="boxLink">
&lt;p>&lt;a class="olSpawnWindow" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science?_ob=RedirectURL&amp;amp;_method=outwardLink&amp;amp;_partnerName=936&amp;amp;_eid=1-s2.0-S1090023312003280&amp;amp;_pii=S1090023312003280&amp;amp;_origin=article&amp;amp;_zone=art_page&amp;amp;_targetURL=https%3A%2F%2Fs100.copyright.com%2FAppDispatchServlet%3FpublisherName%3DELS%26contentID%3DS1090023312003280%26orderBeanReset%3Dtrue&amp;amp;_acct=C000029718&amp;amp;_version=1&amp;amp;_userid=582538&amp;amp;md5=b82340a3d9e6f062e9d7015c91192b4b" rel="nofollow">Permissions &amp;amp; Reprints&lt;/a>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;div class="boxLink permissions">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#0000cd;">&lt;span style="font-size:18px;">(PDF  is attached at the bottom of this page)&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;br />&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Veterinarians often giving more vitamin D than govt upper limit - 2012</title><link>/posts/veterinarians-often-giving-more-vitamin-d-than-govt-upper-limit-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/veterinarians-often-giving-more-vitamin-d-than-govt-upper-limit-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="veterinarian-jobs-depend-on-span-stylecolorf00preventingspan-disease">Veterinarian jobs depend on &lt;span style="color:#F00;">preventing&lt;/span> disease,&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vets are not paid to follow government recommendations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="human-doctors-jobs-deal-with-span-stylecolorf00treatingspan-disease">Human doctors jobs deal with &lt;span style="color:#F00;">treating&lt;/span> disease,&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Drs. can get sued if they do not follow government recommendations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High-altitude associated with higher vitamin D and better bones (sheep in this case)</title><link>/posts/high-altitude-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-and-better-bones-sheep-in-this-case.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-altitude-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-and-better-bones-sheep-in-this-case.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="influence-of-high-altitude-grazing-on-bone-metabolism-of-growing-sheep">Influence of high-altitude grazing on bone metabolism of growing sheep.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr (Berl). 2013 Feb;97(1):58-66. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Oct 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liesegang A, Hüttenmoser D, Risteli J, Leiber F, Kreuzer M, Wanner M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Animal Nutrition, University of Zurich, Winterthurerstr. 260, Zurich, Switzerland. &lt;a href="mailto:aliese@vetphys.uzh.ch">aliese@vetphys.uzh.ch&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this study was to identify the effect of high alpine grazing, associated with varying pasture grass qualities and more pronounced exercise on typically steep slopes, on bone metabolism by improving bone density and enhancing bone turnover in growing sheep. Twenty-four 5-month-old sheep were randomly assigned to two groups. One group was kept at high altitude (HA; 2000-2200 m a.s.l.) for 3 months, and the other group (C; control) remained in the lowlands (400 m a.s.l.). Both groups were kept in grazing pastures with access to good-quality swards. Before the start of the experiment, blood samples were taken, the sheep were weighed, and the left metatarsus of each animal was analysed by quantitative computer tomography. After 1 month, blood samples were taken and body weight was measured, followed by biweekly sampling. Finally, the animals were slaughtered, and the bones were collected for analysis of various bone parameters. Body weight development did not differ between the groups. Concentrations of 25-OH-Vitamin D, carboxy-terminal telopeptide of type I collagen and activities of bone-specific alkaline phosphatase were always higher in the HA group than in the C group, except on the last two sampling dates. Bone mineral content and density increased in both groups during the experiment, but more intensively in the HA group. In addition, the cortical thickness of the HA group increased. The present study demonstrates an increase in bone turnover and mineral content of the bones of the growing sheep grazing in high alpine pastures. The factors associated with HA grazing, therefore, clearly seem to improve bone composition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Invertebrates use Vitamin D3 as well</title><link>/posts/invertebrates-use-vitamin-d3-as-well.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/invertebrates-use-vitamin-d3-as-well.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="results-of-a-pubmed-search-by-dr-grant-april-2013">Results of a PubMed search by Dr. Grant, April 2013&lt;/h3>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#results-of-a-pubmed-search-by-dr-grant-april-2013">Results of a PubMed search by Dr. Grant, April 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#birdeater-spiders">Birdeater spiders&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sea-animal-which-lack-calcified-skeleton-plankton">Sea animal which lack calcified skeleton, plankton&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#juvenile-grass-shrimp">Juvenile grass shrimp&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#land-snails">Land snails&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#not-sea-lamprey">Not sea lamprey&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#-">? ?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="birdeater-spiders">Birdeater spiders&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Zoo Wildl Med. 2009 Jun;40(2):344-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D3 in the hemolymph of goliath birdeater spiders (Theraphosa blondi).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zachariah TT, Mitchell MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Veterinary Clinical Sciences, School of Veterinary Medicine, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, Louisiana 70803, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:zachariahdvm@yahoo.com">zachariahdvm@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets in Humans and domestic animals</title><link>/posts/rickets-in-humans-and-domestic-animals.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-in-humans-and-domestic-animals.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-metabolism-and-rickets-in-domestic-animals--a-review">Vitamin D Metabolism and Rickets in Domestic Animals – A Review&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Veterinary Pathology March 2011 vol. 48 no. 2 389-407&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K. E. Dittmer 1 and K. G. Thompson 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Institute of Veterinary, Animal and Biomedical Sciences, Massey University, Palmerston North, New Zealand&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 K.E. Dittmer, Institute of Veterinary, Animal and Biomedical Sciences, Tennant Drive, Private Bag 11 222, Massey University, Palmerston North, New Zealand Email: &lt;a href="mailto:K.E.Dittmer@massey.ac.nz">K.E.Dittmer@massey.ac.nz&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-metabolism-and-rickets-in-domestic-animals--a-review">Vitamin D Metabolism and Rickets in Domestic Animals – A Review&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biology-of-vitamin-d">Biology of Vitamin D&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#activation-of-vitamin-d">Activation of Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#catabolism-pathways">Catabolism Pathways&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-vitamin-d-receptor">The Vitamin D Receptor&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#functions-ofvitamin-d">Functions ofVitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#other-effects">Other Effects&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#toxicity">Toxicity&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pathology-of-rickets">Pathology of Rickets&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#rickets-in-humans">Rickets in Humans&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#genetic-causes">Genetic Causes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#animal-models-of-rickets">Animal Models of Rickets&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mouse-models">Mouse Models&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#nonhuman-primates">Nonhuman Primates&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sheep-and-goats">Sheep and Goats&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cattle">Cattle&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#llamas-and-alpacas">Llamas and Alpacas&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#horses">Horses&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pigs">Pigs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dogs">Dogs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cats">Cats&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reptiles">Reptiles&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;p>Rickets and osteomalacia are increasing in prevalence in people because of cultural practices, breast-feeding, decreased sun exposure, and increased sunscreen usage. Several hereditary forms of rickets owing to either renal phosphate wasting or defects in vitamin D metabolism are also reported in people. Rickets is well recognized in domestic animals, but published reports are not always supported by microscopic findings, and diagnoses based on clinical signs and radiology are unreliable. Most cases in domestic animals are caused by dietary deficiency of either vitamin D or phosphorus, but occasional inherited forms are reported in pigs, sheep, cats, and dogs. There is variation between species in susceptibility to dietary vitamin D and phosphorus deficiency and in the ability to manufacture vitamin D in their skin. A number of mouse models have been discovered or created to study human skeletal diseases and skeletal homeostasis. With the discovery that vitamin D is involved in not only calcium and phosphorus homeostasis but also in the immune system and cancer, there is great potential for new and existing animal models to generate valuable information about vitamin D and its many functions. This review presents an overview of vitamin D metabolism and rickets in domestic and laboratory animals and makes comparisons where appropriate with the disease in humans.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tiger got surgery for hip arthritis – not much sun in the cage</title><link>/posts/tiger-got-surgery-for-hip-arthritis-not-much-sun-in-the-cage.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tiger-got-surgery-for-hip-arthritis-not-much-sun-in-the-cage.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Piglets getting single dose of 40,000 IU of vitamin D gained more weight</title><link>/posts/piglets-getting-single-dose-of-40000-iu-of-vitamin-d-gained-more-weight.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/piglets-getting-single-dose-of-40000-iu-of-vitamin-d-gained-more-weight.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="effect-of-oral-vitamin-d3-supplementation-on-growth-and-serum-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-levels-of-pigs-up-to-7-weeks-of-age">Effect of oral vitamin D3 supplementation on growth and serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D levels of pigs up to 7 weeks of age&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Swine Health Prod. 2013;21(2):94–98.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Steven J. P. Tousignant, DVM; Steven C. Henry, DVM; Albert Rovira, DVM, PhD; Robert B. Morrison, DVM, MBA, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SJPT, RBM: University of Minnesota, Population Medicine, St Paul, Minnesota.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SCH: Abilene Animal Hospital, Abilene, Kansas. AR: University of Minnesota, Veterinary Diagnostic Laboratory, St Paul, Minnesota.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omega-3 added to cattle feed increases the level in milk</title><link>/posts/omega-3-added-to-cattle-feed-increases-the-level-in-milk.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-added-to-cattle-feed-increases-the-level-in-milk.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>130% more piglets after giving gilt Calcidiol, a form of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/130-percent-more-piglets-after-giving-gilt-calcidiol-a-form-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/130-percent-more-piglets-after-giving-gilt-calcidiol-a-form-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="feeding-25-hydroxycholecalciferol-improves-gilt-reproductive-performance-and-fetal-vitamin-d-status1">Feeding 25-hydroxycholecalciferol improves gilt reproductive performance and fetal vitamin D status1&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J. D. Coffey*, E. A. Hines*, J. D. Starkey*,2, C. W. Starkey* and T. K. Chung†&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Department of Animal and Food Sciences, Texas Tech University, Lubbock 79409&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>†DSM Nutritional Products Asia Pacific, 2 Havelock Road, #04-01, Singapore 059763&lt;/p>
&lt;p>?2Corresponding author: &lt;a href="mailto:jessica.starkey@ttu.edu">jessica.starkey@ttu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Little information is available regarding the effects of vitamin D and its metabolites on reproduction in swine. To investigate the effects of feeding the circulating metabolite of vitamin D, 25-hydroxycholecalciferol (25OHD3, ROVIMIX Hy•D, DSM Nutritional Products, Basel, Switzerland) on maternal and fetal circulating 25OHD3 concentration and gilt reproductive performance, a total of 40 PIC Camborough-22 gilts (BW on d -6 = 138 kg) in 4 replicates were randomly assigned to 1 of 2 corn-soybean meal-based diets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monkeys have high levels of Vitamin D – 82 ng young, 58 ng senior</title><link>/posts/monkeys-have-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-82-ng-young-58-ng-senior.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/monkeys-have-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-82-ng-young-58-ng-senior.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="25ohd3-and-cardiovascular-risk-factors-in-female-nonhuman-primates">25(OH)D3 and cardiovascular risk factors in female nonhuman primates.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2012 Sep;21(9):959-65. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1089/jwh.2011.3416.">doi: 10.1089/jwh.2011.3416.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Aug 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorgensen MJ, Rudel LL, Nudy M, Kaplan JR, Clarkson TB, Pajewski NM, Schnatz PF &lt;a href="mailto:schnatzp@readinghospital.org">schnatzp@readinghospital.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pathology/Comparative Medicine, Wake Forest School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine if interindividual differences in plasma concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3) (25(OH)D(3)) have pathophysiologic significance, we evaluated a cohort of female monkeys, seeking to identify associations with clinically relevant cardiovascular risk factors, including age, abdominal obesity (waist circumference), and high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In less than 3 weeks chickens have problems if they do not have vitamin D</title><link>/posts/in-less-than-3-weeks-chickens-have-problems-if-they-do-not-have-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/in-less-than-3-weeks-chickens-have-problems-if-they-do-not-have-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="poultry-feed-recalledhttpunion-bulletincomstories20120727poultry-feed-recalled-over-missing-vitamin-d-july-2012">&lt;a href="http://union-bulletin.com/stories/2012/07/27/poultry-feed-recalled-over-missing-vitamin-d">Poultry Feed Recalled&lt;/a> July 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The supplier had failed to include vitamin D in a batch of feed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inadequate levels of vitamin D in a bird&amp;rsquo;s diet for more than two or three weeks may cause bone weakness, fractures or joint problems, and potentially death in birds not exposed to direct sunlight daily, according to a press release from the FDA.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="reminder-before-the-1940s-all-poultry-had-access-to-the-sunshine">Reminder: Before the 1940&amp;rsquo;s all poultry had access to the sunshine.&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/outdoor-chickens.jpg" alt="image" style="max-width: 500px;">
&lt;h4 id="then-farmers-learned-that-by-supplementing-the-poultry-with-vitamin-d-that-they-could-be-span-stylecolor00fcooped-upspan">Then farmers learned that by supplementing the poultry with vitamin D that they could be &amp;lsquo;&lt;span style="color:#00F;">cooped up&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/indoor-chickens.jpg" alt="image" style="max-width: 500px;">
&lt;h4 id="wonder-when-it-will-be-realized-that--cooped-up-humans-also-need-vitamin-d-supplements">Wonder when it will be realized that &amp;lsquo;cooped up humans also need vitamin D supplements&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-veterinary-and-vitamin-d">Overview Veterinary and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Swine with extra vitamin D more likely to get pregnant and have more and larger piglets</title><link>/posts/swine-with-extra-vitamin-d-more-likely-to-get-pregnant-and-have-more-and-larger-piglets.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/swine-with-extra-vitamin-d-more-likely-to-get-pregnant-and-have-more-and-larger-piglets.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="feeding-25-hydroxycholecalciferol-improves-gilt-reproductive-performance-and-fetal-vitamin-d-status1">Feeding 25-hydroxycholecalciferol improves gilt reproductive performance and fetal vitamin D status1&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J ANIM SCI June 4, 2012 jas.2011-5023&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. D. Coffey*, E. A. Hines*, J.D. Starkey*,2, C. W. Starkey* and T. K. Chung†&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Department of Animal and Food Sciences, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX 79409&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>†DSM Nutritional Products Asia Pacific, 2 Havelock Road, #04-01, Singapore 059763&lt;/p>
&lt;p>?2 Corresponding author: &lt;a href="mailto:jessica.starkey@ttu.edu">jessica.starkey@ttu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Little information is available regarding the effects of vitamin D and its metabolites on reproduction in swine. To investigate the effects of feeding the circulating metabolite of vitamin D, 25-hydroxycholecalciferol (25OHD3, Hy· D, DSM Nutritional Products, Basel, Switzerland) on maternal and fetal circulating 25OHD3 concentration and gilt reproductive performance, a total of 40 PIC Camborough-22 gilts (BW on d -6 = 138 kg) in 4 replicates were randomly assigned to 1 of 2 corn-soybean meal-based diets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Experiment with feedlot cattle vitamin A and D</title><link>/posts/experiment-with-feedlot-cattle-vitamin-a-and-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/experiment-with-feedlot-cattle-vitamin-a-and-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="restriction-of-vitamin-a-and-d-in-beef-cattle-finishing-diets-on-feedlot-performance-and-adipose-accretion1">Restriction of vitamin A and D in beef cattle finishing diets on feedlot performance and adipose accretion1&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>C. L. Pickworth2, S. C. Loerch and F. L. Fluharty &lt;a href="mailto:fluharty.1@osu.edu">fluharty.1@osu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Animal Sciences, The Ohio State University, Wooster 44691&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Current address: Department of Animal Science, North Carolina State University, Raleigh 27695.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feedlot producers often exceed NRC recommendations for vitamin A and D supplementation; however, increased concentrations of these vitamins have been shown to limit adipocyte differentiation in vitro. A feedlot trial was conducted using 168 Angus crossbred steers (BW = 284 ± 0.4 kg) allotted to 24 pens. The experiment had a 2 × 2 factorial arrangement of treatments: no supplemental vitamin A or D (NAND), 3,750 IU vitamin A/kg dietary DM with no supplemental vitamin D (SAND), no supplemental vitamin A and 1,860 IU vitamin D/kg dietary DM (NASD), and 3,750 IU and 1,860 IU vitamin A and D/ kg dietary DM (SASD), respectively. Serum, liver, and intramuscular and subcutaneous adipose tissue retinol concentrations were decreased in (P &amp;lt; 0.001) in cattle fed the no supplemental vitamin A diets (NAND and NASD combined) compared with those consuming supplemental vitamin A (SAND and SASD combined) diets. In addition, intramuscular retinol concentration was 38% less than in the subcutaneous depot. Serum 25(OH)D3 concentrations were reduced (P &amp;lt; 0.001) during the first 70 d when cattle were fed no supplemental vitamin D diets (NAND and SAND combined); however, liver 25(OH)D3 concentrations remained unchanged (P &amp;gt; 0.10) through d 184. Serum and liver 25(OH)D3 concentrations increased (P &amp;lt; 0.001) with vitamin D supplementation (NASD and SASD combined). The DMI, ADG, G:F, and morbidity were not affected (P &amp;gt; 0.10) by dietary concentration of vitamin A or D. There were vitamin A and D interactions (P &amp;lt; 0.03) for backfat thickness and USDA Yield grade. Cattle fed the NAND diet had greater (P &amp;lt; 0.03) Yield grades than other treatments because of greater (P &amp;lt; 0.005) 12th rib backfat thickness in NAND steers than the NASD and SAND steers. Vitamin D concentrations were attenuated and minimal carcass adiposity responses to vitamin D supplementation were observed. Feeding a diet without supplemental vitamin A increased (P &amp;lt; 0.05) Quality grades and marbling scores and tended (P = 0.06) to increase ether extractable lipid of the LM. As retinol and 25(OH)D3 concentrations in feedlot cattle declined as a result of a lack of dietary supplementation, adipose accretion increased, resulting in elevated Quality and Yield grades. Withdrawal of supplemental vitamin A, D, or both from the finishing diet of feedlot beef cattle had minimal impact carcass composition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Senior pets rejuvenated with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/senior-pets-rejuvenated-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/senior-pets-rejuvenated-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="many-stories-of-people-helping-their-aging-dogs-cats-and-other-pets-with-vitamin-d">Many stories of people helping their aging dogs, cats and other pets with Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Apparently there are no studies as of June 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-veterinary-and-vitamin-d">Overview Veterinary and vitamin D&lt;/a> many items on pets&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-following-is-a-story-of-an-old-dog-benefiting-from-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d">The following is a story of an old dog benefiting from 4000 IU of vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Beaus History&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a report on how we have managed Beaus asthma attacks since 2008. Beau is a Border Collie Cross, 17 years old, weighing in at 20kg.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D increased absorption of Phosphorus and Calcium in steers</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-increased-absorption-of-phosphorus-and-calcium-in-steers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-increased-absorption-of-phosphorus-and-calcium-in-steers.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="phosphorus-and-calcium-retention-in-steers-fed-a-roughage-diet-is-influenced-by-dietary-25oh-vitamin-d">Phosphorus and calcium retention in steers fed a roughage diet is influenced by dietary 25OH-vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Animal Production Science - &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1071/AN11293">http://dx.doi.org/10.1071/AN11293&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. J. McGrath A C, D. B. Savage A, J. V. Nolan A and R. Elliott B&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Environmental and Rural Science, University of New England, Armidale, NSW 2350, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B DSM Nutritional Products Australia Pty Ltd, Princeton Court 3, Suite 6, 13 Princeton Street, Kenmore, Qld 4069, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Corresponding author. Email: &lt;a href="mailto:jmcgrat4@une.edu.au">jmcgrat4@une.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Piglets get more vitamin D than recommended by the govt, for piglets or humans</title><link>/posts/piglets-get-more-vitamin-d-than-recommended-by-the-govt-for-piglets-or-humans.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/piglets-get-more-vitamin-d-than-recommended-by-the-govt-for-piglets-or-humans.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-syndromes-in-swine-iihttpwwwpig333comwhat_the_experts_sayvitamin-d-deficiency-syndromes-in-swine-ii_548520">&lt;a href="http://www.pig333.com/what_the_experts_say/vitamin-d-deficiency-syndromes-in-swine-ii_5485/%20">Vitamin D deficiency syndromes in swine (II)&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>16-Mar-2012 , Darin MadsonJesse Goff&lt;/p>
&lt;p>– – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – –&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Starts very low: &amp;lt; 5 ng if sow does NOT get loading dose of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Starts at 10-15 ng when sow gets loading dose before farrowing&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Loading does for 500 lb sow is 5 million IU = 10,000 IU per pound&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cow, mouse, and human immune system and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cow-mouse-and-human-immune-system-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cow-mouse-and-human-immune-system-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Piglet rickets decreased with single 40000 IU dose of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/piglet-rickets-decreased-with-single-40000-iu-dose-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/piglet-rickets-decreased-with-single-40000-iu-dose-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Even cows need more than 90 minutes in the sun each day</title><link>/posts/even-cows-need-more-than-90-minutes-in-the-sun-each-day.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/even-cows-need-more-than-90-minutes-in-the-sun-each-day.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxycholecalciferol-status-in-plasma-is-span-stylecolor00flinearly-correlatedspan--to-daily-summer-pasture-time-in-cattle-at-56n">25-Hydroxycholecalciferol status in plasma is &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">linearly correlated&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> to daily summer pasture time in cattle at 56°N.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2012 Feb 6:1-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hymøller L, Jensen SK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Animal Science, Aarhus University, Blichers Allé 20, Box 50, DK-8830 Tjele, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In vitro studies with skin samples or pure precursors of cholecalciferol indicated that cholecalciferol synthesis during UV light exposure is a non-linear process. However, in vitro studies indicate nothing about the relationship between sunlight exposure and physiological cholecalciferol status of living organisms. Due to the lack of cholecalciferol in plant material, this relationship is important for herbivores including domestic cattle, particularly in organic agriculture, because the use of synthetic additives, like cholecalciferol, is restricted in order to fulfil the principles of sustainable organic production. The major physiological metabolite of cholecalciferol is the liver-derived 25-hydroxycholecalciferol (25(OH)D3). The purpose of the present study was to determine the relationship between sunlight exposure and 25(OH)D3 status in vivo in large herbivores during mid-summer at 56°N.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>200 IU per 100 gram of egg yoke when add vitamin D to poultry feed in Europe</title><link>/posts/200-iu-per-100-gram-of-egg-yoke-when-add-vitamin-d-to-poultry-feed-in-europe.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/200-iu-per-100-gram-of-egg-yoke-when-add-vitamin-d-to-poultry-feed-in-europe.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-different-vitamin-d-supplementations-in-poultry-feed-on-vitamin-d-content-of-eggs-and-chicken-meat">Effect of different vitamin D supplementations in poultry feed on vitamin D content of eggs and chicken meat.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Agric Food Chem. 2011 Aug 10;59(15):8298-303. Epub 2011 Jul 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mattila PH, Valkonen E, Valaja J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Biotechnology and Food Research, MTT Agrifood Research Finland, Jokioinen, Finland. &lt;a href="mailto:pirjo.mattila@mtt.fi">pirjo.mattila@mtt.fi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>According to a new European Union regulation, vitamin D(3) can be partially or totally substituted with 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3) (25-OH-D(3)) in hens&amp;rsquo; feed.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this study was to clarify how this regulation has affected the vitamin D content of commercial eggs and chicken meat. Another aim was to investigate how effectively 25-OH-D(3) is transferred from the hens&amp;rsquo; diet to egg yolk by analyzing eggs from farms using known commercial feeds and by conducting an animal study. Vitamin D determinations were made by HPLC methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wonder when the first doctor will be found liable for not providing vitamin D to a patient</title><link>/posts/wonder-when-the-first-doctor-will-be-found-liable-for-not-providing-vitamin-d-to-a-patient.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wonder-when-the-first-doctor-will-be-found-liable-for-not-providing-vitamin-d-to-a-patient.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="go-to-court-not-enough-vitamin-dsunshine-for-the-monkey">Go to court: Not enough vitamin D/sunshine for the monkey&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-birmingham-16169756%20">Stourbridge pair in court for monkey cruelty&lt;/a> BBC Dec 2011&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Monkey had many bone fractures&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Owners got four charges of cruelty under the Animal Welfare Act 2006.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/monkey.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Owners of some pet reptiles setup UV lamps which their animals can use as they desire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The administrator of this wiki site has setup UV lamp for himself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several friends who have cats have also purchased UV lamps - which their cats enjoy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sheep in upper pastures had more vitamin D and better bones</title><link>/posts/sheep-in-upper-pastures-had-more-vitamin-d-and-better-bones.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sheep-in-upper-pastures-had-more-vitamin-d-and-better-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="influence-of-high-altitude-grazing-on-bone-metabolism-of-growing-sheep">Influence of high-altitude grazing on bone metabolism of growing sheep.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr (Berl). 2011 Oct 13. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liesegang A, Hüttenmoser D, Risteli J, Leiber F, Kreuzer M, Wanner M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>?Institute of Animal Nutrition, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland ?Department of Clinical Chemistry, University of Oulu, Oulu, Finland ?ETH Zurich, Institute of Agricultural Sciences, Zurich, Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this study was to identify the effect of high alpine grazing, associated with varying pasture grass qualities and more pronounced exercise on typically steep slopes, on bone metabolism by improving bone density and enhancing bone turnover in growing sheep. Twenty-four 5-month-old sheep were randomly assigned to two groups. One group was kept at high altitude (HA; 2000-2200?m a.s.l.) for 3?months, and the other group (C; control) remained in the lowlands (400?m a.s.l.). Both groups were kept in grazing pastures with access to good-quality swards. Before the start of the experiment, blood samples were taken, the sheep were weighed, and the left metatarsus of each animal was analysed by quantitative computer tomography. &lt;strong>After 1?month&lt;/strong> , blood samples were taken and body weight was measured, followed by biweekly sampling. Finally, the animals were slaughtered, and the bones were collected for analysis of various bone parameters. Body weight development did not differ between the groups.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cattle need 66 IU of vitamin D per pound</title><link>/posts/cattle-need-66-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-pound.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cattle-need-66-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-pound.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-nutrient-requirements-of-dairy-cattle-seventh--2001">From Nutrient Requirements of Dairy Cattle: Seventh — 2001&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="subcommittee-on-dairy-cattle-nutrition-committee-on-animal-nutrition-national-research-council-408-pages">Subcommittee on Dairy Cattle Nutrition, Committee on Animal Nutrition, National Research Council 408 pages&lt;/h3>
&lt;h1 id="pdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-this-page">PDF is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="includes-vitamin-d-vitamin-k-sulfur-iodine-magnesium-and-many-others">Includes Vitamin D, Vitamin K, Sulfur, Iodine, Magnesium, and many others&lt;/h3>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d">Vitamin D&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="physiology">PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a pro-hormone, a necessary precursor for the production of the calcium regulating hormone 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D. Vitamin D can be produced within the skin of most mammals, including cattle, as a result of the photochemical conversion of 7-dehydrocholesterol to vitamin D3. In plants, ultraviolet irradiation causes photochemical conversion of ergosterol to vitamin D2. Vitamin D, supplied by the skin or the diet, is rapidly transported to and sequestered by the liver. The rapid removal of vitamin D from circulation prevents concentrations of vitamin D in blood from becoming very high; the normal concentration is 1 to 2 ng vitamin D/ml plasma (Horst and Littledike, 1982). Within the liver, vitamin D can be converted to 25-hydroxyvitamin D by vitamin D 25-hydrox-ylase and released into the blood. The production of 25-hydroxyvitamin D within the liver is dependent on the vitamin D content of the diet. Thus plasma 25-hydroxy-vitamin D concentration is the best indicator of vitamin D status of an animal (Horst et al., 1994).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Controversy cats and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/controversy-cats-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/controversy-cats-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#there-is-much-disagreement-on-the-internet-about-the-source-of-vitamin-d-for-cats">There is much disagreement on the internet about the source of vitamin D for cats&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cats-get-it-from-preyfood">Cats get it from prey/food&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cats-get-it-from-their-fur-if-they-get-time-in-the-sun">Cats get it from their fur if they get time in the sun&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cats-like-uv">Cats like UV&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cat-and-dog-distemper">Cat and Dog distemper&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="there-is-much-disagreement-on-the-internet-about-the-source-of-vitamin-d-for-cats">There is much disagreement on the internet about the source of vitamin D for cats&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="cats-get-it-from-preyfood">Cats get it from prey/food&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Example &lt;a href="http://www.2ndchance.info/birdsvitd.htm%20">How Much Vitamin D Should My Pet Receive? &lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogs and cats cannot synthesize vitamin D-3; in the wild they would obtain it by eating prey so it is added to all their complete commercial pet foods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Primates Nutrient Requirements – 2003</title><link>/posts/primates-nutrient-requirements-2003.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/primates-nutrient-requirements-2003.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="nutrient-requirements-of-nonhuman-primates-second-revised-edition">Nutrient Requirements of Nonhuman Primates: Second Revised Edition&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Committee on Animal Nutrition, Ad Hoc Committee on Nonhuman Primate Nutrition, National Research Council&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ISBN: 0-309-51524-6, 308 pages, 8.5 x 11, (2003)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Includes Vitamin D, Vitamin K, Sulfur, Iodine, Magnesium, and many others&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note IU are typically given per&lt;/strong> &lt;span style="color:#00F;">kg of FEED&lt;/span> &lt;strong>not WEIGHT&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/primates-nutrional-requirements.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki.&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d">Vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For the primate species that have been studied, vitamin D is not an essential component of the diet as long as they have adequate exposure to sunlight (Holick, 1994). But it appears to be essential in the tissues of most primates for maintenance of calcium and phosphorus homeostasis and for normal bone mineralization (Holick, 1996). In the absence of solar exposure, these primates must be exposed to sources of artificial light of appropriate wavelengths or must receive sufficient vitamin D in the diet. In this review we will try to put into perspective what is known about vitamin D in humans and to compare this information with what is known about its role in nonhuman primates and other vertebrates.!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Health and Light - Ott 1973</title><link>/posts/health-and-light-ott-1973.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/health-and-light-ott-1973.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Health and Light by John N. Ott&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-effects-of-natural-and-artificial-light-on-man-and-other-living-things">The Effects of Natural and Artificial Light on Man and Other Living Things.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>How light can work for you &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>for your health, your emotional well-being and your vibrant energy &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>no matter where you live or work!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published by Pocket Books – New York; Copyright John Ott Pictures, Inc. ; First printing 1973 – ISBN: 0-671-80537-1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reprint edition (April 1, 2000) – ISBN: 0-898-04098-1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogs – like humans – with IBD were low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dogs-like-humans-with-ibd-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dogs-like-humans-with-ibd-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-dogs-with-inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-hypoalbuminaemia">Hypovitaminosis D in dogs with inflammatory bowel disease and hypoalbuminaemia.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>A G Gow, R Else, H Evans, J L Berry, M E Herrtage and R J Mellanby J Small Anim Pract 52(8):411-418 (2011) PMID 21797872&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To compare serum vitamin D metabolites and plasma parathyroid hormone concentrations in dogs with inflammatory bowel disease and normal albumin concentration, dogs with inflammatory bowel disease and hypoalbuminaemia, healthy dogs and hospitalised ill dogs with non-gastrointestinal illness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sun-cured hay often has 2000 IU of vitamin D per kilogram</title><link>/posts/sun-cured-hay-often-has-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kilogram.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sun-cured-hay-often-has-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kilogram.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#if-he-doesnt-get-enough">If he doesn&amp;rsquo;t get enough:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>

 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h1 id="fresh-hay-has-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kilogram-1999httphorsepurinamillscomnutritionvitamindasp20">&lt;a href="http://horse.purinamills.com/nutrition/vitamind.asp%20">Fresh hay has 2000 IU of vitamin D per kilogram 1999&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>By Christine Barakat&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fast fact: Vitamin D is the only nutrient more abundant in dried forage than in fresh.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How your horse uses it: Both types of vitamin D-D2 and D3-help maintain your horse&amp;rsquo;s critical electrolyte balance by binding to calcium and magnesium, aiding in their absorption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where it&amp;rsquo;s found: Your horse synthesizes vitamin D3 within his body when ultraviolet rays from sunlight combine with a form of cholesterol naturally present in his skin. Vitamin D2 is found in the dried leaves of cut plants that have been exposed to sunlight-in other words, hay.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>6 days of 7,000,000 IU of vitamin D improved the resulting beef</title><link>/posts/6-days-of-7000000-iu-of-vitamin-d-improved-the-resulting-beef.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/6-days-of-7000000-iu-of-vitamin-d-improved-the-resulting-beef.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lots of vitamin D for steers</title><link>/posts/lots-of-vitamin-d-for-steers.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lots-of-vitamin-d-for-steers.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>10 million IU of vitamin D3 for cows was great unless had vitamin D2</title><link>/posts/10-million-iu-of-vitamin-d3-for-cows-was-great-unless-had-vitamin-d2.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10-million-iu-of-vitamin-d3-for-cows-was-great-unless-had-vitamin-d2.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reindeer can see UVA</title><link>/posts/reindeer-can-see-uva.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reindeer-can-see-uva.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="clipps-from-reindeer-see-a-weird-and-wonderful-world-of-ultraviolet-lighthttpwwwphysorgcomnews2011-05-reindeer-weird-world-ultraviolethtml">Clipps from &lt;a href="http://www.physorg.com/news/2011-05-reindeer-weird-world-ultraviolet.html">Reindeer see a weird and wonderful world of ultraviolet light&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>“Humans and almost all other mammals could never do this as our lenses just don&amp;rsquo;t let UV through into the eye.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“. . .they can handle wavelengths down to around 350-320nm, . . . “&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;When we used cameras that could pick up UV, we noticed that there are some very important things that absorb UV light and therefore appear black, contrasting strongly with the snow. This includes&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monkeys each got 1000 IU daily - but vitamin D in blood varied with HDL</title><link>/posts/monkeys-each-got-1000-iu-daily-but-vitamin-d-in-blood-varied-with-hdl.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/monkeys-each-got-1000-iu-daily-but-vitamin-d-in-blood-varied-with-hdl.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="identification-of-a-mechanism-for-increased-cardiovascular-risk-among-individuals-with-low-vitamin-d-concentrations">Identification of a mechanism for increased cardiovascular risk among individuals with low vitamin D concentrations.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Menopause. 2011 May 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schnatz PF, Nudy M, O&amp;rsquo;Sullivan DM, Ethun K, Appt SE, Clarkson TB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Departments of 1 ObGyn and 2 Internal Medicine, The Reading Hospital and Medical Center, Reading, PA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of 3 ObGyn and 4 Internal Medicine, Jefferson Medical College of Thomas Jefferson University, Philadelphia, PA; and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>5 Department of Pathology/Comparative Medicine, Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, NC.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Swine need sunshine or 500-2800 IU vitamin D3</title><link>/posts/swine-need-sunshine-or-500-2800-iu-vitamin-d3.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/swine-need-sunshine-or-500-2800-iu-vitamin-d3.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="table-is-from-article-attached-to-this-page">Table is from article attached to this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="200-lb-swine-needs-500-to-2800-iu-per-day">200 lb swine needs 500 to 2800 IU per day&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="50-lb-swine-needs-200-to-1200-iu-per-day">50 lb swine needs 200 to 1200 IU per day&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/gif/vitamin-d3-for-swine.gif" alt="image">
&lt;h2 id="nutrient-requirements-of-swine-10th-revised-edition-1998-httpwwwnapeduopenbookphprecord_id6016page73">&lt;a href="http://www.nap.edu/openbook.php?record_id=6016&amp;amp;page=73">Nutrient Requirements of Swine: 10th Revised Edition (1998) &lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="a-few-quotes-clipped-from-dsmhttpwwwdsmcomen_ushtmldnpnaanh_swin_vit_d_reqhtm-on-swine-and-vitamin-d">A few quotes clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.dsm.com/en_US/html/dnpna/anh_swin_vit_d_req.htm">DSM&lt;/a> on swine and vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>“Vitamin D becomes a nutritionally important factor in the &lt;strong>absence of sufficient sunlight.&lt;/strong> ”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“The &lt;strong>colors of the skin&lt;/strong> are important in determining response to irradiation. Irradiation is less effective on dark-pigmented skin. This has been shown to be true for white and black breeds of hogs. White pigs have been shown to resist vitamin D deficiency signs about &lt;strong>twice as long as colored pigs&lt;/strong> ; an average of 45 minutes of daily exposure to January sunshine for two weeks was sufficient to cure rickets in white pigs in Minnesota (Cunha, 1977).”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lambs get 10X more vitamin D3 in their milk formula than humans</title><link>/posts/lambs-get-10x-more-vitamin-d3-in-their-milk-formula-than-humans.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lambs-get-10x-more-vitamin-d3-in-their-milk-formula-than-humans.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="lambs-and-sheep-royal-instant-lamb-milk-replacer-12000-iu-lbhttpwwwroyalmilcinccomlambs_and_sheephtml">&lt;a href="http://www.royalmilcinc.com/lambs_and_sheep.html">Lambs and Sheep: Royal Instant Lamb Milk Replacer 12,000 IU /lb&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>An excellent all milk protein, high fat (30%), low lactose (less than 25%), formula made with human grade ingredients, human-edible lard and coconut oil, soluble vitamins, chelated trace minerals, selenium and zinc proteinate providing a complete milk ration for lambs until weaning. Feed Royal Instant Milk Replacer to lambs cold, manually or free choice as a substitute for ewe&amp;rsquo;s milk to maximize economic use of milk, whenever ewe&amp;rsquo;s milk is inadequate or unavailable. It will stay preserved for up to 24 hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reptiles ate as well with all UV sources</title><link>/posts/reptiles-ate-as-well-with-all-uv-sources.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reptiles-ate-as-well-with-all-uv-sources.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-vitamin-d-levels-and-skeletal-and-general-development-of-young-bearded-dragon-lizards-pogona-vitticeps-under-different-conditions-of-uv-b-radiation-exposure">Serum Vitamin D Levels and Skeletal and General Development of Young Bearded Dragon Lizards (Pogona vitticeps), under Different Conditions of UV-B Radiation Exposure&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>K.R. Kroenlein, K.L. Zimmerman, G. Saunders and S.D. Holladay&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Animal and Veterinary Advances&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Year: 2011 | Volume: 10 | Issue: 2 | Page No.: 229-234&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.3923/javaa.2011.229.234&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="click-herehttpwwwmedwelljournalscomfulltextdoijavaa2011229234-for-full-research">&lt;a href="http://www.medwelljournals.com/fulltext/?doi=javaa.2011.229.234">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for full research&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Tried many different UV sources, but the bearded dragon reptiles ate as much under each UV source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fish need vitamin D and C for their bones</title><link>/posts/fish-need-vitamin-d-and-c-for-their-bones.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fish-need-vitamin-d-and-c-for-their-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="overview-of-vitamin-d-and-c-requirements-in-fish-and-their-influence-on-the-skeletal-system">Overview of vitamin D and C requirements in fish and their influence on the skeletal system&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>M.J. Dariasa, &lt;a href="mailto:maria.darias@irta.cat">maria.darias@irta.cat&lt;/a>, D. Mazuraisa, G. Koumoundourosb, C.L. Cahua and J.L. Zambonino-Infantea&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Ifremer Marine Fish Nutrition Team, Nutrition Aquaculture and Genomics Research Unit, UMR 1067. Ifremer, Technopole Brest-Iroise, BP 70, 29280 Plouzané, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b University of Patras, Biology Department, 26500 Patras, Rio, Greece&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 6 May 2010; revised 3 December 2010; accepted 17 December 2010. Available online 7 January 2011. j.aquaculture.2010.12.030&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV for is for the birds</title><link>/posts/uv-for-is-for-the-birds.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-for-is-for-the-birds.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Some fish can see in UV</title><link>/posts/some-fish-can-see-in-uv.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-fish-can-see-in-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="fish-can-recognize-a-face-based-on-uv-pattern-alone">Fish can recognize a face based on UV pattern alone&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>February 25, 2010 &lt;a href="http://www.physorg.com/news186328108.html">http://www.physorg.com/news186328108.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two species of damselfish may look identical - not to mention drab - to the human eye. But that&amp;rsquo;s because, in comparison to the fish, all of us are essentially colorblind. A new study published online on February 25th in Current Biology reveals that the fish can easily tell one species from another based entirely on the shape of the ultraviolet (UV) patterns on their faces.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB better than vitamin D supplements for pet reptiles</title><link>/posts/uvb-better-than-vitamin-d-supplements-for-pet-reptiles.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-better-than-vitamin-d-supplements-for-pet-reptiles.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation-and-uvb-exposure-on-the-growth-and-plasma-concentration-of-vitamin-d3-metabolites-in-juvenile-bearded-dragons-pogona-vitticeps">Effects of vitamin D(3) supplementation and UVb exposure on the growth and plasma concentration of vitamin D(3) metabolites in juvenile bearded dragons (Pogona vitticeps).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Comp Biochem Physiol B Biochem Mol Biol. 2010 Mar 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oonincx DG, Stevens Y, van den Borne JJ, van Leeuwen JP, Hendriks WH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Animal Nutrition Group, Department of Animal Sciences, Wageningen University, Wageningen, The Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The effectiveness of dietary vitamin D(3) and UVb exposure on plasma vitamin D metabolites in growing bearded dragons (Pogona vitticeps) was studied. A total of 84 (40 males and 44 females) newly hatched bearded dragons were allocated to six levels of oral vitamin D(3) supplementation (0 to 400%) or six UVb exposure times (2 to 12h). At 3 and 6months of age, blood samples were obtained from each animal and analysed for 25(OH)D(3) and 1,25(OH)(2)D(3). At 3months of age, plasma concentrations of 25(OH)D(3) did not increase with increasing vitamin D(3) supplementation unlike the 1,25(OH)(2)D(3). At 6months of age, plasma concentrations of both 25(OH)D(3) and 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) increased with increasing vitamin D(3) supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calves do well with 1930 IU of vitamin D - 6X more that feed recommendations</title><link>/posts/calves-do-well-with-1930-iu-of-vitamin-d-6x-more-that-feed-recommendations.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calves-do-well-with-1930-iu-of-vitamin-d-6x-more-that-feed-recommendations.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="model-developed-for-manipulating-vitamin-d-levels-in-calves">Model Developed for Manipulating Vitamin D Levels in Calves&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>By Chris Guy May 25, 2010 &lt;a href="http://www.ars.usda.gov/is/pr/2010/100525.htm">http://www.ars.usda.gov/is/pr/2010/100525.htm&lt;/a> (which has hyperlinks)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A new model for manipulating vitamin D levels in young calves has been developed by Agricultural Research Service (ARS) scientists who say it could help establish just how much of this important nutrient the young animals need to promote optimal growth and health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Newborn dairy calves get crucial vitamin D in the colostrum from their mothers as they nurse during the first few days after birth. Later, the neonatal calf often receives vitamin D in commercial milk replacers. But levels of vitamin D in these supplements may need to be reevaluated, given recent evidence suggesting vitamin D status influences not only bone growth, but also immune function.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vit D3 generated in spite of cow fur</title><link>/posts/vit-d3-generated-in-spite-of-cow-fur.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vit-d3-generated-in-spite-of-cow-fur.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Vitamin D(3) synthesis in the entire skin surface of dairy cows despite hair coverage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>profile L Hymøller and profile S K Jensen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Animal Health and Bioscience, Aarhus University, Faculty of Agricultural Sciences, Blichers Allé 20, Box 50, DK-8830 Tjele, Denmark. &lt;a href="mailto:Lone.Hymoller@agrsci.dk">Lone.Hymoller@agrsci.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Dairy Science Volume 93, Issue 5, (May 2010)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How hair-coated animals such as dairy cows synthesize endogenous vitamin D(3) during exposure to summer sunlight has been unclear since vitamin D(3) and its relation to sunlight was discovered. The fur of fur-bearing animals is thought to be comparable to clothing in humans, which prevents vitamin D(3) synthesis in the skin during exposure to sunlight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets increasing in dogs</title><link>/posts/rickets-increasing-in-dogs.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-increasing-in-dogs.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="rickets-in-dogs--vitamin-d-mar-2010">Rickets in Dogs &amp;amp; Vitamin D Mar 2010&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>1-800-PetMeds Drs. Foster and Smith Inc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>from &lt;a href="http://www.liquid-vitamins-minerals-humans-pets.com/Ricketsindogs.html">http://www.liquid-vitamins-minerals-humans-pets.com/Ricketsindogs.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frank Will, EzineArticles.com Platinum Author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rickets in dogs is becoming a lot more common than it used to be and it is speculated that it may be caused by Puppy mills and the lack of the proper nutrients that all growing dogs require. However, there may be some other issues with your dog that causes this disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why do animals seem to need more vitamin D than humans</title><link>/posts/why-do-animals-seem-to-need-more-vitamin-d-than-humans.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-do-animals-seem-to-need-more-vitamin-d-than-humans.html</guid><description>&lt;p>From Merck Veterinary Manual 1998&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="at-400-iuday-the-fda-appears-to-believe-that-humans-require-less-than-the-majority-of-animals-in-the-merck-vet-manual-and-far-less-than-the-non-human-primates-2500-iukg">At 400 IU/day the FDA appears to believe that humans require less than the majority of animals in the Merck Vet Manual, and far less than the non-human primates (2,500 IU/kg).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A great many animals have their vitamin D requirements specified in terms of IU per kilogram of dry feed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Often there is a reduced requirement if the animal has access to sunshine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wonder if vets in the northern latitudes or cloudy areas increase the vitamin D in the feed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Veterinary and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-veterinary-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-veterinary-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pigs-get--10000-iu-of-water-soluble-vitamin-d-per-gallon-of-drinking-water">Pigs get 10,000 IU of water-soluble Vitamin D per gallon of drinking water&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.qcsupply.com/emcelle-vitamind3-liquid-1liter.html?utm_medium=cpc&amp;amp;utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_campaign=&amp;amp;utm_content=&amp;amp;utm_term=&amp;amp;gad_source=1&amp;amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwzIK1BhAuEiwAHQmU3id6bsjCW1rOfvh73J3MSbSXvb5My1syaWklZzMU1oXEh4Wp-8V8cxoCoU4QAvD_BwE">Cost: $1 per 2 million IU&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> (2 million IU of Vitamin D costs humans &lt;strong>$8&lt;/strong> )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or give newborn pig 42,250 I.U Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-cow-experts-probably-base-their-ideas-on">The cow experts probably base their ideas on&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>what is needed,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>what actually works,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>what is cost effective (vitamin D for a cow costs about $1/year), and&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>what does not have ANY long-term bad side-effects&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>