<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Veterinary on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/veterinary-.html</link><description>Recent content in Veterinary on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/veterinary-/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Obese baboons consume 73 percent more vitamin D – keeping blood level the same</title><link>/posts/obese-baboons-consume-73-percent-more-vitamin-d-keeping-blood-level-the-same.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-baboons-consume-73-percent-more-vitamin-d-keeping-blood-level-the-same.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-vitamin-d-concentrations-in-baboons-papio-spp-during-pregnancy-and-obesity">Serum Vitamin D Concentrations in Baboons (Papio spp.) during Pregnancy and Obesity.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Comp Med. 2016;66(2):137-42.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schlabritz-Loutsevitch NE1, Comuzzie AG2, Mahaney MM3, Hubbard GB4, Dick EJ5, Kocak M6, Gupta S7, Carrillo M8, Schenone M7, Postlethwaite A9, Slominski A10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Texas Tech University HSC School of Medicine at the Permian Basin, Odessa, Texas, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:Natalia.schlabritz-lutsevich@ttuhsc.edu">Natalia.schlabritz-lutsevich@ttuhsc.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Departments of Genetics, Texas Biomedical Research Institute, San Antonio, Texas, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3The University of Texas Rio Grande Valley, Brownsville, Texas, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Animals get a lot more vitamin D than minimum recommended for humans – 2016</title><link>/posts/animals-get-a-lot-more-vitamin-d-than-minimum-recommended-for-humans-2016.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/animals-get-a-lot-more-vitamin-d-than-minimum-recommended-for-humans-2016.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="dsm-vitamin-supplementation-guidelines-2016-for-animal-nutrition">DSM Vitamin Supplementation Guidelines 2016 for animal nutrition&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="the-goal-of-a-vet-is-to-keep-animals-healthy">The goal of a Vet is to keep animals healthy.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The goal of a goverment is to avoid any possible risk to the recomenders in the govt.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolorf00humans-need-more-vitamin-dspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Humans need more vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>IU is typically per kilogram of feed&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It seems that a human adult eats about 2 kg of dry food/day, so might multiply by 2X for adult&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>They often also use HyD – a semi-activated form of Vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Companion animals (dog, cats) need vitamin D too</title><link>/posts/companion-animals-dog-cats-need-vitamin-d-too.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/companion-animals-dog-cats-need-vitamin-d-too.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#beyond-the-skeleton-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-companion-animal-health---2016">Beyond the skeleton: the role of vitamin D in companion animal health - 2016&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-metabolism">Vitamin D metabolism&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-gastrointestinal-diseases">Vitamin D and gastrointestinal diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-kidney-diseases">Vitamin D and kidney diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-cardiac-diseases">Vitamin D and cardiac diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-infectious-diseases">Vitamin D and infectious diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-cancer">Vitamin D and cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-inflammation">Vitamin D and inflammation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-mortality">Vitamin D and mortality&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#future-directions">FUTURE DIRECTIONS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="beyond-the-skeleton-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-companion-animal-health---2016">Beyond the skeleton: the role of vitamin D in companion animal health - 2016&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Small Animal Practice (2016) 57, 175-180 DOI: 10.1111/jsap.12458&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More surviving offspring if mother had high vitamin D (sheep in this case)</title><link>/posts/more-surviving-offspring-if-mother-had-high-vitamin-d-sheep-in-this-case.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-surviving-offspring-if-mother-had-high-vitamin-d-sheep-in-this-case.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-predicts-reproductive-fitness-in-a-wild-sheep-population">Vitamin D status predicts reproductive fitness in a wild sheep population&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 18986 (2016), doi:10.1038/srep18986&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ian Handel, Kathryn A. Watt, Jill G. Pilkington, Josephine M. Pemberton, Alastair Macrae, Philip Scott, Tom N. McNeilly, Jacqueline L. Berry, Dylan N. Clements, Daniel H. Nussey &amp;amp; Richard J. Mellanby&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with the development of many human diseases, and with poor reproductive performance in laboratory rodents. We currently have no idea how natural selection directly acts on variation in vitamin D metabolism due to a total lack of studies in wild animals. Here, we measured serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentrations in female Soay sheep that were part of a long-term field study on St Kilda. We found that total 25(OH)D was strongly influenced by age, and that light coloured sheep had higher 25(OH)D3 (but not 25(OH)D2) concentrations than dark sheep. The coat colour polymorphism in Soay sheep is controlled by a single locus, suggesting vitamin D status is heritable in this population. &lt;strong>We also observed a very strong relationship between total 25(OH)D concentrations in summer and a ewe’s fecundity the following spring.&lt;/strong> This resulted in a positive association between total 25(OH)D and the number of lambs produced that survived their first year of life, an important component of female reproductive fitness. Our study provides the first insight into naturally-occurring variation in vitamin D metabolites, and offers the first evidence that vitamin D status is both heritable and under natural selection in the wild.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pigs have about 2X less variation in response to calcidiol as humans do to vitamin D – 2015</title><link>/posts/pigs-have-about-2x-less-variation-in-response-to-calcidiol-as-humans-do-to-vitamin-d-2015.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pigs-have-about-2x-less-variation-in-response-to-calcidiol-as-humans-do-to-vitamin-d-2015.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cats with feline HIV and hospitalized cats have low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cats-with-feline-hiv-and-hospitalized-cats-have-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cats-with-feline-hiv-and-hospitalized-cats-have-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-cats-with-feline-immunodeficiency-virus">Vitamin D status in cats with feline immunodeficiency virus&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Veterinary Medicine and Science, Volume 1, Issue 2, pages 72–78, Oct2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Helen F. Titmarsh1,*, Stephanie M. Lalor1, Severine Tasker2, Emily N. Barker2, Jacqueline Berry3, Danielle Gunn-More1 and Richard J Mellanby1&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/feline-hiv.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Feline immunodeficiency virus (FIV) is a lentivirus that can lead to a syndrome of acquired immune dysfunction. Infected cats often remain asymptomatic for several years before immune dysfunction leads to an increased risk for the development of systemic diseases, neoplasia and opportunistic infections. FIV is structurally related to human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and the pathogenesis of FIV-related disease is similar to that seen in HIV-infected patients. Observational studies have documented an association between low plasma vitamin D and HIV infection. Vitamin D status has been shown to be associated with HIV-related disease progression, morbidity and mortality. The objective of this study was to examine the hypothesis that vitamin D status, as assessed by serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations, are lower in cats with FIV infection compared to healthy control cats. Serum 25(OH)D concentrations were measured in 20 healthy cats, 39 hospitalized ill cats and 59 cats infected with FIV. Cats which were FIV infected had significantly lower 25(OH)D concentrations compared to healthy control cats. Serum 25(OH)D concentrations were not significantly different between FIV-infected cats and hospitalized ill cats. Further investigations are warranted to determine whether vitamin D status influences the prognosis of cats infected with FIV.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Behavior changes due to low vitamin D – in rodents</title><link>/posts/behavior-changes-due-to-low-vitamin-d-in-rodents.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/behavior-changes-due-to-low-vitamin-d-in-rodents.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-impact-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-on-behavior-and-brain-function-in-rodents">The impact of vitamin D deficiency on behavior and brain function in rodents&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Current Opinion in Behavioral Sciences, Available online 26 November 2015, doi:10.1016/j.cobeha.2015.11.012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K Overeem1, DW Eyles1, 2, JJ McGrath1, 2, THJ Burne1, 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•We review studies using rodent models of vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•Prenatal vitamin D deficiency alters brain development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•Adult vitamin D deficiency alters behaviour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been proposed as an environmental risk factor for several neurological disorders. To investigate the biological plausibility of this risk factor, vitamin D (DVD) deficiency rodent models have been used to examine the impact of DVD deficiency on neurobiology and behaviour. The majority of these studies have taken a developmental stance and examined the impact of vitamin D deficiency during gestation on the adult behaviour of the &lt;strong>offspring&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dog Cancer 4X more likely if low Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dog-cancer-4x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dog-cancer-4x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="new-study-shows-dogs-with-low-vitamin-d-are-at-risk-for-cancerhttpwwwdogsnaturallymagazinecomnew-study-shows-dogs-with-low-vitamin-d-are-at-risk-for-cancer-dogsnaturally">&lt;a href="http://www.dogsnaturallymagazine.com/new-study-shows-dogs-with-low-vitamin-d-are-at-risk-for-cancer/">New Study Shows Dogs with Low Vitamin D Are At Risk For Cancer&lt;/a> DogsNaturally&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/cancer-in-dogs---low-vitamin-d.jpg" alt="image" width="300">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Some other factors that are known to decrease the ability to convert dietary vitamin D to 25-VitD:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Polyunsaturated fats can decrease the bioavailability of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fluoride (which is present in many pet foods and water supplies)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>decreases magnesium, which is an essential cofactor for vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Strong magnetic fields can reduce vitamin D levels&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>PCBs increase the risk of deficiency by 3%&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is great for dogs and cats too</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-great-for-dogs-and-cats-too.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-great-for-dogs-and-cats-too.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#50-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-pound-of-dog-helps-blood-in-this-study---may2024">50 IU of Vitamin D per pound of dog (helps blood in this study) - May 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#might-vitamin-d-improve-the-health-and-life-of-pet-cats---asked-perplexity-ai-june2024">Might vitamin D improve the health and life of pet cats? - asked Perplexity AI June 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cats-and-dogs-can-generate-vitamin-d-in-their-fur-and-then-lick-if-off---2012">Cats and dogs can generate Vitamin D in their fur, and then lick if off - 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-in-health-and-disease-in-dogs-and-cats-nov2020">Vitamin D in Health and Disease in Dogs and Cats Nov 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#web">Web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#examples-of-vitamin-d-suppliers-fordogs">Examples of Vitamin D suppliers for dogs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="50-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-pound-of-dog-helps-blood-in-this-study---may2024">50 IU of Vitamin D per pound of dog (helps blood in this study) - May 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A study on the effects of vitamin D supplementation on hematological parameters and serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D in healthy dogs&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Receptor and immune differences between mice and men</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-and-immune-differences-between-mice-and-men.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-and-immune-differences-between-mice-and-men.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="species-specific-regulation-of-innate-immunity-by-vitamin-d-signaling">Species-specific regulation of innate immunity by vitamin D signaling&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, doi:10.1016/j.jsbmb.2015.09.016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vassil Dimitrov, John H. White,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•The hormonal form of vitamin D, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D, is a key regulator of innate immunity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•In humans, the activated vitamin D receptor (VDR) is a direct regulator of transcription of genes encoding antimicrobial peptides, pattern recognition receptors, and innate immune cytokines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•While regulation of VDR target genes implicated in innate immunity in humans appears to be widely conserved in primates, the regulation is not conserved in mice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High dose vitamin D (20,000 IU per kg of feed) safe for pigs</title><link>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-d-20000-iu-per-kg-of-feed-safe-for-pigs.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-d-20000-iu-per-kg-of-feed-safe-for-pigs.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="tolerance-evaluation-of-overdosed-dietary-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-in-growing-piglets">Tolerance evaluation of overdosed dietary levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 in growing piglets.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr (Berl). 2015 Aug 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/jpn.12355">doi: 10.1111/jpn.12355&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>von Rosenberg SJ1, Weber GM2, Erhardt A1, Höller U2, Wehr UA1, Rambeck WA1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forty-eight, cross-bred (GL × LW × P) piglets were used in a 42-day tolerance trial to assess the effects of feeding diets supplemented with vitamin D or increasing levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25-OH-D3 ). Six-week-old piglets (24 castrate males, 24 females) were used. Two replicate groups of 6 piglets were randomized by weight and allocated to four dietary treatments. The control group (T1) was supplemented with 50 μg vitamin D3 /kg feed. The experimental groups received 25-OH-D3 at the recommended dose (T2: 50 μg/kg = 1x), at 250 μg/kg (T3: 5x) or at 500 μg/kg (T4: 10x) respectively. Feed intake and daily weight gain were measured weekly, and the animals were examined by a veterinarian daily. After 42 days, body mass, blood, urine, bone and tissue samples were analysed and a pathology examination conducted. Dietary treatments had no significant effect on final body mass or daily weight gain. The 25-OH-D3 plasma concentration in T1 was 17 ± 3 ng/ml (mean ± SD) while the respective values of the experimental groups were significantly increased in T2, T3 and T4. Tissue concentrations of 25-OH-D3 were higher in liver and muscle for T3 and T4 and in skin for T4 than in T1. However, neither gross pathology nor histology, nor blood and urine characteristics, nor bone parameters were affected by dietary treatments. Weight of organs as well as dry matter, ash and calcium content of kidneys remained unaffected by dietary 25-OH-D3 intake. Furthermore, no changes were observed for general indicators of health. The results of this study demonstrated that feeding piglets with 25-OH-D3 at 5 or 10 times the recommended level had no adverse effects on any of the biological parameters measured. It was concluded that 25-OH-D3 can be regarded as a supplement with a very high safety margin when used at the recommended level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultraviolet B needed for indoor cows to have enough vitamin D in milk</title><link>/posts/ultraviolet-b-needed-for-indoor-cows-to-have-enough-vitamin-d-in-milk.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ultraviolet-b-needed-for-indoor-cows-to-have-enough-vitamin-d-in-milk.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="short-communication-artificial-ultraviolet-b-light-exposure-increases-vitamin-d-levels-in-cow-plasma-and-milk">Short communication: Artificial ultraviolet B light exposure increases vitamin D levels in cow plasma and milk.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Dairy Sci. 2015 Jun 24. pii: S0022-0302(15)00433-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3168/jds.2014-9277.">doi: 10.3168/jds.2014-9277.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jakobsen J1, Jensen SK2, Hymøller L2, Andersen EW3, Kaas P4, Burild A5, Jäpelt RB5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1National Food Institute, Technical University of Denmark, 2860 Søborg, Denmark. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:jeja@food.dtu.dk">jeja@food.dtu.dk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Animal Science, Aarhus University, 8830 Tjele, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Applied Mathematics and Computer Science, Technical University of Denmark, 2800 Lyngby, Denmark.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Neonate horses (as well as neonate humans) having low vitamin D are more likely to die.</title><link>/posts/neonate-horses-as-well-as-neonate-humans-having-low-vitamin-d-are-more-likely-to-die.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/neonate-horses-as-well-as-neonate-humans-having-low-vitamin-d-are-more-likely-to-die.html</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="vitamin-d-metabolites-and-their-association-with-calcium-phosphorus-and-pth-concentrations-severity-of-illness-and-mortality-in-hospitalized-equine-neonates">Vitamin D Metabolites and Their Association with Calcium, Phosphorus, and PTH Concentrations, Severity of Illness, and Mortality in Hospitalized Equine Neonates&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>PLOS ONE doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0127684.g003&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ahmed M. Kamr1,4, Katarzyna A. Dembek1, Stephen M. Reed2, Nathan M. Slovis3, Ahmed A. Zaghawa4, Thomas J. Rosol1, Ramiro E. Toribio1 toribio.1 @osu.edu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>College of Veterinary Medicine, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, United States of America,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rood and Riddle Equine Hospital, Lexington, Kentucky, United States of America, 3 Hagyard Equine Medical Institute, Lexington, Kentucky, United States of America, 4 Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, University of Sadat City, Sadat City, Egypt&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hospitalized cats 8X more likely to die if low vitamin D (Vit. D helps humans too)</title><link>/posts/hospitalized-cats-8x-more-likely-to-die-if-low-vitamin-d-vit-d-helps-humans-too.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hospitalized-cats-8x-more-likely-to-die-if-low-vitamin-d-vit-d-helps-humans-too.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-predicts-30-day-mortality-in-hospitalised-cats">Vitamin d status predicts 30 day mortality in hospitalised cats.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2015 May 13;10(5):e0125997. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0125997.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0125997.&lt;/a> eCollection 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Titmarsh H1, Kilpatrick S1, Sinclair J1, Boag A1, Bode EF1, Lalor SM1, Gaylor D1, Berry J2, Bommer NX1, Gunn-Moore D1, Reed N1, Handel I1, Mellanby RJ1.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/cat-mortality.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/webp/cat-mortality.webp" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;p>Vitamin D insufficiency, defined as low serum concentrations of the major circulating form of vitamin D, 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D), has been associated with the development of numerous infectious, inflammatory, and neoplastic disorders in humans. In addition, vitamin D insufficiency has been found to be predictive of mortality for many disorders. However, interpretation of human studies is difficult since vitamin D status is influenced by many factors, including diet, season, latitude, and exposure to UV radiation. In contrast, domesticated cats do not produce vitamin D cutaneously, and most cats are fed a commercial diet containing a relatively standard amount of vitamin D. Consequently, domesticated cats are an attractive model system in which to examine the relationship between serum 25(OH)D and health outcomes. The hypothesis of this study was that vitamin D status would predict short term, all-cause mortality in domesticated cats. Serum concentrations of 25(OH)D, together with a wide range of other clinical, hematological, and biochemical parameters, were measured in 99 consecutively hospitalised cats. Cats which died within 30 days of initial assessment had significantly lower serum 25(OH)D concentrations than cats which survived. In a linear regression model including 12 clinical variables, serum 25(OH)D concentration in the lower tertile was significantly predictive of mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 primates have higher levels of vitamin D than clothed humans, level varies between individuals</title><link>/posts/3-primates-have-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-than-clothed-humans-level-varies-between-individuals.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-primates-have-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d-than-clothed-humans-level-varies-between-individuals.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="measurement-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d23-and-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d23-by-tandem-mass-spectrometry-a-primate-multispecies-comparison">Measurement of 25-hydroxyvitamin D2&amp;amp;3 and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D2&amp;amp;3 by tandem mass spectrometry: A primate multispecies comparison&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Primatology, 2 APR 2015, DOI: 10.1002/ajp.22403&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Toni E. Ziegler 1,2,*, Amita Kapoor 1,2, Curtis J. Hedman 1,2,3, Neil Binkley 4 and Joseph W. Kemnitz 1,2,5&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/3-primates.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>Vitamin D metabolites are widely studied for their roles in bone health, immune functions, and other potential physiologic roles in humans. However, the optimal blood levels of vitamin D metabolites are still unclear. Various methods for measuring vitamin D metabolites have been used and recently liquid chromatography tandem mass spectroscopy (LC-MS/MS) has been adopted as the gold standard for vitamin D metabolite measurement. Here, we report the use of LC-MS/MS to measure 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D2&amp;amp;3), and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)2D2&amp;amp;3), in three laboratory nonhuman primate species:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone strength increased when sow and piglets had enough Vitamin D and Phosphorus</title><link>/posts/bone-strength-increased-when-sow-and-piglets-had-enough-vitamin-d-and-phosphorus.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-strength-increased-when-sow-and-piglets-had-enough-vitamin-d-and-phosphorus.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="neonatal-pig-femur-integrity-responses-to-dietary-vitamin-d-and-p-depend-on-maternal-dietary-vitamin-d">Neonatal Pig Femur Integrity Responses to Dietary Vitamin D and P Depend on Maternal Dietary Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>L Amundson1 and T Crenshaw1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Dept Anim Sci Univ of Wisconsin Madison Wisconsin United States&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/bone-strength.jpg" alt="image" width="650">
&lt;p>Kyphosis, an idiopathic disease, occurs in swine and humans. We induced kyphosis by altering maternal dietary vitamin D (D) and pig dietary D, Ca and P. The objective was to characterize bone traits and gene expression in the kyphosis model and assess maternal carryover effects. Traits from mechanical tests to characterize femur integrity are reported herein. Sows were fed diets with 0, 325 or 1750 IU D/kg (n = 6, 8, or 9/diet). At weaning (23 ± 2 d) pigs were fed diets with 0 (-D) or 280 (+D) IU D/kg, each with 95% (95P) or 120% (120P) of the P requirement. Pigs were killed at birth (n = 23), weaning (n = 22), and at the end of nursery (n = 185) for bone and tissue analysis. Excised femurs were subjected to a 4-point bending test to determine bending moment (BM), stress, strain, and modulus of elasticity (ME) at the yield point of load deformation curves. Mass moment of inertia (MOI) was derived from CT scans. ME encompasses of BM, stress, strain and MOI and is assumed to be a constant property of a material. No differences in ME were detected at birth. At weaning ME increased in pigs produced by sows fed 1750 (P &amp;lt; 0.05). At the end of nursery ME depended on maternal diets (interaction, P &amp;lt; 0.05). ME increased in pigs fed +D95P if produced by sows fed 0 or 325 but decreased if produced by sows fed 1750. As previously reported, DXA whole body bone mineral density also indicated maternal carryover effects, but the pattern differed among diets. Therefore whole body bone and femur integrity traits differ, but provide unique characterization of the model. As previously reported, the kyphosis model was further characterized by molecular analysis of bone and D homeostatic cell signaling mechanisms. All traits contribute to the characterization of the kyphosis model but a specific mechanism by which the deformity is induced has yet to be determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active vitamin D increased fractional rate of protein synthesis in chickens by 3X</title><link>/posts/active-vitamin-d-increased-fractional-rate-of-protein-synthesis-in-chickens-by-3x.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-vitamin-d-increased-fractional-rate-of-protein-synthesis-in-chickens-by-3x.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="25-hydroxycholecalciferol-enhances-male-broiler-breast-meat-yield-through-the-mtor-pathway">25-Hydroxycholecalciferol Enhances Male Broiler Breast Meat Yield through the mTOR Pathway.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2015 Mar 18. pii: jn207936. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vignale K1, Greene ES1, Caldas JV1, England JA1, Boonsinchai N1, Sodsee P1, Pollock ED2, Dridi S3, Coon CN3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In recent years, there has been a growing body of evidence indicating that replacing cholecalciferol (vitamin D3) with 25-hydroxycholecalciferol &lt;span>[25(OH)D3]&lt;/span> through dietary supplementation &lt;strong>enhances breast meat yield in broiler chickens&lt;/strong> . However, the underlying molecular mechanisms are still unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cows in pastures need vitamin D for milk production</title><link>/posts/cows-in-pastures-need-vitamin-d-for-milk-production.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cows-in-pastures-need-vitamin-d-for-milk-production.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="invited-the-role-and-potential-advantages-of-vitamin-d-metabolites-in-maintaining-calcium-status-in-high-producing-dairy-herds">INVITED: The role and potential advantages of Vitamin D metabolites in maintaining calcium status in high producing dairy herds.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Animal Production Science, AN14450 Accepted 06 March 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joseph McGrath, Darryl Savage, Ian Godwin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Long-term, declining fertility is a reported trend in high production dairy herds. Nutrition management is identified as a key area where improvement is required. Most published literature relating to nutrition management of dairy cow fertility examines energy and protein status and peri-parturient Ca homeostasis availability. This article examines the current understanding of calcium homeostasis relevant to improving performance in the high production dairy herd.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hens fed a form of vitamin D had more hatchable eggs and more immune chicks</title><link>/posts/hens-fed-a-form-of-vitamin-d-had-more-hatchable-eggs-and-more-immune-chicks.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hens-fed-a-form-of-vitamin-d-had-more-hatchable-eggs-and-more-immune-chicks.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-hen-age-and-maternal-vitamin-d-source-on-performance-hatchability-bone-mineral-density-and-progeny-in-vitro-early-innate-immune-function">Effect of hen age and maternal vitamin D source on performance, hatchability, bone mineral density, and progeny in vitro early innate immune function.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Poult Sci. 2015 Mar 5. pii: pev002. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saunders-Blades JL1, Korver DR2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Agricultural, Food, and Nutritional Science, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada T6G 2P5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Agricultural, Food, and Nutritional Science, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada T6G 2P5 &lt;a href="mailto:doug.korver@ualberta.ca">doug.korver@ualberta.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The metabolite 25-hydroxy vitamin D3 (25-OHD) can complement or replace vitamin D3 in poultry rations, and may influence broiler production and immune function traits. The effect of broiler breeder dietary 25-OHD on egg production, hatchability, and chick early innate immune function was studied. We hypothesized that maternal dietary 25-OHD would support normal broiler breeder production and a more mature innate immune system of young chicks. Twenty-three-week-old Ross 308 hens (n = 98) were placed in 4 floor pens and fed either&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dog Cancer (hemangiosarcoma) is rare if more than 100 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dog-cancer-hemangiosarcoma-is-rare-if-more-than-100-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dog-cancer-hemangiosarcoma-is-rare-if-more-than-100-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-dogs---correlation-with-health-and-cancer-risk">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations in dogs - correlation with health and cancer risk&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Veterinary and Comparative Oncology,DOI:10.1111/vco.12101&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K. A. Selting1,C. R. Sharp2,R. Ringold3,D. H. Thamm4 and R. Backus1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Veterinary Medical Teaching Hospital, University of Missouri, Columbia, MO, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Cummings School of Veterinary Medicine, Tufts University, North Grafton, MA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Veterinary Diagnostics Institute, Simi Valley, CA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Department of Clinical Sciences, Animal Cancer Center, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less weight gain in mice getting lots of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/less-weight-gain-in-mice-getting-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-weight-gain-in-mice-getting-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-protects-against-diet-induced-obesity-by-enhancing-fatty-acid-oxidation">Vitamin D protects against diet-induced obesity by enhancing fatty acid oxidation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cited-146-times-as-of-dec-2023">Cited 146 times as of Dec 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-protects-against-diet-induced-obesity-by-enhancing-fatty-acid-oxidation">Vitamin D protects against diet-induced obesity by enhancing fatty acid oxidation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Nutritional Biochemistry. Available online 21 June 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Julie Marcotorchinoa, b, c, Franck Tourniairea, b, c, Julien Astiera, b, c, Esma Karkenia, b, c, Matthias Canaulta, b, c, Marie-Josèphe Amiota, b, c, David Bendahanc, d, Monique Bernardc, d, Jean-Charles Martina, b, c, Benoit Giannesinic, d, Jean-François Landriera, b, c, &lt;a href="mailto:jean-francois.landrier@univ-amu.fr">jean-francois.landrier@univ-amu.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rotovarious virus less of a problem for pigs with enough vitamin D – CT</title><link>/posts/rotovarious-virus-less-of-a-problem-for-pigs-with-enough-vitamin-d-ct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rotovarious-virus-less-of-a-problem-for-pigs-with-enough-vitamin-d-ct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dietary-vitamin-d-supplementation-attenuates-immune-responses-of-pigs-challenged-with-rotavirus-potentially-through-the-retinoic-acid-inducible-gene-i-signalling-pathway">Dietary vitamin D supplementation attenuates immune responses of pigs challenged with rotavirus potentially through the retinoic acid-inducible gene I signalling pathway.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2014 May 15:1-9. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhao Y, Yu B, Mao X, He J, Huang Z, Zheng P, Yu J, Han G, Liang X, Chen D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Animal Nutrition, Sichuan Agricultural University,Xinkang Road 46#,Ya&amp;rsquo;an Sichuan Province 625014, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the present study, twenty-four Duroc × Landrance × Yorkshire (initial body weight (BW) of 21·82 (sem 2·06) kg) cross-bred pigs were used to determine whether dietary vitamin D supplementation could confer protection against viral infections through the retinoic acid-inducible gene I (RIG-I) signalling pathway in pigs. Experimental treatments were arranged in a 2 × 2 factorial manner with the main effects of immune challenge (control v. porcine rotavirus (PRV) challenge) and dietary concentrations of vitamin D (200 and 5000 IU; where 1 IU of vitamin D is defined as the biological activity of 0.025 mg of cholecalciferol). The pigs were fed a diet containing 200 or 5000 IU vitamin D in the first week of the study period. On day 8, the pigs were orally dosed with 4 ml of Dulbecco&amp;rsquo;s modified Eagle&amp;rsquo;s medium/Ham&amp;rsquo;s F-12 medium containing PRV or essential medium (control). Serum samples were collected on day 8 (pre-challenge), and 6 d after the PRV challenge, the pigs were killed to evaluate intestinal morphology and tissue gene expression following the last blood collection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chinchillas are another furry animal which makes vitamin D from UVB</title><link>/posts/chinchillas-are-another-furry-animal-which-makes-vitamin-d-from-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chinchillas-are-another-furry-animal-which-makes-vitamin-d-from-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-ultraviolet-radiation-on-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-captive-chinchillas-chinchilla-laniger">Effects of ultraviolet radiation on serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D Concentrations in captive Chinchillas (chinchilla laniger)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Exotic Pet Medicine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anne E. Rivas, DVM, Mark A. Mitchell, DVM, MS, PhD, Dip. ECZM (Herpetology)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mark A. Mitchell, DVM, MS, PhD, Dip. ECZM (Herpetology), College of Veterinary Medicine, University of Illinois, 1108W. Hazelwood Dr., Urbana, IL 61802 USA.Tel.: 217-244-9386. &lt;a href="mailto:mmitch@illinois.edu">mmitch@illinois.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DVM, Kenneth R. Welle, DVM, Dip. ABVP (Avian), Julia K. Whittington, DVM&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is an important hormone in vertebrates, and most animals acquire this hormone through their diet and/or exposure to ultraviolet B (UVB) radiation. To date, no study has determined how chinchillas (Chinchilla laniger) acquire vitamin D. The objective of this study was to determine whether exposure to UVB radiation had an effect on serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in captive chinchillas.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D recommended for all animals (FEEDAP does not say how much)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-recommended-for-all-animals-feedap-does-not-say-how-much.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-recommended-for-all-animals-feedap-does-not-say-how-much.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="scientific-opinion-on-the-safety-and-efficacy-of-vitamin-d3-cholecalciferol-as-a-feed-additive-for-all-animal-species-or-categories-based-on-a-dossier-submitted-by-lohmann-animal-health-gmbh">Scientific Opinion on the safety and efficacy of vitamin D3 (cholecalciferol) as a feed additive for all animal species or categories based on a dossier submitted by Lohmann Animal Health GmbH&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>EFSA Journal 2014;12(2):3568 &lt;span>[2 pp.]&lt;/span>. doi:10.2903/j.efsa.2014.3568&lt;/p>
&lt;p>EFSA Panel on Additives and Products or Substances used in Animal Feed (FEEDAP)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Type: Opinion of the Scientific Committee/Scientific Panel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On request from: European Commission, Question number: EFSA-Q-2011-00952&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adopted: 30 January 2014, Published: 20 February 2014&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inflammatory Bowel Disease and Lymphoma – associated with low vitamin D in cats too</title><link>/posts/inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-lymphoma-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-cats-too.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-lymphoma-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-cats-too.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cats-with-inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-intestinal-small-cell-lymphoma-have-low-serum-concentrations-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d">Cats with Inflammatory Bowel Disease and Intestinal Small Cell Lymphoma Have Low Serum Concentrations of 25-Hydroxyvitamin D.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Vet Intern Med. 2014 Jan 16. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/jvim.12294.">doi: 10.1111/jvim.12294.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lalor S, Schwartz AM, Titmarsh H, Reed N, Tasker S, Boland L, Berry J, Gunn-Moore D, Mellanby RJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Royal (Dick) School of Veterinary Studies, Division of Clinical Veterinary Sciences, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) and intestinal small cell lymphoma (ISCL) are common diseases in cats. The prevalence of alterations in the serum concentrations of fat soluble vitamins, such as vitamin D, in cats with IBD and ISCL is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is HyD (25(OH)D) a better form of vitamin D for some animals and maybe humans with liver problems</title><link>/posts/is-hyd-25ohd-a-better-form-of-vitamin-d-for-some-animals-and-maybe-humans-with-liver-problems.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-hyd-25ohd-a-better-form-of-vitamin-d-for-some-animals-and-maybe-humans-with-liver-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dsm-recommendations-of-vitamin-d-andor-their-hyd-product">DSM recommendations of Vitamin D AND/OR their HyD product&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note the IUs are per of dry FEED, not WEIGHT&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">It seems that a human adult eats about 2 kg of dry food per day, so might multiply by 2X for human adult&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">2011 PDF is attached at the bottom of this page has all of the recommended nutrients&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="updated-animals-get-a-lot-more-vitamin-d-than-minimum-recommended-for-humans--2016postsanimals-get-a-lot-more-vitamin-d-than-minimum-recommended-for-humans-2016">Updated &lt;a href="/posts/animals-get-a-lot-more-vitamin-d-than-minimum-recommended-for-humans-2016">Animals get a lot more vitamin D than minimum recommended for humans – 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-poultry.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-turkey.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-swine.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-ruminants.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-fish-and-shrimp.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ovn-horses-and-others.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ocn-dogs-and-cats.jpg" alt="image"></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D: calcium and bone homeostasis during evolution</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-calcium-and-bone-homeostasis-during-evolution.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-calcium-and-bone-homeostasis-during-evolution.html</guid><description>&lt;p>BoneKEy Reports 3, Article number: 480 (2014) | doi:10.1038/bonekey.2013.214&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roger Bouillon &lt;a href="mailto:roger.bouillon@med.kuleuven.be">roger.bouillon@med.kuleuven.be&lt;/a> 1 and Tatsuo Suda2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Clinical and Experimental Endocrinology, KU Leuven; Department of Endocrinology, University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium. 2Research Center for Genomic Medicine, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D3 is already found early in the evolution of life but essentially as inactive end products of the photochemical reaction of 7-dehydrocholestol with ultraviolet light B. A full vitamin D (refers to vitamin D2 and D3) endocrine system, characterized by a specific VDR (vitamin D receptor, member of the nuclear receptor family), specific vitamin D metabolizing CYP450 enzymes regulated by calciotropic hormones and a dedicated plasma transport-protein is only found in vertebrates. In the earliest vertebrates (lamprey), vitamin D metabolism and VDR may well have originated from a duplication of a common PRX/VDR ancestor gene as part of a xenobiotic detoxification pathway. The vitamin D endocrine system, however, subsequently became an important regulator of calcium supply for an extensive calcified skeleton. Vitamin D is essential for normal calcium and bone homeostasis as shown by rickets in vitamin D-deficient growing amphibians, reptiles, birds and mammals. From amphibians onward, bone is gradually more dynamic with regulated bone resorption, mainly by combined action of PTH and 1 a,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3) on the generation and function of multinucleated osteoclasts. Therefore, bone functions as a large internal calcium reservoir, under the control of osteoclasts. Osteocytes also display a remarkable spectrum of activities, including mechanical sensing and regulating mineral homeostasis, but also have an important role in global nutritional and energy homeostasis. Mineralization from reptiles onward is under the control of well-regulated SIBLING proteins and associated enzymes, nearly all under the control of 1,25(OH)2D3. The vitamin D story thus started as inert molecule but gained an essential role for calcium and bone homeostasis in terrestrial animals to cope with the challenge of higher gravity and calcium-poor environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>National requirement of vitamin D for pigs increased by 4X, (4X more than for humans)</title><link>/posts/national-requirement-of-vitamin-d-for-pigs-increased-by-4x-4x-more-than-for-humans.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/national-requirement-of-vitamin-d-for-pigs-increased-by-4x-4x-more-than-for-humans.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="establishment-of-the-2012-vitamin-d-requirements-in-swine-with-focus-on-dietary-forms-and-levels-of-vitamin-d">Establishment of the 2012 vitamin D requirements in swine with focus on dietary forms and levels of vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J ANIM SCI January 7, 2014 jas.2013-7201&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C. Lauridsen &lt;a href="mailto:charlotte.lauridsen@agrsci.dk">charlotte.lauridsen@agrsci.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Animal Science, Aarhus University, 8830 Tjele, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In swine nutrition, little is known about vitamin requirements for reproductive processes and bone health, especially vitamin D. Supplemental vitamin D is usually added to animal feed as cholecalciferol (vitamin D3), which is transported to the liver and hydroxylated to 25-hydroxycholecalciferol &lt;span>[25(OH)D3]&lt;/span>, and this metabolite has become commercially available for swine nutrition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lizard (brown sagrei) seeks more UVB if less Vitamin D in diet</title><link>/posts/lizard-brown-sagrei-seeks-more-uvb-if-less-vitamin-d-in-diet.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lizard-brown-sagrei-seeks-more-uvb-if-less-vitamin-d-in-diet.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="ultraviolet-light-exposure-and-response-to-dietary-vitamin-d3-in-two-jamaican-anoles">Ultraviolet Light Exposure and Response to Dietary Vitamin D3 in Two Jamaican Anoles&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Herpetology 47(4):524-529. 2013, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/http">doi: http&lt;/a>://dx.doi.org/10.1670/12-020&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gary W. Ferguson &lt;a href="mailto:g.ferguson@tcu.edu">g.ferguson@tcu.edu&lt;/a>, Adam J. Kingeter 2, and William H. Gehrmann&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Biology, Texas Christian University, Fort Worth, Texas 76129 USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Present address: Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Department of Anesthesiology, Nashville, Tennessee 37232 USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Jamaica, free-living male and female-sized Anolis sagrei are exposed to more natural ultraviolet-B (UVB) from sunlight than male and female-sized Anolis lineatopus. In the laboratory, &lt;strong>we tested predictions derived from the hypothesis that Anolis possess a mechanism for behaviorally photo-regulating their exposure to UVB depending on their dietary intake of vitamin D3&lt;/strong> . Anolis sagrei voluntarily exposed themselves more frequently to visible and UVB light and received higher doses of UVB in an artificial light gradient when fed a low vitamin D3 diet for 6 weeks than when subsequently fed a high dietary vitamin D3 diet for 6 weeks. When we returned the anole&amp;rsquo;s diet to the low vitamin D3 regimen for a third 6-week period, UVB exposure remained lower than in the first 6-week period. This suggests an initial UV photo-regulatory adjustment to high dietary vitamin-D3 but a slow return to greater reliance on UVB-induced endogenous vitamin D3 production.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Feed chicken lots of vitamin D, get 6000 IU per egg with no change in production</title><link>/posts/feed-chicken-lots-of-vitamin-d-get-6000-iu-per-egg-with-no-change-in-production.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/feed-chicken-lots-of-vitamin-d-get-6000-iu-per-egg-with-no-change-in-production.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="effects-of-long-term-supplementation-of-laying-hens-with-high-concentrations-of-cholecalciferol-on-performance-and-egg-quality">Effects of long-term supplementation of laying hens with high concentrations of cholecalciferol on performance and egg quality&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Poult. Sci. November 2013 vol. 92 no. 11 2930-2937&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. E. Persia*, &lt;a href="mailto:mpersia@iastate.edu">mpersia@iastate.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. Higgins†,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>T. Wang‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D. Trample‡ and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E. A. Bobeck*&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Department of Animal Science,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>†Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡Veterinary Diagnostic and Production Animal Medicine, Iowa State University, Ames 50011&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/egg.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>There is current interest in increasing human vitamin D dietary intake without having to modify human eating habits. One method to increase human dietary vitamin D intake is to generate eggs with increased concentrations of vitamin D through high-concentration vitamin D feeding in the diets of laying hens. Although eggs can be produced with high concentrations of vitamin D, the consequences of these diets on hen performance and egg quality have not been validated. The objective of this research is to quantify the effects of high concentrations of cholecalciferol (D3) on laying hen performance and egg quality. Hy-Line W36 laying hens were placed on 1 of 5 experimental diets for 40 wk:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>During brown bear hibernation Vitamin D3 decreases but D2 increases (surprise)</title><link>/posts/during-brown-bear-hibernation-vitamin-d3-decreases-but-d2-increases-surprise.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/during-brown-bear-hibernation-vitamin-d3-decreases-but-d2-increases-surprise.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-and-bone-and-connective-tissue-turnover-in-brown-bears-ursus-arctos-during-hibernation-and-the-active-state">Vitamin D Status and Bone and Connective Tissue Turnover in Brown Bears (Ursus arctos) during Hibernation and the Active State&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 6(6): e21483. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0021483&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter Vestergaard mail, Ole-Gunnar Støen, Jon E. Swenson, Leif Mosekilde, Lene Heickendorff, Ole Fröbert&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Extended physical inactivity causes disuse osteoporosis in humans. In contrast, brown bears (Ursus arctos) are highly immobilised for half of the year during hibernation without signs of bone loss and therefore may serve as a model for prevention of osteoporosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduced bacterial infection in cows – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-bacterial-infection-in-cows-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-bacterial-infection-in-cows-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="treatment-of-an-intramammary-bacterial-infection-with-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3">Treatment of an Intramammary Bacterial Infection with 25-Hydroxyvitamin D3&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PLOS One PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John D. Lippolis &lt;a href="mailto:john.lippolis@ars.usda.gov">john.lippolis@ars.usda.gov&lt;/a>, Timothy A. Reinhardt, Randy A. Sacco, Brian J. Nonnecke, Corwin D. Nelson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deficiency of serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 has been correlated with increased risk of infectious diseases such as tuberculosis and influenza. A plausible reason for this association is that expression of genes encoding important antimicrobial proteins depends on concentrations of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 produced by activated immune cells at sites of infection, and that synthesis of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 is dependent on the availability of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3. Thus, increasing the availability of 25(OH)D3 for immune cell synthesis of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 at sites of infection has been hypothesized to aid in clearance of the infection. This report details the treatment of an acute intramammary infection with infusion of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 to the site of infection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breed cows based on vitamin D production</title><link>/posts/breed-cows-based-on-vitamin-d-production.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breed-cows-based-on-vitamin-d-production.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="variation-of-vitamin-d-in-cows-milk-and-interaction-with-p-lactoglobulin">Variation of Vitamin D in Cow&amp;rsquo;s Milk and Interaction with P-Lactoglobulin&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Molecules 2013, 18, 10122-10131; doi:10.3390/moleculesl80910122&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omar Bulgari 1, Anna Maria Caroli Stefania Chessa 2, Rita Rizzi 3 and Carmen Gigliotti 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Molecular and Translational Medicine, University of Brescia, Brescia 25123, Italy; E-Mails: &lt;a href="mailto:bulgari.omar@libero.it">bulgari.omar@libero.it&lt;/a> (O.B.); &lt;a href="mailto:giglio@med.unibs.it">giglio@med.unibs.it&lt;/a> (C.G.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Institute of Agricultural Biology and Biotechnology—National Research Council, Milano 20133, Italy; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:chessa@ibba.cnr.it">chessa@ibba.cnr.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Veterinary Science and Public Health (DIVET), Milano 20133, Italy; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:rita.rizzi@unimi.it">rita.rizzi@unimi.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Piglets helped a lot with 40,000 IU on day 1, provided they did not have diarrhea</title><link>/posts/piglets-helped-a-lot-with-40000-iu-on-day-1-provided-they-did-not-have-diarrhea.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/piglets-helped-a-lot-with-40000-iu-on-day-1-provided-they-did-not-have-diarrhea.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-what-is-all-the-fuss-abouthttpnationalhogfarmercomnutritionvitamin-d-deficiency-what-all-fuss-about20">&lt;a href="http://nationalhogfarmer.com/nutrition/vitamin-d-deficiency-what-all-fuss-about%20">Vitamin D Deficiency: What Is All the Fuss About?&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>nice story in National Hog Farmer. Before many piglets raised indoors were dying&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-levels-indoor-pigs--10ngml-outdoor-pigs-50-ngml">Vitamin D levels: indoor pigs &amp;lt; 10ng/ml, outdoor pigs &amp;gt;50 ng/ml&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/pig-farm.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/rickets-in-humans-and-domestic-animals">Rickets in Humans and domestic animals - March 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/piglets-getting-single-dose-of-40000-iu-of-vitamin-d-gained-more-weight">Piglets getting single dose of 40,000 IU of vitamin D gained more weight – March 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/swine-with-extra-vitamin-d-more-likely-to-get-pregnant-and-have-more-and-larger-piglets" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Swine with extra vitamin D more likely to get pregnant and have more and larger piglets – June 2012">Swine with extra vitamin D more likely to get pregnant and have more and larger piglets – June 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB on legs of chickens resulted in 70 IU vitamin D per egg yoke</title><link>/posts/uvb-on-legs-of-chickens-resulted-in-70-iu-vitamin-d-per-egg-yoke.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-on-legs-of-chickens-resulted-in-70-iu-vitamin-d-per-egg-yoke.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="uvb-exposure-of-farm-animals-study-on-a-food-based-strategy-to-bridge-the-gap-between-current-vitamin-d-intakes-and-dietary-targets">UVB Exposure of Farm Animals: Study on a Food-Based Strategy to Bridge the Gap between Current Vitamin D Intakes and Dietary Targets&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLOS ONE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alexandra Schutkowski, Julia Krämer, Holger Kluge, Frank Hirche, Andreas Krombholz, Torsten Theumer, Gabriele I. Stangl &lt;a href="mailto:gabriele.stangl@landw.uni-halle.de">gabriele.stangl@landw.uni-halle.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is a global health problem. This study aimed to investigate the efficacy of ultraviolet (UV) B radiation for improving vitamin D3 content of eggs and meat. In a two-factorial design hens that received diets with 0 (-D3) or 3,000 IU (+D3) vitamin D3/kg were non-exposed (-UVB) or exposed to UVB radiation (+UVB) for 3 h daily over 4 weeks. Data show that UVB radiation was very effective in raising the vitamin D3 content of egg yolk and meat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vets getting excited about vitamin D</title><link>/posts/vets-getting-excited-about-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vets-getting-excited-about-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 class="svTitle">
&lt;p>&lt;span style="font-size:22px;">It’s not just bones anymore: The new and exciting world of vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/h1>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="publicationHead">
&lt;div class="title">
&lt;p>&lt;a class="cLink" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/journal/10900233" title="Go to The Veterinary Journal on SciVerse ScienceDirect">&lt;span>The Veterinary Journal,&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/journal/10900233/194/1" title="Go to table of contents for this volume/issue"> Volume 194, Issue 1&lt;/a>, October 2012, Pages 5–6&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul class="authorGroup noCollab">&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="authorName" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1090023312003280#" id="authname_N4255ecc0N4251ac88">Keren Dittmer&lt;/a> &lt;a href="mailto:K.E.Dittmer@massey.ac.nz">K.E.Dittmer@massey.ac.nz&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;/ul>&lt;ul class="affiliation">&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;span>Institute of Veterinary, Animal and Biomedical Sciences, Massey University, Palmerston North 4472, New Zealand&lt;/span>&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;/ul>&lt;ul class="articleDoi">&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tvjl.2012.07.025" id="ddDoi">&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tvjl.2012.07.025">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tvjl.2012.07.025&lt;/a>&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/help/doi.htm">How to Cite or Link Using DOI&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;/ul>&lt;ul class="articleInfo">&lt;li class="permissions" id="permissions">
&lt;div class="boxLink">
&lt;p>&lt;a class="olSpawnWindow" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science?_ob=RedirectURL&amp;amp;_method=outwardLink&amp;amp;_partnerName=936&amp;amp;_eid=1-s2.0-S1090023312003280&amp;amp;_pii=S1090023312003280&amp;amp;_origin=article&amp;amp;_zone=art_page&amp;amp;_targetURL=https%3A%2F%2Fs100.copyright.com%2FAppDispatchServlet%3FpublisherName%3DELS%26contentID%3DS1090023312003280%26orderBeanReset%3Dtrue&amp;amp;_acct=C000029718&amp;amp;_version=1&amp;amp;_userid=582538&amp;amp;md5=b82340a3d9e6f062e9d7015c91192b4b" rel="nofollow">Permissions &amp;amp; Reprints&lt;/a>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;div class="boxLink permissions">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#0000cd;">&lt;span style="font-size:18px;">(PDF  is attached at the bottom of this page)&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;br />&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Veterinarians often giving more vitamin D than govt upper limit - 2012</title><link>/posts/veterinarians-often-giving-more-vitamin-d-than-govt-upper-limit-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/veterinarians-often-giving-more-vitamin-d-than-govt-upper-limit-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="veterinarian-jobs-depend-on-span-stylecolorf00preventingspan-disease">Veterinarian jobs depend on &lt;span style="color:#F00;">preventing&lt;/span> disease,&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vets are not paid to follow government recommendations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="human-doctors-jobs-deal-with-span-stylecolorf00treatingspan-disease">Human doctors jobs deal with &lt;span style="color:#F00;">treating&lt;/span> disease,&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Drs. can get sued if they do not follow government recommendations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High-altitude associated with higher vitamin D and better bones (sheep in this case)</title><link>/posts/high-altitude-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-and-better-bones-sheep-in-this-case.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-altitude-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-and-better-bones-sheep-in-this-case.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="influence-of-high-altitude-grazing-on-bone-metabolism-of-growing-sheep">Influence of high-altitude grazing on bone metabolism of growing sheep.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr (Berl). 2013 Feb;97(1):58-66. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Oct 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liesegang A, Hüttenmoser D, Risteli J, Leiber F, Kreuzer M, Wanner M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Animal Nutrition, University of Zurich, Winterthurerstr. 260, Zurich, Switzerland. &lt;a href="mailto:aliese@vetphys.uzh.ch">aliese@vetphys.uzh.ch&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this study was to identify the effect of high alpine grazing, associated with varying pasture grass qualities and more pronounced exercise on typically steep slopes, on bone metabolism by improving bone density and enhancing bone turnover in growing sheep. Twenty-four 5-month-old sheep were randomly assigned to two groups. One group was kept at high altitude (HA; 2000-2200 m a.s.l.) for 3 months, and the other group (C; control) remained in the lowlands (400 m a.s.l.). Both groups were kept in grazing pastures with access to good-quality swards. Before the start of the experiment, blood samples were taken, the sheep were weighed, and the left metatarsus of each animal was analysed by quantitative computer tomography. After 1 month, blood samples were taken and body weight was measured, followed by biweekly sampling. Finally, the animals were slaughtered, and the bones were collected for analysis of various bone parameters. Body weight development did not differ between the groups. Concentrations of 25-OH-Vitamin D, carboxy-terminal telopeptide of type I collagen and activities of bone-specific alkaline phosphatase were always higher in the HA group than in the C group, except on the last two sampling dates. Bone mineral content and density increased in both groups during the experiment, but more intensively in the HA group. In addition, the cortical thickness of the HA group increased. The present study demonstrates an increase in bone turnover and mineral content of the bones of the growing sheep grazing in high alpine pastures. The factors associated with HA grazing, therefore, clearly seem to improve bone composition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Invertebrates use Vitamin D3 as well</title><link>/posts/invertebrates-use-vitamin-d3-as-well.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/invertebrates-use-vitamin-d3-as-well.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="results-of-a-pubmed-search-by-dr-grant-april-2013">Results of a PubMed search by Dr. Grant, April 2013&lt;/h3>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#results-of-a-pubmed-search-by-dr-grant-april-2013">Results of a PubMed search by Dr. Grant, April 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#birdeater-spiders">Birdeater spiders&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sea-animal-which-lack-calcified-skeleton-plankton">Sea animal which lack calcified skeleton, plankton&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#juvenile-grass-shrimp">Juvenile grass shrimp&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#land-snails">Land snails&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#not-sea-lamprey">Not sea lamprey&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#-">? ?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="birdeater-spiders">Birdeater spiders&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Zoo Wildl Med. 2009 Jun;40(2):344-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D3 in the hemolymph of goliath birdeater spiders (Theraphosa blondi).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zachariah TT, Mitchell MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Veterinary Clinical Sciences, School of Veterinary Medicine, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, Louisiana 70803, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:zachariahdvm@yahoo.com">zachariahdvm@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets in Humans and domestic animals</title><link>/posts/rickets-in-humans-and-domestic-animals.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-in-humans-and-domestic-animals.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-metabolism-and-rickets-in-domestic-animals--a-review">Vitamin D Metabolism and Rickets in Domestic Animals – A Review&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Veterinary Pathology March 2011 vol. 48 no. 2 389-407&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K. E. Dittmer 1 and K. G. Thompson 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Institute of Veterinary, Animal and Biomedical Sciences, Massey University, Palmerston North, New Zealand&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 K.E. Dittmer, Institute of Veterinary, Animal and Biomedical Sciences, Tennant Drive, Private Bag 11 222, Massey University, Palmerston North, New Zealand Email: &lt;a href="mailto:K.E.Dittmer@massey.ac.nz">K.E.Dittmer@massey.ac.nz&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-metabolism-and-rickets-in-domestic-animals--a-review">Vitamin D Metabolism and Rickets in Domestic Animals – A Review&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biology-of-vitamin-d">Biology of Vitamin D&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#activation-of-vitamin-d">Activation of Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#catabolism-pathways">Catabolism Pathways&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-vitamin-d-receptor">The Vitamin D Receptor&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#functions-ofvitamin-d">Functions ofVitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#other-effects">Other Effects&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#toxicity">Toxicity&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pathology-of-rickets">Pathology of Rickets&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#rickets-in-humans">Rickets in Humans&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#genetic-causes">Genetic Causes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#animal-models-of-rickets">Animal Models of Rickets&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mouse-models">Mouse Models&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#nonhuman-primates">Nonhuman Primates&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sheep-and-goats">Sheep and Goats&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cattle">Cattle&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#llamas-and-alpacas">Llamas and Alpacas&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#horses">Horses&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pigs">Pigs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dogs">Dogs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cats">Cats&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reptiles">Reptiles&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;p>Rickets and osteomalacia are increasing in prevalence in people because of cultural practices, breast-feeding, decreased sun exposure, and increased sunscreen usage. Several hereditary forms of rickets owing to either renal phosphate wasting or defects in vitamin D metabolism are also reported in people. Rickets is well recognized in domestic animals, but published reports are not always supported by microscopic findings, and diagnoses based on clinical signs and radiology are unreliable. Most cases in domestic animals are caused by dietary deficiency of either vitamin D or phosphorus, but occasional inherited forms are reported in pigs, sheep, cats, and dogs. There is variation between species in susceptibility to dietary vitamin D and phosphorus deficiency and in the ability to manufacture vitamin D in their skin. A number of mouse models have been discovered or created to study human skeletal diseases and skeletal homeostasis. With the discovery that vitamin D is involved in not only calcium and phosphorus homeostasis but also in the immune system and cancer, there is great potential for new and existing animal models to generate valuable information about vitamin D and its many functions. This review presents an overview of vitamin D metabolism and rickets in domestic and laboratory animals and makes comparisons where appropriate with the disease in humans.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tiger got surgery for hip arthritis – not much sun in the cage</title><link>/posts/tiger-got-surgery-for-hip-arthritis-not-much-sun-in-the-cage.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tiger-got-surgery-for-hip-arthritis-not-much-sun-in-the-cage.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Piglets getting single dose of 40,000 IU of vitamin D gained more weight</title><link>/posts/piglets-getting-single-dose-of-40000-iu-of-vitamin-d-gained-more-weight.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/piglets-getting-single-dose-of-40000-iu-of-vitamin-d-gained-more-weight.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="effect-of-oral-vitamin-d3-supplementation-on-growth-and-serum-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-levels-of-pigs-up-to-7-weeks-of-age">Effect of oral vitamin D3 supplementation on growth and serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D levels of pigs up to 7 weeks of age&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Swine Health Prod. 2013;21(2):94–98.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Steven J. P. Tousignant, DVM; Steven C. Henry, DVM; Albert Rovira, DVM, PhD; Robert B. Morrison, DVM, MBA, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SJPT, RBM: University of Minnesota, Population Medicine, St Paul, Minnesota.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SCH: Abilene Animal Hospital, Abilene, Kansas. AR: University of Minnesota, Veterinary Diagnostic Laboratory, St Paul, Minnesota.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omega-3 added to cattle feed increases the level in milk</title><link>/posts/omega-3-added-to-cattle-feed-increases-the-level-in-milk.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-added-to-cattle-feed-increases-the-level-in-milk.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>130% more piglets after giving gilt Calcidiol, a form of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/130-percent-more-piglets-after-giving-gilt-calcidiol-a-form-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/130-percent-more-piglets-after-giving-gilt-calcidiol-a-form-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="feeding-25-hydroxycholecalciferol-improves-gilt-reproductive-performance-and-fetal-vitamin-d-status1">Feeding 25-hydroxycholecalciferol improves gilt reproductive performance and fetal vitamin D status1&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J. D. Coffey*, E. A. Hines*, J. D. Starkey*,2, C. W. Starkey* and T. K. Chung†&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Department of Animal and Food Sciences, Texas Tech University, Lubbock 79409&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>†DSM Nutritional Products Asia Pacific, 2 Havelock Road, #04-01, Singapore 059763&lt;/p>
&lt;p>?2Corresponding author: &lt;a href="mailto:jessica.starkey@ttu.edu">jessica.starkey@ttu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Little information is available regarding the effects of vitamin D and its metabolites on reproduction in swine. To investigate the effects of feeding the circulating metabolite of vitamin D, 25-hydroxycholecalciferol (25OHD3, ROVIMIX Hy•D, DSM Nutritional Products, Basel, Switzerland) on maternal and fetal circulating 25OHD3 concentration and gilt reproductive performance, a total of 40 PIC Camborough-22 gilts (BW on d -6 = 138 kg) in 4 replicates were randomly assigned to 1 of 2 corn-soybean meal-based diets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monkeys have high levels of Vitamin D – 82 ng young, 58 ng senior</title><link>/posts/monkeys-have-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-82-ng-young-58-ng-senior.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/monkeys-have-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-82-ng-young-58-ng-senior.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="25ohd3-and-cardiovascular-risk-factors-in-female-nonhuman-primates">25(OH)D3 and cardiovascular risk factors in female nonhuman primates.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2012 Sep;21(9):959-65. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1089/jwh.2011.3416.">doi: 10.1089/jwh.2011.3416.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Aug 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorgensen MJ, Rudel LL, Nudy M, Kaplan JR, Clarkson TB, Pajewski NM, Schnatz PF &lt;a href="mailto:schnatzp@readinghospital.org">schnatzp@readinghospital.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pathology/Comparative Medicine, Wake Forest School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine if interindividual differences in plasma concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3) (25(OH)D(3)) have pathophysiologic significance, we evaluated a cohort of female monkeys, seeking to identify associations with clinically relevant cardiovascular risk factors, including age, abdominal obesity (waist circumference), and high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In less than 3 weeks chickens have problems if they do not have vitamin D</title><link>/posts/in-less-than-3-weeks-chickens-have-problems-if-they-do-not-have-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/in-less-than-3-weeks-chickens-have-problems-if-they-do-not-have-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="poultry-feed-recalledhttpunion-bulletincomstories20120727poultry-feed-recalled-over-missing-vitamin-d-july-2012">&lt;a href="http://union-bulletin.com/stories/2012/07/27/poultry-feed-recalled-over-missing-vitamin-d">Poultry Feed Recalled&lt;/a> July 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The supplier had failed to include vitamin D in a batch of feed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inadequate levels of vitamin D in a bird&amp;rsquo;s diet for more than two or three weeks may cause bone weakness, fractures or joint problems, and potentially death in birds not exposed to direct sunlight daily, according to a press release from the FDA.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="reminder-before-the-1940s-all-poultry-had-access-to-the-sunshine">Reminder: Before the 1940&amp;rsquo;s all poultry had access to the sunshine.&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/outdoor-chickens.jpg" alt="image" style="max-width: 500px;">
&lt;h4 id="then-farmers-learned-that-by-supplementing-the-poultry-with-vitamin-d-that-they-could-be-span-stylecolor00fcooped-upspan">Then farmers learned that by supplementing the poultry with vitamin D that they could be &amp;lsquo;&lt;span style="color:#00F;">cooped up&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/indoor-chickens.jpg" alt="image" style="max-width: 500px;">
&lt;h4 id="wonder-when-it-will-be-realized-that--cooped-up-humans-also-need-vitamin-d-supplements">Wonder when it will be realized that &amp;lsquo;cooped up humans also need vitamin D supplements&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-veterinary-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 17">Overview Veterinary and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>