<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Breast Cancer on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/breast-cancer.html</link><description>Recent content in Breast Cancer on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/breast-cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D receptor as a target for breast cancer therapy (abstract only)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-as-a-target-for-breast-cancer-therapy-abstract-only.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-as-a-target-for-breast-cancer-therapy-abstract-only.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breast Cancer was 4.6 times more likely if have a poor Vitamin D Receptor</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-was-46-times-more-likely-if-have-a-poor-vitamin-d-receptor.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-was-46-times-more-likely-if-have-a-poor-vitamin-d-receptor.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Do genetic polymorphisms of the vitamin D receptor contribute to breast/ovarian cancer?&lt;br>
A systematic review and network meta-analysis - Nov 2018&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/off-topic-10-ways-to-find-medical-studies-on-the-web" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Off Topic: 10 ways to find medical studies on the web">PDF is available free at Sci-Hub&lt;/a>  10.1016/j.gene.2018.07.070&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/bc-vdr.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is involved in a wide variety of biological processes including bone metabolism, modulation of the immune response, and regulation of cell proliferation and differentiation. The present study aimed to investigate vitamin D status and the genetic polymorphism BsmI (A/G) of vitamin D receptor (VDR) among a group of Egyptian female patients with breast cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer outcomes much better if higher vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-outcomes-much-better-if-higher-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-outcomes-much-better-if-higher-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Vitamin D treating of breast and other cancers may be via CCN genes</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-treating-of-breast-and-other-cancers-may-be-via-ccn-genes.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-treating-of-breast-and-other-cancers-may-be-via-ccn-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="regulation-of-the-ccn-genes-by-vitamin-d-a-possible-adjuvant-therapy-in-the-treatment-of-cancer-and-fibrosis">Regulation of the CCN genes by vitamin D: A possible adjuvant therapy in the treatment of cancer and fibrosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cellular Signalling; Vol 28, Issue 10, October 2016, pg 1604–1613; &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cellsig.2016.07.009">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cellsig.2016.07.009&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Richard T. Piszczatowskia, Nathan H. Lentsb&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The CCN family is composed of six cysteine-rich, modular, and conserved proteins whose functions span a variety of tissues and include cell proliferation, adhesion, angiogenesis, and wound healing. Roles for the CCN proteins throughout the entire body including the skin, kidney, brain, blood vessels, hematopoietic compartment and others, are continuously being elucidated. Likewise, an understanding of the regulation of this important gene family is constantly becoming clearer, through identification of transcription factors that directly activate, repress, or respond to upstream cell signaling pathways, as well as other forms of gene expression control. Vitamin D (1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 or calcitriol), a vitamin essential for numerous biological processes, acts as a potent gene expression modulator. The regulation of the CCN gene family members by calcitriol has been described in many contexts. Here, we provide a concise and thorough overview of what is known about calcitriol and its regulation of the CCN genes, and argue that its regulation is of physiological importance in a wide breadth of tissues in which CCN genes function. In addition, we highlight the effects of vitamin D on CCN gene expression in the setting of two common pathologic conditions, fibrosis and cancer, and propose that the therapeutic effects of vitamin D3 described in these disease states may in part be attributable to CCN gene modulation. As vitamin D is perfectly safe in a wide range of doses and already showing promise as an adjuvant therapeutic agent, a deeper understanding of its control of CCN gene expression may have profound implications in clinical management of disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Digital Mammography Specialists – Breast Cancer prevented and treated with Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/digital-mammography-specialists-breast-cancer-prevented-and-treated-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/digital-mammography-specialists-breast-cancer-prevented-and-treated-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency--breast-cancer-relationship-high-vitamin-d-levels-increase-survival-rate-after-mammogram-breast-cancer-detection--diagnosishttpsdmsradcomvitamin-d-deficiency-breast-cancer-relationship-high-vitamin-d-levels-increase-survival-rate-after-mammogram-breast-cancer-detection-diagnosis">&lt;a href="https://dmsrad.com/vitamin-d-deficiency-breast-cancer-relationship-high-vitamin-d-levels-increase-survival-rate-after-mammogram-breast-cancer-detection-diagnosis/">Vitamin D Deficiency &amp;amp; Breast Cancer Relationship; High Vitamin D Levels Increase Survival Rate After Mammogram Breast Cancer Detection &amp;amp; Diagnosis&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Digital Mammography Specialists, Georgia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Section Titles&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Low Vitamin D &amp;amp; Breast Cancer Risk&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D Deficiency &amp;amp; Breast Cancer Recurrence&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Role of Sunlight in Reducing the Risk of Breast Cancer&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Causes of Vitamin D Deficiency in Adult Women&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Recognize Symptoms of Vitamin D Deficiency&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to Get More Vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death after Breast Cancer 2 times less likely if take lots of Magnesium</title><link>/posts/death-after-breast-cancer-2-times-less-likely-if-take-lots-of-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-after-breast-cancer-2-times-less-likely-if-take-lots-of-magnesium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D review of Colorectal, Breast, and Prostate Cancers</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-review-of-colorectal-breast-and-prostate-cancers.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-review-of-colorectal-breast-and-prostate-cancers.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and cancer – epidemiological association with colon and breast</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-epidemiological-association-with-colon-and-breast.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-epidemiological-association-with-colon-and-breast.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-an-overview-on-epidemiological-studies">Vitamin D and Cancer: An overview on Epidemiological studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology 810:17-32 · September 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>José Manuel Ordóñez Mena1,2 and Hermann Brenner1,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Clinical Epidemiology and Aging Research, German Cancer Research Centre, Im Neuenheimer Feld 581, 69120 Heidelberg, Germany.E-Mail: 2 &lt;a href="mailto:jose.ordonezmena@dkfz.de">jose.ordonezmena@dkfz.de&lt;/a> ; 3 &lt;a href="mailto:hermann.brenner@dkfz.de">hermann.brenner@dkfz.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In recent years, a rapidly increasing number of studies have investigated the relationship of vitamin D with total cancer and site-specific cancer obtaining diverse findings. In this chapter we provide an overview of epidemiological studies of vitamin D intake, 25-hydroxyvitamin D and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D serum levels and vitamin D associated polymorphisms in relation to total and site-specific cancer risk. Overall, epidemiological evidence for total cancer is inconclusive.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer risk reduced 65 percent by vitamin D levels greater than 40 nanograms</title><link>/posts/cancer-risk-reduced-65-percent-by-vitamin-d-levels-greater-than-40-nanograms.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-risk-reduced-65-percent-by-vitamin-d-levels-greater-than-40-nanograms.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#159-citations-of-this-study-as-of-dec-2022">159 citations of this study as of Dec 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="159-citations-of-this-study-as-of-dec-2022">159 citations of this study as of Dec 2022&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?cites=10766508281430724889&amp;amp;as_sdt=5,48&amp;amp;sciodt=0,48&amp;amp;hl=en">Google Scholar&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Review of Recent Advances in Understanding the Role of Vitamin D in Reducing Cancer Risk: Breast, Colorectal, Prostate, and Overall Cancer - GRANT - Jan 2020 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.21873/anticanres.13977">https://doi.org/10.21873/anticanres.13977&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Increased Breast Cancer metastasis if low vitamin D or poor VDR</title><link>/posts/increased-breast-cancer-metastasis-if-low-vitamin-d-or-poor-vdr.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-breast-cancer-metastasis-if-low-vitamin-d-or-poor-vdr.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D is 100X better than folic acid during pregnancy</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-100x-better-than-folic-acid-during-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-100x-better-than-folic-acid-during-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="new-web-page-a-hrefpostsvitamin-d-is-at-least-100-x-better-than-folic-acid-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-vitamin-d-is-at-least-100-x-better-than-folic-acidvitamin-d-is-at-least-100-x-better-than-folic-acida-sept-2018">New web page &lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-is-at-least-100-x-better-than-folic-acid" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Vitamin D is at least 100 X better than Folic Acid">Vitamin D is at least 100 X better than Folic Acid&lt;/a> Sept 2018&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Giving Folic Acid before 2,000 births would reduce&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1 Spina Bifida birth&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>100 preterm births&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Note: Premature Birth is the biggest cause the death for children age 0 - 5 years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Similar lifetime cost (about $700,000 ) of a premature birth and a Spina bifida birth&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer Chemotherapy dropped Vitamin D levels by 6 nanograms</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-dropped-vitamin-d-levels-by-6-nanograms.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-dropped-vitamin-d-levels-by-6-nanograms.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-25-0h-d3-status-and-pathological-response-to-neoadjuvant-chemotherapy-in-stage-iiiii-breast-cancer-data-from-the-neozotac-trial-boog-10-01">Vitamin D (25-0H D3) status and pathological response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in stage II/III breast cancer: Data from the NEOZOTAC trial (BOOG 10-01).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Breast. 2015 Nov 21. pii: S0960-9776(15)00230-1. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.breast.2015.10.005.">doi: 10.1016/j.breast.2015.10.005.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charehbili A1, Hamdy NA2, Smit VT3, Kessels L4, van Bochove A5, van Laarhoven HW6, Putter H7, Meershoek-Klein Kranenbarg E8, van Leeuwen-Stok AE9, van der Hoeven JJ10, van de Velde CJ8, Nortier JW10, Kroep JR11; Dutch Breast Cancer Research Group (BOOG).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer survived much longer if have more than 20 nanograms of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-survived-much-longer-if-have-more-than-20-nanograms-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-survived-much-longer-if-have-more-than-20-nanograms-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breast Cancer: 26 percent less risk if menopausal hormone therapy plus vitamin D</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-26-percent-less-risk-if-menopausal-hormone-therapy-plus-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-26-percent-less-risk-if-menopausal-hormone-therapy-plus-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breast Cancer inhibited by Vitamin D and Calcitriol – mouse studies provide insight</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-inhibited-by-vitamin-d-and-calcitriol-mouse-studies-provide-insight.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-inhibited-by-vitamin-d-and-calcitriol-mouse-studies-provide-insight.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="inhibition-of-mouse-breast-tumor-initiating-cells-by-calcitriol-and-dietary-vitamin-d">Inhibition of Mouse Breast Tumor-Initiating Cells by Calcitriol and Dietary Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mol Cancer Ther August 2015 14; 1951&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Youngtae Jeong 1,2, Srilatha Swami 3, Aruna V. Krishnan 3, Jasmaine D. Williams 4,5, Shanique Martin 1,2, Ronald L. Horst 6, Megan A. Albertelli 7, Brian J. Feldman 1,2,4,5, David Feldman 1,3, &lt;a href="mailto:dfeldman@stanford.edu">dfeldman@stanford.edu&lt;/a> , and Maximilian Diehn 1,2,8, &lt;a href="mailto:diehn@stanford.edu">diehn@stanford.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Stanford Cancer Institute, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Institute for Stem Cell Biology and Regenerative Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast cancer associated with high Calcium AND low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-associated-with-high-calcium-and-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-associated-with-high-calcium-and-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="significance-of-serum-levels-of-vitamin-d-and-some-related-minerals-in-breast-cancer-patients">Significance of serum levels of vitamin D and some related minerals in breast cancer patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Clin Exp Pathol. 2015 Apr 1;8(4):4074-4082.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abdelgawad IA1, El-Mously RH2, Saber MM3, Mansour OA4, Shouman SA5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Clinical &amp;amp; Chemical Pathology, NCI, Cairo University Cairo, Egypt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Oncology, NCI, Cairo University Cairo, Egypt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Pharmaceutical Sciences Cairo, Egypt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4Departement of Biochemitry, Faculty of Pharmacy, Alazhar University Cairo, Egypt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>5Department of Biochemitry, Faculty of Pharmacy, Cairo University Cairo, Egypt.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast cancer – reduced proliferation with Vitamin K2 in lab</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-reduced-proliferation-with-vitamin-k2-in-lab.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-reduced-proliferation-with-vitamin-k2-in-lab.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="real-time-cell-analysis-of-the-inhibitory-effect-of-vitamin-k2-on-adhesion-and-proliferation-of-breast-cancer-cells">Real Time Cell Analysis of the inhibitory effect of Vitamin K2 on adhesion and proliferation of breast cancer cells&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrition Research; Available online 30 May 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 5 November 2014, Revised 12 May 2015, Accepted 27 May 2015, Available online 30 May 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maeve Kielya, b, c; Spencer J. Hodgins d; B. Anne Merrigan e; Shona Tormey d, e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patrick A. Kiely a, b, c; Eibhlís M. O’Connor a&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Life Sciences, University of Limerick&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer aromatase therapy can cause sore tendons if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-aromatase-therapy-can-cause-sore-tendons-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-aromatase-therapy-can-cause-sore-tendons-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hypovitaminosis-d-is-a-predictor-of-aromatase-inhibitor-musculoskeletal-symptoms">Hypovitaminosis D is a predictor of aromatase inhibitor musculoskeletal symptoms.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Breast J. 2014 Mar-Apr;20(2):174-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/tbj.12227.">doi: 10.1111/tbj.12227.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Jan 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Singer O1, Cigler T, Moore AB, Levine AB, Do HT, Mandl LA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Rheumatology, Department of Medicine, Georgia Health Sciences University, Augusta, Georgia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aromatase inhibitor (AI)-associated musculoskeletal (MSK) pain symptoms are often debilitating and limit compliance with this important hormonal breast cancer therapy. The etiology of this syndrome is unknown. Hypovitaminosis D has been suggested as a possible risk factor for the development of MSK symptoms in women starting AIs. The objective of this substudy was to define the prevalence of low 25(OH)D in this population, to assess risk of low levels on developing pain and to define a target therapeutic goal for 25(OH)D in this population. This analysis was part of a 6-month prospective cohort study examining the MSK side effects of adjuvant AI therapy in postmenopausal women. Patients were evaluated by a rheumatologist with a joint examination, had 25(OH)D levels measured and completed quality of life questionnaires at baseline, 3 and 6 months. Symptomatic patients were defined as those that self-reported new or worsening MSK symptoms. Of 52 patients, 28 (54%) were symptomatic, and two (3.8%) stopped AIs due to MSK ailments. Thirteen patients had objective evidence of tendonitis on rheumatologic examination. Thirty-three percent of all subjects had baseline 25(OH)D levels &amp;lt;40 ng/mL, 19.2% had levels &amp;lt;30 ng/mL and 5.8% had levels &amp;lt;20 ng/mL. Symptomatic patients were more likely to have had baseline levels below 40 ng/mL, compared with asymptomatic patients ( &lt;strong>46.4% versus 16.7%&lt;/strong> , p = 0.037). In multivariate regression analyses, levels &amp;lt;40 ng/mL were associated with developing objective tenosynovitis (p = 0.033) but not with developing nonspecific myalgias. Our findings suggest hypovitaminosis D may be contributing to the AI-associated MSK pain syndrome and in particular to the development of tendonitis. Repletion to 25(OH)D levels &amp;gt;40 ng/mL is advisable. Further research should be carried out on identifying additional modifiable risk factors for this syndrome.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D associated with 2X better health and less stress, both before and after Breast Cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-associated-with-2x-better-health-and-less-stress-both-before-and-after-breast-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-associated-with-2x-better-health-and-less-stress-both-before-and-after-breast-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breast Cancer risk reduced (in mice) which got vitamin D</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-risk-reduced-in-mice-which-got-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-risk-reduced-in-mice-which-got-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="inhibition-of-mouse-breast-tumor-initiating-cells-by-calcitriol-and-dietary-vitamin-d">Inhibition of Mouse Breast Tumor Initiating Cells by Calcitriol and Dietary Vitamin D.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mol Cancer Ther. 2015 May 1. pii: molcanther.0066.2015. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jeong Y 1, Swami S 2, Krishnan AV 3, Williams JD 4, Martin S 5, Horst RL 6, Albertelli MA 7, Feldman BJ 4, Feldman D 3, Diehn M 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Radiation Oncology, Stanford University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Medicine / Endocrinology, Stanford University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Medicine/Endocrinology, Stanford University School of Medicine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased risk of some female cancers if low vitamin D (due to genes) – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/increased-risk-of-some-female-cancers-if-low-vitamin-d-due-to-genes-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-risk-of-some-female-cancers-if-low-vitamin-d-due-to-genes-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cancer deaths strongly related to low vitamin D if sampled near time of diagnosis</title><link>/posts/cancer-deaths-strongly-related-to-low-vitamin-d-if-sampled-near-time-of-diagnosis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-deaths-strongly-related-to-low-vitamin-d-if-sampled-near-time-of-diagnosis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-survival-in-norwegian-patients-with-cancer-of-breast-colon-lung-and-lymphoma-a-population-based-study">Serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D and survival in Norwegian patients with cancer of breast, colon, lung, and lymphoma: a population-based study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2012 Feb;23(2):363-70. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10552-011-9885-6.">doi: 10.1007/s10552-011-9885-6.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tretli S1, Schwartz GG, Torjesen PA, Robsahm TE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1The Cancer Registry of Norway, Institute of Population-based Cancer Research, Majorstuen, 0304 Oslo, Norway. &lt;a href="mailto:steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no">steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We investigated the association between serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) and risk of death in Norwegian cancer patients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer is prevented by vitamin D – but more RCT are needed to understand why</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-is-prevented-by-vitamin-d-but-more-rct-are-needed-to-understand-why.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-is-prevented-by-vitamin-d-but-more-rct-are-needed-to-understand-why.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-reduction-of-breast-cancer-risk">Vitamin D and Reduction of Breast Cancer Risk&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Current Breast Cancer Reports, April 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jennifer K. Lue, Katherine D. Crew&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Photodynamic Therapy used to kill cancer in mice was improved 4X by Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/photodynamic-therapy-used-to-kill-cancer-in-mice-was-improved-4x-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/photodynamic-therapy-used-to-kill-cancer-in-mice-was-improved-4x-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-enhances-the-efficacy-of-photodynamic-therapy-in-a-murine-model-of-breast-cancer">Vitamin D enhances the efficacy of photodynamic therapy in a murine model of breast cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Kishore R. Rollakanti 1,2, Sanjay Anand 2,3 andEdward V. Maytin 1,2,3,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer Medicine: online: 25 FEB 2015, DOI: 10.1002/cam4.361&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>Chemicals are put into bloodstream which attach themselves to cancerous cells&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A laser (633 nm = red) is used to activate those chemicals to kill a wide variety of cancerous cells.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is called Photodynamic Therapy (PDT)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ALL of the top 10 health problems of women are associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/all-of-the-top-10-health-problems-of-women-are-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/all-of-the-top-10-health-problems-of-women-are-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="major-causes-of-all-dalys-2003--2023--females">Major Causes of all DALYs 2003 &amp;amp; 2023 – Females&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="condition2003-2023">||Condition|2003| |2023|&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=48&amp;amp;deep=off&amp;amp;type=">Anxiety - Depression&lt;/a>|10.0%|1|8.7%|1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-diabetes-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Diabetes and vitamin D">Type 2 Diabetes&lt;/a>|4.9%|4|8.0%|2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-alzheimers-cognition-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Alzheimer's-Cognition and Vitamin D">Dementia&lt;/a>|4.8%|5|7.4%|3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-cardiovascular-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Cardiovascular and vitamin D">Ischaemic Heart&lt;/a> |8.9%|2|6.1%|4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-stroke-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Stroke and vitamin D">Stroke&lt;/a>|5.1%|3|3.8%|5&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast cancer chemotherapy benefits from highest vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-benefits-from-highest-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-benefits-from-highest-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pretreatment-vitamin-d-level-and-response-to-neoadjuvant-chemotherapy-in-women-with-breast-cancer-on-the-i-spy-trial-calgb-150007150015acrin6657">Pretreatment vitamin D level and response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in women with breast cancer on the I-SPY trial (CALGB 150007/150015/ACRIN6657).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Med. 2014 Jun;3(3):693-701. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/cam4.235.">doi: 10.1002/cam4.235.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Apr 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clark AS1, Chen J, Kapoor S, Friedman C, Mies C, Esserman L, DeMichele A; I-SPY1 Investigators.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>Most of the women had low levels of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The one graph which shows women with &amp;gt; 30 ng shows a nice benefit&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/breast-cancer-recurrence.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>Suspect that there would be a virtually flat survival line for women having &amp;gt; 50 ng of vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer rate reduced 72 percent by vitamin D gene polymorphism CYP24A1</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-rate-reduced-72-percent-by-vitamin-d-gene-polymorphism-cyp24a1.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-rate-reduced-72-percent-by-vitamin-d-gene-polymorphism-cyp24a1.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-related-gene-polymorphisms-plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-risk">Vitamin D-related gene polymorphisms, plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D, and breast cancer risk.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2014 Nov 25. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reimers LL1, Crew KD, Bradshaw PT, Santella RM, Steck SE, Sirosh I, Terry MB, Hershman DL, Shane E, Cremers S, Dworakowski E, Teitelbaum SL, Neugut AI, Gammon MD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology, Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University, 722 W 168th St, 7th Floor, New York, NY, 10032, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:llr2124@columbia.edu">llr2124@columbia.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer (colon, breast, lymph) survival about 2X better with high level vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cancer-colon-breast-lymph-survival-about-2x-better-with-high-level-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-colon-breast-lymph-survival-about-2x-better-with-high-level-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="review-the-impacts-of-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-on-cancer-patient-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Review: the impacts of circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels on cancer patient outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014 Jul;99(7):2327-36. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2013-4320.">doi: 10.1210/jc.2013-4320.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Apr 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Li M1, Chen P, Li J, Chu R, Xie D, Wang H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CONTEXT:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Circulating levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> may affect the prognosis of cancer patients; however, the epidemiological results are not consistent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To perform a meta-analysis of all published studies to assess the associations of circulating 25(OH)D levels measured at or near the time of diagnosis and outcomes for cancer patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More than an hour of daily sun associated with 30 percent less ERplus Breast Cancer</title><link>/posts/more-than-an-hour-of-daily-sun-associated-with-30-percent-less-erplus-breast-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-an-hour-of-daily-sun-associated-with-30-percent-less-erplus-breast-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sun-exposure-vitamin-d-receptor-genetic-variants-and-risk-of-breast-cancer-in-the-agricultural-health-study">Sun Exposure, Vitamin D Receptor Genetic Variants, and Risk of Breast Cancer in the Agricultural Health Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Environ Health Perspect 122:165–171; &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1289/ehp.1206274">http://dx.doi.org/10.1289/ehp.1206274&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lawrence S. Engel,1 Jaya Satagopan,2 Camelia S. Sima,2 Irene Orlow,2 Urvi Mujumdar,2 Joseph Coble,3 Pampa Roy,2 Sarah Yoo,2 Dale P. Sandler,4 and Michael C. Alavanja3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Epidemiology, University of North Carolina Gillings School of Global Public Health, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, USA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center, New York, New York, USA;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Premenopausal Breast Cancer 10X more likely if total body coverage (Iran) – 2014</title><link>/posts/premenopausal-breast-cancer-10x-more-likely-if-total-body-coverage-iran-2014.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/premenopausal-breast-cancer-10x-more-likely-if-total-body-coverage-iran-2014.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="role-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-lack-of-sun-exposure-in-the-incidence-of-premenopausal-breast-cancer-a-case-control-study-in-sabzevar-iran">Role of vitamin D deficiency and lack of sun exposure in the incidence of premenopausal breast cancer: a case control study in Sabzevar, Iran.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2014;15(8):3391-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bidgoli SA1, Azarshab H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Toxicology and Pharmacology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Islamic Azad University, Pharmaceutical Sciences Branch (IAUPS), Tehran, Iran E-mail : &lt;a href="mailto:sepideharbabi@yaho.com">sepideharbabi@yaho.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has been suggested as one of the critical factors for female reproductive health with protective activities against different cancers but there are conflicting facts regarding its role on breast cancer without any clear data on premenopausal cases. This study aimed to evaluate the role of vitamin D from dietary sources and sunlight exposure on the incidence of premenopausal breast cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer survival 4 percent more likely with just a little more vitamin D (4 ng) - meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cancer-survival-4-percent-more-likely-with-just-a-little-more-vitamin-d-4-ng-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-survival-4-percent-more-likely-with-just-a-little-more-vitamin-d-4-ng-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-impacts-of-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-on-cancer-patient-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">The Impacts of Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels on Cancer Patient Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-impacts-of-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-on-cancer-patient-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">The Impacts of Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels on Cancer Patient Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014 Apr 29:jc20134320.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Li M1, Chen P, Li J, Chu R, Xie D, Wang H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Key Laboratory of Food Safety Research (M.L., P.C., J.L., R.C., D.X., H.W.), Institute for Nutritional Sciences, Shanghai Institutes for Biological Sciences, Chinese Academy of Sciences, University of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai 200031, China; Key Laboratory of Food Safety Risk Assessment (D.X., H.W.), Ministry of Health, Beijing 100021, China; and School of Life Science and Technology (D.X., H.W.), Shanghai Tech University, Shanghai, 200031, China.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death due to breast cancer reduced 40 percent if high vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/death-due-to-breast-cancer-reduced-40-percent-if-high-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-due-to-breast-cancer-reduced-40-percent-if-high-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-intake-blood-25ohd-levels-and-breast-cancer-risk-or-mortality-a-meta-analysis">Vitamin D intake, blood 25(OH)D levels, and breast cancer risk or mortality: a meta-analysis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>British Journal of Cancer , (8 April 2014) | doi:10.1038/bjc.2014.175&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Y Kim and Y Je&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Experimental studies suggest potential anti-carcinogenic properties of vitamin D against breast cancer risk, but the epidemiological evidence to date is inconsistent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: We searched MEDLINE and EMBASE databases along with a hand search for eligible studies to examine the association between vitamin D status (based on diet and blood 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D)) and breast cancer risk or mortality in a meta-analysis. A random-effect model was used to calculate a pooled adjusted relative risk (RR).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer probability reduced 12 percent with daily hour of (outdoor) exercise</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-probability-reduced-12-percent-with-daily-hour-of-outdoor-exercise.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-probability-reduced-12-percent-with-daily-hour-of-outdoor-exercise.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="regular-physical-activity-reduces-breast-cancer-risk-irrespective-of-age">Regular physical activity reduces breast cancer risk irrespective of age&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.ecco-org.eu/Global/News/EBCC9-PR/2014/03/Boniol-Regular-physical-activity-reduces-breast-cancer-risk-irrespective-of-age.aspx">press release&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glasgow, UK: Practising sport for more than an hour day reduces the risk of contracting breast cancer, and this applies to women of any age and any weight, and also unaffected by geographical location, according to research presented to the &lt;strong>9th European Breast Cancer Conference (EBCC-9)&lt;/strong> . Compared with the least active women, those with the highest level of physical activity reduced their risk of breast cancer by 12%, researchers say.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer patients wearing concealing clothing were 13X more likely to be vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-patients-wearing-concealing-clothing-were-13x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-patients-wearing-concealing-clothing-were-13x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-levels-in-patients-with-breast-cancer-importance-of-dressing-style">Vitamin d levels in patients with breast cancer: importance of dressing style.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2014;15(3):1357-62.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alco G1, Igdem S, Dincer M, Ozmen V, Saglam S, Selamoglu D, Erdogan Z, Ordu C, Pilanci KN, Bozdogan A, Yenice S, Tecimer C, Demir G, Koksal G, Okkan S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Radiation Oncology, Gayrettepe Florence Nightingale Hospital, stanbul, Turkey E-mail : &lt;a href="mailto:gulalco@gmail.com">gulalco@gmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency is a potentially modifiable risk factor that may be targeted for breast cancer (BC) prevention. It may also be related to prognosis after diagnosis and treatment. The aim of our study was to determine the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency as measured by serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25-OHD) levels in patients with BC and to evaluate its correlations with life-style and treatments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on encouraging Vitamin D to reduce Breast Cancer, etc.</title><link>/posts/thoughts-on-encouraging-vitamin-d-to-reduce-breast-cancer-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/thoughts-on-encouraging-vitamin-d-to-reduce-breast-cancer-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Got started on this when I realized that more data is not needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Had made the following summary in the &lt;a href="/posts/overview-of-breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 4290">Overview of Breast Cancer and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are over &lt;strong>118 studies&lt;/strong> of vitamin D and the prevention/treatment of Breast Cancer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are over &lt;strong>12 meta-analysis&lt;/strong> of vitamin D and Breast Cancer&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the most recent 2 both found a 2X reduction of deaths from Breast Cancer for those with sufficient vitamin D.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>There are &lt;strong>43 clinical trials with vitamin D intervention&lt;/strong> for the prevention/treatment of Breast Cancer&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More survive Breast Cancer if more vitamin D – 2X fewer deaths with just 30 ng -meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/more-survive-breast-cancer-if-more-vitamin-d-2x-fewer-deaths-with-just-30-ng-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-survive-breast-cancer-if-more-vitamin-d-2x-fewer-deaths-with-just-30-ng-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="meta-analysis-of-vitamin-d-sufficiency-for-improving-survival-of-patients-with-breast-cancer">Meta-analysis of Vitamin D Sufficiency for Improving Survival of Patients with Breast Cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Anticancer Research March 2014 vol. 34 no. 3 1163-1166&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SHARIF B. MOHR 1⇑, EDWARD D. GORHAM 1,2, JUNE KIM 1, HEATHER HOFFLICH 2 and CEDRIC F. GARLAND 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Scientific Programs Office, Code 01A, Naval Health Research Center, San Diego, CA, U.S.A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Family and Preventive Medicine 0620, University of California, San Diego, La Jolla, CA, U.S.A.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colorectal and Breast Cancer – Vitamin D is associated with fewer deaths – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colorectal-and-breast-cancer-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-fewer-deaths-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-and-breast-cancer-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-fewer-deaths-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-survival-in-colorectal-and-breast-cancer-patients-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-prospective-cohort-studies">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels and survival in colorectal and breast cancer patients: Systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Cancer. 2014 Feb 27. pii: S0959-8049(14)00124-5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejca.2014.02.006.">doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2014.02.006.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maalmi H1, Ordóñez-Mena JM1, Schöttker B1, Brenner H2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ), Division of Clinical Epidemiology and Aging Research, Im Neuenheimer Feld 581, 69120 Heidelberg, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ), Division of Clinical Epidemiology and Aging Research, Im Neuenheimer Feld 581, 69120 Heidelberg, Germany; German Cancer Consortium (DKTK), Heidelberg, Germany. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:h.brenner@dkfz.de">h.brenner@dkfz.de&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer – review of 2 RCT did not find association with 1000 IU of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-review-of-2-rct-did-not-find-association-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-review-of-2-rct-did-not-find-association-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-and-breast-cancer-prevention-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-randomized-clinical-trials">Vitamin D supplementation and breast cancer prevention: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2013 Jul 22;8(7):e69269. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0069269.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0069269.&lt;/a> Print 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sperati F1, Vici P, Maugeri-Saccà M, Stranges S, Santesso N, Mariani L, Giordano A, Sergi D, Pizzuti L, Di Lauro L, Montella M, Crispo A, Mottolese M, Barba M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In recent years, the scientific evidence linking vitamin D status or supplementation to breast cancer has grown notably. To investigate the role of vitamin D supplementation on breast cancer incidence, we conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials comparing vitamin D with placebo or no treatment. We used OVID to search MEDLINE (R), EMBASE and CENTRAL until April 2012. We screened the reference lists of included studies and used the &amp;ldquo;Related Article&amp;rdquo; feature in PubMed to identify additional articles. No language restrictions were applied. Two reviewers independently extracted data on methodological quality, participants, intervention, comparison and outcomes. Risk Ratios and 95% Confident Intervals for breast cancer were pooled using a random-effects model. Heterogeneity was assessed using the I(2) test. In sensitivity analysis, we assessed the impact of vitamin D dosage and mode of administration on treatment effects. Only two randomized controlled trials fulfilled the pre-set inclusion criteria. The pooled analysis included 5372 postmenopausal women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer associated with low vitamin D in low latitudes only in white women</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-low-latitudes-only-in-white-women.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-low-latitudes-only-in-white-women.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-is-associated-with-decreased-risk-of-postmenopausal-breast-cancer-in-whites-a-nested-case-control-study-in-the-multiethnic-cohort-study">Plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 is associated with decreased risk of postmenopausal breast cancer in whites: a nested case-control study in the multiethnic cohort study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Cancer. 2014 Jan 17;14(1):29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim Y, Franke AA, Shvetsov YB, Wilkens LR, Cooney RV, Lurie G, Maskarinec G, Hernandez BY, Le Marchand L, Henderson BE, Kolonel LN, Goodman MT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Higher sunlight exposure is correlated with lower incidence of breast cancer in ecological studies, but findings from prospective studies regarding the association of circulating levels of vitamin D with the risk of breast cancer have been null. The objective of this study was to examine the relation between plasma levels of vitamin D and the risk of postmenopausal breast cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D proven to treat or prevent many cancers in animals, but only breast cancer in humans so far</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-proven-to-treat-or-prevent-many-cancers-in-animals-but-only-breast-cancer-in-humans-so-far.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-proven-to-treat-or-prevent-many-cancers-in-animals-but-only-breast-cancer-in-humans-so-far.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#chen-abstract">Chen Abstract&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-the-promise-not-yet-fulfilled">Vitamin D and cancer: the promise not yet fulfilled&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocrine. 2014 Jan 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bikle DD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The negative association of the latitude where people live and the incidence of non cutaneous cancer in that population in North America have been demonstrated in many studies for many types of cancer. Since the intensity of UVB exposure decreases with increasing latitude, and UVB exposure provides the mechanism for vitamin D production in the skin, the hypothesis that increased vitamin D provides protection against the development of cancer has been proposed. This hypothesis has been tested in a substantial number of prospective and case control studies and in a few randomized clinical trials (RTC) assessing whether either vitamin D intake or serum levels of 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) correlate (inversely) with cancer development. Most of the studies have focused on colorectal, breast, and prostate cancer. The results have been mixed. The most compelling data for a beneficial relationship between vitamin D intake or serum 25OHD levels and cancer have been obtained for colorectal cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30 percent reduced chance of breast cancer death if take tiny amount of vitamin D (one-a-day)</title><link>/posts/30-percent-reduced-chance-of-breast-cancer-death-if-take-tiny-amount-of-vitamin-d-one-a-day.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/30-percent-reduced-chance-of-breast-cancer-death-if-take-tiny-amount-of-vitamin-d-one-a-day.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="multivitamin-and-mineral-use-and-breast-cancer-mortality-in-older-women-with-invasive-breast-cancer-in-the-womens-health-initiative">Multivitamin and mineral use and breast cancer mortality in older women with invasive breast cancer in the women&amp;rsquo;s health initiative.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2013 Oct;141(3):495-505. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10549-013-2712-x.">doi: 10.1007/s10549-013-2712-x.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Oct 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wassertheil-Smoller S, McGinn AP, Budrys N, Chlebowski R, Ho GY, Johnson KC, Lane DS, Li W, Neuhouser ML, Saquib J, Shikany JM, Song Y, Thomson C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Population Health, Albert Einstein College of Medicine, 1300 Morris Park Avenue, Bronx, NY, 10461, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:sylvia.smoller@einstein.yu.edu">sylvia.smoller@einstein.yu.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast cancer increasing in India (perhaps due to lowering vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-increasing-in-india-perhaps-due-to-lowering-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-increasing-in-india-perhaps-due-to-lowering-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="breast-cancer-cases-to-double-by-2030-studyhttptimesofindiaindiatimescomindiabreast-cancer-cases-to-double-by-2030-studyarticleshow24224757cms-times-of-india">&lt;a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/Breast-cancer-cases-to-double-by-2030-Study/articleshow/24224757.cms">Breast cancer cases to double by 2030: Study&lt;/a> Times of India&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>breast cancer is now the second most common cancer diagnosed in Indian women after cervical cancer.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Indian women develop breast cancer roughly a decade earlier than women in western countries **Women in India have much lower levels of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>in India, the number of cases of breast cancer have increased by 10-15% over the last decade.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>One in 58 women are affected by breast cancer in the age group 30-70 years and are mainly from the urban population&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shift work increases breast cancer risk by 22 percent (Vitamin D is 1 of 5 possible ways)</title><link>/posts/shift-work-increases-breast-cancer-risk-by-22-percent-vitamin-d-is-1-of-5-possible-ways.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shift-work-increases-breast-cancer-risk-by-22-percent-vitamin-d-is-1-of-5-possible-ways.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="biological-mechanisms-that-underlie-shiftwork-as-a-risk-factor-for-breast-cancer">Biological mechanisms that underlie shiftwork as a risk factor for breast cancer&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Occup Environ Med 2013;70:A69-A70 doi:10.1136/oemed-2013-101717.205&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Session: Mini symposium V: Shift work and cancer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>L Fritschi1, T Erren2, D Glass3, C Saunders1, J Girschik1, T Boyle1, S El-Zaemey1, A K Thomson1, P Rogers1, S Peters1, T Slevin4, A D’Orsogna1, F De Vocht5, J Heyworth1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1University of Western Australia, Perth, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Cologne University, Cologne, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Monash University, Melbourne, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4Cancer Council of WA, Perth, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Walking an hour a day (more vitamin D) decreased chance of breast cancer by 14 percent</title><link>/posts/walking-an-hour-a-day-more-vitamin-d-decreased-chance-of-breast-cancer-by-14-percent.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/walking-an-hour-a-day-more-vitamin-d-decreased-chance-of-breast-cancer-by-14-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-24381469">http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-24381469&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>73,000 women followed for 17 years&lt;/p>
&lt;p>7 hours a week of walking: 14% less breast cancer than those who walked three or fewer hours per week&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was no mention in the article of sunshine and vitamin D reducing Breast Cancer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Probably no need to walk 7 hours a week every week of the year&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Best to walk during the summer, at noon, with as much skin exposed to the sun as possible (see tan-thru shirts below)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Breast Cancer: Emerging Concepts</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-emerging-concepts.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-emerging-concepts.html</guid><description>&lt;ul class="authorGroup noCollab">&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="authorName" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0304383512006398#" id="authname_N29a5a5a8N489844b0">Rajendra G. Mehta&lt;/a>&lt;a class="intra_ref auth_corr" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0304383512006398#cor1" id="bcor1" title="Corresponding author contact information">&lt;img alt="Corresponding author contact information" class="imgLazyJSB" src="http://cdn.els-cdn.com/sd/entities/REcor.gif" />&lt;/a>&lt;sup>, &lt;/sup>&lt;a href="mailto:RMehta@iitri.org">RMehta@iitri.org&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="authorName" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0304383512006398#" id="authname_N29a5a5a8N48984540">Xinjian Peng&lt;/a>,&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="authorName" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0304383512006398#" id="authname_N29a5a5a8N489845d0">Fatouma Alimirah&lt;/a>,&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="authorName" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0304383512006398#" id="authname_N29a5a5a8N48984660">Genoveva Murillo&lt;/a>,&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="authorName" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0304383512006398#" id="authname_N29a5a5a8N489846f0">Rajeshwari Mehta&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;/ul>&lt;ul class="affiliation">&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;span>IIT Research Institute, 10 West 35th Street, Chicago, IL 60616, United States&lt;/span>&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;/ul>&lt;ul class="articleDoi">&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.canlet.2012.10.034" id="ddDoi">&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.canlet.2012.10.034">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.canlet.2012.10.034&lt;/a>&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/help/doi.htm">How to Cite or Link Using DOI&lt;/a>&lt;/li>&lt;/p>
&lt;/ul>&lt;ul class="articleInfo">&lt;li class="permissions" id="permissions">
&lt;div class="boxLink">
&lt;p>&lt;a class="olSpawnWindow" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science?_ob=RedirectURL&amp;amp;_method=outwardLink&amp;amp;_partnerName=936&amp;amp;_eid=1-s2.0-S0304383512006398&amp;amp;_pii=S0304383512006398&amp;amp;_origin=article&amp;amp;_zone=art_page&amp;amp;_targetURL=https%3A%2F%2Fs100.copyright.com%2FAppDispatchServlet%3FpublisherName%3DELS%26contentID%3DS0304383512006398%26orderBeanReset%3Dtrue&amp;amp;_acct=C000029718&amp;amp;_version=1&amp;amp;_userid=582538&amp;amp;md5=c9a5a207fa39334d1f64f54d726bd94d" rel="nofollow">Permissions &amp;amp; Reprints&lt;/a>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;div class="boxLink permissions">
&lt;p>&lt;span style="font-size:18px;">&lt;span style="color:rgb(255,0,0);">&lt;strong>(Most of the hyperlinks in this page will not work)&lt;/strong>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;br />&lt;span style="color:#0000cd;">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="font-size:16px;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page &lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/span>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr id="author1" />&lt;div class="abstract svAbstract">
&lt;h2 class="secHeading" id="section_abstract">
&lt;p>&lt;span style="font-size:18px;">Abstract&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More sunlight (more vitamin D), less dense breasts</title><link>/posts/more-sunlight-more-vitamin-d-less-dense-breasts.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-sunlight-more-vitamin-d-less-dense-breasts.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sunlight-exposure-and-breast-density-a-population-based-study">Sunlight Exposure and Breast Density: A Population-Based Study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Journal of Breast Cancer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sheng-Hui Wu1,2, Suzanne C. Ho1 &lt;a href="mailto:suzanneho@cuhk.edu.hk">suzanneho@cuhk.edu.hk&lt;/a> , Edwin So1, Tsz-ping Lam3, Jean Woo4, PY Yuen5, Ling Qin3, Susanna Ku1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;School of Public Health and Primary Care, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China; 2Division of Epidemiology, Department of Medicine, Institute of Medicine and public Health, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville, USA; Departments of &amp;lsquo;Orthopaedics and Traumatology and &amp;ldquo;Medicine and Therapeutics, 5Physical Education Unit, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer post menopause down 12 percent for every 5 ng of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-post-menopause-down-12-percent-for-every-5-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-post-menopause-down-12-percent-for-every-5-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="plasma-vitamin-d-levels-menopause-and-risk-of-breast-cancer-dose-response-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Plasma vitamin D levels, menopause, and risk of breast cancer: dose-response meta-analysis of prospective studies.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Medicine (Baltimore). 2013 May;92(3):123-31. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0b013e3182943bc2.">doi: 10.1097/MD.0b013e3182943bc2.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bauer SR, Hankinson SE, Bertone-Johnson ER, Ding EL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Channing Laboratory, Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous evidence suggests that higher circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels are variably associated with lower breast cancer risk; however, prospective studies and clinical trials have been inconsistent, particularly between older and younger women of differing menopausal status. We conducted a quantitative nonlinear dose-response meta-analysis of prospective studies evaluating the association between circulating 25(OH)D and breast cancer risk, stratified by menopause. A systematic search of MEDLINE and EMBASE included studies published through May 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast cancer 2X more likely if have taken statins for 10 years</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-2x-more-likely-if-have-taken-statins-for-10-years.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-2x-more-likely-if-have-taken-statins-for-10-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="long-term-statin-use-and-risk-of-ductal-and-lobular-breast-cancer-among-women-55-74-years-of-age">Long-term statin use and risk of ductal and lobular breast cancer among women 55-74 years of age.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2013 Jul 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>McDougall JA, Malone KE, Daling JR, Cushing-Haugen KL, Porter PL, Li CI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiology, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Mechanistic studies largely support the chemopreventive potential of statins. However, results of epidemiologic studies investigating statin use and breast cancer risk have been inconsistent and lacked the ability to evaluate long-term statin use.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If have BRCA1 breast cancer gene, instead of double mastectomy, get 40ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/if-have-brca1-breast-cancer-gene-instead-of-double-mastectomy-get-40ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-have-brca1-breast-cancer-gene-instead-of-double-mastectomy-get-40ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="note-in-may-2013-angela-jolie-had-a-double-mastectomy-after-learning-that-she-had-brca1-gene-which-results-in-breast-cancer-in-more-than-half-of-all-females">Note: In May 2013 Angela Jolie had a double mastectomy after learning that she had BRCA1 gene which results in breast cancer in more than half of all females&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/jolie.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/jolie2.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h2 id="from-a-presentation-at-vitamin-d-workshop-in-june-2013">From a presentation at Vitamin D Workshop in June 2013&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/brca-1.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/brca-2.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/brca-3.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d">Overview Breast Cancer and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/Search+Results?hl=en&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search&amp;amp;googles.x=0&amp;amp;googles.y=0&amp;amp;q=brca1&amp;amp;domains=VitaminDWiki.com&amp;amp;sitesearch=VitaminDWiki.com">Search VitaminDWiki for BRCA1&lt;/a> 7 items as of Oct 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/the-deadly-breast-cancer-gene-is-a-myth-lancet-study-confirms" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: The “Deadly Breast Cancer Gene” Is A Myth, Lancet Study Confirms – Jan 2018">The “Deadly Breast Cancer Gene” Is A Myth, Lancet Study Confirms – Jan 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Breast Cancer and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="74-breast-cancer-clinical-trials-with-vitamin-d-interventionhttpclinicaltrialsgovct2resultsterm22breastcancer22recrrslttypecondintr22vitamind22titlesoutcsponsleadidstate1cntry1state2cntry2state3cntry3locngndrrcv_srcv_elup_slup_e-april-2024">&lt;a href="http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/results?term=%22breast+Cancer%22&amp;amp;recr=&amp;amp;rslt=&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;cond=&amp;amp;intr=%22vitamin+d%22&amp;amp;titles=&amp;amp;outc=&amp;amp;spons=&amp;amp;lead=&amp;amp;id=&amp;amp;state1=&amp;amp;cntry1=&amp;amp;state2=&amp;amp;cntry2=&amp;amp;state3=&amp;amp;cntry3=&amp;amp;locn=&amp;amp;gndr=&amp;amp;rcv_s=&amp;amp;rcv_e=&amp;amp;lup_s=&amp;amp;lup_e=">74 Breast Cancer clinical trials with Vitamin D intervention&lt;/a> (April 2024)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT01948128?term=NCT01948128&amp;amp;rank=1">Example: 40,000 IU of vitamin D DAILY to possibly eliminate need for surgery&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-is-one-of-many-ways-to-preventtreat-breast-cancer---life-extension---aug-2024">Vitamin D is one of many ways to prevent/treat Breast Cancer - Life Extension - Aug 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Avoiding smoking,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>reducing alcohol intake,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>improving diet,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>losing weight&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>increasing exercise&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>FLAVONOIDS,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Selenium,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>CRUCIFEROUS COMPOUNDS,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D, (appears to be the most effective and low cost)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>curcumin can make breast cancer cells more sensitive to chemotherapy drugs&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3.2 percent less Breast Cancer for 2.4 ng more vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/32-percent-less-breast-cancer-for-24-ng-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/32-percent-less-breast-cancer-for-24-ng-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-risk-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and breast cancer risk: a meta-analysis of prospective studies.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Tumour Biol. 2013 Jun 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wang D, Vélez de-la-Paz OI, Zhai JX, Liu DW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Hebei Medical University, No. 361 Zhongshan East Road, Shijiazhuang, Hebei Province, 050017, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were some case-control studies, nested case-control studies, and cohort studies with controversial results on the association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> and breast cancer risk. Case-control studies are prone to selection bias, which limit the strength and quality of the evidence. To overcome the shortcoming of the case-control studies, the meta-analysis of prospective studies including nested case-control studies and cohort studies was conducted. PubMed, Embase, and Web of Science databases were searched, and the last retrieval date was March 24, 2013. For the highest versus the lowest level of serum 25(OH)D, the relative risks (RRs) and its 95 % confidence intervals (CIs) from each study were used to estimate summary RR and its 95 % CI. Subgroup analyses by geographic region, menopausal status, and adjusted status of RR were also performed, respectively. A dose-response association between serum 25(OH)D concentration and breast cancer risk was assessed. Fourteen articles with 9,110 breast cancer cases and 16,244 controls were included in the meta-analysis. Overall, serum 25(OH)D levels were inversely significantly associated with breast cancer risk (RR = 0.845, 95 % CI = 0.750-0.951). Inversely statistically significant associations were observed in North American studies, postmenopausal women, and studies with adjusted and unadjusted RR, respectively. No statistically significant associations were observed in European studies and premenopausal women, respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer survival 2X more likely if vitamin D sufficient – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-survival-2x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-sufficient-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-survival-2x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-sufficient-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-relationship-between-serum-vitamin-d-levels-and-breast-cancer-prognosis-a-meta-analysis">The relationship between serum vitamin D levels and breast cancer prognosis: A meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology, 2013 ASCO Annual Meeting Proceedings (Post-Meeting Edition).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol 31, No 15_suppl (May 20 Supplement), 2013: 1521&lt;/p>
&lt;p>April Ann Nicole Rose, Christine Elser and Pamela Jean Goodwin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Faculty of Medicine, McGill University, Montreal, QC, Canada; Princess Margaret Hospital, Toronto, ON, Canada; Samuel Lunenfeld Research Institute, Mount Sinai Hospital, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer and Vitamin D: Dr Garland - video</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d-dr-garland-video.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d-dr-garland-video.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>6X less Breast Cancer if have even minimal vitamin D</title><link>/posts/6x-less-breast-cancer-if-have-even-minimal-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/6x-less-breast-cancer-if-have-even-minimal-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-status-and-breast-cancer-in-saudi-arabian-women-case-control-study">Vitamin D status and breast cancer in Saudi Arabian women: case-control study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr July 2013 ajcn.054445&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fatimah M Yousef, Elizabeth T Jacobs, Paul T Kang, Iman A Hakim,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scott Going, Jehad M Yousef, Rajaa M Al-Raddadi, Taha A Kumosani, and Cynthia A Thomson &lt;a href="mailto:cthomson@E-mail.arizona.edu">cthomson@E-mail.arizona.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Department of Nutritional Sciences (FMY, CAT, and SG), the Mel and Enid Zuckerman College of Public Health (ETJ, IAH, PTK, and CAT), and the Arizona Cancer Center (CAT, ETJ, and IAH), University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ; the Faculty of Science for Girls (TAK and JMY) and the Faculty of Science (TAK and JMY), Department of Biochemistry, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia; and the Center of Excellence for Osteoporosis Research, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia (RMA).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Women taking Vitamin D had fewest deaths after post-menopause breast cancer</title><link>/posts/women-taking-vitamin-d-had-fewest-deaths-after-post-menopause-breast-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-taking-vitamin-d-had-fewest-deaths-after-post-menopause-breast-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D Might Be Able to Slash Your Breast Cancer Risk by 90 Percent - Baggerly, Mercola:</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-might-be-able-to-slash-your-breast-cancer-risk-by-90-percent-baggerly-mercola.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-might-be-able-to-slash-your-breast-cancer-risk-by-90-percent-baggerly-mercola.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and breast cancer – overview – Oncologist 2012</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-overview-oncologist-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-overview-oncologist-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-breast-cancer">Vitamin D and breast cancer.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Oncologist. 2012;17(1):36-45. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1634/theoncologist.2011-0278.">doi: 10.1634/theoncologist.2011-0278.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jan 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shao T, Klein P, Grossbard ML.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beth Israel Medical Center, 325 West 15th Street, New York, New York 10011, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:tshao@chpnet.org">tshao@chpnet.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to its role in calcium homeostasis and bone health, vitamin D has also been reported to have anticancer activities against many cancer types, including breast cancer. The discovery that breast epithelial cells possess the same enzymatic system as the kidney, allowing local manufacture of active vitamin D from circulating precursors, makes the effect of vitamin D in breast cancer biologically plausible. Preclinical and ecologic studies have suggested a role for vitamin D in breast cancer prevention. Inverse associations have also been shown between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level (25(OH)D) and breast cancer development, risk for breast cancer recurrence, and mortality in women with early-stage breast cancer. Clinical trials of vitamin D supplementation, however, have yielded inconsistent results. Regardless of whether or not vitamin D helps prevent breast cancer or its recurrence, vitamin D deficiency in the U.S. population is very common, and the adverse impact on bone health, a particular concern for breast cancer survivors, makes it important to understand vitamin D physiology and to recognize and treat vitamin D deficiency. In this review, we discuss vitamin D metabolism and its mechanism of action. We summarize the current evidence of the relationship between vitamin D and breast cancer, highlight ongoing research in this area, and discuss optimal dosing of vitamin D for breast cancer prevention.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2900 IU not enough vitamin D to deal with Breast Cancer</title><link>/posts/2900-iu-not-enough-vitamin-d-to-deal-with-breast-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2900-iu-not-enough-vitamin-d-to-deal-with-breast-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wide variety of data on vitamin D and breast cancer, but still insufficient clinical data</title><link>/posts/wide-variety-of-data-on-vitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-but-still-insufficient-clinical-data.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wide-variety-of-data-on-vitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-but-still-insufficient-clinical-data.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-are-we-ready-to-supplement-for-breast-cancer-prevention-and-treatment">Vitamin d: are we ready to supplement for breast cancer prevention and treatment?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ISRN Oncol. 2013;2013:483687. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1155/2013/483687.">doi: 10.1155/2013/483687.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Feb 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katherine D. Crew 1,2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Medicine, Division of Hematology/Oncology, College of Physicians and Surgeons, Columbia University, New York, NY 10032, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Epidemiology, Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University, New York, NY 10032, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Herbert Irving Comprehensive Cancer Center, Columbia University, New York, NY 10032, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D receptor in breasts and breast cancer vary with race</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-in-breasts-and-breast-cancer-vary-with-race.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-in-breasts-and-breast-cancer-vary-with-race.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-and-prognosis-of-breast-cancer-among-african-american-and-hispanic-women">Vitamin D Receptor Gene Polymorphisms and Prognosis of Breast Cancer among African-American and Hispanic Women&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(3): e57967. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0057967&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dhruva K. Mishra, Yanyuan Wu, Marianna Sarkissyan, Suren Sarkissyan, Zujian Chen, Xiying Shang, May Ong, David Heber, H. Phillip Koeffler, Jaydutt V. Vadgama&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D plays a role in cancer development and acts through the vitamin D receptor (VDR). Although African-Americans have the lowest levels of serum vitamin D, there is a dearth of information on VDR gene polymorphisms and breast cancer among African-Americans and Hispanics. This study examines whether VDR gene polymorphisms are associated with breast cancer in these cohorts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer and long term vitamin D studies</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-and-long-term-vitamin-d-studies.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-and-long-term-vitamin-d-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="long-follow-up-time-after-blood-draw-adversely-affected-this-nested-case-control-study">Long follow-up time after blood draw adversely affected this nested case-control study&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="a-letter-to-editor-by-william-b-grant">A letter to editor, by William B. Grant&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>^Circulating levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D and risk of breast cancer: a nested case-control study&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Breast Cancer Research 2013, 15:R15 doi:10.1186/bcr3390&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephanie Scarmo, Yelena Afanasyeva, Per Lenner, Karen L Koenig, Ronald L Horst, Tess V Clendenen, Alan A Arslan, Yu Chen, Göran Hallmans, Eva Lundin, Sabina Rinaldi, Paolo Toniolo, Roy E Shore and Anne Zeleniuch-Jacquotte^&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer not correlated with vitamin D – were they all low</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-not-correlated-with-vitamin-d-were-they-all-low.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-not-correlated-with-vitamin-d-were-they-all-low.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Suspect that all of the women were vitamin D deficient&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was unable to find the Vitamin D quintile levels in the PDF attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you happen to discover the levels, please email me &lt;a href="mailto:hlahore@gmail.com">hlahore@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X increase in metastatic breast cancer in young women since 1976</title><link>/posts/2x-increase-in-metastatic-breast-cancer-in-young-women-since-1976.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-increase-in-metastatic-breast-cancer-in-young-women-since-1976.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="incidence-of-breast-cancer-with-distant-involvement-among-women-in-the-united-states-1976-to-2009">Incidence of Breast Cancer With Distant Involvement Among Women in the United States, 1976 to 2009&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Rebecca H. Johnson, MD; Franklin L. Chien, BA; Archie Bleyer, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>JAMA. 2013;309(8):800-805. doi:10.1001/jama.2013.776.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Importance Evidence from the US National Cancer Institute Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) database suggests that the incidence of advanced breast cancer in young women is increasing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective To quantify this trend and analyze it as a function of stage at diagnosis, race/ethnicity, residence, and hormone receptor status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Premenopausal Iron deficiency causes increased recurrence of breast cancer – 2008</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-premenopausal-iron-deficiency-causes-increased-recurrence-of-breast-cancer-2008.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-premenopausal-iron-deficiency-causes-increased-recurrence-of-breast-cancer-2008.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="does-iron-have-a-role-in-breast-cancer">Does iron have a role in breast cancer?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Lancet Oncol. 2008 Aug;9(8):803-7. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/S1470-2045(08)70200-6.">doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(08)70200-6.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Huang X.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Environmental Medicine and New York University (NYU) Cancer Institute, NYU School of Medicine, New York, NY 10016, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:xi.huang@nyumc.org">xi.huang@nyumc.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oestrogen and family history are two of the most important risk factors for breast cancer. However, these risk factors cannot explain the differences in the incidence and recurrence of breast cancer between premenopausal and postmenopausal women. In this paper I propose that, in premenopausal women, an iron deficiency caused by menstruation stabilises hypoxia inducible factor-1alpha, which increases the formation of vascular endothelial growth factor. This mechanism results in premenopausal women being more susceptible to angiogenesis and, consequently, leads to a high recurrence of breast cancer. Conversely, increased concentrations of iron in postmenopausal women, as a result of menstrual cessation, contribute to a high incidence of breast cancer via oxidative-stress pathways. Although the focus of this Personal View is on iron, this by no means negates the roles of other known risk factors in breast-cancer development. Characterisation of the role of iron in breast cancer could potentially benefit patients by decreasing recurrence and incidence and increasing overall survival.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If have breast cancer, should increase vitamin D to more than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/if-have-breast-cancer-should-increase-vitamin-d-to-more-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-have-breast-cancer-should-increase-vitamin-d-to-more-than-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-breast-cancer">Vitamin D and Breast Cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Oncologist. 2012 January; 17(1): 36–45.10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1634/theoncologist.2011-0278">doi: 10.1634/theoncologist.2011-0278&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Theresa Shao,a,c Paula Klein,a,c and Michael L. Grossbarda,b,c&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to its role in calcium homeostasis and bone health, vitamin D has also been reported to have anticancer activities against many cancer types, including breast cancer. The discovery that breast epithelial cells possess the same enzymatic system as the kidney, allowing local manufacture of active vitamin D from circulating precursors, makes the effect of vitamin D in breast cancer biologically plausible. Preclinical and ecologic studies have suggested a role for vitamin D in breast cancer prevention. Inverse associations have also been shown between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level (25(OH)D) and breast cancer development, risk for breast cancer recurrence, and mortality in women with early-stage breast cancer. Clinical trials of vitamin D supplementation, however, have yielded inconsistent results. Regardless of whether or not vitamin D helps prevent breast cancer or its recurrence, vitamin D deficiency in the U.S. population is very common, and the adverse impact on bone health, a particular concern for breast cancer survivors, makes it important to understand vitamin D physiology and to recognize and treat vitamin D deficiency. In this review, we discuss vitamin D metabolism and its mechanism of action. We summarize the current evidence of the relationship between vitamin D and breast cancer, highlight ongoing research in this area, and discuss optimal dosing of vitamin D for breast cancer prevention.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer chance decreased 16 percent for every extra ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-chance-decreased-16-percent-for-every-extra-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-chance-decreased-16-percent-for-every-extra-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="higher-blood-25ohd-level-may-reduce-the-breast-cancer-risk">Higher Blood 25(OH)D Level May Reduce the Breast Cancer Risk:&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="evidence-from-a-chinese-population-based-case-control-study-and-meta-analysis-of-the-observational-studies">Evidence from a Chinese Population Based Case-Control Study and Meta-Analysis of the Observational Studies.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0049312%20">PLoS One&lt;/a>. 2013;8(1):e49312. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0049312.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0049312.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Jan 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chen P, Li M, Gu X, Liu Y, Li X, Li C, Wang Y, Xie D, Wang F, Yu C, Li J, Chen X, Chu R, Zhu J, Ou Z, Wang H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Key Laboratory of Nutrition and Metabolism, Institute for Nutritional Sciences, Shanghai Institutes for Biological Sciences, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Graduate School of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai, P. R. China.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Quantum dots should deliver active vitamin D directly to inflammatory breast cancer tumors</title><link>/posts/quantum-dots-should-deliver-active-vitamin-d-directly-to-inflammatory-breast-cancer-tumors.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/quantum-dots-should-deliver-active-vitamin-d-directly-to-inflammatory-breast-cancer-tumors.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="using-calcitriol-conjugated-quantum-dots-to-target-inflammatory-breast-cancer-tumors-and-metastasis-in-vivo">USING CALCITRIOL CONJUGATED QUANTUM DOTS TO TARGET INFLAMMATORY BREAST CANCER TUMORS AND METASTASIS IN VIVO.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Session Title: 	Protein Biophysics in vivo (Biophysical Society Meeting)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Location: 	Hall C&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presentation Number: 	2953-Pos&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Board Number: 	B108&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presentation Time: 	2/6/2013 10:30:00 AM&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author Block: 	Jeremy Bonor, Rachel Schaefer, Anja Nohe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Delaware, Newark, DE, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calcitriol is the active form of Vitamin D3. Epidemiological data show that women with Vitamin D deficiency at the time of breast cancer diagnosis are 94% more likely to experience cancer spread and 73% more likely to die over the next 10 years, compared to women with adequate Vitamin D levels. Since vitamin D deficiency is especially common in African American and obese women, this observation may partially explain the relatively poor clinical outcome experienced by these patients &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>. Although current treatments for IBC are very aggressive and include surgery and radiation, IBC is still the most deadly breast cancer and has a survival rate of only 40% past 5 years. Novel treatments are desperately needed &lt;sup>[3]&lt;/sup>. Current limitations for the use of calcitriol as a treatment for IBC and non-IBC breast cancer is that high concentrations of calcitriol must be delivered to the tumor. This is even more complicated for IBC, since the tumor rapidly metastasizes and disseminates trough the lymphatic system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X increased chance of Breast Cancer if recent vitamin D levels were low</title><link>/posts/3x-increased-chance-of-breast-cancer-if-recent-vitamin-d-levels-were-low.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-increased-chance-of-breast-cancer-if-recent-vitamin-d-levels-were-low.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-in-the-military-a-case-control-study-utilizing-pre-diagnostic-serum">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and breast cancer in the military: a case-control study utilizing pre-diagnostic serum.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2013 Jan 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohr SB, Gorham ED, Alcaraz JE, Kane CI, Macera CA, Parsons JK, Wingard DL, Horst R, Garland CF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Epidemiology, Department of Family and Preventive Medicine, University of California San Diego, 9500 Gilman Drive 0620, La Jolla, CA, 92093-0620, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:sbmohr75@yahoo.com">sbmohr75@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this study was to ascertain whether a relationship exists between pre-diagnostic serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and risk of breast cancer in young women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast cancer tissues in petri dish benefit from active but not inactive vitamin D</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-tissues-in-petri-dish-benefit-from-active-but-not-inactive-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-tissues-in-petri-dish-benefit-from-active-but-not-inactive-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-comparison-of-vitamin-d-activity-in-paired-non-malignant-and-malignant-human-breast-tissues">A comparison of vitamin D activity in paired non-malignant and malignant human breast tissues.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2012 Oct 15;362(1-2):202-10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mce.2012.06.022.">doi: 10.1016/j.mce.2012.06.022.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jun 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suetani RJ, Ho K, Jindal S, Manavis J, Neilsen PM, Pishas KI, Rippy E, Bochner M, Kollias J, Gill PG, Morris HA, Callen DF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Breast Cancer Genetics Group, Centre for Personalised Cancer Medicine, University of Adelaide, Australia. &lt;a href="mailto:Rachel.Suetani@adelaide.edu.au">Rachel.Suetani@adelaide.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Links between a low vitamin D status and an increased risk of breast cancer have been observed in epidemiological studies. These links have been investigated in human tissue homogenates and cultured cell lines. We have used non-malignant, malignant and normal reduction mammoplasty breast tissues to investigate the biological and metabolic consequences of the application of vitamin D to intact ex vivo human breast tissue. Tissues were exposed to 1α,25(OH)(2)D(3) (1,25D; active metabolite) and 25(OH)D (25D; pre-metabolite). Changes in mRNA expression and protein expression after vitamin D exposure were analysed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off Topic GMO Roundup Corn causes lots of cancer and other problems in rats</title><link>/posts/off-topic-gmo-roundup-corn-causes-lots-of-cancer-and-other-problems-in-rats.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-gmo-roundup-corn-causes-lots-of-cancer-and-other-problems-in-rats.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>The sun appears better at reducing incidence of some cancers than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-prevention-of-cancer-by-sun-exposure-more-than-just-the-effect-of-vitamin-d--a-systematic-review-of-epidemiological-studies">Is prevention of cancer by sun exposure more than just the effect of vitamin D? -A systematic review of epidemiological studies.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Cancer. 2012 Dec 10. pii: S0959-8049(12)00885-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.">doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van der Rhee H, Coebergh JW, de Vries E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Hagaziekenhuis, P.O. Box 40551, Leyweg 275, 2504 LN Den Haag, Zuid-Holland, The Netherlands. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:hvdrhee@casema.nl">hvdrhee@casema.nl&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The number of studies reporting on the association between sunlight exposure, vitamin D and cancer risk is steadily increasing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Breast Cancer Incidence and Outcome</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-incidence-and-outcome.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-incidence-and-outcome.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.98-106 (9)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author: Rowan T. Chlebowski&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Based on preclinical studies and early clinical observations, an association between vitamin D status and breast cancer incidence and outcome has been proposed. Against this background, information on vitamin D and breast cancer was reviewed with focused attention on emerging clinical studies in this area. Prospective cohort studies do not associate 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels with breast cancer incidence. While case-control studies of this question are positive, they may be confounded by reverse causality as 25- hydroxyvitamin D levels are influenced by breast cancer presence and stage. Studies of 25-hydroxyvitamin D and subsequent breast cancer recurrence provide mixed results but strongest associations were seen in analyses uncontrolled for prognostic variables, cancer therapy, BMI and physical activity. The one full-scale randomized, placebo-controlled trial evaluating calcium (1000 mg elemental calcium per day) and vitamin D supplementation (400 IU D3 per day) with 36,282 participants failed to demonstrate a supplement effect on lowering breast cancer incidence. Breast cancer patients not uncommonly have vitamin D deficiency but limited control populations in available reports preclude precise prevalence estimates. As breast cancer patients are at risk for bone loss and musculoskeletal complaints from cancer or associated therapies, monitoring 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels and vitamin D3 supplementation in moderate dose (1,000- 1,500 IU D3 per day) can be recommended with expectation of mainly bone benefit. In women with breast cancer, future vitamin D supplementation studies need to be appropriately designed and powered to provide definitive assessments. However, a full-scale randomized trial evaluating the influence of vitamin D supplementation on breast cancer recurrence is likely not feasible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer - Breast</title><link>/posts/cancer-breast.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-breast.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">&lt;/nav></description></item><item><title>Big Pharma continues to seek a patentable form of vitamin D for Breast Cancer</title><link>/posts/big-pharma-continues-to-seek-a-patentable-form-of-vitamin-d-for-breast-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/big-pharma-continues-to-seek-a-patentable-form-of-vitamin-d-for-breast-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Postmenopausal Breast cancer 63 percent more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/postmenopausal-breast-cancer-63-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/postmenopausal-breast-cancer-63-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breast Cancer incidence change by 40 percent with vitamin D receptor genes</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-incidence-change-by-40-percent-with-vitamin-d-receptor-genes.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-incidence-change-by-40-percent-with-vitamin-d-receptor-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-gene-haplotypes-and-polymorphisms-and-risk-of-breast-cancer-a-nested-casecontrol-study">Vitamin D Receptor Gene Haplotypes and Polymorphisms and Risk of Breast Cancer: A Nested Case–Control Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev; 21(10); 1856–67. ©2012 AACR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lawrence S. Engel 1, Irene Orlow 3, Camelia S. Sima 3, Jaya Satagopan 3, Urvi Mujumdar 3, Pampa Roy 3, Sarah Yoo 3, Dale P. Sandler 2, and Michael C. Alavanja 4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Epidemiology, Gillings School of Global Public Health, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ginger kills breast cancer cells in petri dish</title><link>/posts/ginger-kills-breast-cancer-cells-in-petri-dish.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ginger-kills-breast-cancer-cells-in-petri-dish.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="interesting-article-on-ginger-and-cancer-in-green-medical-informationhttpwwwgreenmedinfocomblogresearch-ginger-selectively-kills-breast-cancer-cells20">Interesting article on Ginger and Cancer in &lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/research-ginger-selectively-kills-breast-cancer-cells%20">Green Medical Information&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="one-of-the-supports-for-the-article-is--span-stylecolor00fattached-at-the-bottom-of-this-pagespan">One of the supports for the article is &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Appears to be nice petri dish science.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Will be interesting to see if this applies to the human body&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="many-medical-benefits-of-ginger-is-also-at-green-medical-informationhttpwwwgreenmedinfocomsubstancegingertypesummarysortasc---sept-2012">&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/substance/ginger?type=summary&amp;amp;sort=ASC">Many medical benefits of Ginger is also at Green Medical Information&lt;/a> - Sept 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="ginger-better-than-acid-blockers---also-at-green-medical-informationhttpwwwgreenmedinfocomblogcan-ginger-beat-out-multi-billion-dollar-acid-blockers---aug-2012">&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/can-ginger-beat-out-multi-billion-dollar-acid-blockers">Ginger better than acid blockers - also at Green Medical Information&lt;/a> - Aug 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Researchers found that one fraction of ginger exhibited six- to eight-fold better potency over lansoprazole (trade name Prevacid) at inhibiting acid production&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Vitamin D is related to breast cancer racial disparities in the US</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-is-related-to-breast-cancer-racial-disparities-in-the-us.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-is-related-to-breast-cancer-racial-disparities-in-the-us.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Increasing bone mineral density increases breast cancer by at least 2X</title><link>/posts/increasing-bone-mineral-density-increases-breast-cancer-by-at-least-2x.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increasing-bone-mineral-density-increases-breast-cancer-by-at-least-2x.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="osteoporosis-myth-the-dangers-of-high-bone-mineral-densityhttpwwwgreenmedinfocomblogosteoporosis-myth-dangers-high-bone-mineral-densityutm_sourcewwwgreenmedinfocomutm_campaignb739c633e3-greenmedinfoutm_mediumemail-green-med-info">&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/osteoporosis-myth-dangers-high-bone-mineral-density?utm_source=www.GreenMedInfo.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=b739c633e3-Greenmedinfo&amp;amp;utm_medium=email">Osteoporosis Myth: The Dangers of High Bone Mineral Density&lt;/a> Green Med Info&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="the-following-was-clipped-from-the-above-item">The following was clipped from the above item&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of the most important facts about bone mineral density, conspicuously absent from discussion, is that having higher-than-normal bone density in middle-aged and older women actually &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">INCREASES their risk of breast cancer by 200-300%&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> , and this is according to research published in some of the world&amp;rsquo;s most well-respected and authoritative journals, e.g. Lancet, JAMA, NCI. (see citations below).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>County with 20 pcnt higher breast cancer rate has 2X more modified vitamin D receptor</title><link>/posts/county-with-20-pcnt-higher-breast-cancer-rate-has-2x-more-modified-vitamin-d-receptor.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/county-with-20-pcnt-higher-breast-cancer-rate-has-2x-more-modified-vitamin-d-receptor.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Compelling evidence – Breast Cancer and vitamin D – Dissertation</title><link>/posts/compelling-evidence-breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d-dissertation.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/compelling-evidence-breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d-dissertation.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breast Cancer stages and vitamin D levels – 2011</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-stages-and-vitamin-d-levels-2011.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-stages-and-vitamin-d-levels-2011.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breast Cancer reduced 20 percent by just 400 IU of vitamin D plus Calcium – 2011</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-reduced-20-percent-by-just-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-plus-calcium-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-reduced-20-percent-by-just-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-plus-calcium-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-supplements-and-health-outcomes-a-reanalysis-of-the-womens-health-initiative-whi-limited-access-data-set">Calcium and vitamin D supplements and health outcomes: a reanalysis of the Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Initiative (WHI) limited-access data set.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Oct;94(4):1144-9. Epub 2011 Aug 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bolland MJ, Grey A, Gamble GD, Reid IR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand. &lt;a href="mailto:m.bolland@auckland.ac.nz">m.bolland@auckland.ac.nz&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Frequent use of personal, nonprotocol calcium supplements obscured an adverse effect of coadministered calcium and vitamin D (CaD) on cardiovascular risk in the Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Initiative (WHI).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>