<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bone - Health on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/bone---health.html</link><description>Recent content in Bone - Health on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/bone---health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>7 X more likely to get hip fracture if have highest level of vitamin A</title><link>/posts/7-x-more-likely-to-get-hip-fracture-if-have-highest-level-of-vitamin-a.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7-x-more-likely-to-get-hip-fracture-if-have-highest-level-of-vitamin-a.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-retinol-levels-and-the-risk-of-fracture">Serum retinol levels and the risk of fracture.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med. 2003 Jan 23;348(4):287-94.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michaëlsson K, Lithell H, Vessby B, Melhus H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Surgical Sciences, Section of Orthopedics, University Hospital, Uppsala, Sweden. &lt;a href="mailto:karl.michaelsson@surgsci.uu.se">karl.michaelsson@surgsci.uu.se&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Although studies in animals and epidemiologic studies have indicated that a high vitamin A intake is associated with increased bone fragility, no biologic marker of vitamin A status has thus far been used to assess the risk of fractures in humans.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beyond the bone: conference summary</title><link>/posts/beyond-the-bone-conference-summary.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/beyond-the-bone-conference-summary.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-beyond-bone">Vitamin D: beyond bone&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>ANNALS OF THE NEW YORK ACADEMY OF SCIENCES&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sylvia Christakos,1 Martin Hewison,2 David G. Gardner,3 Carol L. Wagner,4 Igor N. Sergeev,5 Erica Rutten,6 Anastassios G. Pittas,7 Ricardo Boland,8 Luigi Ferrucci,9 and Daniel D. Bikle10&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, UMDNJ-New Jersey Medical School, Newark, New Jersey. 2Department of Orthopedic Surgery, The David Geffen School of Medicine at the University of California, Los Angeles, California.3Diabetes Center and Department of Medicine, University of California, San Francisco, California.4Division of Neonatology, Department of Pediatrics, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina. 5Department of Health and Nutritional Sciences, South Dakota State University, Brookings, South Dakota. 6Ciro, Center of Expertise for Chronic Organ Failure, Horn, the Netherlands. 7Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes and Metabolism, Tufts Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts. 8Departamento de Biologla, Bioqulmica, y Farmacia, Universidad Nacional del Sur, Bahia Blanca, Argentina. 9Longitudinal Studies Section, National Institute on Aging, National Institutes of Health, Baltimore, Maryland. 10Departments of Medicine and Dermatology, University of California San Francisco, and VA Medical Center, San Francisco, California&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>22 percent more bone cracking found with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/22-percent-more-bone-cracking-found-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/22-percent-more-bone-cracking-found-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-induces-early-signs-of-aging-in-human-bone-increasing-the-risk-of-fracture">Vitamin D Deficiency Induces Early Signs of Aging in Human Bone, Increasing the Risk of Fracture&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Sci Transl Med 10 July 2013: Vol. 5, Issue 193, p. 193ra88&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Björn Busse 1,2, &lt;a href="mailto:b.busse@uke.uni-hamburg.de">b.busse@uke.uni-hamburg.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hrishikesh A. Bale 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elizabeth A. Zimmermann 1,2,3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brian Panganiban 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Holly D. Barth 2,3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alessandra Carriero 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eik Vettorazzi 4,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Josef Zustin 5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael Hahn 1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joel W. Ager III 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Klaus Püschel 6,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael Amling 1 and&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High-altitude associated with higher vitamin D and better bones (sheep in this case)</title><link>/posts/high-altitude-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-and-better-bones-sheep-in-this-case.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-altitude-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-and-better-bones-sheep-in-this-case.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="influence-of-high-altitude-grazing-on-bone-metabolism-of-growing-sheep">Influence of high-altitude grazing on bone metabolism of growing sheep.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr (Berl). 2013 Feb;97(1):58-66. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Oct 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liesegang A, Hüttenmoser D, Risteli J, Leiber F, Kreuzer M, Wanner M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Animal Nutrition, University of Zurich, Winterthurerstr. 260, Zurich, Switzerland. &lt;a href="mailto:aliese@vetphys.uzh.ch">aliese@vetphys.uzh.ch&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this study was to identify the effect of high alpine grazing, associated with varying pasture grass qualities and more pronounced exercise on typically steep slopes, on bone metabolism by improving bone density and enhancing bone turnover in growing sheep. Twenty-four 5-month-old sheep were randomly assigned to two groups. One group was kept at high altitude (HA; 2000-2200 m a.s.l.) for 3 months, and the other group (C; control) remained in the lowlands (400 m a.s.l.). Both groups were kept in grazing pastures with access to good-quality swards. Before the start of the experiment, blood samples were taken, the sheep were weighed, and the left metatarsus of each animal was analysed by quantitative computer tomography. After 1 month, blood samples were taken and body weight was measured, followed by biweekly sampling. Finally, the animals were slaughtered, and the bones were collected for analysis of various bone parameters. Body weight development did not differ between the groups. Concentrations of 25-OH-Vitamin D, carboxy-terminal telopeptide of type I collagen and activities of bone-specific alkaline phosphatase were always higher in the HA group than in the C group, except on the last two sampling dates. Bone mineral content and density increased in both groups during the experiment, but more intensively in the HA group. In addition, the cortical thickness of the HA group increased. The present study demonstrates an increase in bone turnover and mineral content of the bones of the growing sheep grazing in high alpine pastures. The factors associated with HA grazing, therefore, clearly seem to improve bone composition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20 percent fewer male hip fractures if more Magnesium in the water</title><link>/posts/20-percent-fewer-male-hip-fractures-if-more-magnesium-in-the-water.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/20-percent-fewer-male-hip-fractures-if-more-magnesium-in-the-water.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="nationwide-data-on-municipal-drinking-water-and-hip-fracture">Nationwide data on municipal drinking water and hip fracture:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Could calcium and magnesium be protective? A NOREPOS study&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone, Available online 2 July 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cecilie Dahl a, b, &lt;a href="mailto:Cecilie.Dahl@fhi.no">Cecilie.Dahl@fhi.no&lt;/a>, Anne Johanne Søgaard a, Grethe S. Tel b, Trond Peder Flaten c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dag Hongve d, Tone Kristin Omsland b, e, Kristin Holvik b, Haakon E. Meyer a, e, Geir Aamodt a&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Division of Epidemiology, Norwegian Institute of Public Health, Oslo, Norway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Public Health and Primary Health Care, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Not vitamin D deficient if have normal PTH and BMD</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-not-vitamin-d-deficient-if-have-normal-pth-and-bmd.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-not-vitamin-d-deficient-if-have-normal-pth-and-bmd.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="calcium-homeostasis-and-clinical-or-subclinical-vitamin-d-deficiency---can-a-hypothesis-of-intestinal-calcistat-explain-it-all">Calcium homeostasis, and clinical or subclinical vitamin D deficiency ‰%- Can a hypothesis of &amp;ldquo;intestinal calcistat&amp;rdquo; explain it all?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Med Hypotheses. 2013 May 13. pii: S0306-9877(13)00205-3. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mehy.2013.04.035.">doi: 10.1016/j.mehy.2013.04.035.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Garg MK, Mahalle N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology, Command Hospital (Southern Command), Pune 411040, Maharashtra, India. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:mkgargs@gmail.com">mkgargs@gmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main physiological function of vitamin D is maintenance of calcium homeostasis by its effect on calcium absorption, and bone health in association with parathyroid gland. Vitamin D deficiency (VDD) is defined as serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25OHD) levels &amp;lt;20ng/ml. Vitamin D insufficiency is called when serum 25OHD levels are between 20-29ng/ml, though existence of this entity has been questioned. Do all subjects with VDD have clinical disease according to this definition? Analysis of published studies suggests that calcium absorption in inversely correlated with serum 25OHD levels and calcium intake. We hypothesize that there exist an intestinal calcistat, which controls the calcium absorption independent of PTH levels. It consists of calcium sensing receptor (CaSR) on intestinal brush border, which senses calcium in intestinal cells and vitamin D system in intestinal cells. CaSR dampens the generation of active vitamin D metabolite in intestinal cells and decrease active transcellular calcium transport. It also facilitates passive paracellular diffusion of calcium in intestine. This local adaptation adjusts the fractional calcium absorption according the body requirement. Failure of local adaptation due to decreased calcium intake, decreased supply of 25OHD, mutation in CaSR or vitamin D system decreases systemic calcium levels and systemic adaptations comes into the play. Systemic adaptations consist of rise in PTH and increase in active vitamin D metabolites. These adaptations lead to bone resorption and maintenance of calcium homeostasis. Not all subjects with varying levels of VDD manifest with secondary hyperparathyroidism and decreased in bone mineral density. We suggest that rise in PTH is first indicator of VDD is rise in PTH along with decrease in BMD depending on duration of VDD. Hence, subjects with any degree of VDD with normal PTH and BMD should not be labeled as vitamin D deficient. These subjects can be called subclinical VDD, and further studies are required to assess beneficial effect of vitamin D supplementation in this subset of population. This hypothesis further highlights pitfalls in treatment of hypoparathyroidism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Soy isoflavones synergistically aid vitamin D in building bones</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-soy-isoflavones-synergistically-aid-vitamin-d-in-building-bones.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-soy-isoflavones-synergistically-aid-vitamin-d-in-building-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-interactions-with-soy-isoflavones-on-bone-after-menopause-a-review">Vitamin D interactions with soy isoflavones on bone after menopause: a review.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Park CY, Weaver CM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutrition Science, Purdue University, 700 W State St, West Lafayette, IN 47907, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:cypark@purdue.edu">cypark@purdue.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>There might also be BAD Soy= with Glysophate&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/gmo-soybeans-have-high-levels-of-glyphosate" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: GMO soybeans have high levels of glyphosate – June 2014">GMO soybeans have high levels of glyphosate – June 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/20-x-more-parkinsons-and-100x-more-autism-with-gmo-soy-in-china" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: 20 X more Parkinson's and 100X more Autism with GMO soy in China">20 X more Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s and 100X more Autism with GMO soy in China&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnesium may be more important to kids’ bone health than calcium</title><link>/posts/magnesium-may-be-more-important-to-kids-bone-health-than-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/magnesium-may-be-more-important-to-kids-bone-health-than-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#highlight-dietary-magnesium-intake-but-not-calcium-intake-was-significantly-associated-with-both-total-body-bone-mineral-content-and-density">Highlight: dietary magnesium intake, but not calcium intake, was significantly associated with both total body bone mineral content and density&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#27153-magnesium-but-not-calcium-intake">2715.3 Magnesium, but Not Calcium Intake&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#press-release">Press Release&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="highlight-dietary-magnesium-intake-but-not-calcium-intake-was-significantly-associated-with-both-total-body-bone-mineral-content-and-density">Highlight: dietary magnesium intake, but not calcium intake, was significantly associated with both total body bone mineral content and density&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="27153-magnesium-but-not-calcium-intake">2715.3 Magnesium, but Not Calcium Intake&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Is Significantly Association with Bone Mineral Status in 4 to 8 Year Old Children&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Summary of Vitamin D portion of Bone and Mineral Research Meeting</title><link>/posts/summary-of-vitamin-d-portion-of-bone-and-mineral-research-meeting.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/summary-of-vitamin-d-portion-of-bone-and-mineral-research-meeting.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="meeting-report-from-the-34th-annual-meeting-of-the-american-society-for-bone-and-mineral-research">Meeting report from the 34th Annual Meeting of the American Society for Bone and Mineral Research,&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Minneapolis, MN, USA, 12–15 October 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Report on recent vitamin D research (ASBMR 2012)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IBMS BoneKEy, (2013), 10, Article number: 329; doi:10.1038/bonekey.2013.63; Published online, 10 April 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roger Bouillon&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#meeting-report-from-the-34th-annual-meeting-of-the-american-society-for-bone-and-mineral-research">Meeting report from the 34th Annual Meeting of the American Society for Bone and Mineral Research,&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-and-bone">1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D and bone&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2425-dihydroxyvitamin-d">24,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-the-intestine">Vitamin D and the intestine&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#extra-renal-cyp27b1-expression-and-production-of-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d">Extra renal cyp27b1 expression and production of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#fgf23-and-production-of-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d">FGF23 and production of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#skin-synthesis-of-vitamin-d">Skin synthesis of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-worldwide">Vitamin D status worldwide&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-and-vitamin-d-status">Vitamin D supplementation and vitamin D status&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#intermittent-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-vitamin-d-status">Intermittent high-dose vitamin D supplementation and vitamin D status&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pregnancy-and-second-generation-effects">Pregnancy and second-generation effects&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-muscle-and-falls">Vitamin D supplementation: muscle and falls&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-the-metabolic-syndrome">Vitamin D and the metabolic syndrome&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#assay-methodology-for-vitamin-d-metabolites">Assay methodology for vitamin D metabolites&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references-numbers-are-approximate">References (numbers are approximate)&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ion-line-index-to-abstracts">IOn-line index to abstracts&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-and-bone">1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D and bone&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is well known for its effects on promoting bone mineralization as the primary characteristic of rickets, and osteomalacia refers to decreased mineralization of the bone matrix. However, the direct effects of the vitamin D endocrine system on bone cells need further clarification. Earlier studies revealed that overexpression of VDR in osteoblasts (driven by osteocalcin promoter) increased bone mass and strength.1 Deletion of VDR in osteocytes (using a dmp1 cre system) did not influence bone mass or other parameters of bone metabolism.2 Deletion of VDR in osteoblasts using an osteocalcin cre system, however, increased (&amp;gt;20%) bone mass (total and trabecular femoral bone, mainly by increase in the number of trabeculae) as reported by Anderson et al.3 and by S Kato (presented at the 2012 Endocrine Society Meeting as summarized in Bouillon4). However, the mechanisms involved are not clear, as preliminary data suggested increase bone formation (as reported by Anderson et al.3) and decreased bone resorption in the Japanese osteoblast-selective VDR mice. These observations imply that VDR activation can have beneficial effects (prevent rickets and osteomalacia) but can also impair bone formation or mineralization in case of exposure to very high serum concentrations of 1,25(OH)2D.2, 5 Such negative effects of vitamin D on mineral deposition were also observed by studying the gene expression profile after exposure to 1,25(OH)2D (Pike’s group, as reported in the previous BoneKey Report4) and now in a series of in vitro experiments using osteoblasts from different regions (calvaria and femur). Exposure to 1,25(OH)2D could inhibit mineral deposition in early-stage calvaria-derived osteoblasts, whereas it enhanced mineral deposition in more mature cortical-bone-derived osteoblasts, at least in the presence of high extracellular calcium concentration.6 The direct effects of the vitamin D endocrine system on bone cells were also explored by analyzing mice with transgenic overexpression of cyp27b1 in osteoblasts using an osteocalcin promoter region. At 20 weeks of age, such mice displayed a 10% increase in bone volume as well in the lumbar vertebrae as in the femoral metaphysis.7 This beneficial effect was due to increased bone formation with unaltered bone resorption, indicating a direct bone anabolic effect of locally produced 1,25(OH)2D in osteoblasts. All these new observations indicate that the vitamin D endocrine system has a yin/yang effect on bone: in most circumstances it enhances mineral deposition but in the presence of low calcium supply the vitamin D endocrine system tries to maintain serum calcium homeostasis at the expense of bone (increased resorption and decreased mineralization).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin K-2 (180 ug MK-7) helped both bone density and strength – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k-2-180-ug-mk-7-helped-both-bone-density-and-strength-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k-2-180-ug-mk-7-helped-both-bone-density-and-strength-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="three-year-low-dose-menaquinone-7-supplementation-helps-decrease-bone-loss-in-healthy-postmenopausal-women">Three-year low-dose menaquinone-7 supplementation helps decrease bone loss in healthy postmenopausal women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis International March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. H. J. Knapen, N. E. Drummen, E. Smit, C. Vermeer, E. Theuwissen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have investigated whether low-dose vitamin K2 supplements (menaquinone-7, MK-7) could beneficially affect bone health. Next to an improved vitamin K status, MK-7 supplementation significantly decreased the age-related decline in bone mineral density and bone strength. Low-dose MK-7 supplements may therefore help postmenopausal women prevent bone loss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip bone loss stopped with 1000 IU of vitamin D, while 400 IU similar to placebo – RCT</title><link>/posts/hip-bone-loss-stopped-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-while-400-iu-similar-to-placebo-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-bone-loss-stopped-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-while-400-iu-similar-to-placebo-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hip-bone-loss-is-attenuated-with-1000-iu-but-not-400-iu-daily-vitamin-d3-a-1-year-double-blind-rct-in-postmenopausal-women">Hip bone loss is attenuated with 1000 IU but not 400 IU daily vitamin D3: a 1 year double-blind RCT in postmenopausal women&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Bone and Mineral Research, Vol. 28 Issue 4, DOI: 10.1002/jbmr.1959&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Helen M Macdonald1,‖, &lt;a href="mailto:h.macdonald@abdn.ac.uk">h.macdonald@abdn.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adrian D Wood1,‖,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lorna S Aucott1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alison J Black3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William D Fraser4,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alexandra Mavroeidi2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David M Reid1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karen R Secombes1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William G Simpson5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frank Thies1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Aberdeen, Foresterhill, Aberdeen&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lumbar spinal stenosis pain strongly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/lumbar-spinal-stenosis-pain-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lumbar-spinal-stenosis-pain-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-lumbar-spinal-stenosis-and-its-relationship-with-pain">Prevalence of vitamin d deficiency in patients with lumbar spinal stenosis and its relationship with pain.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pain Physician. 2013 Mar;16(2):165-76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim TH, Lee BH, Lee HM, Lee SH, Park JO, Kim HS, Kim SW, Moon SH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spine Center, Hallym University Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Anyang, Korea; Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Patients with lumbar spinal stenosis (LSS) are at a great risk of a fall and fracture, which vitamin D protects against. Vitamin D deficiency is expected to be highly prevalent in LSS patient, and pain is thought to have a profound effect on vitamin D status by limiting activity and sunlight exposure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low levels of vitamin D prior to spine surgery</title><link>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-prior-to-spine-surgery.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-prior-to-spine-surgery.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="preoperative-vitamin-d-status-of-adults-undergoing-surgical-spinal-fusion">Preoperative Vitamin D Status of Adults Undergoing Surgical Spinal Fusion&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Spine: 15 March 2013 - Volume 38 - Issue 6 - p 507–515&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stoker, Geoffrey E. BS; Buchowski, Jacob M. MD, MS; Bridwell, Keith H. MD; Lenke, Lawrence G. MD; Riew, K. Daniel MD; Zebala, Lukas P. MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Study Design. Retrospective investigation of cross-sectional data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective. To define the prevalence and determinants of preoperative vitamin D deficiency among adults undergoing spinal fusion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>88 percent of Intestinal failures had both low vitamin D and low bone density</title><link>/posts/88-percent-of-intestinal-failures-had-both-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/88-percent-of-intestinal-failures-had-both-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="high-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-osteoporosis-in-out-patients-with-intestinal-failure">High prevalence of vitamin D deficiency and osteoporosis in out-patients with intestinal failure.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clin Nutr. 2013 Feb 21. pii: S0261-5614(13)00051-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnu.2013.02.005">doi: 10.1016/j.clnu.2013.02.005&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ellegård L, Kurlberg G, Bosaeus I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Nutrition, Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Göteborg, Sweden. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:lasse.ellegard@nutrition.gu.se">lasse.ellegard@nutrition.gu.se&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: In intestinal failure, specific nutrient deficiencies especially for fat-soluble vitamins can be expected in addition to energy-protein malnutrition. We report serum levels of fat soluble vitamins, and bone density in out-patients with intestinal failure (IF).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D injections of a total of 1,800,000 IU reduced shinbone tenderness</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-injections-of-a-total-of-1800000-iu-reduced-shinbone-tenderness.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-injections-of-a-total-of-1800000-iu-reduced-shinbone-tenderness.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="tibial-tenderness-identifies-secondary-hyperparathyroidism-responding-to-high-dose-vitamin-d-in-pakistani-women">Tibial Tenderness Identifies Secondary Hyperparathyroidism Responding to High Dose Vitamin D in Pakistani Women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2013 Feb 20:1-20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ali B, Butt A, Fatima A, McDonnell ME, Masud F.; Department of Medicine, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To assess the utility of &lt;strong>anterior tibial tenderness&lt;/strong> (ATT) measured by visual analogue score (VAS) as a clinical diagnostic tool for vitamin D deficiency in a high-risk population of Pakistani women&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: ATT using a VAS was assessed in 75 premenopausal women, ages 17-56 (mean 41.3) with generalized aches and pains and calcium of less than 11.0mg/dl (normal: 8-11) at a tertiary care center in Lahore, Pakistan. This was followed by administration of &lt;strong>1.8 million units of vitamin D3&lt;/strong> in divided doses. ATT, vitamin D and parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels were checked before and after the injections. Correlation between ATT, vitamin D and PTH as well as change in ATT, vitamin D and (PTH) following supplementation was determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hungry bone syndrome post hyperparathyoidism – review</title><link>/posts/hungry-bone-syndrome-post-hyperparathyoidism-review.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hungry-bone-syndrome-post-hyperparathyoidism-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="therapy-of-endocrine-disease-hungry-bone-syndrome-still-a-challenge-in-the-post-operative-management-of-primary-hyperparathyroidism-a-systematic-review-of-the-literature">THERAPY OF ENDOCRINE DISEASE: Hungry bone syndrome: still a challenge in the post-operative management of primary hyperparathyroidism: a systematic review of the literature&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Eur J Endocrinol March 1, 2013 168 R45-R53&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J E Witteveen1, &lt;a href="mailto:j.e.witteveen@lumc.nl">j.e.witteveen@lumc.nl&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S van Thiel1,2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J A Romijn1,3 and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N A T Hamdy1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Endocrinology and Metabolic Diseases, Leiden University Medical Center, Leiden, The Netherlands&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Internal Medicine, Amphia Medical Center, Breda, The Netherlands and&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ankylosing spondylitis and low vitamin D – many studies</title><link>/posts/ankylosing-spondylitis-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ankylosing-spondylitis-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ankylosing-spondylitis--patients-should-increase-vitamin-d-levels---meta-analysis-nov-2022">Ankylosing Spondylitis patients should increase Vitamin D levels - meta-analysis Nov 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ankylosing-spondylitis-is-still-associated-with-low-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-sept-2022">Ankylosing Spondylitis is still associated with low Vitamin D - meta-analysis Sept 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#considering-testing-all-as-patients-for-low-vitamin-d----jan-2017">Considering testing all AS patients for low Vitamin D - Jan 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#patients-with-ankylosing-spondylitis-continue-to-have-low-vitamin-d---march-2021">Patients with Ankylosing Spondylitis continue to have low Vitamin D - March 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#males-with-ankylosing-spondylitis-having-10ng-of-vitamin-d-had-a-22-x-higher-risk-of-dying---may-2020">Males with Ankylosing Spondylitis having &amp;lt;10ng of vitamin D had a 2.2 X higher risk of dying - May 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#as-related-to-low-vitamin-d---sept-2018">AS related to low Vitamin D - Sept 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#higher-vitamin-d-associated-with-less-risk-of-as---span-stylecolorf00review--meta-analysisspan-sept-2014">Higher Vitamin D associated with less risk of AS - &lt;span style="color:#F00;">review &amp;amp; meta-analysis&lt;/span> Sept 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sponsdyloarthritis-is-21-x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficiency---nov-2017">Sponsdyloarthritis is 2.1 X more likely if Vitamin D Deficiency - Nov 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#decreased-plasma-vitamin-d-levels-in-patients-with-undifferentiated-spondyloarthritis-and-ankylosing-spondylitis---2013">Decreased plasma vitamin d levels in patients with undifferentiated spondyloarthritis and ankylosing spondylitis - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#systematic-review-of-association-between-vitamin-d-levels-and-susceptibility-and-disease-activity-of-ankylosing-spondylitis---2014">Systematic review of association between vitamin D levels and susceptibility and disease activity of ankylosing spondylitis - 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#4-out-of-7-studies-found-as-associated-with-low-vitamin-d---july-2014">4 out of 7 studies found AS associated with low vitamin D - July 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="ankylosing-spondylitis--patients-should-increase-vitamin-d-levels---meta-analysis-nov-2022">Ankylosing Spondylitis patients should increase Vitamin D levels - meta-analysis Nov 2022&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Ankylosing spondylitis disease activity and serum vitamin D levels: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone changes during and after pregnancy</title><link>/posts/bone-changes-during-and-after-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-changes-during-and-after-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="changes-in-bone-mineral-density-and-body-composition-during-pregnancy-and-postpartum-a-controlled-cohort-study">Changes in bone mineral density and body composition during pregnancy and postpartum. A controlled cohort study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Apr;23(4):1213-23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-011-1654-6.">doi: 10.1007/s00198-011-1654-6.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 May 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Møller UK, Við Streym S, Mosekilde L, Rejnmark L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Internal Medicine, MEA, Aarhus Sygehus, Aarhus University Hospital, Tage Hansens Gade 2, DK-8000, Aarhus C, Denmark. &lt;a href="mailto:kristine.moller@ki.au.dk">kristine.moller@ki.au.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a controlled cohort study, bone mineral density (BMD) was measured in 153 women pre-pregnancy; during pregnancy; and 0.5, 4, 9, and 19 months postpartum. Seventy-five age-matched controls, without pregnancy plans, were followed in parallel. Pregnancy and breastfeeding cause a reversible bone loss, which, initially, is most pronounced at trabecular sites but also involves cortical sites during prolonged breastfeeding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone health not correlated with Vitamin D level in multiple sclerosis – review</title><link>/posts/bone-health-not-correlated-with-vitamin-d-level-in-multiple-sclerosis-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-health-not-correlated-with-vitamin-d-level-in-multiple-sclerosis-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-health-in-multiple-sclerosis">Bone health in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Dec;22(12):2935-49. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-011-1644-8.">doi: 10.1007/s00198-011-1644-8.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 May 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gibson JC, Summers GD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Level 2, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Royal Derby Hospital, Uttoxeter Road, Derby, DE22 3NE, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:jeremy.gibson@nhs.net">jeremy.gibson@nhs.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People who are disabled with multiple sclerosis (MS) may be at increased risk of osteoporosis. This review discusses issues relevant to bone health in MS and makes practical recommendations regarding prevention and screening for osteoporosis and fracture risk in MS. A search of the literature up until 5 April 2011 was performed using key search terms, and articles pertinent to bone health in MS were analysed. Bone mineral density (BMD) is reduced at the lumbar spine, hip and total body in MS, with the degree of reduction being greatest at the hip. A strong relationship exists between the disability level, measured by the Expanded Disability Status Score, and BMD at the lumbar spine and femoral neck, particularly the latter. The rate of loss of BMD also correlates with the level of disability. Pulsed corticosteroids for acute episodes of MS, even with a high cumulative steroid dose, do not significantly affect BMD, but an effect on fracture risk is yet to be elucidated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D monotherapy for just 3 months did not improve bone turnover</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-monotherapy-for-just-3-months-did-not-improve-bone-turnover.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-monotherapy-for-just-3-months-did-not-improve-bone-turnover.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="bone-turnover-is-not-influenced-by-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-pubertal-healthy-black-and-white-children">Bone turnover is not influenced by serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D in pubertal healthy black and white children.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Bone. 2012 Oct;51(4):795-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bone.2012.06.014.">doi: 10.1016/j.bone.2012.06.014.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jun 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hill KM, Laing EM, Hausman DB, Acton A, Martin BR, McCabe GP, Weaver CM, Lewis RD, Peacock M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indiana University School of Medicine, Department of Medicine, Division of Endocrinology, 541 N. Clinical Drive, Indianapolis, IN 46202-5111, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25 (OH) D]&lt;/span> is common in healthy children particularly in blacks. However, serum 25 (OH) D concentrations for optimal bone turnover in children is unknown and few data exist that describe effects of increasing serum 25 (OH) D on bone turnover markers during puberty. The purpose of this study was to determine the relationships between serum 25 (OH) D and changes in serum 25 (OH) D and bone turnover in white and black pubertal adolescents. Bone turnover markers were measured in 318 healthy boys and girls from Georgia (34°N) and Indiana (40°N) who participated in a study of oral vitamin D(3) supplementation (0 to 4000 IU/d). Serum 25 (OH) D, osteocalcin, bone alkaline phosphatase, and urine N-telopeptide cross-links were measured at baseline and 12 weeks. Relationships among baseline 25 (OH) D and bone biomarkers, and between changes over 12 weeks were determined and tested for effects of race, sex, latitude, and baseline 25 (OH) D. Median 25 (OH) D was 27.6 ng/mL (n=318, range 10.1-46.0 ng/mL) at baseline and &lt;strong>34.5 ng/mL (n=302, range 9.7-95.1 ng/mL)&lt;/strong> at 12 weeks. Neither baseline nor change in 25 (OH) D over 12 weeks was associated with bone turnover. The lack of association was not affected by race, sex, latitude, or baseline serum 25 (OH) D. Serum 25 (OH) D in the range of 10-46 ng/mL appears to be sufficient for normal bone turnover in healthy black and white pubertal adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3D images of bone plus position statements on Osteo and vitamin D – 2012</title><link>/posts/3d-images-of-bone-plus-position-statements-on-osteo-and-vitamin-d-2012.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3d-images-of-bone-plus-position-statements-on-osteo-and-vitamin-d-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The following is a fraction of &lt;strong>The fragile beauty of bone architecture&lt;/strong> published in Medicographia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Louis-Georges STE-MARIE,MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Natalie DION PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre Hospitalier de l’Université de Montréal&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Université de Montréal – Montréal, CANADA&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The full issue of Medicographia, which includes the article: CONTROVERSIAL QUESTION, Is systematic supplementation with calcium/vitamin D necessary to treat postmenopausal osteoporosis? Is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/3d-bone.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h2 id="figure-2-structural-impairment-in-bone-disease">Figure 2. Structural impairment in bone disease.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Undecalcified bone biopsies (3D microcomputed tomography or 2D microscopic histology &lt;span>[Goldner’s stain]&lt;/span>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone fracture healing not a function of vitamin D level</title><link>/posts/bone-fracture-healing-not-a-function-of-vitamin-d-level.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-fracture-healing-not-a-function-of-vitamin-d-level.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-concentration-in-patients-with-normal-and-impaired-bone-union">Vitamin D concentration in patients with normal and impaired bone union.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pol Orthop Traumatol. 2013 Jan 2;78:1-3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boszczyk AM, Zakrzewski P, Pomianowski S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Musculoskeletal Trauma Surgery and Orthopaedics CMKP, Otwock, Poland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: The aim of the study was to compare vitamin D concentration in patients treated due to delayed bone union and non-union (pseudoarthrosis) and patients with normal fracture healing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Material/Methods: A retrospective case-control study was conducted. We enrolled 35 patients with inexplicable (standard and correct surgery, closed fracture, no comorbid metabolic diseases) fracture healing impairment, and 35 patients assigned by age and measurement season. Vitamin D (as 25OHD) concentration was measured in all patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D different relationship between whites and blacks for bone and plaque</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-different-relationship-between-whites-and-blacks-for-bone-and-plaque.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-different-relationship-between-whites-and-blacks-for-bone-and-plaque.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-race-and-genetics-on-vitamin-d-metabolism-bone-and-vascular-health">Effect of race and genetics on vitamin D metabolism, bone and vascular health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Nephrol. 2012 Jun 12;8(8):459-66. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneph.2012.112.">doi: 10.1038/nrneph.2012.112.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Freedman BI, Register TC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Section on Nephrology, Wake Forest School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, NC 27157-1053, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:bfreedma@wakehealth.edu">bfreedma@wakehealth.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pathophysiology of chronic kidney disease-mineral and bone disorder accounts for an inverse relationship between bone mineralization and vascular calcification in progressive nephropathy. Inverse associations between bone mineral density (BMD) and calcified atherosclerotic plaque are also observed in individuals of European and African ancestry without nephropathy, suggesting a mechanistic link between these processes that is independent of kidney disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Healthy bones need Ca, Silicon, Vitamins B, C, D, and K</title><link>/posts/healthy-bones-need-ca-silicon-vitamins-b-c-d-and-k.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/healthy-bones-need-ca-silicon-vitamins-b-c-d-and-k.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Update on nutrients involved in maintaining healthy bone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinol Nutr. 2012 Dec 27. pii: S1575-0922(12)00294-X. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.endonu.2012.09.006.">doi: 10.1016/j.endonu.2012.09.006.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Article in English, Spanish]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rondanelli M, Opizzi A, Perna S, Faliva MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Applied Health Sciences, Section of Human Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Medicine, University of Pavia, Endocrinology and Nutrition Unit, Azienda di Servizi alla Persona di Pavia, Pavia, Italy. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:mariangela.rondanelli@unipv.it">mariangela.rondanelli@unipv.it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis is a leading cause of morbidity and mortality in the elderly and influences quality of life, as well as life expectancy. Currently, there is a growing interest among the medical scientists in search of specific nutrients and/or bioactive compounds of natural origin for the prevention of disease and maintenance of bone health. Although calcium and vitamin D have been the primary focus of nutritional prevention of osteoporosis, a recent research has clarified the importance of several additional nutrients and food constituents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More than Calcium and Vitamin D can improve bones</title><link>/posts/more-than-calcium-and-vitamin-d-can-improve-bones.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-calcium-and-vitamin-d-can-improve-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Skeletal effects of nutrients and nutraceuticals, beyond calcium and vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Nov 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nieves JW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology, Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University, 722 West 168th Street, New York, NY, 10032, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:nievesj@helenhayeshosp.org">nievesj@helenhayeshosp.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a need to understand the role of nutrition, beyond calcium and vitamin D, in the treatment and prevention of osteoporosis in adults. Results regarding soy compounds on bone density and bone turnover are inconclusive perhaps due to differences in dose and composition or in study population characteristics. The skeletal benefit of black cohosh and red clover are unknown. Dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA) use may benefit elderly individuals with low serum dehydroepiandrosterone-sulfate levels, but even in this group, there are inconsistent benefits to bone density (BMD). Higher fruit and vegetable intakes may relate to higher BMD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Strong bones need both physical activity and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/strong-bones-need-both-physical-activity-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/strong-bones-need-both-physical-activity-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-status-and-physical-activity-interact-to-improve-bone-mass-in-adolescents">Vitamin D status and physical activity interact to improve bone mass in adolescents.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="the-helena-study">The HELENA Study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Aug;23(8):2227-37. Epub 2012 Jan 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Valtueña J, Gracia-Marco L, Vicente-Rodríguez G, González-Gross M, Huybrechts I, Rey-López JP, Mouratidou T, Sioen I, Mesana MI, Martínez AE, Widhalm K, Moreno LA; HELENA Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Collaborators (230)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Health and Human Performance, Faculty of Physical Activity and Sport Sciences-INEF, Technical University of Madrid, C/ Martín Fierro 7, Madrid, Spain. &lt;a href="mailto:jara.valtuena@upm.es">jara.valtuena@upm.es&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3, not D2 helps childhood bone development</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-not-d2-helps-childhood-bone-development.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-not-d2-helps-childhood-bone-development.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-levels-are-positively-related-to-subsequent-cortical-bone-development-in-childhood">25-Hydroxyvitamin-D3 levels are positively related to subsequent cortical bone development in childhood:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="findings-from-a-large-prospective-cohort-study">findings from a large prospective cohort study.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Aug;23(8):2117-28. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-011-1813-9.">doi: 10.1007/s00198-011-1813-9.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Nov 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sayers A, Fraser WD, Lawlor DA, Tobias JH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Musculoskeletal Research Unit, School of Clinical Sciences, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:adrian.sayers@bristol.ac.uk">adrian.sayers@bristol.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In exploring relationships between vitamin D status in childhood and cortical bone, little relationship was observed with plasma concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin-D(2) &lt;span>[25(OH)D(2)]&lt;/span>, whereas 25-hydroxyvitamin-D(3) &lt;span>[25(OH)D(3)]&lt;/span> was positively related to cortical bone mineral content (BMC(C)) and cortical thickness, suggesting D(3) exerts a beneficial effect on cortical bone development in contrast to D(2).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sickle cell and low vitamin D – 3 presentations</title><link>/posts/sickle-cell-and-low-vitamin-d-3-presentations.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sickle-cell-and-low-vitamin-d-3-presentations.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>All presented at 2012 American Society of Hematology December 8-11, 2012 Atlanta, GA&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-zinc-deficiency-associated-with-increased-pain-episodes-in-children-with-sickle-cell-disease-poster-abstract-3237">Vitamin D and Zinc Deficiency Associated with Increased Pain Episodes in Children with Sickle Cell Disease: poster, Abstract 3237&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#relationship-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-bone-fragility-in-sickle-cell-disease">Relationship Between vitamin D Deficiency and Bone Fragility in Sickle Cell Disease:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-deficiency-cd40l-and-vegf-in-a-young-population-with-sickle-cell-disease-abstract-4768">Vitamin Deficiency, CD40L and VEGF in a Young Population with Sickle Cell Disease, Abstract 4768&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-zinc-deficiency-associated-with-increased-pain-episodes-in-children-with-sickle-cell-disease-poster-abstract-3237">Vitamin D and Zinc Deficiency Associated with Increased Pain Episodes in Children with Sickle Cell Disease: poster, Abstract 3237&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Abi Vijenthira, BHSc*,1, Christine G Chretien, BSCN*,2, Sydney Harris-Janz, RD*,2 and Robert J Klaassen, MD2&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Relevance of Vitamin D in Bone and Muscle Health of Cancer Patients</title><link>/posts/relevance-of-vitamin-d-in-bone-and-muscle-health-of-cancer-patients.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/relevance-of-vitamin-d-in-bone-and-muscle-health-of-cancer-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.58-64 (7)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author: Heike Bischoff-Ferrari&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer patients with advanced disease frequently feel weak and fatigued, and have an increased risk of fracture. At the same time several reports describe the high prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in these patients. This review will summarize the impact of vitamin D deficiency on muscle weakness and fracture risk. While larger clinical trials of vitamin D supplementation are lacking in cancer patients, the evidence from clinical trials among older adults of the general population support a significant benefit of vitamin D on muscle strength, and fall and fracture reduction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone - Health</title><link>/posts/bone-health.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-health.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#calcium-and-bone-health-supplements-review---including-vit-d-vit-k-mg-and-boron">Calcium and Bone Health Supplements Review - Including Vit D, Vit K, Mg and Boron&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="calcium-and-bone-health-supplements-review---including-vit-d-vit-k-mg-and-boron">Calcium and Bone Health Supplements Review - Including Vit D, Vit K, Mg and Boron&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.consumerlab.com/reviews/bone-supplements-calcium-with-vitamin-d-k-magnesium/calcium/?j=3004340&amp;amp;sfmc_sub=4618332&amp;amp;l=529_HTML&amp;amp;u=31627246&amp;amp;mid=7276525&amp;amp;jb=14001&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=exacttarget&amp;amp;utm_campaign=newsletter&amp;amp;utm_term=&amp;amp;utm_content=vit_d_omega_member_de_send">ConsumerLab&lt;/a> May 2022&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/bone-supplements-cl.jpg" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;p>You can access if you elect to take a one week free trial&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/excellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlab" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Excellent reviews of supplements at ConsumerLab">Excellent reviews of supplements at ConsumerLab&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Previous Review: &lt;a href="/posts/supplement-reviews-by-consumerlab-vitamin-d-magnesium-vitamin-k-calcium-boron" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Supplement reviews by ConsumerLab – Vitamin D, Magnesium, Vitamin K, Calcium , Boron – Nov 2019">Supplement reviews by ConsumerLab – Vitamin D, Magnesium, Vitamin K, Calcium , Boron – Nov 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vertebral fracture 3X more likely with aortic calcification – Vitamins D3 and K2</title><link>/posts/vertebral-fracture-3x-more-likely-with-aortic-calcification-vitamins-d3-and-k2.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vertebral-fracture-3x-more-likely-with-aortic-calcification-vitamins-d3-and-k2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="aortic-calcification-and-bone-metabolism">Aortic Calcification and Bone Metabolism:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="the-relationship-between-aortic-calcification-bmd-vertebral-fracture-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-osteocalcin">The Relationship between Aortic Calcification, BMD, Vertebral Fracture, 25-Hydroxyvitamin D, and Osteocalcin.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Calcif Tissue Int. 2012 Sep 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim KJ, Kim KM, Park KH, Choi HS, Rhee Y, Lee YH, Cha BS, Kim MJ, Oh SM, Brown JK, Lim SK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Department of Internal Medicine, Yonsei University College of Medicine, 134 Shinchon-dong, Seodaemun-gu, Seoul, 120-752, South Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study was to investigate the relationship between aortic calcification (AC) and low bone mineral density (BMD), 25(OH)D, C-terminal telopeptide (CTx), and osteocalcin levels in Asian women. We also tried to find the association between AC and the risk of vertebral fracture. We included 769 patients in this study. All patients underwent QCT. Aortic calcium score (ACS) was quantified by the Agatston scoring method. Spinal fracture was defined by lumbar spine radiography.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increasing bone mineral density increases breast cancer by at least 2X</title><link>/posts/increasing-bone-mineral-density-increases-breast-cancer-by-at-least-2x.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increasing-bone-mineral-density-increases-breast-cancer-by-at-least-2x.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="osteoporosis-myth-the-dangers-of-high-bone-mineral-densityhttpwwwgreenmedinfocomblogosteoporosis-myth-dangers-high-bone-mineral-densityutm_sourcewwwgreenmedinfocomutm_campaignb739c633e3-greenmedinfoutm_mediumemail-green-med-info">&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/osteoporosis-myth-dangers-high-bone-mineral-density?utm_source=www.GreenMedInfo.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=b739c633e3-Greenmedinfo&amp;amp;utm_medium=email">Osteoporosis Myth: The Dangers of High Bone Mineral Density&lt;/a> Green Med Info&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="the-following-was-clipped-from-the-above-item">The following was clipped from the above item&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of the most important facts about bone mineral density, conspicuously absent from discussion, is that having higher-than-normal bone density in middle-aged and older women actually &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">INCREASES their risk of breast cancer by 200-300%&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> , and this is according to research published in some of the world&amp;rsquo;s most well-respected and authoritative journals, e.g. Lancet, JAMA, NCI. (see citations below).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Forearm fracture 3.5X more often in black children with low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/forearm-fracture-35x-more-often-in-black-children-with-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/forearm-fracture-35x-more-often-in-black-children-with-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="bone-mineral-density-and-vitamin-d-status-among-african-american-children-with-forearm-fractures">Bone mineral density and vitamin d status among african american children with forearm fractures.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatrics. 2012 Sep;130(3):e553-60. Epub 2012 Aug 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ryan LM, Teach SJ, Singer SA, Wood R, Freishtat R, Wright JL, McCarter R, Tosi L, Chamberlain JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Children&amp;rsquo;s National Medical Center, Division of Emergency Medicine, 111 Michigan Ave NW, Washington, DC 20010. &lt;a href="mailto:lryan@childrensnational.org">lryan@childrensnational.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine whether African American children with forearm fractures have decreased bone mineral density and an increased prevalence of vitamin D deficiency (serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level ?20 ng/mL) compared with fracture-free control patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Major depression associated with low vitamin D and low bone density</title><link>/posts/major-depression-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/major-depression-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="do-premenopausal-women-with-major-depression-have-low-bone-mineral-density-a-36-month-prospective-study">Do Premenopausal Women with Major Depression Have Low Bone Mineral Density? A 36-Month Prospective Study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(7):e40894. Epub 2012 Jul 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cizza G &lt;a href="mailto:cizzag@intra.niddk.nih.gov">cizzag@intra.niddk.nih.gov&lt;/a>, Mistry S, Nguyen VT, Eskandari F, Martinez P, Torvik S, Reynolds JC, Gold PW, Sinai N, Csako G; for the POWER Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Section on Neuroendocrinology of Obesity, National Institutes of Diabetes and Digestive Kidney Diseases (NIDDK), National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland, United States of America.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone health markers generally not improved by 550 IU of vitamin D after birth</title><link>/posts/bone-health-markers-generally-not-improved-by-550-iu-of-vitamin-d-after-birth.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-health-markers-generally-not-improved-by-550-iu-of-vitamin-d-after-birth.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="impact-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-markers-of-bone-mineral-metabolism-in-term-infants">Impact of vitamin D supplementation on markers of bone mineral metabolism in term infants.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Bone. 2012 Jul 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Czech-Kowalska J, Pludowski P, Dobrzanska A, Kryskiewicz E, Karczmarewicz E, Gruszfeld D, Pleskaczynska A, Golkowska M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neonatology and Neonatal Intensive Care, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Health Institute, 04-730 Warsaw, Al. Dzieci Polskich 20, Poland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) may influence bone turnover. We compared the dynamics of bone markers in 30 infants on vitamin D supplementation (?550IU/d) with different degrees of hypovitaminosis D (25OHD &amp;lt;11ng/ml - deficiency vs. ?11&amp;lt;20ng/ml - insufficiency). Baseline and follow-up (after 10 weeks), 25OHD, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)(2)D), alkaline phosphatase (ALP), PTH, osteocalcin (OC), N-terminal propeptide of type I procollagen (PINP), C-terminal telopeptide of type I collagen (CTX), amino-terminal propeptide of C-type natriuretic peptide (NT-proCNP) were measured. None of the newborns had craniotabes, hypocalcaemia or hyperparathyroidism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fractures reduced 30 percent with 800 IU of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-pooled-analysis-of-vitamin-d-dose-requirements-for-fracture-prevention">A pooled analysis of vitamin D dose requirements for fracture prevention.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med. 2012 Jul 5;367(1):40-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Willett WC, Orav EJ, Lips P, Meunier PJ, Lyons RA, Flicker L, Wark J, Jackson RD, Cauley JA, Meyer HE, Pfeifer M, Sanders KM, Stähelin HB, Theiler R, Dawson-Hughes B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center on Aging and Mobility, University of Zurich and Waid City Hospital, Zurich, Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The results of meta-analyses examining the relationship between vitamin D supplementation and fracture reduction have been inconsistent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Female Athlete health problems may be due to lack of vitamin D and Iron</title><link>/posts/female-athlete-health-problems-may-be-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d-and-iron.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/female-athlete-health-problems-may-be-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d-and-iron.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Healthy bones need: Calcium, Vitamin D, Magnesium, Silicon, Vitamin K, and Boron – 2012</title><link>/posts/healthy-bones-need-calcium-vitamin-d-magnesium-silicon-vitamin-k-and-boron-2012.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/healthy-bones-need-calcium-vitamin-d-magnesium-silicon-vitamin-k-and-boron-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Essential Nutrients for Bone Health and a Review of their Availability in the Average North American Diet.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open Orthop J. 2012;6:143-9&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price CT, Langford JR, Liporace FA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Orlando Health, 1222 Orange Avenue, 5 Floor, Orlando, Florida 32806, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis and low bone mineral density affect millions of Americans. The majority of adults in North America have insufficient intake of vitamin D and calcium along with inadequate exercise. Physicians are aware that vitamin D, calcium and exercise are essential for maintenance of bone health. Physicians are less likely to be aware that dietary insufficiencies of magnesium, silicon, Vitamin K, and boron are also widely prevalent, and each of these essential nutrients is an important contributor to bone health. In addition, specific nutritional factors may improve calcium metabolism and bone formation. It is the authors&amp;rsquo; opinion that nutritional supplements should attempt to provide ample, but not excessive, amounts of factors that are frequently insufficient in the typical American diet.In contrast to dietary insufficiencies, several nutrients that support bone health are readily available in the average American diet. These include zinc, manganese, and copper which may have adverse effects at higher levels of intake. Some multivitamins and bone support products provide additional quantities of nutrients that may be unnecessary or potentially harmful.The purpose of this paper is to identify specific nutritional components of bone health, the effects on bone, the level of availability in the average American diet, and the implications of supplementation for each nutritional component. A summary of recommended dietary supplementation is included.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Osteoanabolics (increase bone mass) with vitamin D etc.</title><link>/posts/osteoanabolics-increase-bone-mass-with-vitamin-d-etc.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/osteoanabolics-increase-bone-mass-with-vitamin-d-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="osteoanabolics">Osteoanabolics&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>REVIEW ARTICLE &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vishal Gupta, Mitul Abhaykumar Shah, Sagar Kirtibhai Shah, Jinen Mukeshbhai Shah&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Medicine, Jaslok Hospital and Research Centre, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indian J Endocr Metab 2012 May 9;16:409-13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence Address: Vishal Gupta&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology, Jaslok Hospital and Research Centre, 15 - Dr. Deshmukh Marg, Pedder Road, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis is characterized by reduced bone mass, impaired bone quality, and a propensity to fracture. An &amp;ldquo;osteoanabolic&amp;rdquo; should be referred to any therapy that helps increase bone mass. Bone mass represents 80% of bone mechanical strength. A low bone mass therefore provides the strongest association of future risk of fracture. This review aims to discuss all available and future therapies that attempt to increase bone mass be it organic or inorganic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sickle Cell Anemia: 64 percent had less than 10ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/sickle-cell-anemia-64-percent-had-less-than-10ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sickle-cell-anemia-64-percent-had-less-than-10ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D: an essential component for skeletal health</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-an-essential-component-for-skeletal-health.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-an-essential-component-for-skeletal-health.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2011 Dec;1240:E1-12. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.2011.06374.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1749-6632.2011.06374.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wimalawansa SJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Metabolism &amp;amp; Nutrition, Department of Medicine, and UMDNJ, Robert Wood Johnson Medical School, Physiology and Integrative Biology, Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, New Brunswick, New Jersey 08903-0019, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:wimalasu@umdnj.edu">wimalasu@umdnj.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is increasing worldwide. Ultraviolet rays are supposed to provide humans over 80% of our vitamin D requirement; the rest is received through diet and supplements. In addition to enhancing calcium absorption from the intestine and mineralization of the osteoid tissue, vitamin D has many other physiological effects, including neuromodulation, improving muscle strength and coordination, insulin release, immunity and prevention of infections, and curtailing cancer. Whether the increased incidence of vitamin D deficiency is related to increased incidences of nonskeletal disorders remains to be determined. Serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> above 30 ng/mL indicate vitamin D sufficiency. An additional 1,000 IU of vitamin D/day is sufficient for most lighter-skinned individuals, whereas an extra 2,000 IU/day is needed by the elderly and dark-skinned individuals to maintain normal 25(OH)D levels. Additional research is needed to clarify the relationship between vitamin D and the nonskeletal systems, nonclassic functions, and targets of vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D did not increase BMD among some ballet dancers</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-did-not-increase-bmd-among-some-ballet-dancers.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-did-not-increase-bmd-among-some-ballet-dancers.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-and-musculoskeletal-health-in-adolescent-male-ballet-dancers-a-pilot-study">Vitamin D status and musculoskeletal health in adolescent male ballet dancers a pilot study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Dance Med Sci. 2011;15(3):99-107.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ducher G, Kukuljan S, Hill B, Garnham AP, Nowson CA, Kimlin MG, Cook J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Noll Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology, Pennsylvania State University, University Park 16802, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:gaele.ducher@hotmail.com">gaele.ducher@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adequate vitamin D levels during growth are critical to ensuring optimal bone development. Vitamin D synthesis requires sun exposure; thus, athletes engaged in indoor activities such as ballet dancing may be at relatively high risk of vitamin D insufficiency. The objective of this study was to investigate the prevalence of low vitamin D levels in young male ballet dancers and its impact on musculoskeletal health. Eighteen male ballet dancers, aged 10 to 19 years and training for at least 6 hours per week, were recruited from the Australian Ballet School, Melbourne, Australia. Serum 25(OH)D and intact PTH were measured in winter (July) from a non-fasting blood sample. Pubertal stage was determined using self-assessed Tanner criteria. Body composition and areal bone mineral density (aBMD) at the whole body and lumbar spine were measured using dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA). Injury history and physical activity levels were assessed by questionnaire. Blood samples were obtained from 16 participants. Serum 25(OH)D levels ranged from 20.8 to 94.3 nmol/L, with a group mean of 50.5 nmol/L. Two participants (12.5%) showed vitamin D deficiency &lt;a href="serum%2025(OH)D%20level%20%3C%2025%20nmol/L">serum 25(OH)D level &amp;lt; 25 nmol/L&lt;/a>, seven dancers (44%) had vitamin D insufficiency (25 to 50 nmol/L), and the remaining seven dancers (44%) had normal levels (&amp;gt; 50 nmol/L).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>6500 IU vitamin D not improve bone density without co-factors</title><link>/posts/6500-iu-vitamin-d-not-improve-bone-density-without-co-factors.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/6500-iu-vitamin-d-not-improve-bone-density-without-co-factors.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Half as many fractures for girls with high vitamin D intake</title><link>/posts/half-as-many-fractures-for-girls-with-high-vitamin-d-intake.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-as-many-fractures-for-girls-with-high-vitamin-d-intake.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-calcium-and-dairy-intakes-and-stress-fractures-among-female-adolescents">Vitamin D, Calcium, and Dairy Intakes and Stress Fractures Among Female Adolescents&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Kendrin R. Sonneville, ScD, RD; Catherine M. Gordon, MD, MSc; Mininder S. Kocher, MD, MPH; Laura M. Pierce, BA; Arun Ramappa, MD; Alison E. Field, ScD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. Published online March 5, 2012. , doi:10.1001/archpediatrics.2012.5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective To identify whether calcium, vitamin D, and/or dairy intakes are prospectively associated with stress fracture risk among female adolescents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Design Prospective cohort study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Too much vitamin D might result in poor bone growth</title><link>/posts/too-much-vitamin-d-might-result-in-poor-bone-growth.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/too-much-vitamin-d-might-result-in-poor-bone-growth.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-dose-125oh2d3-inhibits-osteoblast-mineralization-in-vitro">High dose 1,25(OH)2D3 inhibits osteoblast mineralization in vitro.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int J Mol Med. 2012 Feb 1. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3892/ijmm.2012.900.">doi: 10.3892/ijmm.2012.900.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yamaguchi M, Weitzmann MN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism and Lipids, Department of Medicine, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA 30322, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is essential for optimal calcium absorption needed for maintaining normal bone mineral density (BMD). Consequently, vitamin D-deficiency leads to poorly mineralized bone with diminished strength and load bearing capacity. Surprisingly, several animal and clinical studies have identified suppressive effects of high dose vitamin D supplementation on bone formation. These data suggest that while vitamin D is necessary for basal bone homeostasis, excessive concentrations may be detrimental to the skeleton.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium (alone) does not reduce risk of bone fracture</title><link>/posts/calcium-alone-does-not-reduce-risk-of-bone-fracture.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-alone-does-not-reduce-risk-of-bone-fracture.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D, K2, Magnesium, etc increase bone density when taking together</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-k2-magnesium-etc-increase-bone-density-when-taking-together.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-k2-magnesium-etc-increase-bone-density-when-taking-together.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bone Health and vitamin D book - 2011</title><link>/posts/bone-health-and-vitamin-d-book-2011.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-health-and-vitamin-d-book-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Natural Products: Still More Questions to Be Answered&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(page 283: trace minerals - Vitamin D Wiki believes &lt;a href="/posts/boron" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1084">Boron&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="/posts/silicon" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1506">Silicon&lt;/a> are more important than book states)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vibration-therapy" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1788">Vibration Therapy&lt;/a>: Good, Good, Good, Good Vibrations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(&lt;a href="http://www.henrylahore.com/Health/WBV/index.html">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> to see how to add vibration while doing the dishes)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes increases probability of bone fracture</title><link>/posts/diabetes-increases-probability-of-bone-fracture.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-increases-probability-of-bone-fracture.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="several-articles-on-this-page">Several articles on this page&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="got-the-suggestion-from-a-hrefpoststhe-complete-book-of-bone-health-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-2312the-complete-book-of-bone-healtha---diane-schneider---2011">Got the suggestion from: &lt;a href="/posts/the-complete-book-of-bone-health" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2312">The Complete Book of Bone Health&lt;/a> - Diane Schneider - 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>– – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – –&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="bone-metabolism-and-fracture-risk-in-type-2-diabetes-mellitus-spanreviewspan">Bone metabolism and fracture risk in type 2 diabetes mellitus &lt;span>[Review]&lt;/span>.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocr J. 2011;58(8):613-24. Epub 2011 Jul 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yamaguchi T, Sugimoto T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Internal Medicine 1, Shimane University Faculty of Medicine, Japan. &lt;a href="mailto:yamaguch@med.shimane-u.ac.jp">yamaguch@med.shimane-u.ac.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wonder when the first doctor will be found liable for not providing vitamin D to a patient</title><link>/posts/wonder-when-the-first-doctor-will-be-found-liable-for-not-providing-vitamin-d-to-a-patient.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wonder-when-the-first-doctor-will-be-found-liable-for-not-providing-vitamin-d-to-a-patient.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="go-to-court-not-enough-vitamin-dsunshine-for-the-monkey">Go to court: Not enough vitamin D/sunshine for the monkey&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-birmingham-16169756%20">Stourbridge pair in court for monkey cruelty&lt;/a> BBC Dec 2011&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Monkey had many bone fractures&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Owners got four charges of cruelty under the Animal Welfare Act 2006.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;935&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Owners of some pet reptiles setup UV lamps which their animals can use as they desire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The administrator of this wiki site has setup UV lamp for himself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several friends who have cats have also purchased UV lamps - which their cats enjoy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BONE SPURS not produced if have enough Vitamin D3, Vitamin K2, etc.</title><link>/posts/bone-spurs-not-produced-if-have-enough-vitamin-d3-vitamin-k2-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-spurs-not-produced-if-have-enough-vitamin-d3-vitamin-k2-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-toxicity--bone-spurs-httpwwwlivestrongcomarticle550949-vitamin-d-toxicity-bone-spurs20-at-livestrong">&lt;a href="http://www.livestrong.com/article/550949-vitamin-d-toxicity-bone-spurs/%20">VITAMIN D TOXICITY &amp;amp; BONE SPURS &lt;/a> at Livestrong&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nov 8, 2011 | By Sirah Dubois&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clips from the page&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bone-spurs">BONE SPURS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Bone spurs are abnormal calcifications that occur in places beyond the boundaries of normal bone. Bone spurs commonly form on the heel and around joints such as your knee, shoulder, spine and fingers. Bone spurs cause problems because they interfere with the motion of joints and often physically irritate surrounding connective tissue such as ligaments and tendons. Reduced range of motion, inflammation and pain are common symptoms of bone spurs. Conventional treatment for bone spurs involves surgical removal, but natural remedies attempt to reverse the biochemical or hormonal conditions that caused the spur in hopes your body will naturally dissolve it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinal fusion patients often low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/spinal-fusion-patients-often-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-fusion-patients-often-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="lower-levels-of-vitamin-d-may-put-spinal-fusion-patients-at-risk-study-findshttpwwwjsonlinecomfeatureshealthlower-levels-of-vitamin-d-may-put-spinal-fusion-patients-at-risk-study-finds-133155178html">&lt;a href="http://www.jsonline.com/features/health/lower-levels-of-vitamin-d-may-put-spinal-fusion-patients-at-risk-study-finds-133155178.html">Lower levels of vitamin D may put spinal fusion patients at risk, study finds&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>57% inadequate (&amp;lt; 30 ng)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>27% deficient (20 ng)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4% severe deficient (&amp;lt; 10 ng)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The paper, presented Thursday at the North American Spine Society annual meeting,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Buchowski said the idea of checking vitamin D levels of patients first occurred to him in 2008.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A woman in her 40s who had undergone cervical fusion surgery and did not get an adequate fusion told him that she had been treated for a vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is the first of three ways to make unbreakable bones</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-the-first-of-three-ways-to-make-unbreakable-bones.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-the-first-of-three-ways-to-make-unbreakable-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="three-steps-to-unbreakable-bones-on-world-osteoporosis-day">Three steps to unbreakable bones on World Osteoporosis Day&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For this year&amp;rsquo;s World Osteoporosis Day (October 20), the International Osteoporosis Foundation (IOF) is releasing a 24-page report promoting a three-step strategy for healthy bones and strong muscles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Professor Heike Bischoff-Ferrari, director Centre on Aging and Mobility at the University of Zurich/Waid City Hospital and author of the report, stated,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Put simply, no matter how old you are, you can optimize your bone health by following three essential steps.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black seniors near equator: increased vitamin D decreases bone density</title><link>/posts/black-seniors-near-equator-increased-vitamin-d-decreases-bone-density.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-seniors-near-equator-increased-vitamin-d-decreases-bone-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-association-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-with-indicators-of-bone-quality-in-men-of-caucasian-and-african-ancestry">The association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D with indicators of bone quality in men of Caucasian and African ancestry.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Sep;22(9):2475-85. Epub 2010 Nov 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbour KE, Zmuda JM, Horwitz MJ, Strotmeyer ES, Boudreau R, Evans RW, Ensrud KE, Gordon CL, Petit MA, Patrick AL, Cauley JA; Osteoporotic Fractures in Men (MrOS) Research Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology, Graduate School of Public Health, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:barbourk@edc.pitt.edu">barbourk@edc.pitt.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We examined the association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> with indices of bone quality in older men. Positive associations for 25(OH)D and bone mineral density, content, cortical thickness, and axial and polar strength strain indices were observed among Caucasians; however, among men of African descent findings were either null or negative.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D history back to Egyptians and fortification</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-history-back-to-egyptians-and-fortification.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-history-back-to-egyptians-and-fortification.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="world-nutrition-journal-of-the-world-public-health-nutrition-association-wwwwphnaorg-volume-2-number-7-august-2011">World Nutrition. Journal of the World Public Health Nutrition Association, &lt;a href="https://www.wphna.org">www.wphna.org&lt;/a> Volume 2, Number 7, August 2011&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/11-08-pdf-wn2-vitamin-d-fortification-editorial-gone.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of the World Public Health Nutrition Association Published monthly at &lt;a href="https://www.wphna.org">www.wphna.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Association is an affiliated body of the International Union of Nutritional Sciences&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For membership andfor other contributions, news, columns and services, go to: &lt;a href="https://www.wphna.org">www.wphna.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="editorial-things-may-not-be-what-they-seem">Editorial Things may not be what they seem&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Bangladeshi children with rickets (left), and prevention and cure for rickets with cod-liver oil or with sun-rays (right). The sun itself is the best remedy&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>14000 IU vitamin D (50000 twice a week) often stops Sickle Cell pain</title><link>/posts/14000-iu-vitamin-d-50000-twice-a-week-often-stops-sickle-cell-pain.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/14000-iu-vitamin-d-50000-twice-a-week-often-stops-sickle-cell-pain.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="several-items-on-this-page">Several items on this page&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - &lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="can-sometimes-stop-sickle-cell-pain-with-vitamin-d---oct-2011">Can sometimes stop sickle cell pain with vitamin D - Oct 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="complete-resolution-of-sickle-cell-chronic-pain-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-therapy">Complete Resolution of Sickle Cell Chronic Pain With High Dose Vitamin D Therapy:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A Case Report and Review of the Literature&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Pediatric Hematology/Oncology: October 2011 - Volume 33 - Issue 7 - p 549–551, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/MPH.0b013e31821ed3ea">doi: 10.1097/MPH.0b013e31821ed3ea&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Forum on Aging and Skeletal Health</title><link>/posts/forum-on-aging-and-skeletal-health.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/forum-on-aging-and-skeletal-health.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Forum on aging and skeletal health: Summary of the proceedings of an ASBMR workshop&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sundeep Khosla1, &lt;a href="mailto:khosla.sundeep@mayo.edu">khosla.sundeep@mayo.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Teresita M Bellido2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marc K Drezner3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Catherine M Gordon4,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tamara B Harris5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Douglas P Kiel6,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara E Kream7,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meryl S LeBoff8,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jane B Lian9,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charlotte A Peterson10,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clifford J Rosen11,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John P Williams12,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karen K Winer13,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sherry S Sherman14, &lt;a href="mailto:shermans@nia.nih.gov">shermans@nia.nih.gov&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 College of Medicine, Mayo Clinic&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Indiana University School of Medicine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 University of Wisconsin–Madison&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Allergies and bone health may be connected by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/allergies-and-bone-health-may-be-connected-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/allergies-and-bone-health-may-be-connected-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="allergy-and-the-bone-unexpected-relationships">Allergy and the bone: unexpected relationships.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2011 Sep;107(3):202-6. Epub 2011 May 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gatti D, Senna G, Viapiana O, Rossini M, Passalacqua G, Adami S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatologic Department, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To examine the relationships between allergy and bone metabolism as represented by the effects of antihistamines and leukotriene modifiers on bone resorption and formation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DATA SOURCES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The major databases MEDLINE and Scopus were searched using the keywords bone metabolism, bone resorption, bone formation, antihistamines, h1 antagonist, leukotriene antagonist, and leukotriene modifier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Military in hot climates and vitamin D deficiency - 2010</title><link>/posts/military-in-hot-climates-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2010.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/military-in-hot-climates-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2010.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin K1 reduced hip fracture but Vitamin K2 did not</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k1-reduced-hip-fracture-but-vitamin-k2-did-not.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k1-reduced-hip-fracture-but-vitamin-k2-did-not.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="intake-of-vitamin-k1-and-k2-and-risk-of-hip-fractures-the-hordaland-health-study">Intake of vitamin K1 and K2 and risk of hip fractures: The Hordaland Health Study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ellen M. Apalset a,b &lt;a href="mailto:ellen.apalset@isf.uib.no">ellen.apalset@isf.uib.no&lt;/a>; Clara G. Gjesdal b, c, Geir E. Eide a, d, and Grethe S. Tell a,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Public Health and Primary Health Care, University of Bergen, Kalfarveien 31, N-5018 Bergen, Norway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Rheumatology, Haukeland University Hospital, N-5021 Bergen, Norway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c Section of Rheumatology, Institute of Medicine, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cadavers with good skeletons had 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cadavers-with-good-skeletons-had-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cadavers-with-good-skeletons-had-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-mineralization-defects-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-histomorphometric-analysis-of-iliac-crest-bone-biopsies-and-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-675-patients">Bone mineralization defects and vitamin D deficiency: histomorphometric analysis of iliac crest bone biopsies and circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D in 675 patients.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2010 Feb;25(2):305-12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Priemel M, von Domarus C, Klatte TO, Kessler S, Schlie J, Meier S, Proksch N, Pastor F, Netter C, Streichert T, Püschel K, Amling M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Osteology and Biomechanics, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parathyroid hormone (PTH) is only one measurable index of skeletal health, and we reasoned that a histomorphometric analysis of iliac crest biopsies would be another and even more direct approach to assess bone health and address the required minimum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> level. A cohort from the northern European population with its known high prevalence of vitamin D deficiency therefore would be ideal to answer the latter question.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mastocytosis and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mastocytosis-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mastocytosis-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bone-mineral-density-bone-turnover-markers-and-fractures-in-patients-with-indolent-systemic-mastocytosis---2011">Bone mineral density, bone turnover markers and fractures in patients with indolent systemic mastocytosis - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mastocytosis-society-survey-of-supplementation---2018">Mastocytosis Society Survey of supplementation - 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#web">Web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="bone-mineral-density-bone-turnover-markers-and-fractures-in-patients-with-indolent-systemic-mastocytosis---2011">Bone mineral density, bone turnover markers and fractures in patients with indolent systemic mastocytosis - 2011&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Maurizio Rossinia, b, low asterisk, E-mail The Corresponding Author, Roberta Zanottib, c, Patrizia Bonadonnab, d, Anna Artusob, c, Beatrice Carusob, e, Donatella Schenab, f, Decio Vecchiatoa, b, Massimiliano Bonifaciob, c, Ombretta Viapianaa, b, Davide Gattia, b, Gianenrico Sennab, d, Annamaria Ricciog, Giovanni Passalacquag, Giovanni Pizzolob, c and Silvano Adamia, b&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone marrow transplant – like other traumas – lowers vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/bone-marrow-transplant-like-other-traumas-lowers-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-marrow-transplant-like-other-traumas-lowers-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="decreased-bone-mineral-density-in-young-adults-treated-with-sct-in-childhood-the-role-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d">Decreased bone mineral density in young adults treated with SCT in childhood: the role of 25-hydroxyvitamin D.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bone Marrow Transplant. 2011 Jul 18. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/bmt.2011.147.">doi: 10.1038/bmt.2011.147.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frisk P, Arvidson J, Ljunggren O, Gustafsson J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Women&amp;rsquo;s and Children&amp;rsquo;s Health, Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We measured bone mineral density (BMD) with dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry in the total body, at the lumbar spine, at the femoral neck and in the total hip, in 18 young adults with a median of 18.2 years after SCT. Fifteen patients had undergone auto-SCT and all patients had received TBI. The patients had significantly lower BMD in the total body, at the femoral neck, and in the total hip compared with age- and sex-matched controls.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IoM error: 8 percent, not just 1 percent, had bone loss when vitamin D higher than 20 ng</title><link>/posts/iom-error-8-percent-not-just-1-percent-had-bone-loss-when-vitamin-d-higher-than-20-ng.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/iom-error-8-percent-not-just-1-percent-had-bone-loss-when-vitamin-d-higher-than-20-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="from-nature-magazine-july-2011httpwwwnaturecomnews2011110706full475023ahtml">&lt;a href="http://www.nature.com/news/2011/110706/full/475023a.html">From Nature Magazine July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/nature-july-2011.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="8-not-1-of-the-people-has-20-ngml-had-bone-loss-so-the-20ngml-voted-level-was-incorrect">8%, not 1% of the people has &amp;gt;20 ng/ml had bone loss, so the 20ng/ml voted level was incorrect&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>hashed lines and &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">red &lt;/span>&lt;/strong> were added by VitaminDWiki&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="in-addition-there-are-many-non-bone-for-diseases-that-vitamin-d-has-been-span-stylecolorf33patented-spanfor">In addition, there are many non-bone for diseases that vitamin D has been &lt;span style="color:#F33;">patented &lt;/span>for&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Breast and many other cancers,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Obesity,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fall prevention,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Stroke and other Cardiovascular,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Immune system,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>wounds and reduce scars,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Whole Body Vibration for an 8 week Random Controlled Trial helped bone</title><link>/posts/whole-body-vibration-for-an-8-week-random-controlled-trial-helped-bone.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/whole-body-vibration-for-an-8-week-random-controlled-trial-helped-bone.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="a-randomized-controlled-trial-of-whole-body-vibration-exposure-on-markers-of-bone-turnover-in-postmenopausal-women">A Randomized Controlled Trial of Whole Body Vibration Exposure on Markers of Bone Turnover in Postmenopausal Women&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Osteoporosis, Volume 2011 (2011), Article ID 710387, 10 pages&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doi:10.4061/2011/710387, Research Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah Turner,1 Margaret Torode,1 Mike Climstein,2 Geraldine Naughton,2,3 David Greene,2 Michael K. Baker,1,4,5 and Maria A. Fiatarone Singh1,5,6,7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Exercise, Health and Performance Faculty Research Group, Faculty of Health Sciences, The University of Sydney, Lidcombe, NSW 1825, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2School of Exercise Science, Australian Catholic University, Strathfield, NSW 2135, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perhaps Stress fractures 2X less frequent if 4000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/perhaps-stress-fractures-2x-less-frequent-if-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/perhaps-stress-fractures-2x-less-frequent-if-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-is-associated-with-low-incidence-of-stress-fractures">High serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D is associated with low incidence of stress fractures.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2011 Jun 22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jbmr.451.">doi: 10.1002/jbmr.451.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burgi AA, Gorham ED, Garland CF, Mohr SB, Garland FC, Zeng K, Thompson K, Lappe JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Naval Health Research Center, San Diego, California.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations are associated with hip fractures, but the dose-response relationship of serum 25(OH)D with risk of stress fractures in young women is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5X fewer hip fractures from Parkinson – Alzheimer – Stroke with enough sun</title><link>/posts/5x-fewer-hip-fractures-from-parkinson-alzheimer-stroke-with-enough-sun.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5x-fewer-hip-fractures-from-parkinson-alzheimer-stroke-with-enough-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sunlight-exposure-is-important-for-preventing-hip-fractures-in-patients-with-alzheimers-disease-parkinsons-disease-or-stroke">Sunlight exposure is important for preventing hip fractures in patients with Alzheimer’s disease, Parkinson’s disease, or stroke&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Neurologica Scandinavica, Article first published online: 18 JUN 2011; DOI: 10.1111/j.1600-0404.2011.01555.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. Iwamoto, T. Takeda, H. Matsumoto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives?–? Hypovitaminosis D as a result of malnutrition or sunlight deprivation, increased bone resorption, low bone mineral density (BMD), or an increased risk of falls may contribute to an increased risk of hip fractures in patients with neurological diseases, including Alzheimer’s disease, Parkinson’s disease, and stroke. The purpose of this study was to clarify the efficacy of sunlight exposure for reducing the risk of hip fractures in patients with such neurological diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less than 20 ng of vitamin D associated with lumbar spine density in Saudi men</title><link>/posts/less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-lumbar-spine-density-in-saudi-men.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-lumbar-spine-density-in-saudi-men.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="high-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-among-healthy-saudi-arabian-men-relationship-to-bone-mineral-density-parathyroid-hormone-bone-turnover-markers-and-lifestyle-factors">High prevalence of vitamin D deficiency among healthy Saudi Arabian men: relationship to bone mineral density, parathyroid hormone, bone turnover markers, and lifestyle factors.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Apr 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ardawi MS, Sibiany AM, Bakhsh TM, Qari MH, Maimani AA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center of Excellence for Osteoporosis Research, King Abdulaziz University, P.O. Box 20724, Jeddah, 21465, Saudi Arabia, &lt;a href="mailto:ardawims@yahoo.com">ardawims@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this cross-sectional study, the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency &lt;a href="serum%2025-hydroxyvitamin%20D%20(25(OH)D)%20%3C50%20nmol/L">serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) &amp;lt;50 nmol/L&lt;/a> was 87.8% among Saudi Arabian men. There was a linear inverse relationship between serum 25(OH)D and intact parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels, but without a threshold of 25(OH)D at which intact PTH values plateaued.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fracture patients had only 16 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hip-fracture-patients-had-only-16-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fracture-patients-had-only-16-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-in-hip-and-spine-fracture-patients-in-japan">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status in hip and spine-fracture patients in Japan.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Orthop Sci. 2011 May 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sakuma M, Endo N, Hagino H, Harada A, Matsui Y, Nakano T, Nakamura K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Medical Technology, Niigata University of Health and Welfare, Niigata, Japan, &lt;a href="mailto:m-sakuma@nuhw.ac.jp">m-sakuma@nuhw.ac.jp&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) is used as an index that reflects the level of vitamin D. We have previously reported, on the basis of a study in Sado in Niigata, that patients with hip fracture have lower serum 25(OH)D levels than non-hip-fracture cases. In this study, the serum 25(OH)D status in hip-fracture cases was examined in four regions in Japan. Although most hip-fracture patients have experienced past spine-compression fractures, the relationship of these fractures and 25(OH)D is unknown. Therefore, we also examined the 25(OH)D level in spine-compression fracture patients in the same locations and time periods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reduced vitamin D and BMD and Neurological Conditions</title><link>/posts/reduced-vitamin-d-and-bmd-and-neurological-conditions.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reduced-vitamin-d-and-bmd-and-neurological-conditions.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-mineral-density-in-adults-disabled-through-acquired-neurological-conditions-a-review">Bone Mineral Density in Adults Disabled Through Acquired Neurological Conditions: A Review&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Densitometry&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 14, Issue 2 , Pages 85-94, April 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone Mineral Density in Adults Disabled Through Acquired Neurological Conditions: A Review&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Áine Carroll&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 10 June 2010; received in revised form 12 December 2010; accepted 13 December 2010. published online 07 April 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article is a review of the changes in bone mineral density (BMD), which occur in a number of acquired neurological conditions resulting in disability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skeletal health needs at least 30 ng of vitamin D – German paper</title><link>/posts/skeletal-health-needs-at-least-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-german-paper.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skeletal-health-needs-at-least-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-german-paper.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-much-vitamin-d-do-we-need-for-skeletal-health">How Much Vitamin D Do We Need for Skeletal Health?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2011 Mar 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>von Domarus C, Brown J, Barvencik F, Amling M, Pogoda P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Osteology and Biomechanics, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Martinistrasse 52, 20246, Hamburg, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D is critical for musculoskeletal health and has been implicated in the risk of extraskeletal diseases, including cancer, cardiovascular diseases, and autoimmune diseases, as well as overall mortality. Although numerous studies deal and have dealt with vitamin D deficiency and its consequences, experts cannot agree on the right 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels. This survey aims to shed light on the ongoing vitamin D controversy from different angles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMD improved with 800 mg Calcium, 400 IU of vitamin D, and 100 ug of vitamin K</title><link>/posts/bmd-improved-with-800-mg-calcium-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-100-ug-of-vitamin-k.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bmd-improved-with-800-mg-calcium-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-100-ug-of-vitamin-k.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="possible-site-specific-effect-of-an-intervention-combining-nutrition-and-lifestyle-counselling-with-consumption-of-fortified-dairy-products-on-bone-mass-the-postmenopausal-health-study-ii">Possible site-specific effect of an intervention combining nutrition and lifestyle counselling with consumption of fortified dairy products on bone mass: the Postmenopausal Health Study II.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Bone Miner Metab. 2011 Apr 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moschonis G, Kanellakis S, Papaioannou N, Schaafsma A, Manios Y.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Harokopio University of Athens, 70, El.Venizelou Ave, Kallithea, 176 71, Athens, Greece, &lt;a href="mailto:gmoschi@hua.gr">gmoschi@hua.gr&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of the present study was to examine whether a holistic approach combining nutrition and lifestyle counselling with the consumption of milk and yoghurt enriched with calcium, vitamin D(3) and phylloquinone (vitamin K(1)) or menaquinone (vitamin K(2)) would have any additional benefit on bone mineral density (BMD) indices measured at various skeletal sites using two different techniques, dual energy X-ray absorptiometry and quantitative ultrasonography (QUS). A sample of 115 postmenopausal women were randomized to three intervention groups, receiving daily via fortified milk and yoghurt and for &lt;strong>12 months&lt;/strong> ,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMD associated with free and bioavailable vitamin D</title><link>/posts/bmd-associated-with-free-and-bioavailable-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bmd-associated-with-free-and-bioavailable-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-binding-protein-modifies-the-vitamin-d-bone-mineral-density-relationship">Vitamin D binding protein modifies the vitamin D-bone mineral density relationship.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2011 Mar 17. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jbmr.387.">doi: 10.1002/jbmr.387.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Powe CE, Ricciardi C, Berg AH, Erdenesanaa D, Collerone G, Ankers E, Wenger J, Karumanchi SA, Thadhani R, Bhan I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, Massachusetts General Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Studies examining the relationship between total circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels and bone mineral density (BMD) have yielded mixed results. Vitamin D binding protein (DBP), the major carrier protein for 25(OH)D, may alter the biologic activity of circulating vitamin D. We hypothesized that free and bioavailable 25(OH)D, calculated from total 25(OH)D, DBP and serum albumin levels, would be more strongly associated with BMD than levels of total 25(OH)D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hardly any children had enough vitamin D before bone surgery</title><link>/posts/hardly-any-children-had-enough-vitamin-d-before-bone-surgery.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hardly-any-children-had-enough-vitamin-d-before-bone-surgery.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin K2 from natto improved bone mineral density</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k2-from-natto-improved-bone-mineral-density.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k2-from-natto-improved-bone-mineral-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="association-between-vitamin-k-intake-from-fermented-soybeans-natto-and-bone-mineral-density-in-elderly-japanese-men-the-fujiwara-kyo-osteoporosis-risk-in-men-formen-study">Association between vitamin K intake from fermented soybeans, natto, and bone mineral density in elderly Japanese men: the Fujiwara-kyo Osteoporosis Risk in Men (FORMEN) study&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis International; DOI: 10.1007/s00198-011-1594-1Online First™&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Y. Fujita, M. Iki, J. Tamaki, K. Kouda, A. Yura, E. Kadowaki, Y. Sato, J.-S. Moon, K. Tomioka and N. Okamoto, et al.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summary&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A cross-sectional analysis of 1,662 community dwelling elderly Japanese men suggested that habitual natto intake was significantly associated with higher bone mineral density (BMD). When adjustment was made for undercarboxylated osteocalcin levels, this association was insignificant, showing the natto–bone association to be primarily mediated by vitamin K.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Women with hip fractures very low on vitamins D3 and K</title><link>/posts/women-with-hip-fractures-very-low-on-vitamins-d3-and-k.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-with-hip-fractures-very-low-on-vitamins-d3-and-k.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-prevalence-of-hypovitaminosis-d-and-k-in-patients-with-hip-fracture">High prevalence of hypovitaminosis D and K in patients with hip fracture.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Asia Pac J Clin Nutr. 2011;20(1):56-61.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nakano T, Tsugawa N, Kuwabara A, Kamao M, Tanaka K, Okano T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Health and Nutrition, Osaka Shoin Women&amp;rsquo;s University, 4-2-26 Hishiyanishi, Higashiosaka-shi, Osaka 577-8550 Japan. &lt;a href="mailto:kuwabara.akiko@osaka-shoin.ac.jp">kuwabara.akiko@osaka-shoin.ac.jp&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although hip fracture is considered to be associated with hypovitaminosis D and K, few reports have previously studied both of them. We have studied the vitamin D- and K-status as well as the general nutritional status in ninety-nine patients with hip fracture. Mean serum concentration of 25hydroxy-vitamin D (25OH-D) in female fractured patients was only approximately &lt;strong>9 ng/mL&lt;/strong> , suggesting severe vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shin splints decrease with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/shin-splints-decrease-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shin-splints-decrease-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-may-both-prevent-and-treat-shin-splints">Vitamin D may both prevent and treat shin splints.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has been proven to prevent bone stress fractures and micro cracks.&lt;br>
Vitamin D appears to substantially prevent and treat shin splints, which is a closely related bone problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Google Search below&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Papers attached to the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="wikipedia-provided-alternate-terms-to-searchfor">Wikipedia provided alternate terms to search for&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The most common sources of shin splints are tendinitis, periostitis, stress fractures, and compartment syndrome.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>400 IU of vitamin D Magnesium and Calcium helped Twin bones</title><link>/posts/400-iu-of-vitamin-d-magnesium-and-calcium-helped-twin-bones.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/400-iu-of-vitamin-d-magnesium-and-calcium-helped-twin-bones.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wrist fracture is also associated with vitamin D inadequacy</title><link>/posts/wrist-fracture-is-also-associated-with-vitamin-d-inadequacy.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wrist-fracture-is-also-associated-with-vitamin-d-inadequacy.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="two-items-on-this-page">two items on this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="44-percent-of-postmenopausal-wrist-fractures-had-low-vitamin-d--sept-2011">44 percent of postmenopausal wrist fractures had low vitamin D – Sept 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="from-american-society-for-bone-and-mineral-research-httpwwwasbmrorgitinerarypresentationdetailaspxidfcdadcdd-9898-4825-81be-b13d1e13aed020">From &lt;a href="http://www.asbmr.org/Itinerary/PresentationDetail.aspx?id=fcdadcdd-9898-4825-81be-b13d1e13aed0%20">American Society for Bone and Mineral Research &lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-postmenopausal-women-with-a-distal-radius-fracture">Hypovitaminosis D in Postmenopausal Women with a Distal Radius Fracture&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Poster Sessions, Presentation Number: SU0377&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presenting Author(s): Hyun Sik Gong, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, ROK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>September 18, 2011 11:00 AM — 1:00 PM; San Diego Convention Center, Hall GH&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(later presented at presented at the 2012 Annual Meeting of the American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons (AAOS).)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>200 to 2000 IU vitamin D daily did not improve child bone density – BMJ</title><link>/posts/200-to-2000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-did-not-improve-child-bone-density-bmj.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/200-to-2000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-did-not-improve-child-bone-density-bmj.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-bone-density-in-healthy-children-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Effects of vitamin D supplementation on bone density in healthy children: systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>BMJ 2011; 2011; 342:c7254 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.c7254">doi: 10.1136/bmj.c7254&lt;/a> (Published 25 January 2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tania Winzenberg, senior research fellow in general practice1, &lt;a href="mailto:tania.winzenberg@utas.edu.au">tania.winzenberg@utas.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sandi Powell, endocrinologist2,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kelly Anne Shaw, honorary associate and postdoctoral fellow13,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Graeme Jones, head of musculoskeletal unit1&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Author Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>1Menzies Research Institute, University of Tasmania, Private Bag 23, Hobart, TAS 7000, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Royal Hobart Hospital, Liverpool St Hobart, Tasmania&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding a little vitamin D for 3 months did not help bones of healthy children</title><link>/posts/adding-a-little-vitamin-d-for-3-months-did-not-help-bones-of-healthy-children.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adding-a-little-vitamin-d-for-3-months-did-not-help-bones-of-healthy-children.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-bone-density-in-healthy-children-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Effects of vitamin D supplementation on bone density in healthy children: systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tania Winzenberg, senior research fellow in general practice1,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sandi Powell, endocrinologist2,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kelly Anne Shaw, honorary associate and postdoctoral fellow13,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Graeme Jones, head of musculoskeletal unit1&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Author Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>1.Menzies Research Institute, University of Tasmania, Private Bag 23, Hobart, TAS 7000, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2.Royal Hobart Hospital, Liverpool St Hobart, Tasmania&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3.ASLaRC Aged Services Unit, Southern Cross University, Coffs Harbour, Queensland Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Fractures and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-fractures-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-fractures-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/09/27/well/live/broken-bone-fracture-risk.html">&amp;quot;..only 9 percent of Medicare patients who sustained a hip or spinal fracture were tested for bone loss and offered treatment to head off a future fracture.&amp;quot;&lt;/a> NYT Sept 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Hip Fractures in Older Adults - JAMA 2019&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most estimates of risk of elderly fracture do not consider the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>    falls, cognitive impairment, urinary incontinence, neurological conditions, and medications&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Continues to recommend Vitamin D sufficiency (&amp;gt;30ng?)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/hip-fractures-in-older-adults-in-2019.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Osteoporosis and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-osteoporosis-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-osteoporosis-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bone-density-decreases-with-age">Bone Density decreases with age&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also--osteoporosis-studiescomhttposteoporosis-studiescom">See also &lt;a href="http://osteoporosis-studies.com/">Osteoporosis-studies.com&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also Web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#most-of-the-nih-article-in-jan-2011httpwwwnlmnihgovmedlineplusmagazineissueswinter11articleswinter11pg15html-was-mainly-on-exercise-to-reduce-osteoporosis">&lt;a href="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/magazine/issues/winter11/articles/winter11pg15.html">Most of the NIH article in Jan 2011&lt;/a> was mainly on exercise to reduce osteoporosis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-was-barely-mentioned">Vitamin D was barely mentioned&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-with-or-without-fosamax-is-highly-rated-to-treat-osteoporosis-at-rate-a-drughttpwwwrateadrugcomvitamin-d-side-effectsaspx-july-2011">Vitamin D, with or without Fosamax, is highly rated to TREAT Osteoporosis at &lt;a href="http://www.rateadrug.com/vitamin-d-side-effects.aspx">Rate A Drug&lt;/a> July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hypothesis-moderate-osteoporosis-itself-is-beneficial-for-bones---oct-2019">Hypothesis: Moderate osteoporosis itself is beneficial for bones - Oct 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#admin-of-vitamindwiki-put-together-a-page-on-strong-bones-in-2008-before-learning-about-vitamin-d">Admin of VitaminDWiki put together a page on Strong Bones in 2008 before learning about vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-bone-fractures" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1344">Overview - Bone Fractures&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>800 IU vitamin D in milk did not improve bones of middle-aged adults</title><link>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-in-milk-did-not-improve-bones-of-middle-aged-adults.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-in-milk-did-not-improve-bones-of-middle-aged-adults.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="independent-and-combined-effects-of-calcium-vitamin-d3-and-exercise-on-bone-structure-and-strength-in-older-men-an-18-month-factorial-design-randomized-controlled-trial">Independent and Combined Effects of Calcium-Vitamin D3 and Exercise on Bone Structure and Strength in Older Men: An 18-Month Factorial Design Randomized Controlled Trial&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism , doi:10.1210/jc.2010-2284&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Submitted on September 28, 2010; Accepted on December 15, 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sonja Kukuljan, Caryl A. Nowson, Kerrie M. Sanders, Geoff C. Nicholson, Markus J. Seibel, Jo Salmon, and Robin M. Daly &lt;a href="mailto:rdaly@unimelb.edu.au">rdaly@unimelb.edu.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences (S.K., C.A.N., J.S., R.M.D.), Deakin University, Victoria 3125, Australia; Department of Clinical and Biomedical Sciences: Barwon Health (K.M.S., G.C.N.), University of Melbourne, Geelong Victoria 3220, Australia; Bone Research Program (M.J.S.), ANZAC Research Institute, University of Sydney, New South Wales 2006, Australia; and Department of Medicine (R.M.D.), University of Melbourne, Western Hospital, Melbourne 3011, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fish need vitamin D and C for their bones</title><link>/posts/fish-need-vitamin-d-and-c-for-their-bones.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fish-need-vitamin-d-and-c-for-their-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="overview-of-vitamin-d-and-c-requirements-in-fish-and-their-influence-on-the-skeletal-system">Overview of vitamin D and C requirements in fish and their influence on the skeletal system&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>M.J. Dariasa, &lt;a href="mailto:maria.darias@irta.cat">maria.darias@irta.cat&lt;/a>, D. Mazuraisa, G. Koumoundourosb, C.L. Cahua and J.L. Zambonino-Infantea&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Ifremer Marine Fish Nutrition Team, Nutrition Aquaculture and Genomics Research Unit, UMR 1067. Ifremer, Technopole Brest-Iroise, BP 70, 29280 Plouzané, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b University of Patras, Biology Department, 26500 Patras, Rio, Greece&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 6 May 2010; revised 3 December 2010; accepted 17 December 2010. Available online 7 January 2011. j.aquaculture.2010.12.030&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leg pain 7X more prevalent when vitamin D lower than 20 ng</title><link>/posts/leg-pain-7x-more-prevalent-when-vitamin-d-lower-than-20-ng.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/leg-pain-7x-more-prevalent-when-vitamin-d-lower-than-20-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="association-between-nonspecific-skeletal-pain-and-vitamin-d-deficiency">Association between nonspecific skeletal pain and vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int J Rheum Dis. 2010 Oct;13(4):340-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1756-185X.2010.01561.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1756-185X.2010.01561.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2010 Aug 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Association between nonspecific skeletal pain and vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heidari B, Shirvani JS, Firouzjahi A, Heidari P, Hajian-Tilaki KO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deparment of Medicine, Division of Rheumatology Deparment of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Rouhani Hospital, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol Faculty of Medicine, Islamic Azad University, Tehran Department of Social Medicine, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol, Iran.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less child bone if mother lacked vitamin D</title><link>/posts/less-child-bone-if-mother-lacked-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-child-bone-if-mother-lacked-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-affects-bone-growth-in-early-childhood-a-prospective-cohort-study">Maternal vitamin D status affects bone growth in early childhood-a prospective cohort study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2010 Dec 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Viljakainen HT, Korhonen T, Hytinantti T, Laitinen EK, Andersson S, Mäkitie O, Lamberg-Allardt C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hospital for Children and Adolescents, Helsinki University Central Hospital, Tukholmankatu 2C, PO Box 705, 00029, Helsinki, Finland, &lt;a href="mailto:heli.viljakainen@helsinki.fi">heli.viljakainen@helsinki.fi&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/fetal-bones-helped-a-bit-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Fetal bones helped a bit by 1,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT Feb 2019">Fetal bones helped a bit by 1,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT Feb 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In this prospective study, 87 children were followed up from birth to 14 months with data on maternal vitamin D status during the pregnancy. &lt;strong>Postnatal vitamin D supplementation improved vitamin D status but only partly eliminated the differences in bone variables induced by maternal vitamin D status during the fetal period.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back pain gone and grew 3 inches with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/back-pain-gone-and-grew-3-inches-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/back-pain-gone-and-grew-3-inches-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="one-individuals-experience-with-vitamin-d-and-back-pain">One individual&amp;rsquo;s experience with vitamin D and back pain&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="5000-iu-in-summer-and-10000-iu-in-winter">5,000 IU in summer and 10,000 IU in winter&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="is-ioms-food-and-nutrition-board-wrong-posted-03-dec-2010-by-vitamin-d-survivor">Is IoM’s Food and Nutrition Board Wrong? Posted: 03 Dec 2010 by Vitamin D Survivor&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As doctors scruple over the amount of vitamin D that we need as humans, the best approach is common sense. I started to write this blog because my back healed after 25 years of pain. It turns out that by following the standards that were just set by the IoM; my spine failed. I had two surgeries and was looking at the possibility of many more. I started to take 5,000 IU of vitamin D3 in the summer and 10,000 IU in the winter. This kept my serum level of 25(OH)D at 50 to 80 ng/ml. It turns out that people who live between the latitude of +/- 30 degrees have this value of vitamin D as normal as long as they do not intentionally avoid the sun (54 to 90 ng/ml reported by Dr’s Grant and Holick). At this level of supplementation my spine healed. I just had another MRI done after five years and the disc in my lumbar region are twice as thick now as they were five years ago. Let me repeat that in case you missed it. They are &lt;strong>TWICE AS THICK&lt;/strong> now as they were five years ago. Yes and I did grow &lt;strong>three inches taller&lt;/strong> in my mid-fifties as my spine healed. If I had followed the advice of the IoM’s recent report I would definitely be in a wheel chair or most likely dead either from a heart attack or sleep apnea.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Noticed bones heal faster when more than 60 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/noticed-bones-heal-faster-when-more-than-60-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/noticed-bones-heal-faster-when-more-than-60-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Review of vitamin D and bone health studies – with tables</title><link>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-and-bone-health-studies-with-tables.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-and-bone-health-studies-with-tables.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-health-nutrition-issues-in-aging">Bone Health Nutrition Issues in Aging&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2010, 2(11), 1086-1105; doi:10.3390/nu2111086&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Review&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karen Plawecki &lt;a href="mailto:plawecki@illinois.edu">plawecki@illinois.edu&lt;/a> and Karen Chapman-Novakofski&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nutritional Sciences, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Urbana, IL 61801, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received: 19 September 2010; in revised form: 29 October 2010 / Accepted: 2 November 2010 / Published: 8 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(This article belongs to the Special Issue Nutrition and Aging)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract: Bone health is an important issue in aging. Calcium and vitamin D currently have the most focus in published research on nutrition and bone health in aging, although evidence from published research is not conclusive. A systematic review was conducted to determine the impact of dietary and supplemental interventions focused on calcium and vitamin D over the past 10 years. Using key words to search, and search limits (aging population, English), 62 papers were found related to diet, nutrition, and bone; and 157 were found related to calcium and bone. Our review found a positive effect on bone health for supplements; food-based interventions; and educational strategies. Although there may be a publishing bias related to non-significant findings not being published, our results suggest the effectiveness of food based and educational interventions with less economic impact to the individual, as well as less risk of physiological side effects occurring.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>