<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Injection on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/injection.html</link><description>Recent content in Injection on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/injection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D injections of a total of 1,800,000 IU reduced shinbone tenderness</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-injections-of-a-total-of-1800000-iu-reduced-shinbone-tenderness.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-injections-of-a-total-of-1800000-iu-reduced-shinbone-tenderness.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="tibial-tenderness-identifies-secondary-hyperparathyroidism-responding-to-high-dose-vitamin-d-in-pakistani-women">Tibial Tenderness Identifies Secondary Hyperparathyroidism Responding to High Dose Vitamin D in Pakistani Women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2013 Feb 20:1-20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ali B, Butt A, Fatima A, McDonnell ME, Masud F.; Department of Medicine, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To assess the utility of &lt;strong>anterior tibial tenderness&lt;/strong> (ATT) measured by visual analogue score (VAS) as a clinical diagnostic tool for vitamin D deficiency in a high-risk population of Pakistani women&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: ATT using a VAS was assessed in 75 premenopausal women, ages 17-56 (mean 41.3) with generalized aches and pains and calcium of less than 11.0mg/dl (normal: 8-11) at a tertiary care center in Lahore, Pakistan. This was followed by administration of &lt;strong>1.8 million units of vitamin D3&lt;/strong> in divided doses. ATT, vitamin D and parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels were checked before and after the injections. Correlation between ATT, vitamin D and PTH as well as change in ATT, vitamin D and (PTH) following supplementation was determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>600,000 IU vitamin D normalized virtually all seniors in 3 months (Injection better than oral)</title><link>/posts/600000-iu-vitamin-d-normalized-virtually-all-seniors-in-3-months-injection-better-than-oral.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/600000-iu-vitamin-d-normalized-virtually-all-seniors-in-3-months-injection-better-than-oral.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="efficacy-and-safety-of-high-dose-intramuscular-or-oral-cholecalciferol-in-vitamin-d-deficientinsufficient-elderly">Efficacy and safety of high dose intramuscular or oral cholecalciferol in vitamin D deficient/insufficient elderly.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Maturitas. 2012 May 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tellioglu A, Basaran S, Guzel R, Seydaoglu G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Faculty of Medicine, Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Cukurova University, Adana 01330, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: To evaluate and compare the effects and safety of high dose intramuscular (IM) or oral cholecalciferol on 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels, muscle strength and physical performance in vitamin D deficient/insufficient elderly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300,000 IU injection loading dose of vitamin D3 stopped gestational diabetes in RCT</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-injection-loading-dose-of-vitamin-d3-stopped-gestational-diabetes-in-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-injection-loading-dose-of-vitamin-d3-stopped-gestational-diabetes-in-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-a-single-span-stylecolorf00post-partumspan-injection-of-a-high-dose-of-vitamin-d-on-glucose-tolerance-and-insulin-resistance-in-mothers-with-first-time-gestational-diabetes-mellitus">Effects of a single &lt;span style="color:#F00;">post-partum&lt;/span> injection of a high dose of vitamin D on glucose tolerance and insulin resistance in mothers with first-time gestational diabetes mellitus&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>H. Mozaffari-Khosravi1, M. Hosseinzadeh-Shamsi-Anar1, M.-A. Salami2, H. Hadinedoushan3, M. R. Mozayan4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetic Medicine Vol. 28 Issue 10&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aim? This study was performed to determine the effect of a single, large, intramuscular injection of vitamin D post-partum on glucose tolerance and insulin resistance in women with gestational diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300000 IU injection of vitamin D3</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-injection-of-vitamin-d3.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-injection-of-vitamin-d3.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-effect-of-intramuscular-vitamin-d-cholecalciferol-on-serum-25oh-vitamin-d-levels-in-older-female-acute-hospital-admissions">The effect of intramuscular vitamin D (cholecalciferol) on serum 25OH vitamin D levels in older female acute hospital admissions.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ir J Med Sci. 2010 Mar;179(1):57-61. Epub 2009 Aug 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nugent C, Roche K, Wilson S, Fitzgibbon M, Griffin D, Nichaidhin N, Mulkerrin E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine for the Elderly, University College Hospital Galway, Galway, Ireland. &lt;a href="mailto:cathalnugent@gmail.com">cathalnugent@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Many studies have demonstrated the prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency in the older population.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>