<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vitamin D and Omega-3 on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/vitamin-d-and-omega-3.html</link><description>Recent content in Vitamin D and Omega-3 on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vitamin-d-and-omega-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hypothesis – anticancer benefits from synergy of omega-3 and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-anticancer-benefits-from-synergy-of-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-anticancer-benefits-from-synergy-of-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-anticancer-effects-of-vitamin-d-and-omega-3-pufas-in-combination-via-cod-liver-oil-one-plus-one-may-equal-more-than-two">The anticancer effects of Vitamin D and omega-3 PUFAs in combination via cod-liver oil: One plus one may equal more than two.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Med Hypotheses. 2011 May 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dyck MC, Ma DW, Meckling KA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Human Health and Nutritional Sciences, University of Guelph, Guelph, ON, Canada N1G2W1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past number of years, the anticancer activities of omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (?3-PUFAs) as well as Vitamin D have been intensively studied, but separately. Supplementation of Vitamin D and omega-3 PUFA via cod-liver oil, one of few natural sources of both of these molecules, may have additive and possibly synergistic anticancer effects. Cod-liver oil has been used effectively to treat diseases such as Rheumatism but has not been studied as an anticancer agent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low cost cofactors for vitamin D</title><link>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-for-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-for-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="it-is-important-to-have-cofactors-when-taking-more-than-2000-iu-vitamin-d-average">It is IMPORTANT to have cofactors when taking more than 2000 IU vitamin D average&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/decrease-calcium-and-increase-magnesium-when-increasing-vitamin-d">Decrease Calcium and Increase Magnesium when increasing vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There is a lack of evidence of the interactions - the following are guesses based on incomplete information&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most studies are monotheraputic: e.g. supply Vitamin D, and rarely use any of the cofactors&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="update-2022-taking-most-of-my-supplements-as-pills---average-of-about-3day">Update 2022 taking most of my supplements as pills - average of about 3/day&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/herny-s-weekly-pills.jpg" alt="image" width="800">
&lt;p>Also take Magnesium Chloride as a liquid and Omega-3 as a cream&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ADHD and Vitamin D Deficiency</title><link>/posts/adhd-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adhd-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="adhd-reduced-by-span-stylecolor00fomega-3-spanin-trials-either-using-high-doses-or-over-the-long-term--july2016">ADHD reduced by &lt;span style="color:#00F;">Omega-3 &lt;/span>in trials either using high doses or over the long term – July 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Critical appraisal of omega-3 fatty acids in attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder treatment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2016 Jul 26;12:1869-82. Doi 10.2147/NDT.S68652. eCollection 2016.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Königs A1, Kiliaan AJ1.Department of Anatomy, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition &amp;amp; Behaviour, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, the Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/adhd-t1.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) is a common neurodevelopmental disorder. The classical treatment of ADHD, where stimulant medication is used, has revealed severe side effects and intolerance. Consequently, the demand to search for alternative treatment has increased rapidly. When comparing levels of omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (ω-3 PUFAs) in ADHD patients with those in age-matching controls, lower levels are found in ADHD patients&amp;rsquo; blood. ω-3 PUFAs are essential nutrients and necessary for proper brain function and development. Additionally, there are strong indications that ω-3 PUFA supplements could have beneficial effects on ADHD. However, the results of ω-3 PUFA supplementation studies show high variability. Therefore, we reviewed recent studies published between 2000 and 2015 to identify effective treatment combinations, the quality of design, and the safety and tolerability of ω-3-containing food supplements. We searched the databases MEDLINE, PubMed, and Web of Science with keywords such as &amp;ldquo;ADHD&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ω-3/6 PUFA&amp;rdquo; and identified 25 studies that met the inclusion and exclusion criteria.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>