<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vitamin D and Omega-3 on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/vitamin-d-and-omega-3.html</link><description>Recent content in Vitamin D and Omega-3 on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vitamin-d-and-omega-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alzheimer’s and Vitamins D, B, C, E, as well as Omega-3, metals, etc.</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-and-vitamins-d-b-c-e-as-well-as-omega-3-metals-etc.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-and-vitamins-d-b-c-e-as-well-as-omega-3-metals-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Importance and management of micronutrient deficiencies in patients with Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara Rita Cardoso1 Cristiane Cominetti2 Silvia Maria Franciscato Cozzolino1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Sao Paulo (USP), Sao Paulo, Brazil; 2Faculty of Nutrition, Federal University of Goias, Goias, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Barbara Rita Cardoso; Av Prof Lineu Prestes, 580 - Bloco &amp;lsquo;4 - CEP: 05508-900 – Sao Paulo - SP - Brazil Tel +55 3 09&amp;rsquo; 3625, +55 8 353 8223 Email &lt;a href="mailto:barbaracardoso@usp.br">barbaracardoso@usp.br&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, DHA, Folic, Iodine benefits during pregnancy</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-dha-folic-iodine-benefits-during-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-dha-folic-iodine-benefits-during-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="benefits-of-docosahexaenoic-acid-folic-acid-vitamin-d-and-iodine-on-foetal-and-infant-brain-development-and-function-following-maternal-supplementation-during-pregnancy-and-lactation">Benefits of Docosahexaenoic Acid, Folic Acid, Vitamin D and Iodine on Foetal and Infant Brain Development and Function Following Maternal Supplementation during Pregnancy and Lactation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2012 July; 4(7): 799–840.. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/nu4070799">doi: 10.3390/nu4070799&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nancy L. Morse&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3407995&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scientific literature is increasingly reporting on dietary deficiencies in many populations of some nutrients critical for foetal and infant brain development and function.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose: To highlight the potential benefits of maternal supplementation with docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) and other important complimentary nutrients, including vitamin D, folic acid and iodine during pregnancy and/or breast feeding for foetal and/or infant brain development and/or function.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinal cord problems more likely if TBI if little Omega-3 in diet</title><link>/posts/spinal-cord-problems-more-likely-if-tbi-if-little-omega-3-in-diet.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-cord-problems-more-likely-if-tbi-if-little-omega-3-in-diet.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dietary-omega-3-deficiency-from-gestation-increases-spinal-cord-vulnerability-to-traumatic-brain-injury-induced-damage">Dietary omega-3 deficiency from gestation increases spinal cord vulnerability to traumatic brain injury-induced damage.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(12):e52998. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0052998.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0052998.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Dec 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ying Z, Feng C, Agrawal R, Zhuang Y, Gomez-Pinilla F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Integrative Biology &amp;amp; Physiology, University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although traumatic brain injury (TBI) is often associated with gait deficits, the effects of TBI on spinal cord centers are poorly understood. We seek to determine the influence of TBI on the spinal cord and the potential of dietary omega-3 (n-3) fatty acids to counteract these effects. Male rodents exposed to diets containing adequate or deficient levels of n-3 since gestation received a moderate fluid percussion injury when becoming 14 weeks old. TBI reduced levels of molecular systems important for synaptic plasticity (BDNF, TrkB, and CREB) and plasma membrane homeostasis (4-HNE, iPLA2, syntaxin-3) in the lumbar spinal cord. These effects of TBI were more dramatic in the animals exposed to the n-3 deficient diet. Results emphasize the comprehensive action of TBI across the neuroaxis, and the critical role of dietary n-3 as a means to build resistance against the effects of TBI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traumatic brain injury treated by Vitamin D Progesterone Omega-3 and glutamine</title><link>/posts/traumatic-brain-injury-treated-by-vitamin-d-progesterone-omega-3-and-glutamine.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/traumatic-brain-injury-treated-by-vitamin-d-progesterone-omega-3-and-glutamine.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="combination-therapy-with-vitamin-d3-progesterone-omega-3-fatty-acids-and-glutamine-reverses-coma-and-improves-clinical-outcomes-in-patients-with-severe-traumatic-brain-injuries-a-case-series-of-three-patients">Combination therapy with vitamin D3, progesterone, omega-3 fatty acids, and glutamine reverses coma and improves clinical outcomes in patients with severe traumatic brain injuries: A case series of three patients&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>IJCRI - International Journal of Case Reports and Images, Vol. No. 2013. ISSN - &lt;span>[0976-3198]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Leslie R Matthews&lt;/strong> 1, Omar K Danner1, Y A Ahmed2, Diane M Dennis-Griggs1, Alexis Frederick1, Clarence Clark1, Ronald Moore1, Wilson DuMornay1, Ed W Childs1, Kenneth L Wilson1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Health benefits of seafood: Vitamin D, Omega-3, and Selenium</title><link>/posts/health-benefits-of-seafood-vitamin-d-omega-3-and-selenium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/health-benefits-of-seafood-vitamin-d-omega-3-and-selenium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Omega-3 reduced vitamin D3 inflammation for obese – RCT</title><link>/posts/omega-3-reduced-vitamin-d3-inflammation-for-obese-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-reduced-vitamin-d3-inflammation-for-obese-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="treatment-with-n-3-polyunsaturated-fatty-acids-overcomes-the-inverse-association-of-vitamin-d3">Treatment with n-3 Polyunsaturated Fatty Acids Overcomes the Inverse Association of Vitamin D3&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>D Deficiency with Inflammation in Severely Obese Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PLOS ONE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bianca K. Itariu, Maximilian Zeyda, Lukas Leitner, Rodrig Marculescu, Thomas M. Stulnig &lt;a href="mailto:thomas.stulnig@meduniwien.ac.at">thomas.stulnig@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Internal Medicine III, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria, Christian Doppler Laboratory for Cardio-Metabolic Immunotherapy, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obesity affects the vitamin D status in humans. Vitamin D and long-chain n-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFA) provide benefit for the prevention of fractures and cardiovascular events, respectively, and both are involved in controlling inflammatory and immune responses. However, published epidemiological data suggest a potential interference of n-3 PUFA supplementation with vitamin D status. Therefore, we aimed to investigate in a randomized controlled clinical trial whether treatment with long chain n-3 PUFA affects vitamin D status in severely obese patients and potential interrelations of vitamin D and PUFA treatment with inflammatory parameters. Fifty-four severely obese (BMI≥40 kg/m2) non-diabetic patients were treated for eight weeks with either 3.36 g/d EPA and DHA or the same amount of butter fat as control. Changes in serum 25-hydroxy-vitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations, plasma fatty acid profiles and circulating inflammatory marker concentrations from baseline to end of treatment were assessed. At baseline 43/54 patients were vitamin D deficient (serum 25(OH)D concentration &amp;lt;50 nmol/l). Treatment with n-3 PUFA did not affect vitamin D status (P = 0.91). Serum 25(OH)D concentration correlated negatively with both IL-6 (P = 0.02) and hsCRP serum concentration (P = 0.03) at baseline. Strikingly, the negative correlations of 25(OH)D with IL-6 and hsCRP were lost after n-3 PUFA treatment. In conclusion, vitamin D status of severely obese patients remained unaffected by n-3 PUFA treatment. However, abrogation of the inverse association of 25(OH)D concentration with inflammatory markers indicated that n-3 PUFA treatment could compensate for some detrimental consequences of vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular system benefits from both Omega-3 and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-system-benefits-from-both-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-system-benefits-from-both-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="omega-3-fatty-acids-and-vitamin-d-in-cardiology">Omega-3 Fatty acids and vitamin d in cardiology.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cardiol Res Pract. 2012;2012:729670. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1155/2012/729670.">doi: 10.1155/2012/729670.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Dec 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Güttler N, Zheleva K, Parahuleva M, Chasan R, Bilgin M, Neuhof C, Burgazli M, Niemann B, Erdogan A, Böning A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardiology and Angiology, University Hospital Giessen, 35390 Giessen, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dietary modification and supplementation play an increasingly important role in the conservative treatment of cardiovascular disease. Current interest has focused on n-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFA) and vitamin D. Clinical trial results on this subject are contradictory in many aspects. Several studies indicate that n-3 PUFA consumption improves&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How much vitamin D and other nutrients do I take</title><link>/posts/how-much-vitamin-d-and-other-nutrients-do-i-take.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-much-vitamin-d-and-other-nutrients-do-i-take.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Omega-3 added to cattle feed increases the level in milk</title><link>/posts/omega-3-added-to-cattle-feed-increases-the-level-in-milk.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-added-to-cattle-feed-increases-the-level-in-milk.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Overview: Omega-3 many benefits include helping vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-omega-3-many-benefits-include-helping-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-omega-3-many-benefits-include-helping-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor00fomega-3-and-vitamin-d-separately-and-together-help-with-depression-cardiovascular-cognition-pregnancy-infant-obesity-mortality-breast-cancer----span">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Omega-3 and Vitamin D separately and together help with Depression, Cardiovascular, Cognition, Pregnancy, Infant, Obesity, Mortality, Breast Cancer, . . . &lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="there-are-many-books-on-omega-3--i-such-as-the-omega-3-effect">There are many books on Omega-3: I such as: The Omega-3 Effect&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Everything you need to know about the supernutrient for living longer, happier, and healthier&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Willian Sears, 2012 &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Omega-3-Effect-Everything-Supernutrient-Healthier/dp/0316196843/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1354293017&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+omega-3+effect+everything+you+need+to+know+about+the+supernutrient+for+living+longer">Amazon&lt;/a> $6 Kindle&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="omega-3-content-of-3-ounces-of-wild-not-farmed-fish-150-to-1900-mg">Omega-3 content of 3 ounces of (wild, not farmed) fish (150 to 1,900 mg)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://omegaquant.com/do-all-fish-have-omega-3s/">OmegaQuant&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mackerel (Atlantic &amp;amp; Pacific): 1,900 mg EPA + DHA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart problems such as Afib related to little Magnesium, Omega-3, Vitamin D getting to tissues</title><link>/posts/heart-problems-such-as-afib-related-to-little-magnesium-omega-3-vitamin-d-getting-to-tissues.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-problems-such-as-afib-related-to-little-magnesium-omega-3-vitamin-d-getting-to-tissues.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="for-40-years-cardiovascular-problems-associated-with-low-magnesium">For 40+ years Cardiovascular problems associated with low Magnesium&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJM196904102801504%20">Sudden Death and Ischemic Heart Disease: Correlation With Hardness of the Local Water Supply.&lt;/a> 1969, New England Journal of Medicine&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>People who died suddenly had far lower levels of Magnesium than those who died in accidents&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed?term=magnesium%20(heart%20OR%20cardiac)">PubMed search for magnesium (heart OR cardiac)&lt;/a> 7879 items as of Dec 2018&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17560883%20">Meta-analysis of magnesium therapy for the acute management of rapid atrial fibrillation.&lt;/a> 2007&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unsaturated Fatty acids important for both MS and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/unsaturated-fatty-acids-important-for-both-ms-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/unsaturated-fatty-acids-important-for-both-ms-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>A balanced diet is no longer enough – supplements needed - VitaminDWiki</title><link>/posts/a-balanced-diet-is-no-longer-enough-supplements-needed-vitamindwiki.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-balanced-diet-is-no-longer-enough-supplements-needed-vitamindwiki.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin and Mineral deficiencies – Ames Triage Theory</title><link>/posts/vitamin-and-mineral-deficiencies-ames-triage-theory.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-and-mineral-deficiencies-ames-triage-theory.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-and-mineral-inadequacy-accelerates-aging-associated-diseases">Vitamin and Mineral Inadequacy Accelerates Aging-Associated Diseases&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Commonwealth Medical College 12 April 2012 - Revised&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce N. Ames Senior Scientist, Nutrition and Metabolism Center Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Oakland Research Institute, Oakland, California;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Professor Emeritus University of California, Berkeley&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I posited, and have buttressed, &amp;ldquo;triage theory&amp;rdquo; (1,2): metabolism responds to moderate deficiency of an essential vitamin or mineral (V/M) so that the scarce V/M is preferentially retained by V/M-dependent proteins necessary for short-term survival and reproduction. In contrast, proteins needed for long term health, which I term &amp;ldquo;longevity proteins&amp;rdquo; because they defend against the diseases associated with aging, lose the V/M and are disabled. Most of the world&amp;rsquo;s population, including that of the U.S., are moderately deficient in one or more of the ~30 essential V/Ms. Moreover, since the damage from moderate deficiency is insidious, its importance for long-term health is not being appreciated. Strong support for triage theory comes from Joyce McCann&amp;rsquo;s analyses of the literature on proteins dependent on vitamin K (3) and on selenium (4). Both have built into metabolism this trade-off between short-term survival and long-term health and each uses a different mechanism to accomplish this end. Theory and evidence suggest that this metabolic trade-off accelerates aging-associated diseases, such as cancer, cognitive decline, and cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omega-3 does not help heart patients – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/omega-3-does-not-help-heart-patients-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-does-not-help-heart-patients-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="clipped-from-la-times-sept-2012httpwwwlatimescomnewssciencela-sci-omega-3s-heart-health-2012091203265313story20">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/science/la-sci-omega-3s-heart-health-20120912,0,3265313.story%20">LA Times Sept 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The study, reexamined the results of 20 previous studies dating back to 1989 that included nearly 70,000 patients.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;This evidence,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;should not be generalized to any type of patients or apparently healthy individuals.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="clipped-from-time-magazinehttphealthlandtimecom20120912omega-3-supplements-dont-lower-heart-disease-risk-after-all20">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://healthland.time.com/2012/09/12/omega-3-supplements-dont-lower-heart-disease-risk-after-all/%20">Time Magazine&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Volunteers in the studies, &lt;strong>most of whom were heart patients&lt;/strong> , were randomly assigned to take either 1.5 g of omega-3 supplementation or a placebo every day for about two years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>US supplements survey – 34 percent take omega-3, 30 percent take vitamin D</title><link>/posts/us-supplements-survey-34-percent-take-omega-3-30-percent-take-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/us-supplements-survey-34-percent-take-omega-3-30-percent-take-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Omega 3 increases vitamin D in the blood – many studies</title><link>/posts/omega-3-increases-vitamin-d-in-the-blood-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-increases-vitamin-d-in-the-blood-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Many articles on this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omega-3 increases levels of active vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active vitamin D is the form which the body actually used&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active vitamin D is not measured by standard vitamin D tests&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omega-3 is thus especially useful to get vitamin D to the body if the kidney is not functioning properly&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-effects-of-omega-3-fatty-acid-on-vitamin-d-activation-in-hemodialysis-patients-a-pilot-study--2015">The Effects of Omega-3 Fatty Acid on Vitamin D Activation in Hemodialysis Patients: A Pilot Study- 2015&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/active-d-and-omega-3.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Mar. Drugs 2015, 13(2), 741-755; doi:10.3390/md13020741&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Omega 3 and Exercise are being used in controlled trial to support healthy ageing</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-omega-3-and-exercise-are-being-used-in-controlled-trial-to-support-healthy-ageing.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-omega-3-and-exercise-are-being-used-in-controlled-trial-to-support-healthy-ageing.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and omega-3 are the only supplements which show benefit in meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-omega-3-are-the-only-supplements-which-show-benefit-in-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-omega-3-are-the-only-supplements-which-show-benefit-in-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reasons for low response to vitamin D</title><link>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#detailed-reasons-for-poor-response">Detailed Reasons for poor response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reasons-for-not-getting-benefits---span-stylecolorf00even-if-blood-tests-are-okspan">Reasons for not getting benefits - &lt;span style="color:#F00;">even if blood tests are OK&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsuv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual--2010big-differences-in-uvb-responsesa-20-to-36-ng-after-6-weeks">&lt;a href="/posts/uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: UV production of Vitamin D varies with the individual – 2010">Big differences in UVB responses&lt;/a>: 20 to 36 ng after 6 weeks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#alternate-sources-of-vitamin-d">Alternate sources of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/h4>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>~ 50% of all people have a low response to vitamin D3&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – anticancer benefits from synergy of omega-3 and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-anticancer-benefits-from-synergy-of-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-anticancer-benefits-from-synergy-of-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-anticancer-effects-of-vitamin-d-and-omega-3-pufas-in-combination-via-cod-liver-oil-one-plus-one-may-equal-more-than-two">The anticancer effects of Vitamin D and omega-3 PUFAs in combination via cod-liver oil: One plus one may equal more than two.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Med Hypotheses. 2011 May 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dyck MC, Ma DW, Meckling KA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Human Health and Nutritional Sciences, University of Guelph, Guelph, ON, Canada N1G2W1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past number of years, the anticancer activities of omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (?3-PUFAs) as well as Vitamin D have been intensively studied, but separately. Supplementation of Vitamin D and omega-3 PUFA via cod-liver oil, one of few natural sources of both of these molecules, may have additive and possibly synergistic anticancer effects. Cod-liver oil has been used effectively to treat diseases such as Rheumatism but has not been studied as an anticancer agent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low cost cofactors for vitamin D</title><link>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-for-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-for-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="it-is-important-to-have-cofactors-when-taking-more-than-2000-iu-vitamin-d-average">It is IMPORTANT to have cofactors when taking more than 2000 IU vitamin D average&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/decrease-calcium-and-increase-magnesium-when-increasing-vitamin-d">Decrease Calcium and Increase Magnesium when increasing vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There is a lack of evidence of the interactions - the following are guesses based on incomplete information&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most studies are monotheraputic: e.g. supply Vitamin D, and rarely use any of the cofactors&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="update-2022-taking-most-of-my-supplements-as-pills---average-of-about-3day">Update 2022 taking most of my supplements as pills - average of about 3/day&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/herny-s-weekly-pills.jpg" alt="image" width="800">
&lt;p>Also take Magnesium Chloride as a liquid and Omega-3 as a cream&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ADHD and Vitamin D Deficiency</title><link>/posts/adhd-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adhd-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="adhd-reduced-by-span-stylecolor00fomega-3-spanin-trials-either-using-high-doses-or-over-the-long-term--july2016">ADHD reduced by &lt;span style="color:#00F;">Omega-3 &lt;/span>in trials either using high doses or over the long term – July 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Critical appraisal of omega-3 fatty acids in attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder treatment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2016 Jul 26;12:1869-82. Doi 10.2147/NDT.S68652. eCollection 2016.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Königs A1, Kiliaan AJ1.Department of Anatomy, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition &amp;amp; Behaviour, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, the Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/adhd-t1.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) is a common neurodevelopmental disorder. The classical treatment of ADHD, where stimulant medication is used, has revealed severe side effects and intolerance. Consequently, the demand to search for alternative treatment has increased rapidly. When comparing levels of omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (ω-3 PUFAs) in ADHD patients with those in age-matching controls, lower levels are found in ADHD patients&amp;rsquo; blood. ω-3 PUFAs are essential nutrients and necessary for proper brain function and development. Additionally, there are strong indications that ω-3 PUFA supplements could have beneficial effects on ADHD. However, the results of ω-3 PUFA supplementation studies show high variability. Therefore, we reviewed recent studies published between 2000 and 2015 to identify effective treatment combinations, the quality of design, and the safety and tolerability of ω-3-containing food supplements. We searched the databases MEDLINE, PubMed, and Web of Science with keywords such as &amp;ldquo;ADHD&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ω-3/6 PUFA&amp;rdquo; and identified 25 studies that met the inclusion and exclusion criteria.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>