<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Toxicity on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/toxicity.html</link><description>Recent content in Toxicity on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/toxicity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3 people taking more than 20,000 IU of vitamin D for years</title><link>/posts/3-people-taking-more-than-20000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-years.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-people-taking-more-than-20000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="results-of-daily-oral-dosing-with-up-to-60000-international-units-iu-of-vitamin-d3-for-2-to-6-years-in-3-adult-males">Results of Daily oral Dosing with up to 60,000 International Units (iu) of vitamin d3 for 2 to 6 years in 3 adult males.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, online 21 Dec 2016, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2016.12.009">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2016.12.009&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patrick McCullough a &lt;a href="mailto:Patrick.mccullough@mha.ohio.gov">Patrick.mccullough@mha.ohio.gov&lt;/a> , b, , , Jeffrey Amendb,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Daily intake of high dose vitamin D3, 20,000 to 60,000 IU, was studied in 3 people.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Daily dosing with these doses occurred over a 2 to 6 year period.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caution When Prescribing High Dose Vitamin D (100,000 IU D2 daily for is too much after 4 years)</title><link>/posts/caution-when-prescribing-high-dose-vitamin-d-100000-iu-d2-daily-for-is-too-much-after-4-years.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/caution-when-prescribing-high-dose-vitamin-d-100000-iu-d2-daily-for-is-too-much-after-4-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-word-of-caution-when-prescribing-high-dose-vitamin-d">A Word of Caution When Prescribing High Dose Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Medicine Nov 2016, DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2016.10.025">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2016.10.025&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matthew A. Gorris, MD, Department of Internal Medicine, Wake Forest Baptist Medical Center, Winston Salem, North Carolina, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harkesh Arora, MD, Apogee Physicians, New Mexico, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David C. Lieb, MD, Division of Endocrinology, Eastern Virginia Medical School, Norfolk, Virginia, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joseph A. Aloi, MD, Division of Endocrinology, Wake Forest Baptist Medical Center, Winston Salem, North Carolina, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death from Vitamin D overdose - 600,000 IU daily for 3 weeks</title><link>/posts/death-from-vitamin-d-overdose-600000-iu-daily-for-3-weeks.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-from-vitamin-d-overdose-600000-iu-daily-for-3-weeks.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="i-classfas-fa-file-pdf-stylemargin-right-03emia-hrefhttpsd378j1rmrlek7xcloudfrontnetattachmentspdffatal-600-000-iu-daily-for-21-dayspdfdownload-the-pdf-from-vitamindwikia">&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/fatal-600-000-iu-daily-for-21-days.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-lethal-dose-in-dogs-1934" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Vitamin D Lethal Dose in Dogs – 1934">Vitamin D Lethal Dose in Dogs – 1934&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-toxicity-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Toxicity of vitamin D">Overview Toxicity of vitamin D&lt;/a> shows that that size of dose is very toxic&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="450">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-overdose-kills-10-year-old-boy-in-delhihttptimesofindiaindiatimescomcitydelhivitamin-d-overdose-kills-10-year-old-boy-in-delhiarticleshow52049189cms-times-of-india-coverage-of-this-study">&lt;a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/Vitamin-D-overdose-kills-10-year-old-boy-in-Delhi/articleshow/52049189.cms?">Vitamin D overdose kills 10-year-old boy in Delhi&lt;/a> Times of India coverage of this study&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;. . a dose of Vitamin D that was &lt;strong>several times higher&lt;/strong> than the safe limit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A bit more than several times higher, it was at least &lt;strong>60 times higher&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Infant hospitalized after Vitamin D overdose (8,000 X too much)</title><link>/posts/infant-hospitalized-after-vitamin-d-overdose-8000-x-too-much.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/infant-hospitalized-after-vitamin-d-overdose-8000-x-too-much.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="omaha-ketvhttpwwwketvcomnewspreview-accidental-overdose-puts-infant-in-hospital37817504-feb-2016">&lt;a href="http://www.ketv.com/news/preview-accidental-overdose-puts-infant-in-hospital/37817504">Omaha, KETV&lt;/a> Feb 2016&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Transcript indicates that it took months to notice the 8,000X too high of dose&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.elitereaders.com/mom-inadvertently-causes-infant-overdose-vitamin-d/">1 dropperful instead of one drop&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somthing strange here. A full dropper contains 15-20 drops&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Assuming 400 IU/drop X 8,000 (which is perhaps a full bottle) = 4,300,000 IU daily&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="is-there-even-a-single-ingestable-substance-which-is-not-deadly-at-8000-x-in-a-single-day">Is there even a single ingestable substance which is not deadly at 8000 X in a single day,&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>    much less 2 months?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU of vitamin D- doctors trained that it was too much, but it is often too little</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-doctors-trained-that-it-was-too-much-but-it-is-often-too-little.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-doctors-trained-that-it-was-too-much-but-it-is-often-too-little.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Most doctors limit their vitamin D prescriptions to 2,000 IU&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The doctors training (incorrectly) told them that any more than 2,000 IU could be toxic&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At least one &lt;a href="/posts/breastfeeding-mother-getting-6400-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-similar-to-infant-getting-400-iu-rct">Randomize Controlled Trial had to stop the 2,000 IU leg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>because 2000 IU was not providing the healthful outcome that the 4,000 IU leg provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="see-vitamindwiki">See VitaminDWiki&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/myth-for-50-years-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-toxic-still-taught-as-fact-in-2010" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Myth for 50 years: 2000 IU of vitamin D is toxic - still taught as fact in 2010">Myth for 50 years: 2000 IU of vitamin D is toxic - still taught as fact in 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The fact was that 2,000 IU of vitamin D &lt;strong>per KILOGRAM&lt;/strong> was toxic if cofactors not balanced&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High dose vitamin D (20,000 IU per kg of feed) safe for pigs</title><link>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-d-20000-iu-per-kg-of-feed-safe-for-pigs.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-d-20000-iu-per-kg-of-feed-safe-for-pigs.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="tolerance-evaluation-of-overdosed-dietary-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-in-growing-piglets">Tolerance evaluation of overdosed dietary levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 in growing piglets.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr (Berl). 2015 Aug 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/jpn.12355">doi: 10.1111/jpn.12355&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>von Rosenberg SJ1, Weber GM2, Erhardt A1, Höller U2, Wehr UA1, Rambeck WA1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forty-eight, cross-bred (GL × LW × P) piglets were used in a 42-day tolerance trial to assess the effects of feeding diets supplemented with vitamin D or increasing levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25-OH-D3 ). Six-week-old piglets (24 castrate males, 24 females) were used. Two replicate groups of 6 piglets were randomized by weight and allocated to four dietary treatments. The control group (T1) was supplemented with 50 μg vitamin D3 /kg feed. The experimental groups received 25-OH-D3 at the recommended dose (T2: 50 μg/kg = 1x), at 250 μg/kg (T3: 5x) or at 500 μg/kg (T4: 10x) respectively. Feed intake and daily weight gain were measured weekly, and the animals were examined by a veterinarian daily. After 42 days, body mass, blood, urine, bone and tissue samples were analysed and a pathology examination conducted. Dietary treatments had no significant effect on final body mass or daily weight gain. The 25-OH-D3 plasma concentration in T1 was 17 ± 3 ng/ml (mean ± SD) while the respective values of the experimental groups were significantly increased in T2, T3 and T4. Tissue concentrations of 25-OH-D3 were higher in liver and muscle for T3 and T4 and in skin for T4 than in T1. However, neither gross pathology nor histology, nor blood and urine characteristics, nor bone parameters were affected by dietary treatments. Weight of organs as well as dry matter, ash and calcium content of kidneys remained unaffected by dietary 25-OH-D3 intake. Furthermore, no changes were observed for general indicators of health. The results of this study demonstrated that feeding piglets with 25-OH-D3 at 5 or 10 times the recommended level had no adverse effects on any of the biological parameters measured. It was concluded that 25-OH-D3 can be regarded as a supplement with a very high safety margin when used at the recommended level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many more people now have vitamin D levels above 50 ng, especially seniors</title><link>/posts/many-more-people-now-have-vitamin-d-levels-above-50-ng-especially-seniors.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-more-people-now-have-vitamin-d-levels-above-50-ng-especially-seniors.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Changing Incidence of Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Values Above 50 ng/mL: A 10-Year Population-Based Study&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daniel V. Dudenkov, MD; Barbara P. Yawn, MD, MS, FAAFP;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sara S. Oberhelman, MD; Philip R. Fischer, MD; RavinderJ. Singh, PhD;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen S. Cha, MS; Julie A. Maxson, BA; Stephanie M. Quigg, MS; and Tom D. Thacher, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To determine the incidence trend of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) values above 50 ng/mL and associated toxicity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patients and Methods: We conducted a retrospective population-based study in Olmsted County, Minnesota, in the 10-year period from January 1, 2002, through December 31, 2011, by using the Rochester Epidemiology Project. Individuals were eligible if they resided in Olmsted County during the study period and had a measured 25(OH)D value above 50 ng/mL. The date of the first 25(OH)D value above 50 ng/mL was considered the index date for incidence determination. Hypercalcemia, the primary vitamin D toxicity, was considered potentially associated with the 25(OH)D concentration if it was measured within 3 months of the 25(OH)D measurement, and such cases had a medical record review.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A vitamin D level of 746 ng due to medication error was not toxic</title><link>/posts/a-vitamin-d-level-of-746-ng-due-to-medication-error-was-not-toxic.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-vitamin-d-level-of-746-ng-due-to-medication-error-was-not-toxic.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-nontoxic-case-of-vitamin-d-toxicity">A Nontoxic Case of Vitamin D Toxicity.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Lab Med. 2015 Spring;46(2):146-149.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chakraborty S1, Sarkar AK2, Bhattacharya C2, Krishnan P3, Chakraborty S4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D toxicity also known as hypervitaminosis D was previously believed to be rare. But with an increase in vitamin D supplementation several cases have been reported in literature. Fat soluble vitamins like Vitamin D, due to their ability to accumulate in the body, have a higher potential for toxicity than water soluble vitamins. The main clinical consequence of vitamin D toxicity is hypercalcemia. In this report we describe an adult female patient who developed very high serum Vitamin D levels (746 ng/mL, RI: 20 to 50) as a result of medication error. In spite of such high serum concentrations the patient was without any clinical symptoms and had normal serum calcium. We critically discuss the mechanism of toxicity and hypothesize the possible molecular/metabolic factors which might have been responsible for this nontoxic presentation. This case study highlights the fact that physicians need to consider the risk of medication errors while prescribing Vitamin D therapy. Clinical trials to study Vitamin D toxicity in humans is not possible ethically. Thus the evidence base regarding the safety profile of Vitamin D supplementation in humans has been build through case reports. This review of the paradoxical clinico-laboratory manifestation of hypervitaminosis D could possibly contribute to existing literature.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D toxicity after 50,000 IU daily for 2 years (no surprise)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-toxicity-after-50000-iu-daily-for-2-years-no-surprise.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-toxicity-after-50000-iu-daily-for-2-years-no-surprise.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="bodybuilder-poisons-himself-with-vitamin-dhttpwwwergo-logcombodybuilder-poisons-himself-with-vitamin-dhtml20">&lt;a href="http://www.ergo-log.com/bodybuilder-poisons-himself-with-vitamin-d.html%20">Bodybuilder poisons himself with vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="love-the-hyped-title">Love the hyped title!&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-100000-iu-daily-was-ok-for-dr-cannell-for-6-months">Vitamin D 100,000 IU daily was OK for Dr. Cannell for 6 months – Jan 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note: Researcher added many vital cofactors, such as Magnesium and Vitamin K2 and reduced Calcium&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The body builder did not&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-toxicity-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Toxicity of vitamin D">Overview Toxicity of vitamin D&lt;/a> has the following chart&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"></description></item><item><title>2,000,000 IU Vitamin D was not a problem</title><link>/posts/2000000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-a-problem.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-a-problem.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pharmacokinetics-and-safety-issues-of-an-accidental-overdose-of-2000000-iu-of-vitamin-d3-in-two-nursing-home-patients-a-case-report">Pharmacokinetics and safety issues of an accidental overdose of 2,000,000 IU of vitamin D3 in two nursing home patients: a case report.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Pharmacol Toxicol. 2014 Sep 30;15:57. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/2050-6511-15-57.">doi: 10.1186/2050-6511-15-57.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van den Ouweland J1, Fleuren H, Drabbe M, Vollaard H.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/2-million-iu.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Administration of intermittent high doses of vitamin D3 is increasingly used as a strategy for rapid normalization of low 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) blood concentrations in patients with vitamin D deficiency. Here, we describe the pharmacokinetics of an accidental single oral overdose of 2,000,000 IU of vitamin D3 in two elderly nursing home patients and discuss safety issues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Response and adverse effects of 20,000 and 30,000 IU Vitamin D weekly</title><link>/posts/response-and-adverse-effects-of-20000-and-30000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/response-and-adverse-effects-of-20000-and-30000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Small safety study of women at high risk of getting breast cancer&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="safety-feasibility-and-biomarker-effects-of-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplementation-among-women-at-high-risk-for-breast-cancer">Safety, Feasibility, and Biomarker Effects of High-Dose Vitamin D Supplementation Among Women at High Risk for Breast Cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>International Journal of Food Science, Nutrition and Dietetics (1JFS) ISSN 2326-3350&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Crew KD1,2,3*, Xiao T2, Thomas PS4, Terry MB1,3, Maurer M2,3, Kalinsky K2,3, Feldman S3,5, Brafman L3, Refice SR3, Hershman DL1,2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, College of Physicians and Surgeons, Columbia University, New York, NY, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Warning in Norway – 2,000 IU Vitamin D being sold (800 IU is their upper limit)</title><link>/posts/warning-in-norway-2000-iu-vitamin-d-being-sold-800-iu-is-their-upper-limit.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/warning-in-norway-2000-iu-vitamin-d-being-sold-800-iu-is-their-upper-limit.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="nutragredientshttpwwwnutraingredientscomregulation-policynorway-and-denmark-warn-on-vitamins-16-x-safe-limitsutm_sourcerss_text_newsutm_mediumrss2bfeedutm_campaignrss2btext2bnewsutm_readerfeedly">&lt;a href="http://www.nutraingredients.com/Regulation-Policy/Norway-and-Denmark-warn-on-vitamins-16-x-safe-limits?utm_source=RSS_text_news&amp;amp;utm_medium=RSS%2Bfeed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=RSS%2BText%2BNews&amp;amp;utm_reader=feedly">Nutragredients&lt;/a>&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Overprescribing vitamin D – yes, 600,000 IU daily for 3 weeks is too much</title><link>/posts/overprescribing-vitamin-d-yes-600000-iu-daily-for-3-weeks-is-too-much.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overprescribing-vitamin-d-yes-600000-iu-daily-for-3-weeks-is-too-much.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hyper-vitaminosis-d-are-we-overprescribing-vitamin-d">Hyper Vitaminosis D: Are we Overprescribing Vitamin D?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Family Med Prim Care. 2014 Oct-Dec;3(4):464-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4103/2249-4863.148153.">doi: 10.4103/2249-4863.148153.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hemachandar R1, Shanmugam L2, Malepati B2, Venugopal S2.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>In the paper, not the abstract, we find:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>One woman had &amp;ldquo;received intramuscular injections of&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>cholecalciferol 600,000 IU &lt;strong>daily&lt;/strong> for 20 consecutive days&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Her Vitamin D level was &amp;gt;150 ng/mL&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From this single instance the authors conclude that vitamin D is being overprescribed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Vitamin D, the sunshine vitamin is now considered to be a hormone due to its important role in many physiological functions. Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with many disorders ranging from bone diseases, cardiovascular diseases to cancer. Hence, there is a recent surge in the empirical prescription of vitamin D for various disorders without documentation of vitamin D deficiency and monitoring the treatment. We report a case of iatrogenic hypercalcemia and acute kidney injury due to vitamin D toxicity after empirical and overzealous use of vitamin D and calcium supplements. We present this case to remind clinicians the importance of monitoring the patients treated with mega doses of vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D 100,000 IU daily was OK for Dr. Cannell for 6 months</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-100000-iu-daily-was-ok-for-dr-cannell-for-6-months.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-100000-iu-daily-was-ok-for-dr-cannell-for-6-months.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="highlights-of-email-of-jan-29-2015-which-is-below">Highlights of email of Jan 29, 2015 (which is below)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cofactors: not stated – but probably was taking Magnesium and Vitamin K2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>350 ng after 6 months, no Calcium problems (cofactors?)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunbathing reduced the level to 250ng/ml&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Was anxious so stopped the dose&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back to 100 ng/ml in 6 months&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>In 2012 I decided to do a toxicity study on myself to help answer a few questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started taking 100,000 IU/day in June of 2012.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many doctors still belief (incorrectly) that more than 800 or 2000 IU of vitamin D is toxic</title><link>/posts/many-doctors-still-belief-incorrectly-that-more-than-800-or-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-toxic.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-doctors-still-belief-incorrectly-that-more-than-800-or-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-toxic.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="how-do-primary-care-physicians-and-practitioners-view-and-implement-vitamin-d-in-their-practicehttpwwwvitamindcouncilorgbloghow-do-primary-care-physicians-and-practitioners-view-and-implement-vitamin-d-in-their-practice-vitamin-d-council">&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindcouncil.org/blog/how-do-primary-care-physicians-and-practitioners-view-and-implement-vitamin-d-in-their-practice/">How do primary care physicians and practitioners view and implement vitamin D in their practice?&lt;/a> Vitamin D Council&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="four-themes--found">Four themes found&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The primary driver of demand is the patient&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Reflexive acceptance of patient demand without additional investigation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Incorporation into patient care as a diagnostic tool&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Doubt – “A substantial number of participants viewed the patient-driven demand for vitamin D testing and treatment with skepticism.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="based-on-the-following-study">Based on the following study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/emerging-practice-concerning-vitamin-d-in-primary-care" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Emerging Practice Concerning Vitamin D in Primary Care">Emerging Practice Concerning Vitamin D in Primary Care&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D toxicity after 4 months of weekly 600,000 IU – 2012</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-toxicity-after-4-months-of-weekly-600000-iu-2012.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-toxicity-after-4-months-of-weekly-600000-iu-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="first-case-of-vitamin-d-toxicityhttpwwwsecondopinionnewslettercomhealth-alert-archiveview-archive12179first-case-of-vitamin-d-toxicityhtm">&lt;a href="http://www.secondopinionnewsletter.com/Health-Alert-Archive/View-Archive/12179/First-case-of-vitamin-D-toxicity.htm">First case of vitamin D toxicity&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Clips from the post&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A 67-year-old woman went to the hospital with a history of lethargy, memory impairment, confusion, loss of appetite, and loss of equilibrium for two-weeks duration.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Her routine biochemistry showed elevated blood calcium at 14 mg/dl. This is dangerously high. *The doctors then checked her vitamin D level and it was also extremely high at 254 ng/ml.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>. . all of this woman’s lab tests including her liver tests, lipids, thyroid panel, and blood counts were completely normal. (other than Calcium)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>600,000 IU of Vitamin D2 is rarely toxic in infants</title><link>/posts/600000-iu-of-vitamin-d2-is-rarely-toxic-in-infants.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/600000-iu-of-vitamin-d2-is-rarely-toxic-in-infants.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="spanoverdose-or-hypersensitivity-to-vitamin-dspan-spanarticle-in-frenchspan">&lt;span>[Overdose or hypersensitivity to vitamin D?]&lt;/span> &lt;span>[Article in French]&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Arch Pediatr. 2014 Aug 13. pii: S0929-693X(14)00324-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arcped.2014.06.025.">doi: 10.1016/j.arcped.2014.06.025.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmami F1, Oulmaati A2, Amarti A3, Kottler ML4, Bouharrou A2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Service de néonatologie et réanimation néonatale, CHU Hassan II, 30000 Fès, Maroc; Université Sidi Mohammed Ben Abdellah, faculté de médecine et de pharmacie, Fès, Maroc. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:fhmami@hotmail.com">fhmami@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Service de néonatologie et réanimation néonatale, CHU Hassan II, 30000 Fès, Maroc; Université Sidi Mohammed Ben Abdellah, faculté de médecine et de pharmacie, Fès, Maroc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rare infant vitamin D toxicity – due to errors which resulted in more that 240,000 IU</title><link>/posts/rare-infant-vitamin-d-toxicity-due-to-errors-which-resulted-in-more-that-240000-iu.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rare-infant-vitamin-d-toxicity-due-to-errors-which-resulted-in-more-that-240000-iu.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-and-risk-of-toxicity-in-pediatrics-a-review-of-current-literature">Vitamin D Supplementation and Risk of Toxicity in Pediatrics: A Review of Current Literature.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014 Jan 23:jc20133655.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vogiatzi MG, Jacobson-Dickman E, Deboer MD; for the Drugs, and Therapeutics Committee of The Pediatric Endocrine Society.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weill Cornell Medical College, NY;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Context: While vitamin D toxicity is rare in children, increased use of vitamin D formulations, re-examination of optimal vitamin D levels and use of higher doses lend potential for an increased incidence of vitamin D toxicity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NHS (UK) mistakenly says more than 1000 IU of vitamin D can be harmful</title><link>/posts/nhs-uk-mistakenly-says-more-than-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-can-be-harmful.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nhs-uk-mistakenly-says-more-than-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-can-be-harmful.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="nhshttpwwwnhsukconditionsvitamins-mineralspagesvitamin-daspx20-statement">&lt;a href="http://www.nhs.uk/Conditions/vitamins-minerals/Pages/Vitamin-D.aspx%20">NHS&lt;/a> statement&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If you take vitamin D supplements, do not take more than 25 micrograms (0.025mg) a day, as it could be harmful.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>However, taking less than this is unlikely to cause any harm.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Taking too many vitamin D supplements over a long period of time can cause more calcium to be absorbed than can be excreted.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The excess calcium can be deposited in and damage the kidneys.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Excessive intake of vitamin D can also encourage calcium to be removed from bones, which can soften and weaken them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D: Deficiency, Sufficiency and Toxicity</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-sufficiency-and-toxicity.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-sufficiency-and-toxicity.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5, 3605-3616; doi:10.3390/nu5093605&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fahad Alshahrani and Naji Aljohani 2,3,4,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Medicine, King Abdulaziz Medical City, Riyadh 14611, Saudi Arabia; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:fahad_alshahrani@yahoo.com">fahad_alshahrani@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Specialized Diabetes and Endocrine Center, King Fahad Medical City, Riyadh 59046, Saudi Arabia; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:najijohani@gmail.com">najijohani@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Faculty of Medicine, King Saud bin Abdulaziz University for Health Sciences, Riyadh 22490, Saudi Arabia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Prince Mutaib Chair for Biomarkers of Osteoporosis, College of Science, King Saud University, Riyadh 11451, Saudi Arabia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D intoxication if more than 150 ng</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-intoxication-if-more-than-150-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-intoxication-if-more-than-150-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-intoxication">Vitamin D intoxication&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Turkish Journal of Pediatrics 2012; 54: 93-98 March&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Behzat Ozkan1, §ukru Hatun2, Abdullah Bereket3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Pediatric Endocrinology, 1istanbul Medeniyet University Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul, 2Kocaeli University Faculty of Medicine, Kocaeli, and 3Marmara University Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul, Turkey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUMMARY:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D intoxication (VDI) may result from supplementation rarely, but it has been reported more frequently in recent years. This may be attributable to an increase in vitamin D supplement intake due to an understanding of the role of vitamin D (25OHD) in the pathogenesis of several diseases. The symptoms and findings associated with VDI are closely related to serum calcium concentration and duration of hypercalcemia. In patients with VDI, hypercalcemia, normal or high serum phosphorus levels, normal or low levels of alkaline phosphatase (ALP), high levels of serum 25OHD, low serum parathyroid hormone (PTH), and high urine calcium/creatinine are usually present. Serum 25OHD levels above 150 ng/ml are considered as VDI. The main goal of treatment for VDI is correction of the hypercalcemia. When the calcium concentration exceeds 14 mg/dl, emergency intervention is necessary because of the adverse effects of hypercalcemia on cardiac, central nervous system, renal, and gastrointestinal functions. However, since vitamin D is stored in fat tissues, effects of toxicity may last for months despite the removal of the exogenous source of vitamin D. Treatment for VDI includes: discontinuation of intake, a diet with low calcium and phosphorus content, intravenous hydration with saline, loop diuretics, glucocorticoids, calcitonin, and bisphosphonates. In conclusion, the diagnosis of vitamin D deficiency rickets (VDDR) without checking serum 25OHD level may cause redundant treatment that leads to VDI. All patients who are clinically suspected of VDDR should be checked for serum vitamin D status and questioned for previous vitamin D administration before starting vitamin D therapy. On the other hand, parents of all infants should be asked whether they are using dietary or oral supplements, and serial questioning may be required during supplementation to avoid excessive intake.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1000 IU of vitamin D (per kg) can indeed be toxic – 1947</title><link>/posts/1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-can-indeed-be-toxic-1947.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-can-indeed-be-toxic-1947.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="there-were-many-studies-in-the-1940s-stating-that">There were many studies in the 1940’s stating that&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>    1000 IU of vitamin D &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">per kilogram of body weight&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> was toxic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The average weight of an adult was approximately 70 kg, so yes, I agree, 70,000 IU of vitamin D can be toxic.&lt;br>
I had often wondered why doctors had been told that 1,000 or 2,000 IU of vitamin D was toxic.&lt;br>
My guess is that the old message was trimmed to 1,000 IU of vitamin D is toxic,&lt;br>
Note in the clipping belows that even 35 X higher was sometimes not toxic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D: Is It the Best Thing Under the Sun - Medscape</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-it-the-best-thing-under-the-sun-medscape.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-it-the-best-thing-under-the-sun-medscape.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert Finn; Deborah Flapan; Darbe Rotach&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-following-is-the-first-of-25-images">The following is the first of 25 images&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"> 
&lt;p>The number of research studies on vitamin D has soared in recent years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Citations of studies involving vitamin D increased from 1142 in the year 2000 to 3877 in 2012.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In comparison, citations for research on vitamin A and vitamin C have remained more or less level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to register with &lt;a href="http://www.medscape.com/features/slideshow/vitamin-d#20">Medscape&lt;/a> to see the other images, with text&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is High Dose Vitamin D Harmful</title><link>/posts/is-high-dose-vitamin-d-harmful.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-high-dose-vitamin-d-harmful.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-high-dose-vitamin-d-harmful">Is High Dose Vitamin D Harmful?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Calcif Tissue Int Dec 2012 DOI 10.1007/s00223-012-9679-1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kerrie M. Sanders • Geoffrey C. Nicholson • Peter R. Ebeling&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K. M. Sanders (&amp;amp;) • G. C. Nicholson • P. R. Ebeling Department of Medicine, Western Health, NorthWest Academic Centre, University of Melbourne, PO Box 294, St Albans, VIC 3021, Australia e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:ksanders@unimelb.edu.au">ksanders@unimelb.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G. C. Nicholson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rural Clinical School, School of Medicine, University of Queensland, Toowoomba, QLD, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10,000 IU vitamin D daily is safe, toxicity start at 150 ng (for monotherapy)</title><link>/posts/10000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-is-safe-toxicity-start-at-150-ng-for-monotherapy.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-is-safe-toxicity-start-at-150-ng-for-monotherapy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="anti-cancer-agents-in-medicinal-chemistry-volume-13-issue-1-pp4-10-7">Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.4-10 (7)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Authors: Armin Zittermann, Sylvana Prokop, Jan F. Gummert, Jochen Borgermann&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-toxicity-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 898">Overview Toxicity of vitamin D&lt;/a> which has the following summary&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="color:#390;">Many weeks for a really large DAILY dose of vitamin D to&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#F0C;">become toxic&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h4 id="summary-of-points-of-this-paper-by-vitamin-d-councilhttpblogvitamindcouncilorg20121218vitamin-d-safety-risks-and-benefits-of-fortification-and-supplementation-dec-2012">Summary of points of this paper by &lt;a href="http://blog.vitamindcouncil.org/2012/12/18/vitamin-d-safety-risks-and-benefits-of-fortification-and-supplementation/">Vitamin D Council&lt;/a> Dec 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Data on skin synthesis of vitamin D indicate oral intake of 10,000 IU/day is safe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Concern about accidentally giving infant too much liquid vitamin D</title><link>/posts/concern-about-accidentally-giving-infant-too-much-liquid-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/concern-about-accidentally-giving-infant-too-much-liquid-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#too-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-dhttpwwwindependentiehealthtoo-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-d-3190474html">&lt;a href="http://www.independent.ie/health/too-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-d-3190474.html">Too easy to overdose on infant vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#extremely-unlikely-that-there-would-be-any-problem-with-giving-a-months-worth-of-vitamin-d-accidentally">Extremely unlikely that there would be any problem with giving a months worth of vitamin D accidentally.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="too-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-dhttpwwwindependentiehealthtoo-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-d-3190474html">&lt;a href="http://www.independent.ie/health/too-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-d-3190474.html">Too easy to overdose on infant vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>By EILISH O’REGAN, Monday August 06 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A growing number of parents are contacting the National Poisons Unit with fears that they have harmed their baby by giving them too much vitamin D supplement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The unit, based in Beaumont Hospital in Dublin, pointed out that since May 2010 it has been the policy of the Department of Health that all infants, from birth to 12 months, be given a daily supplement of 5 micrograms (200IU) of vitamin D3, to help development of bones and teeth.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>