<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blood Clotting on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/blood-clotting.html</link><description>Recent content in Blood Clotting on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/blood-clotting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Decreased need for warfarin after Vitamin D levels optimized – RCT</title><link>/posts/decreased-need-for-warfarin-after-vitamin-d-levels-optimized-rct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/decreased-need-for-warfarin-after-vitamin-d-levels-optimized-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-effect-of-treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-on-the-level-of-p-selectin-and-hs-crp-in-patients-with-thromboembolism-a-pilot-randomized-clinical-trial">The Effect of Treatment of Vitamin D Deficiency on the Level of P-Selectin and hs-CRP in Patients With Thromboembolism: A Pilot Randomized Clinical Trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Pharmacol. 2016 May 26. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jcph.774.">doi: 10.1002/jcph.774.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hejazi ME1, Modarresi-Ghazani F2, Hamishehkar H2, Mesgari-Abbasi M2, Dousti S2, Entezari-Maleki T2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Tuberculosis and Lung Disease Research Center, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Drug Applied Research Center, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tuberculosis -100 percent cure rate with 10,000 IU of vitamin D daily – RCT 2006</title><link>/posts/tuberculosis-100-percent-cure-rate-with-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-rct-2006.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tuberculosis-100-percent-cure-rate-with-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-rct-2006.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-effect-of-vitamin-d-as-supplementary-treatment-in-patients-with-moderately-advanced-pulmonary-tuberculous-lesion">The effect of vitamin D as supplementary treatment in patients with moderately advanced pulmonary tuberculous lesion.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-as-supplementary-treatment-in-patients-with-moderately-advanced-pulmonary-tuberculous-lesion">The effect of vitamin D as supplementary treatment in patients with moderately advanced pulmonary tuberculous lesion.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Med Indones. 2006 Jan-Mar;38(1):3-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nursyam EW1, Amin Z, Rumende CM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Departement of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Indonesia-dr.Cipto Mangunkusumo Hospital, Jakarta.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>to compare the vitamin D group of pulmonary tuberculosis patients with a placebo group in terms of clinical improvement, nutritional status, sputum conversion, and radiological improvement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Athletic performance and recovery – importance of vitamin D and vitamin K – 2015</title><link>/posts/athletic-performance-and-recovery-importance-of-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-2015.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/athletic-performance-and-recovery-importance-of-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-2015.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="plausible-ergogenic-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-athletic-performance-and-recovery">Plausible ergogenic effects of vitamin D on athletic performance and recovery&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of the international society of sports nutrition&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dylan T. Dahlquist2, Brad P. Dieter3 and Michael S. Koehle1 &lt;a href="mailto:michael.koehle@ubc.ca">michael.koehle@ubc.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Simon Fraser University, Biomedical Physiology and Kinesiology (BPK), 8888 University Drive - Burnaby, Vancouver, BC V5A 1S6, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this review is to examine vitamin D in the context of sport nutrition and its potential role in optimizing athletic performance. Vitamin D receptors (VDR) and vitamin D response elements (VDREs) are located in almost every tissue within the human body including skeletal muscle. The hormonally-active form of vitamin D, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D, has been shown to play critical roles in the human body and regulates over 900 gene variants. Based on the literature presented, it is plausible that vitamin D levels above the normal reference range (up to 100 nmol/L) might increase skeletal muscle function, decrease recovery time from training, increase both force and power production, and increase testosterone production, each of which could potentiate athletic performance. Therefore, maintaining higher levels of vitamin D could prove beneficial for athletic performance. Despite this situation, large portions of athletic populations are vitamin D deficient. Currently, the research is inconclusive with regards to the optimal intake of vitamin D, the specific forms of vitamin D one should ingest, and the distinct nutrient-nutrient interactions of vitamin D with vitamin K that affect arterial calcification and hypervitaminosis. Furthermore, it is possible that dosages exceeding the recommendations for vitamin D (i.e. dosages up to 4000-5000 IU/day), in combination with 50 to 1000 mcg/day of vitamin K1 and K2 could aid athletic performance. This review will investigate these topics, and specifically their relevance to athletic performance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Earthing to improve health (bare skin grounded to the earth)</title><link>/posts/off-topic-earthing-to-improve-health-bare-skin-grounded-to-the-earth.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-earthing-to-improve-health-bare-skin-grounded-to-the-earth.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="earthing-experience-by-a-person-who-has-ms-and-treats-people-with-ms---june-2019-personalized-vitamin-d3-for-ms-with-michael-cawley-facebook-greetings-from-sunny-mallorca-three-weeks-ago-i-read-clint-obers-book-on-the-medical-benefits-of-free-electrons-from-the-earth-via-grounding-what-grabbed-my-interest-was-the-amount-of-people-with-auto-immune-diseases-reporting-a-sustained-reduction-of-symptoms-from-daily-grounding-i-bought-a-clint-ober-bed-mat-and-brought-it-with-me-to-spain-after-about-10-days-i-noticed-my-energy-and-sense-of-vitality-had-improved-i-love-to-walk-in-the-hills-here-but-since-a-relapse-3-years-ago-my-legs-prefer-not-to-walk-for-more-than-2-hours-this-year-on-the-2-hour-walks-my-legs-felt-like-normal-and-i-decided-to-do-a-walk-i-thought-i-would-never-do-again-it-is-a-5-hour-walk-with-a-400-meter-elevation-which-is-intense-i-set-off-at-9-am-and-enjoyed-a-peaceful-wander-in-the-hills-my-legs-and-energy-were-perfect-and-i-felt-like-i-had-a-new-body">Earthing experience by a person who has MS AND treats people with MS - June 2019** Personalized Vitamin D3 For MS With Michael Cawley, Facebook: **&amp;ldquo;Greetings from Sunny Mallorca! Three weeks ago I read Clint Obers book on the medical benefits of free electrons from the Earth via grounding. What grabbed my interest was the amount of people with auto immune diseases reporting a sustained reduction of symptoms from daily grounding. I bought a Clint Ober bed mat and brought it with me to Spain. After about 10 days I noticed my energy and sense of vitality had improved. I love to walk in the hills here but since a relapse 3 years ago my legs prefer not to walk for more than 2 hours. This year on the 2 hour walks my legs felt like normal and I decided to do a walk I thought I would never do again. It is a 5 hour walk with a 400 meter elevation which is intense. I set off at 9 am and enjoyed a peaceful wander in the hills. My legs and energy were perfect and I felt like I had a new body.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I was grounded (verified) by socket tester for** 9 hours a night and two hours a day **with bare feet on soil for 12 days before this walk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ebola, Vitamin D, and Calcium</title><link>/posts/ebola-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ebola-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="translated-by-google-from-germanhttpwwwaerztezeitungdemedizinkrankheiteninfektionskrankheitenhaemorrhagische-fiebersid86925320--werner-slenczka--author">Translated by Google from &lt;a href="http://www.aerztezeitung.de/medizin/krankheiten/infektionskrankheiten/haemorrhagische-fieber/?sid=869253%20">German&lt;/a> Werner Slenczka = author&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Probably LinkedIn &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/werner-slenczka/72/19/4b3">https://www.linkedin.com/pub/werner-slenczka/72/19/4b3&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ebola-fever---high-mortality-rates-a-matter-of-skin-color">Ebola fever - High mortality rates a matter of skin color?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In infections with Ebola or Marburg viruses black people have a significantly higher risk of death than white. The possible reasons could have implications for therapy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Marburg virus has killed 23 percent of patients in 1967 during his first appearance in Europe (7 of 31). At that time, a staggering figure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why is too much vitamin D bad for bad hearts</title><link>/posts/why-is-too-much-vitamin-d-bad-for-bad-hearts.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-is-too-much-vitamin-d-bad-for-bad-hearts.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="clipped-from-beyond-cholesterol-section--vitamin-d-a-double-edged-swordhttpwwwwestonapriceorgmodern-diseasesbeyond-cholesterol">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.westonaprice.org/modern-diseases/beyond-cholesterol/">Beyond Cholesterol section = Vitamin D: A Double-Edged Sword?&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>While vitamin K, especially vitamin K2, seems to be straightforwardly protective, the story of vitamins A and D is more complex. When vitamins A and D are both provided abundantly, they maximize the protective effect of vitamin K, but when vitamin D is provided in great excess of vitamin A, it actually promotes abnormal, pathological calcification of soft tissues, including arteries.12,13,14 This finding suggests that vitamin D may be a double-edged sword, with the ability to either prevent or promote heart disease, depending on the dietary context in which it is provided.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thrombosis (leads to stroke) worse with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/thrombosis-leads-to-stroke-worse-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/thrombosis-leads-to-stroke-worse-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="is-there-any-association-between-thrombosis-and-tissue-factor-pathway-inhibitor-levels-in-patients-with-vitamin-d-deficiency">Is There Any Association Between Thrombosis and Tissue Factor Pathway Inhibitor Levels in Patients With Vitamin D Deficiency?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>CLIN APPL THROMB HEMOST November 6, 2013 1076029613509477&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oya Topaloglu, MD &lt;a href="mailto:oyasude@gmail.com">oyasude@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Muyesser Sayki Arslan, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Melia Karakose, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bekir Ucan, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zeynep Ginis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evrim Cakir, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Esra Tutal Akkaymak, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mustafa Sahin, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mustafa Ozbek, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Erman Cakal, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tuncay Delibasi, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: The aim of this study was to evaluate the relationship between vitamin D levels and hemostatic factors like tissue factor pathway inhibitor (TFPI).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Roundup may be source of many medical problem increases</title><link>/posts/off-topic-roundup-may-be-source-of-many-medical-problem-increases.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-roundup-may-be-source-of-many-medical-problem-increases.html</guid><description>&lt;div>
&lt;div class="field-label-inline-first">
&lt;p>Following is written By:&lt;b>&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/gmi-blogs/sayer%20ji">Sayer Ji, Founder&lt;/a>&lt;/b>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p class="rtecenter">
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Lethality of Roundup 'Weedkiller' Extends Beyond Plants To Humans, Study Suggests" src="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/sites/default/files/ckeditor/Sayer%20Ji/images/roundup_ready" style="width:300px;height:305px;" />&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A shocking new study finds that glyphosate, the active ingredient in Roundup herbicide, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;may be the most biologically disruptive chemical in our environment,&amp;rdquo; capable of contributing to a wide range of fatal human diseases.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;p>A new report published in the journal &lt;a href="http://www.mdpi.com/1099-4300/15/4/1416" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">&lt;em>Entropy&lt;/em>&lt;/a> links the active ingredient in Roundup herbicide known as glyphosate with a wide range of fatal diseases.&lt;a class="wiki" href="i" rel="">i&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D relationship to many other vitamins</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-relationship-to-many-other-vitamins.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-relationship-to-many-other-vitamins.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="to-the-substantiation-of-the-joint-use-of-vitamin-d-and-the-rest-of-the-12-vitamins-necessary-for-the-creation-and-realization-of-the-vital-functions-of-its-hormone-active-form-the-vitamin-d--12-vitamins-approach">To the Substantiation of the Joint Use of Vitamin D and the Rest of the 12 Vitamins Necessary for the Creation and Realization of the Vital Functions of its Hormone-Active Form (The Vitamin D + 12 Vitamins Approach)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Nutritional Therapeutics, 2013, 2, 1-7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>V.B. Spirichev &lt;a href="mailto:valetek@post.ru">valetek@post.ru&lt;/a>, Doctor of Biological Sciences, Moscow, Russia&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/common-deficiencies-d3-omega-3-k2-mg-b12-e-a-iodine-etc-mercola">Common deficiencies D3, Omega-3, K2, Mg, B12, E, A, Iodine, etc – Mercola Oct 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Abstract: The realization of the multiple vital functions of vitamin D in a human organism closely depends on the sufficient provision of the rest of the vitamins necessary for the creation of the hormone-active form of vitamin D, as well as on the normal realization of the vital biochemical and physiological processes it controls.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autoimmune disorder patients in Brazil helped by vitamin D – video and Facebook</title><link>/posts/autoimmune-disorder-patients-in-brazil-helped-by-vitamin-d-video-and-facebook.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/autoimmune-disorder-patients-in-brazil-helped-by-vitamin-d-video-and-facebook.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="neat-social-media-spreads-the-word-of-the-benefits-of-vitamin-d3-and-vitamin-k2">Neat: Social media spreads the word of the benefits of Vitamin D3 (and Vitamin K2)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Large doses: 20,000 to 150,000 IU/d&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dose sizes are far larger than what what others are using to prevent MS, but this size is being used to TREAT MS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="facebook-page-by-the-patientshttpswwwfacebookcomgroups528624870516079-in-portuguese">&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/528624870516079/">Facebook Page by the patients&lt;/a> in Portuguese&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>15,800 members as of Nov 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="youtube-interview-of-the-doctorhttpwwwyoutubecomwatchvciwiwim4hnm">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cIwIWim4hNM">YouTube interview of the doctor&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/brazil.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="youtube-videohttpwwwyoutubecomwatchveragu1xcy-u-in-portuguese-with-english-and-spanish-subtitles">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=erAgu1XcY-U">YouTube Video&lt;/a> In Portuguese with English and Spanish subtitles&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The documentary was made by Daniel Cunha, a Brazilian journalist.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Benefits of Vitamin D - Chart</title><link>/posts/benefits-of-vitamin-d-chart.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/benefits-of-vitamin-d-chart.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="from-vitamin-dhttpwwwbetterdietislamcomdietvitadhtml-at-betterdietislamcom----dead-2023">from &lt;a href="http://www.betterdietislam.com/diet/vitad.html">VITAMIN D&lt;/a> at BetterDietIslam.com - dead 2023&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="800">
&lt;h3 id="benefits---click-here-for-links-to-detailshttpwwwbetterdietislamcomdietvitadhtml-dead-2023">Benefits &lt;a href="http://www.betterdietislam.com/diet/vitad.html">click here for links to details&lt;/a> dead 2023&lt;/h3>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Age&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Premature aging of the human body, Signs of aging&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Birth&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>ALRI in newborns (Acute lower respiratory Infection), Important for pregnant women, Less risk of needed C-section&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Blood&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Good against high Blood pressure, Hypocalaemia (Not enough Calcium in blood), Normal blood clotting, Good against pre eclampsia (High Blood pressure during pregnancy), Good against septicemia (Blood poisoning)&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Brain&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Alert and less tired, Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease, Autism, Good against depression, Good against dementia, Listlessness, Migraine, Schizophrenia, Seizures, Severe mental retardation, Insomnia (Sleeplessness)&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Cancer&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Breast Cancer, Colon Cancer, Good against Cancer, Lung Cancer, Melanoma, Non Hodgkin&amp;rsquo;s Lymphoma, Prostate Cancer&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Children&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Child Obesity, Helps Growth, Viral infections in children&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Diabetes&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Good against diabetes, both type 1 and 2&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Ears&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Loss of hearing (deafness)&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Eyes&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Good against conjunctivitis, Macular degeneration is the most common cause of blindness in elderly, Myopia&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Fertility&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Fertility in general, Menopause hot flushes&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Heart&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Good against heart disease&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Hormones&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Hypoparathyroidism (Leads to hypocalcemia)&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Immunity&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Viral infections in children, Antibiotic, Good against cold and flu, inflammation, Lupus Erythematosis, Prevents cold if high enough levels&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Lungs&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Asthma, Tuberculosis, URTI (= Upper Respiratory Tract Infection)&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Muscles&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Aches and Pains, Athletic Performance, Muscle Pain, Post operative Muscle contractions, Spasms. Weakness in muscles&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Nutrition&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Good for Calcium absorption, Absorption of Phosphorous&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Other&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Cystic Fibrosis, MS (Multiple Sclerosis)&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Skeleton&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Rheumatoid Arthritis, Good against brittle easily broken bones, fragile bones. Important for teeth and bone, Malformed bones or joints, Osteomalacia (Softness in bones - Adult Rickets), Osteoporosis, Pain in ribs, Pain lower spine, Pain pelvis, Pain in legs, Rickets, Teeth cavities, Developing teeth, Good for teeth&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Skin&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Eczema, Good for skin, Psoriasis&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Stomach&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Crohn&amp;rsquo;s diseases, Inflammatory bowel disease&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Obesity&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Child Obesity, Regular obesity&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/proof-that-vitamin-d-works" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Proof that Vitamin D Works">Proof that Vitamin D Works&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Cholesterol, Vitamins D3 and K2, heart disease, sulfates, LDL, – Masterjohn Interview</title><link>/posts/cholesterol-vitamins-d3-and-k2-heart-disease-sulfates-ldl-masterjohn-interview.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cholesterol-vitamins-d3-and-k2-heart-disease-sulfates-ldl-masterjohn-interview.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="mercola-interviewed-dr-chris-masterohnhttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20130116cholesterol-regulates-cell-signalingaspxe_cid20130116_dnl_art_220">&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2013/01/16/cholesterol-regulates-cell-signaling.aspx?e_cid=20130116_DNL_art_2%20">Mercola interviewed Dr. Chris Masterohn&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Video is 15 minutes long&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Transcript follows&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="update-nutritional-adjuncts-to-the-fat-soluble-vitamins-a-d-and-k-httparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20130318fat-soluble-vitaminsaspxe_cid20130318_dnl_art_2utm_sourcednlutm_mediumemailutm_contentart2utm_campaign20130318_edn4-mercola-march-2013">Update &lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2013/03/18/fat-soluble-vitamins.aspx?e_cid=20130318_DNL_art_2&amp;amp;utm_source=dnl&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=art2&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20130318#_edn4">Nutritional Adjuncts to the Fat-Soluble Vitamins A, D, and K &lt;/a> Mercola March 2013&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eventually earning a reputation as “the most toxic of all the vitamins. still in textbooks in 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Zinc added to vitamin A greatly reduced conjunctiva of the eye&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="here-is-the-73-minute-transcript">Here is the 73+ minute transcript&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-special-interview-with-chris-masterjohn-jan-2013">A Special Interview with Chris Masterjohn Jan 2013&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By Dr. Joseph Mercola&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Baby-sized aspirin doubles chance of getting wet macular degeneration</title><link>/posts/off-topic-baby-sized-aspirin-doubles-chance-of-getting-wet-macular-degeneration.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-baby-sized-aspirin-doubles-chance-of-getting-wet-macular-degeneration.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Just yesterday I happened to again mention to my wife that taking baby aspirin does not really help much (decreases chance of a heart attack by about 10%) but should not hurt either, &lt;span style="color:#F00;">I was wrong!!&lt;/span>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="new-york-timeshttpwellblogsnytimescom20121218aspirin-use-tied-to-eye-disorder-dec-19-2012--commented-on-an-article-in-jama">&lt;a href="http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/12/18/aspirin-use-tied-to-eye-disorder/">New York Times&lt;/a> Dec 19, 2012 commented on an article in JAMA.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Taking baby aspirin on a regular basis (at least twice a week) was found to raise &lt;strong>neovascular macular degeneration&lt;/strong> from 1 in 200 to 1 in 100. DOUBLE!!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview of Vitamin K2 and Calcium Paradox author by Dr. Mercola</title><link>/posts/interview-of-vitamin-k2-and-calcium-paradox-author-by-dr-mercola.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/interview-of-vitamin-k2-and-calcium-paradox-author-by-dr-mercola.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="youtube-2012httpwwwyoutubecomwatchvfymexqnostq-1-hour---concerning-ca-k2-and-ostoeporosis">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fYMExQNosTQ">YouTube, 2012&lt;/a> 1 hour - concerning Ca, K2 and Ostoeporosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="interview-of-author-by-mercolahttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20121216vitamin-k2aspxe_cid20121216_snl_art_1-dec-2012">&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2012/12/16/vitamin-k2.aspx?e_cid=20121216_SNL_Art_1">Interview of author by Mercola&lt;/a> Dec 2012&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostsvitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-2908vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox--2012-booka-review--and-table-of-contents-on-vitamindwiki">&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2908">Vitamin K2 and the Calcium Paradox – 2012 book&lt;/a> Review and table of contents on VitaminDWiki&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/kate.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostsoverview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-765overview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-da">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 765">Overview Vitamin K and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights in BLUE added by VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>