<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer - After Diagnosis on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/cancer---after-diagnosis.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer - After Diagnosis on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cancer---after-diagnosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Less radiation therapy needed if have more vitamin D (lung cancer in lab)</title><link>/posts/less-radiation-therapy-needed-if-have-more-vitamin-d-lung-cancer-in-lab.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-radiation-therapy-needed-if-have-more-vitamin-d-lung-cancer-in-lab.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reduced palliative cancer pain after Vitamin D supplementation</title><link>/posts/reduced-palliative-cancer-pain-after-vitamin-d-supplementation.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reduced-palliative-cancer-pain-after-vitamin-d-supplementation.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-patients-with-palliative-cancer">Vitamin D and patients with palliative cancer&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>BMJ Support Palliat Care doi:10.1136/bmjspcare-2015-000921&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Linda Björkhem-Bergman1,2 and Peter Bergman2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Palliative Home Care and Hospice Ward, ASIH Stockholm Södra, Älvsjö, Sweden&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Division of Clinical Microbiology, Department of Laboratory Medicine, Karolinska Institutet and Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence to: Dr Linda Björkhem-Bergman, Department of Palliative Medicine and Advanced Medical Home Care, ASIH Långbro Park, Bergtallsvägen 12, Älvsjö 12559, Sweden; &lt;a href="mailto:linda.bjorkhem-bergman@ki.se">linda.bjorkhem-bergman@ki.se&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/pain-reduced-when-enough-vitamin-d-was-given-review">Pain reduced when enough vitamin D was given – review March 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – Chemotherapy can be aided by Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-chemotherapy-can-be-aided-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-chemotherapy-can-be-aided-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dna-repair-in-despair-vitamin-d-is-not-fair">DNA Repair in Despair-Vitamin D Is not Fair&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="dna-repair-in-despair-vitamin-d-is-not-fair">DNA Repair in Despair-Vitamin D Is not Fair&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Cellular Biochemistry, DOI: 10.1002/jcb.25552&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elżbieta Gocek, George P. Studzinski &lt;a href="mailto:studzins@njms.rutgers.edu">studzins@njms.rutgers.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of vitamin D as a treatment option for neoplastic diseases, once considered to have a bright future, remains controversial. The preclinical studies discussed herein show compelling evidence that Vitamin D Derivatives (VDDs) can convert some cancer and leukemia cells to a benign phenotype, by differentiation/maturation, cell cycle arrest or induction of apoptosis. Further, there is considerable, though still evolving, knowledge of the molecular mechisms underlying these changes. However, the attempts to clearly document that the treatment outcomes of human neoplastic diseases can be positively influenced by VDDs have been, so far, disappointing. The clinical trials to date of VDDs, alone or combined with other agents, have not shown consistent results. It is our contention, shared by others, that there were limitations in the design or execution of these trials which have not yet been fully addressed. Based on the connection between upregulation of JNK by VDDs and DNA repair, &lt;strong>we propose a new avenue of attack on cancer cells by increasing the toxicity of the current, only partially effective, cancer chemotherapeutic drugs by combining them with VDDs&lt;/strong> . This can impair DNA repair and thus kill the malignant cells, warranting a comprehensive study of this novel concept.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased Breast Cancer metastasis if low vitamin D or poor VDR</title><link>/posts/increased-breast-cancer-metastasis-if-low-vitamin-d-or-poor-vdr.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-breast-cancer-metastasis-if-low-vitamin-d-or-poor-vdr.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cancer treatment needs Vitamin D, Selenium, and other micronutrients</title><link>/posts/cancer-treatment-needs-vitamin-d-selenium-and-other-micronutrients.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-treatment-needs-vitamin-d-selenium-and-other-micronutrients.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chemo drug (Nitrogen Mustard in this study) side effects minimized by vitamin D (mice)</title><link>/posts/chemo-drug-nitrogen-mustard-in-this-study-side-effects-minimized-by-vitamin-d-mice.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chemo-drug-nitrogen-mustard-in-this-study-side-effects-minimized-by-vitamin-d-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="suppression-of-hyperactive-immune-responses-protects-against-nitrogen-mustard-injury">Suppression of Hyperactive Immune Responses Protects against Nitrogen Mustard Injury.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Invest Dermatol. 2015 Dec;135(12):2971-81. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/jid.2015.322.">doi: 10.1038/jid.2015.322.&lt;/a> Epub 2015 Aug 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:750px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Nitrogen Mustard was the first Chemotherapy Drug (based on WWI mustard gas) 1 atom different&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/mustard.jpg" alt="image" width="450">
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Nitrogen Mustard is still being used for&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Leukemia, Lymphoma, Hodgkin&amp;rsquo;s disease, Lung cancer, Breast cancer&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Nitrogen Mustard has major side effects (but not everyone gets ALL of them)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nausea and vomiting, Hair loss, Mouth sores, Darkening of veins, Loss of fertility&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer Chemotherapy dropped Vitamin D levels by 6 nanograms</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-dropped-vitamin-d-levels-by-6-nanograms.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-dropped-vitamin-d-levels-by-6-nanograms.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-25-0h-d3-status-and-pathological-response-to-neoadjuvant-chemotherapy-in-stage-iiiii-breast-cancer-data-from-the-neozotac-trial-boog-10-01">Vitamin D (25-0H D3) status and pathological response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in stage II/III breast cancer: Data from the NEOZOTAC trial (BOOG 10-01).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Breast. 2015 Nov 21. pii: S0960-9776(15)00230-1. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.breast.2015.10.005.">doi: 10.1016/j.breast.2015.10.005.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charehbili A1, Hamdy NA2, Smit VT3, Kessels L4, van Bochove A5, van Laarhoven HW6, Putter H7, Meershoek-Klein Kranenbarg E8, van Leeuwen-Stok AE9, van der Hoeven JJ10, van de Velde CJ8, Nortier JW10, Kroep JR11; Dutch Breast Cancer Research Group (BOOG).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less fatigue if more vitamin D (90 percent of palliative cancer were deficient)</title><link>/posts/less-fatigue-if-more-vitamin-d-90-percent-of-palliative-cancer-were-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-fatigue-if-more-vitamin-d-90-percent-of-palliative-cancer-were-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-its-association-with-fatigue-and-quality-of-life-in-advanced-cancer-patients-under-palliative-care-a-cross-sectional-study">Vitamin D deficiency and its association with fatigue and quality of life in advanced cancer patients under palliative care: A cross-sectional study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Palliat Med August 27, 2015 0269216315601954&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Montserrat Martínez-Alonso 1, Adriana Dusso 2,3; Gemma Ariza 4; Maria Nabal 5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Unit of Biostatistics and Methodological Support, IRBLLEIDA, Lleida, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Division of Experimental Nephrology, IRBLLEIDA, Lleida, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Bone and Mineral Research Unit, Hospital Universitario Central de Asturias, Oviedo, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4Rehabilitation Unit, Hospital Universitari Arnau de Vilanova de Lleida, Lleida, Spain&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X less pelvic inflammation from cancer radiation if high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/3x-less-pelvic-inflammation-from-cancer-radiation-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-less-pelvic-inflammation-from-cancer-radiation-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-the-severity-of-radiation-induced-proctitis-in-cancer-patients">Vitamin D Deficiency is Associated with the Severity of Radiation-Induced Proctitis in Cancer Patients&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Radiation Oncology, Received: December 27, 2014; Feb 11, 2015, DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijrobp.2015.02.011">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijrobp.2015.02.011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amir Ghorbanzadeh Moghaddam, MDemail, Ali Gholamrezaei, MD, Simin Hemati, MD, Associate Prof. Radiation Oncology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Radiation-induced injury to the normal tissues is a common complication of radiotherapy in cancer patients. Considering the role of vitamin D in mucosal barrier hemostasis and inflammatory responses, we investigated whether vitamin D deficiency is associated with the severity of radiation-induced acute proctitis in cancer patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast cancer chemotherapy benefits from highest vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-benefits-from-highest-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-benefits-from-highest-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pretreatment-vitamin-d-level-and-response-to-neoadjuvant-chemotherapy-in-women-with-breast-cancer-on-the-i-spy-trial-calgb-150007150015acrin6657">Pretreatment vitamin D level and response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in women with breast cancer on the I-SPY trial (CALGB 150007/150015/ACRIN6657).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Med. 2014 Jun;3(3):693-701. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/cam4.235.">doi: 10.1002/cam4.235.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Apr 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clark AS1, Chen J, Kapoor S, Friedman C, Mies C, Esserman L, DeMichele A; I-SPY1 Investigators.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>Most of the women had low levels of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The one graph which shows women with &amp;gt; 30 ng shows a nice benefit&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/breast-cancer-recurrence.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>Suspect that there would be a virtually flat survival line for women having &amp;gt; 50 ng of vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer patients at high risk of vitamin D deficiency were not tested as often (paradoxically)</title><link>/posts/cancer-patients-at-high-risk-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-were-not-tested-as-often-paradoxically.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-patients-at-high-risk-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-were-not-tested-as-often-paradoxically.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-people-with-a-solid-tumor-cancer-diagnosis-the-tip-of-the-iceberg">Low 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in people with a solid tumor cancer diagnosis: the tip of the iceberg?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Support Care Cancer. 2014 Jul;22(7):1931-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00520-014-2154-y.">doi: 10.1007/s00520-014-2154-y.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Feb 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hauser K1, Walsh D, Shrotriya S, Karafa M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1The Harry R. Horvitz Center for Palliative Medicine, Cleveland, OH, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels have been linked to both cancer incidence and poor prognosis. The frequency of 25(OH)D tests and clinical factors associated with low levels in cancer patients are unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20,000 IU weekly did not get 43 percent of Scottish Cancer patients to a level of 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/20000-iu-weekly-did-not-get-43-percent-of-scottish-cancer-patients-to-a-level-of-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/20000-iu-weekly-did-not-get-43-percent-of-scottish-cancer-patients-to-a-level-of-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-an-edinburgh-general-practice-population-and-anecdotal-evidence">Vitamin D supplementation in an Edinburgh general practice population and anecdotal evidence&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Rhein HM (1,2), Johnson G (1).&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Sighthill Health Centre, 380 Calder Road, Edinburgh EH114AU, Scotland, UK.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Centre for Population Health Sciences: GP Section, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh EH8 9AG, Scotland UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Background&lt;/strong> : After we became aware of the widespread vitamin D deficiency in our Scottish general practice population in Edinburgh at a latitude of 56; our patients have received for the past few years the offer of prescriptions for vitamin D supplements:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Chemo brain and other cognitive impairements are associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-chemo-brain-and-other-cognitive-impairements-are-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-chemo-brain-and-other-cognitive-impairements-are-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/chemo-brain.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="hints-of-cognitive-impairment-associated-with-low-vitamin-d">Hints of cognitive impairment associated with low vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/deep-sedation-in-icu-reduced-cognition-even-a-year-later-needed-more-vitamin-d">Deep sedation in ICU reduced cognition even a year later (needed more vitamin D) – Oct 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/posts/senior-moment-25x-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d&amp;quot; style=&amp;ldquo;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;ldquo;This post/category does not exist yet: &amp;ldquo;Senior moment&amp;rdquo; 25X more likely with low vitamin D - Feb 2012&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;Senior moment&amp;rdquo; 25X more likely with low vitamin D - Feb 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/dementia-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-two-thirds-of-studies-systematic-review">Dementia associated with low vitamin D in two thirds of studies – systematic review May 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chemotherapy (cisplatin) and vitamin D synergistically stop stomach cancer</title><link>/posts/chemotherapy-cisplatin-and-vitamin-d-synergistically-stop-stomach-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chemotherapy-cisplatin-and-vitamin-d-synergistically-stop-stomach-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3-and-cisplatin-synergistically-induce-apoptosis-and-cell-cycle-arrest-in-gastric-cancer-cells">1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D3 and cisplatin synergistically induce apoptosis and cell cycle arrest in gastric cancer cells.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Mol Med. 2014 Feb 24. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3892/ijmm.2014.1664.">doi: 10.3892/ijmm.2014.1664.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bao A 1, Li Y 1, Tong Y 1, Zheng H 1, Wu W 1, Wei C 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Clinical Laboratory, Renmin Hospital of Wuhan University, Wuhan, Hubei 430060, P.R. China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Clinical Laboratory, Affiliated Hospital of Youjiang Medical University for Nationalities, Baise, Guangxi 533000, P.R. China.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chemo reduced leukemia patients vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/chemo-reduced-leukemia-patients-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chemo-reduced-leukemia-patients-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-levels-in-patients-of-acute-leukemia-before-and-after-remission-induction-therapy">Vitamin D levels in patients of acute leukemia before and after remission-induction therapy.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pak J Med Sci. 2013 Jan;29(1):10-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.12669/pjms.291.2764.">doi: 10.12669/pjms.291.2764.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Naz A1, N Qureshi R2, S Shamsi T3, Mahboob T4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To determine the levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin &lt;span>[25(OH)D3]&lt;/span> in patients with acute leukemia and the effect of remission-induction chemotherapy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methodology: This study was case control, all newly diagnosed patients of acute leukemia between the age of one to sixty years and residents of Pakistan were enrolled and evaluated. Those who were unwilling or unable to provide written informed consent were excluded. All selected patients (n=86) were grouped in to acute myeloid leukemia (AML) and acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL). AML was further categorized as A1 before remission-induction (n=17) and B1 after remission induction (n=13), ALL was further categorized as A2 before remission-induction (n=31) and B2 after remission induction (n=25). The 25-hydroxyvitamin &lt;span>[25(OH)D3]&lt;/span> levels were measured in the sera of all patients (before and after remission-induction) by one step delayed chemiluminescent micro particle immunoassay (CMIA).We compared 25(OH)D3 levels in all patients before and after the remission-induction chemotherapy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D improves Cancer survival</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-improves-cancer-survival.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-improves-cancer-survival.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-inverse-relationship-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-cancer-survival">The Inverse Relationship between 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Cancer Survival:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Discussion of Causation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancers (Basel). 2013 Nov 5;5(4):1439-55. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers5041439.">doi: 10.3390/cancers5041439.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robsahm TE, Schwartz GG, Tretli S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cancer Registry of Norway, Institute of Population-based Cancer Research, Oslo 0304, Norway. &lt;a href="mailto:trude.eid.robsahm@kreftregisteret.no">trude.eid.robsahm@kreftregisteret.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer mortality rates vary inversely with geographic latitude and solar ultraviolet-B doses. This relationship may be due to an inhibitory role of vitamin D on cancer development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between vitamin D and cancer appears to be stronger for studies of cancer mortality than incidence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colorectal cancer radiation reduced 2X by calcitriol (Vitamin D) with some genes</title><link>/posts/colorectal-cancer-radiation-reduced-2x-by-calcitriol-vitamin-d-with-some-genes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-cancer-radiation-reduced-2x-by-calcitriol-vitamin-d-with-some-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="slug-expression-inhibits-calcitriol-mediated-sensitivity-to-radiation-in-colorectal-cancer">Slug expression inhibits calcitriol-mediated sensitivity to radiation in colorectal cancer.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Mol Carcinog. 2013 Aug 31. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/mc.22054.">doi: 10.1002/mc.22054.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Findlay VJ, Moretz RE, Wang C, Vaena SG, Bandurraga SG, Ashenafi M, Marshall DT, Watson DK, Camp ER.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, a reciprocal relationship between calcitriol and epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition has been described. Therefore, we hypothesized that calcitriol (1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 ) would enhance radiation sensitivity in colorectal cancer regulated by epithelial mesenchymal transition. Vitamin-D receptor, E-cadherin and vimentin protein as well as E-cadherin, Snail and Slug mRNA levels were assessed in a panel of human colorectal cancer cell lines at baseline and in response calcitriol. We defined cell lines as calcitriol sensitive based on demonstrating an enhanced epithelial phenotype with increased E-cadherin, reduced vimentin and decreased expression of Snail and Slug as well as decreased cellular migration in response to calcitriol.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer Chemotherapy and vitamin D – Review</title><link>/posts/cancer-chemotherapy-and-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-chemotherapy-and-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-pharmacokinetics-and-safety-when-used-in-conjunction-with-the-pharmaceutical-drugs-used-in-cancer-patients-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D: Pharmacokinetics and Safety When Used in Conjunction with the Pharmaceutical Drugs Used in Cancer Patients: A Systematic Review&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancers 2013, 5(1), 255-280; doi:10.3390/cancers5010255&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deborah A. Kennedy 1 , Kieran Cooley 1 , Becky Skidmore 1 Heidi Fritz 1 , Tara Campbell 1 email and Dugald Seely 1,2, &lt;a href="mailto:dseely@ccnm.edu">dseely@ccnm.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Canadian College of Naturopathic Medicine, 1255 Sheppard Avenue East, Toronto, Ontario, M2K 1E2, Canada 2 Ottawa Integrative Cancer Centre, 29 Bayswater Avenue, Ottawa, Ontario, K1Y 2E5, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer with bisphosphonates was not helped by 200 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cancer-with-bisphosphonates-was-not-helped-by-200-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-with-bisphosphonates-was-not-helped-by-200-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-oncology-patients--an-ignored-condition">Vitamin D deficiency in oncology patients&amp;ndash;an ignored condition:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="impact-on-hypocalcemia-and-quality-of-life">impact on hypocalcemia and quality of life.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Isr Med Assoc J. 2012 Oct;14(10):607-12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency in oncology patients&amp;ndash;an ignored condition: impact on hypocalcemia and quality of life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Segal E, Felder S, Haim N, Yoffe-Sheinman H, Peer A, Wollner M, Shen-Or Z, Ish-Shalom S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Metabolic Bone Diseases Unit, Rambam Health Care Campus, Haifa, Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D status is not evaluated routinely in cancer patients with bone metastasis who are treated with bisphosphonates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer - After diagnosis</title><link>/posts/cancer-after-diagnosis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-after-diagnosis.html</guid><description>&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>                  &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">click on chart for details&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="40-less-cancer-recurrence-after-breast-cancer-surgery-if-no-radiation-treatment---dec-2023">40% less Cancer recurrence after Breast Cancer surgery if NO radiation treatment - Dec 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.mdedge.com/hematology-oncology/article/266920/breast-cancer/compelling-case-skipping-rt-some-early-breast?ecd=WNL_EVE_231207_mdedge">Compelling case for skipping RT in some early breast cancers - MD Edge&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Recurrence rate: 1% in 5 years if no radiation therapy vs 1.7% if radiation therapy&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Omitting radiation therapy led to better health-related quality of life and functional and cosmetic outcomes, and the women viewed not having radiation as highly acceptable and appropriate treatment, not undertreatment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer medicine pain reduced with 4300 IU vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-medicine-pain-reduced-with-4300-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-medicine-pain-reduced-with-4300-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="highlight-from-vitamin-d-may-help-breast-cancer-survivors-stay-on-track-httpwwwmedscapecomviewarticle76627320medscape-medical-news">Highlight from &lt;a href="http://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/766273%20">Vitamin D May Help Breast Cancer Survivors Stay on Track &lt;/a>Medscape Medical News&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>2012 Annual Meeting of the American Society of Clinical Oncology®&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>aromatase inhibitors&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>half of the women have severe musculoskeletal pain from these agents, and 18% to 30% report fatigue, &lt;span>[resulting in]&lt;/span> a discontinuation rate of about 10% each year,&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>30,000 IU of oral vitamin D3 weekly on starting letrozole therapy achieved significant benefits in terms of fatigue, joint pain, and disability from joint pain.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>