<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Veterinary and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/veterinary-and-vitamin-d/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Veterinary and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/veterinary-and-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cats often have similar range of Vitamin D as humans - 10 to 30 ng</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cats-often-have-similar-range-of-vitamin-d-as-humans-10-to-30-ng/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cats-often-have-similar-range-of-vitamin-d-as-humans-10-to-30-ng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;serum-concentration-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-apparently-healthy-cats-regarding-age-gender-breed-diet-type-reproductive-status-and-housing-condition&#34;&gt;Serum concentration of 25-hydroxyvitamin D in apparently healthy cats regarding age, gender, breed, diet type, reproductive status, and housing condition&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iran J Vet Res 2023;24(3):265-269. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.22099/IJVR.2023.46793.6721.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.22099/IJVR.2023.46793.6721.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S Amirnezhad 1, S Ahmadi Sheikhsarmast 2, J Khoshnegah 3, M Mohri 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;span-stylecolororangecommercial-cat-food-has-a-lot-of-vitamin-dspan&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;Commercial cat food has a lot of Vitamin D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Optimal vitamin D levels for an effective role in immune function and rickets prevention are thought to vary, but have not yet been definitively determined. Reports on reference values of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) in cats are limited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feed Additives as Antiviral Agents: Probiotics, Vitamin D, Zn, Se, etc.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/feed-additives-as-antiviral-agents-probiotics-vitamin-d-zn-se-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/feed-additives-as-antiviral-agents-probiotics-vitamin-d-zn-se-etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;feed-additives-as-antiviral-agents-book-chapter&#34;&gt;Feed Additives as Antiviral Agents (book chapter)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-42855-5_12&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-42855-5_12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. R. Yasmin, M. N. Sohaimi, S. N. A. Azaman, S. H. Nur-Fazila &amp;amp; F. M. A. Amirul&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Viral infection is a major devastating challenge in the livestock industry. Hardy to completely eradicate the virus, the emergence of new variants accompanied by high morbidity and mortality further substantiates the problems in poultry, ruminant, and swine farms. Notifiable diseases caused by virus infection such as avian influenza (AI), infectious bursal disease (IBD), Newtle disease (ND), foot and mouth disease (FMD), Aujeszky’s disease, classical swine fever (CSF), and other viral diseases are controlled by vaccination, proper husbandry, and strict biosecurity. The nutritional factors also play a pivotal role in ensuring optimum growth and immunity of the livestock as well as safeguarding sustainable food security as a protein source to human. Continuous global demand requires crucial maintenance of the good quality and value of livestock-based protein.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UVB not help chickens much (no surprise – shined on feathers, not legs)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/uvb-not-help-chickens-much-no-surprise-shined-on-feathers-not-legs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/uvb-not-help-chickens-much-no-surprise-shined-on-feathers-not-legs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;minimal-effects-of-ultraviolet-light-supplementation-on-egg-production-egg-and-bone-quality-and-health-during-early-lay-of-laying-hens&#34;&gt;Minimal effects of ultraviolet light supplementation on egg production, egg and bone quality, and health during early lay of laying hens&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PeerJ . 2023 Mar 15;11:e14997. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.14997&#34;&gt;doi: 10.7717/peerj.14997&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Md Sohel Rana 1 2 3, Jonathon Clay 1, Prafulla Regmi 4, Dana L M Campbell 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chicken vision is sensitive to ultraviolet (UV) light containing the UVA spectrum, while UVB plays a key role in the endogenous production of vitamin D3. However, commercially available light sources are typically deficient in the UV spectrum and thus may not adequately fulfill the lighting requirements of indoor-housed laying hens. We hypothesized that supplementary UVB light may improve egg production and egg quality, and bone health during early lay relative to UVA supplementation or standard control lighting. To investigate the effects of UV light supplementation, an experiment was conducted on 252 ISA Brown hens during 16 to 27 weeks of age. Birds were housed in eighteen pens (14 hens/pen) under three different light treatment groups each with six replications: (i) UVO: standard control lighting with LED white light, (ii) UVA: control lighting plus supplemental daylight with an avian bulb, and (iii) UVA/B: control lighting plus a supplemental full spectrum reptile bulb containing both UVA and UVB wavelengths. Hen-day egg production and egg quality, blood parameters including plasma Ca and P, and serum 25(OH)D3, and hen body weight and external health scoring were measured at different age points; while bone quality was assessed at the end of the experiment at 27 weeks. Data were analyzed in JMP® 16.0 using general linear mixed models with a level set at 0.05. Results showed that UVA and UVA/B supplemented birds reached sexual maturity (50% production) 3 and 1 day earlier, respectively, than control birds. There was a trend for UV lights to increase hen-day egg production (P = 0.06). Among egg quality traits, only eggshell reflectivity and yolk index were affected by UV lights (P = 0.02 and 0.01, respectively); however, most of the egg quality traits changed over age (all P &amp;lt; 0.01). Post-hoc tests showed higher serum 25(OH)D3 in the UVA/B group relative to control hens (P &amp;lt; 0.05); but there was no treatment effect on plasma Ca and P or on bone quality parameters (all P &amp;gt; 0.05). A significant interaction was observed between light treatment and age for the number of comb wounds (P = 0.0004), with the UV supplemented hens showing more comb wounds after 24 weeks. These results demonstrated that supplemental UVA/B light had minimal effects on egg production and egg quality, whereas, UVA/B exposure may increase vitamin D3 synthesis during the early laying period. The optimum duration of exposure and level of intensity needs to be determined to ensure these benefits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2,000 IU of Vitamin D per kg of food – best growth, bone strength, etc. (pig trial)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-of-food-best-growth-bone-strength-etc-pig-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-of-food-best-growth-bone-strength-etc-pig-trial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effects-of-25ohvd3-on-growth-performance-pork-quality-and-calcium-deposit-in-growing-finishing-pigs&#34;&gt;Effects of 25(OH)VD3 on Growth Performance, Pork Quality and Calcium Deposit in Growing-Finishing Pigs&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Animals (Basel) . 2022 Dec 26;13(1):86. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ani13010086.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/ani13010086.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zeyu Zhang 1, Gang Zhang 1, Jindang Cao 2, Baoqin Qiu 2, Xiaoyu Qin 2, Jinbiao Zhao 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study was conducted to evaluate the effects of 25(OH)VD3 with different inclusion levels of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;0, 25, 50 and 75 µg/kg in the diet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  on growth performance, nutrient digestibility, bone properties and pork quality in growing-finishing pigs. The results showed that the average daily gain (p &amp;lt; 0.05) and body weight (p &amp;lt; 0.10) of pigs showed a trend of increasing quadratically as inclusion levels of 25(OH)VD3 increased.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
