<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Veterinary and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/veterinary-and-vitamin-d.html</link><description>Recent content in Veterinary and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/veterinary-and-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sheep in upper pastures had more vitamin D and better bones</title><link>/posts/sheep-in-upper-pastures-had-more-vitamin-d-and-better-bones.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sheep-in-upper-pastures-had-more-vitamin-d-and-better-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="influence-of-high-altitude-grazing-on-bone-metabolism-of-growing-sheep">Influence of high-altitude grazing on bone metabolism of growing sheep.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr (Berl). 2011 Oct 13. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1439-0396.2011.01242.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liesegang A, Hüttenmoser D, Risteli J, Leiber F, Kreuzer M, Wanner M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>?Institute of Animal Nutrition, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland ?Department of Clinical Chemistry, University of Oulu, Oulu, Finland ?ETH Zurich, Institute of Agricultural Sciences, Zurich, Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this study was to identify the effect of high alpine grazing, associated with varying pasture grass qualities and more pronounced exercise on typically steep slopes, on bone metabolism by improving bone density and enhancing bone turnover in growing sheep. Twenty-four 5-month-old sheep were randomly assigned to two groups. One group was kept at high altitude (HA; 2000-2200?m a.s.l.) for 3?months, and the other group (C; control) remained in the lowlands (400?m a.s.l.). Both groups were kept in grazing pastures with access to good-quality swards. Before the start of the experiment, blood samples were taken, the sheep were weighed, and the left metatarsus of each animal was analysed by quantitative computer tomography. &lt;strong>After 1?month&lt;/strong> , blood samples were taken and body weight was measured, followed by biweekly sampling. Finally, the animals were slaughtered, and the bones were collected for analysis of various bone parameters. Body weight development did not differ between the groups.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cattle need 66 IU of vitamin D per pound</title><link>/posts/cattle-need-66-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-pound.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cattle-need-66-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-pound.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-nutrient-requirements-of-dairy-cattle-seventh--2001">From Nutrient Requirements of Dairy Cattle: Seventh — 2001&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="subcommittee-on-dairy-cattle-nutrition-committee-on-animal-nutrition-national-research-council-408-pages">Subcommittee on Dairy Cattle Nutrition, Committee on Animal Nutrition, National Research Council 408 pages&lt;/h3>
&lt;h1 id="pdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-this-page">PDF is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="includes-vitamin-d-vitamin-k-sulfur-iodine-magnesium-and-many-others">Includes Vitamin D, Vitamin K, Sulfur, Iodine, Magnesium, and many others&lt;/h3>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d">Vitamin D&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="physiology">PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a pro-hormone, a necessary precursor for the production of the calcium regulating hormone 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D. Vitamin D can be produced within the skin of most mammals, including cattle, as a result of the photochemical conversion of 7-dehydrocholesterol to vitamin D3. In plants, ultraviolet irradiation causes photochemical conversion of ergosterol to vitamin D2. Vitamin D, supplied by the skin or the diet, is rapidly transported to and sequestered by the liver. The rapid removal of vitamin D from circulation prevents concentrations of vitamin D in blood from becoming very high; the normal concentration is 1 to 2 ng vitamin D/ml plasma (Horst and Littledike, 1982). Within the liver, vitamin D can be converted to 25-hydroxyvitamin D by vitamin D 25-hydrox-ylase and released into the blood. The production of 25-hydroxyvitamin D within the liver is dependent on the vitamin D content of the diet. Thus plasma 25-hydroxy-vitamin D concentration is the best indicator of vitamin D status of an animal (Horst et al., 1994).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Controversy cats and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/controversy-cats-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/controversy-cats-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#there-is-much-disagreement-on-the-internet-about-the-source-of-vitamin-d-for-cats">There is much disagreement on the internet about the source of vitamin D for cats&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cats-get-it-from-preyfood">Cats get it from prey/food&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cats-get-it-from-their-fur-if-they-get-time-in-the-sun">Cats get it from their fur if they get time in the sun&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cats-like-uv">Cats like UV&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cat-and-dog-distemper">Cat and Dog distemper&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="there-is-much-disagreement-on-the-internet-about-the-source-of-vitamin-d-for-cats">There is much disagreement on the internet about the source of vitamin D for cats&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="cats-get-it-from-preyfood">Cats get it from prey/food&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Example &lt;a href="http://www.2ndchance.info/birdsvitd.htm%20">How Much Vitamin D Should My Pet Receive? &lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogs and cats cannot synthesize vitamin D-3; in the wild they would obtain it by eating prey so it is added to all their complete commercial pet foods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Primates Nutrient Requirements – 2003</title><link>/posts/primates-nutrient-requirements-2003.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/primates-nutrient-requirements-2003.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="nutrient-requirements-of-nonhuman-primates-second-revised-edition">Nutrient Requirements of Nonhuman Primates: Second Revised Edition&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Committee on Animal Nutrition, Ad Hoc Committee on Nonhuman Primate Nutrition, National Research Council&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ISBN: 0-309-51524-6, 308 pages, 8.5 x 11, (2003)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Includes Vitamin D, Vitamin K, Sulfur, Iodine, Magnesium, and many others&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note IU are typically given per&lt;/strong> &lt;span style="color:#00F;">kg of FEED&lt;/span> &lt;strong>not WEIGHT&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/primates-nutrional-requirements.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki.&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d">Vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For the primate species that have been studied, vitamin D is not an essential component of the diet as long as they have adequate exposure to sunlight (Holick, 1994). But it appears to be essential in the tissues of most primates for maintenance of calcium and phosphorus homeostasis and for normal bone mineralization (Holick, 1996). In the absence of solar exposure, these primates must be exposed to sources of artificial light of appropriate wavelengths or must receive sufficient vitamin D in the diet. In this review we will try to put into perspective what is known about vitamin D in humans and to compare this information with what is known about its role in nonhuman primates and other vertebrates.!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Health and Light - Ott 1973</title><link>/posts/health-and-light-ott-1973.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/health-and-light-ott-1973.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Health and Light by John N. Ott&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-effects-of-natural-and-artificial-light-on-man-and-other-living-things">The Effects of Natural and Artificial Light on Man and Other Living Things.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>How light can work for you &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>for your health, your emotional well-being and your vibrant energy &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>no matter where you live or work!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published by Pocket Books – New York; Copyright John Ott Pictures, Inc. ; First printing 1973 – ISBN: 0-671-80537-1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reprint edition (April 1, 2000) – ISBN: 0-898-04098-1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogs – like humans – with IBD were low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dogs-like-humans-with-ibd-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dogs-like-humans-with-ibd-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-dogs-with-inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-hypoalbuminaemia">Hypovitaminosis D in dogs with inflammatory bowel disease and hypoalbuminaemia.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>A G Gow, R Else, H Evans, J L Berry, M E Herrtage and R J Mellanby J Small Anim Pract 52(8):411-418 (2011) PMID 21797872&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To compare serum vitamin D metabolites and plasma parathyroid hormone concentrations in dogs with inflammatory bowel disease and normal albumin concentration, dogs with inflammatory bowel disease and hypoalbuminaemia, healthy dogs and hospitalised ill dogs with non-gastrointestinal illness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sun-cured hay often has 2000 IU of vitamin D per kilogram</title><link>/posts/sun-cured-hay-often-has-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kilogram.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sun-cured-hay-often-has-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kilogram.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#if-he-doesnt-get-enough">If he doesn&amp;rsquo;t get enough:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>

 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h1 id="fresh-hay-has-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kilogram-1999httphorsepurinamillscomnutritionvitamindasp20">&lt;a href="http://horse.purinamills.com/nutrition/vitamind.asp%20">Fresh hay has 2000 IU of vitamin D per kilogram 1999&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>By Christine Barakat&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fast fact: Vitamin D is the only nutrient more abundant in dried forage than in fresh.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How your horse uses it: Both types of vitamin D-D2 and D3-help maintain your horse&amp;rsquo;s critical electrolyte balance by binding to calcium and magnesium, aiding in their absorption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where it&amp;rsquo;s found: Your horse synthesizes vitamin D3 within his body when ultraviolet rays from sunlight combine with a form of cholesterol naturally present in his skin. Vitamin D2 is found in the dried leaves of cut plants that have been exposed to sunlight-in other words, hay.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>6 days of 7,000,000 IU of vitamin D improved the resulting beef</title><link>/posts/6-days-of-7000000-iu-of-vitamin-d-improved-the-resulting-beef.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/6-days-of-7000000-iu-of-vitamin-d-improved-the-resulting-beef.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lots of vitamin D for steers</title><link>/posts/lots-of-vitamin-d-for-steers.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lots-of-vitamin-d-for-steers.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>10 million IU of vitamin D3 for cows was great unless had vitamin D2</title><link>/posts/10-million-iu-of-vitamin-d3-for-cows-was-great-unless-had-vitamin-d2.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10-million-iu-of-vitamin-d3-for-cows-was-great-unless-had-vitamin-d2.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reindeer can see UVA</title><link>/posts/reindeer-can-see-uva.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reindeer-can-see-uva.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="clipps-from-reindeer-see-a-weird-and-wonderful-world-of-ultraviolet-lighthttpwwwphysorgcomnews2011-05-reindeer-weird-world-ultraviolethtml">Clipps from &lt;a href="http://www.physorg.com/news/2011-05-reindeer-weird-world-ultraviolet.html">Reindeer see a weird and wonderful world of ultraviolet light&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>“Humans and almost all other mammals could never do this as our lenses just don&amp;rsquo;t let UV through into the eye.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“. . .they can handle wavelengths down to around 350-320nm, . . . “&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;When we used cameras that could pick up UV, we noticed that there are some very important things that absorb UV light and therefore appear black, contrasting strongly with the snow. This includes&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monkeys each got 1000 IU daily - but vitamin D in blood varied with HDL</title><link>/posts/monkeys-each-got-1000-iu-daily-but-vitamin-d-in-blood-varied-with-hdl.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/monkeys-each-got-1000-iu-daily-but-vitamin-d-in-blood-varied-with-hdl.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="identification-of-a-mechanism-for-increased-cardiovascular-risk-among-individuals-with-low-vitamin-d-concentrations">Identification of a mechanism for increased cardiovascular risk among individuals with low vitamin D concentrations.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Menopause. 2011 May 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schnatz PF, Nudy M, O&amp;rsquo;Sullivan DM, Ethun K, Appt SE, Clarkson TB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Departments of 1 ObGyn and 2 Internal Medicine, The Reading Hospital and Medical Center, Reading, PA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of 3 ObGyn and 4 Internal Medicine, Jefferson Medical College of Thomas Jefferson University, Philadelphia, PA; and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>5 Department of Pathology/Comparative Medicine, Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, NC.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Swine need sunshine or 500-2800 IU vitamin D3</title><link>/posts/swine-need-sunshine-or-500-2800-iu-vitamin-d3.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/swine-need-sunshine-or-500-2800-iu-vitamin-d3.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="table-is-from-article-attached-to-this-page">Table is from article attached to this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="200-lb-swine-needs-500-to-2800-iu-per-day">200 lb swine needs 500 to 2800 IU per day&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="50-lb-swine-needs-200-to-1200-iu-per-day">50 lb swine needs 200 to 1200 IU per day&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;477&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="nutrient-requirements-of-swine-10th-revised-edition-1998-httpwwwnapeduopenbookphprecord_id6016page73">&lt;a href="http://www.nap.edu/openbook.php?record_id=6016&amp;amp;page=73">Nutrient Requirements of Swine: 10th Revised Edition (1998) &lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="a-few-quotes-clipped-from-dsmhttpwwwdsmcomen_ushtmldnpnaanh_swin_vit_d_reqhtm-on-swine-and-vitamin-d">A few quotes clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.dsm.com/en_US/html/dnpna/anh_swin_vit_d_req.htm">DSM&lt;/a> on swine and vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>“Vitamin D becomes a nutritionally important factor in the &lt;strong>absence of sufficient sunlight.&lt;/strong> ”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“The &lt;strong>colors of the skin&lt;/strong> are important in determining response to irradiation. Irradiation is less effective on dark-pigmented skin. This has been shown to be true for white and black breeds of hogs. White pigs have been shown to resist vitamin D deficiency signs about &lt;strong>twice as long as colored pigs&lt;/strong> ; an average of 45 minutes of daily exposure to January sunshine for two weeks was sufficient to cure rickets in white pigs in Minnesota (Cunha, 1977).”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lambs get 10X more vitamin D3 in their milk formula than humans</title><link>/posts/lambs-get-10x-more-vitamin-d3-in-their-milk-formula-than-humans.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lambs-get-10x-more-vitamin-d3-in-their-milk-formula-than-humans.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="lambs-and-sheep-royal-instant-lamb-milk-replacer-12000-iu-lbhttpwwwroyalmilcinccomlambs_and_sheephtml">&lt;a href="http://www.royalmilcinc.com/lambs_and_sheep.html">Lambs and Sheep: Royal Instant Lamb Milk Replacer 12,000 IU /lb&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>An excellent all milk protein, high fat (30%), low lactose (less than 25%), formula made with human grade ingredients, human-edible lard and coconut oil, soluble vitamins, chelated trace minerals, selenium and zinc proteinate providing a complete milk ration for lambs until weaning. Feed Royal Instant Milk Replacer to lambs cold, manually or free choice as a substitute for ewe&amp;rsquo;s milk to maximize economic use of milk, whenever ewe&amp;rsquo;s milk is inadequate or unavailable. It will stay preserved for up to 24 hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reptiles ate as well with all UV sources</title><link>/posts/reptiles-ate-as-well-with-all-uv-sources.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reptiles-ate-as-well-with-all-uv-sources.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-vitamin-d-levels-and-skeletal-and-general-development-of-young-bearded-dragon-lizards-pogona-vitticeps-under-different-conditions-of-uv-b-radiation-exposure">Serum Vitamin D Levels and Skeletal and General Development of Young Bearded Dragon Lizards (Pogona vitticeps), under Different Conditions of UV-B Radiation Exposure&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>K.R. Kroenlein, K.L. Zimmerman, G. Saunders and S.D. Holladay&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Animal and Veterinary Advances&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Year: 2011 | Volume: 10 | Issue: 2 | Page No.: 229-234&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.3923/javaa.2011.229.234&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="click-herehttpwwwmedwelljournalscomfulltextdoijavaa2011229234-for-full-research">&lt;a href="http://www.medwelljournals.com/fulltext/?doi=javaa.2011.229.234">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for full research&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Tried many different UV sources, but the bearded dragon reptiles ate as much under each UV source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fish need vitamin D and C for their bones</title><link>/posts/fish-need-vitamin-d-and-c-for-their-bones.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fish-need-vitamin-d-and-c-for-their-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="overview-of-vitamin-d-and-c-requirements-in-fish-and-their-influence-on-the-skeletal-system">Overview of vitamin D and C requirements in fish and their influence on the skeletal system&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>M.J. Dariasa, &lt;a href="mailto:maria.darias@irta.cat">maria.darias@irta.cat&lt;/a>, D. Mazuraisa, G. Koumoundourosb, C.L. Cahua and J.L. Zambonino-Infantea&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Ifremer Marine Fish Nutrition Team, Nutrition Aquaculture and Genomics Research Unit, UMR 1067. Ifremer, Technopole Brest-Iroise, BP 70, 29280 Plouzané, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b University of Patras, Biology Department, 26500 Patras, Rio, Greece&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 6 May 2010; revised 3 December 2010; accepted 17 December 2010. Available online 7 January 2011. j.aquaculture.2010.12.030&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>