<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lupus on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/lupus.html</link><description>Recent content in Lupus on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/lupus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D2 did not help Lupus (no surprise, D2 was given weekly)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-did-not-help-lupus-no-surprise-d2-was-given-weekly.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-did-not-help-lupus-no-surprise-d2-was-given-weekly.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-in-sle-modest-association-with-disease-activity-and-urine-proteincreatinine-ratio">Vitamin D in SLE: Modest association with disease activity and urine protein/creatinine ratio&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Arthritis &amp;amp; Rheumatism Vol. 65 Issue 6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michelle Petri 1,†,*, Kayode J. Bello 1, Hong Fang 1, Laurence S. Magder 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: We investigated whether an increase in vitamin D levels in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus was associated with improvement in disease activity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: 1006 SLE patients were followed over 128 weeks. SLE patients with low levels of 25-hydroxy Vitamin D (&amp;lt;40 ng/mL) were supplemented with 50,000 units Vitamin D2 weekly, with Ca/D3 200 units twice daily. Longitudinal regression models were used to estimate the association between levels of vitamin D and various measures of disease activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus in blacks associated with low vitamin D AND short telomeres</title><link>/posts/lupus-in-blacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-short-telomeres.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-in-blacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-short-telomeres.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="systemic-lupus-erythematosus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-are-associated-with-shorter-telomere-length-among-african-americans-a-case-control-study">Systemic Lupus Erythematosus and Vitamin D Deficiency Are Associated with Shorter Telomere Length among African Americans: A Case-Control Study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2013 May 20;8(5):e63725. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0063725.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0063725.&lt;/a> Print 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hoffecker BM, Raffield LM, Kamen DL, Nowling TK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina, United States of America.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a chronic systemic autoimmune disease that disproportionately affects African American females. The causes of SLE are unknown but postulated to be a combination of genetic predisposition and environmental triggers. Vitamin D deficiency is one of the possible environmental triggers. In this study we evaluated relationships between vitamin D status, cellular aging (telomere length) and anti-telomere antibodies among African American Gullah women with SLE. The study population included African American female SLE patients and unaffected controls from the Sea Island region of South Carolina. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were measured using a nonchromatographic radioimmunoassay. Telomere length was measured in genomic DNA of peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) by monochrome multiplex quantitative PCR. Anti-telomere antibody levels were measured by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). Patients with SLE had significantly shorter telomeres and higher anti-telomere antibody titers compared to age- and gender-matched unaffected controls. There was a positive correlation between anti-telomere antibody levels and disease activity among patients and a significant correlation of shorter telomeres with lower 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in both patients and controls. In follow-up examination of a subset of the patients, the patients who remained vitamin D deficient tended to have shorter telomeres than those patients whose 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were repleted. Increasing 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in African American patients with SLE may be beneficial in maintaining telomere length and preventing cellular aging. Moreover, anti-telomere antibody levels may be a promising biomarker of SLE status and disease activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus biomarker ( regulatory T cell, treg) is associated with level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/lupus-biomarker-regulatory-t-cell-treg-is-associated-with-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-biomarker-regulatory-t-cell-treg-is-associated-with-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="association-between-the-low-levels-of-vitamin-d-and-treg-function-in-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-patients">Association between the low levels of vitamin d and treg function in systemic lupus erythematosus patients.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Acta Med Indones. 2013 Jan;45(1):26-31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Handono K, Marisa D, Kalim H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Pathology, Faculty of Medicine, Brawijaya University. Jl. Veteran Malang, Malang, Indonesia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aim: to determine the relationships between vitamin D and CCR4 expression on Treg, and Treg migratory capacity in SLE patients in Indonesia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: vitamin D level assesment, CCR4 expression on Treg and Treg migratory capacity were performed on 41 SLE patients and 20 healthy controls. Serum vitamin D levels were measured by ELISA (Cusabio). The expression of CCR4 on Treg was detected by flow cytometry and Treg migratory capacity was performed in chemotaxis chamber using CCR4 ligands, TARC and MDC, and subsequently analyzed by flow cytometry using FACS Calibur (Becton Dickinson). The number of migrated Treg is the ratio of CD4+CD25+CCR4+ cells number in lower chamber of chemotaxis compared to the total number of CD4+CD25+CCR4+ cells before migration, and stated in percentage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D increasingly associated with inflammation such as RA, TB, Lupus, and cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-increasingly-associated-with-inflammation-such-as-ra-tb-lupus-and-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-increasingly-associated-with-inflammation-such-as-ra-tb-lupus-and-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="there-are-two-articles-on-this-page">There are two articles on this page&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="an-update-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-risk-for-rheumatic-diseases">An Update: Vitamin D Deficiency and Risk for Rheumatic Diseases&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Paul Gatenby, Robyn Lucas, Ashwin Swaminathan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2013;25(2):184-191.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="diseases-include">Diseases include&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Lupus&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rheumatoid Arthritis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Systemic Vasculitis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Psoriatic Arthritis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Scleroderma&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Behcet&amp;rsquo;s Disease&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Spondyloarthropathies&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Connective Tissue Disease&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="further-emergent-evidence-for-the-vitamin-d-endocrine-system-involvement-in-autoimmune-rheumatic-disease-risk-and-prognosis">Further emergent evidence for the vitamin D endocrine system involvement in autoimmune rheumatic disease risk and prognosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Annals of Rheumatic Diseases EDITORIAL&lt;/strong> , April 2013 Vol 72 No 4&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus and Vitamin D: good evidence, no conclusions – Review</title><link>/posts/lupus-and-vitamin-d-good-evidence-no-conclusions-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-and-vitamin-d-good-evidence-no-conclusions-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-clinical-significance-of-vitamin-d-in-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-a-systematic-review">The Clinical Significance of Vitamin D in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus: A Systematic Review&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PLOS 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rajalingham Sakthiswary &lt;a href="mailto:sakthis5@hotmail.com">sakthis5@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azman Ali Raymond&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency is more prevalent among SLE patients than the general population. Over the past decade, many studies across the globe have been carried out to investigate the role of vitamin D in SLE from various clinical angles. Therefore, the aim of this systematic review is to summarise and evaluate the evidence from the published literature; focusing on the clinical significance of vitamin D in SLE.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus flareups cut in half by just 2,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/lupus-flareups-cut-in-half-by-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-flareups-cut-in-half-by-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-inflammatory-and-hemostatic-markers-and-disease-activity-in-patients-with-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-a-randomized-placebo-controlled-trial">The Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation on Inflammatory and Hemostatic Markers and Disease Activity in Patients with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus: A Randomized Placebo-controlled Trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Rheumatology jrheum.111594 Published online before print December 1, 2012,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anna Abou-Raya, Suzan Abou-Raya and Madihah Helmii&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Internal Medicine Department, Faculty of Medicine, University of Alexandria; the Biochemistry Department, Medical Research Institute; and the Alexandria Centre for Women’s Health, Alexandria, Egypt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. Abou-Raya, MD, Rheumatology and Immunology Department, Faculty of Medicine, University of Alexandria, and Alexandria Centre for Women’s Health; S. Abou-Raya, MD, Internal Medicine Department, Faculty of Medicine, University of Alexandria, and Alexandria Centre for Women’s Health; M. Helmii, MD, Biochemistry Department, Medical Research Institute.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When lupus affects the kidneys vitamin D levels drop even further</title><link>/posts/when-lupus-affects-the-kidneys-vitamin-d-levels-drop-even-further.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/when-lupus-affects-the-kidneys-vitamin-d-levels-drop-even-further.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-predictive-factors-of-low-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-systemic-lupus-erythematosus">The predictive factors of low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and vitamin D deficiency in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Rheumatol Int. 2012 Nov 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sumethkul K, Boonyaratavej S, Kitumnuaypong T, Angthararuk S, Cheewasat P, Manadee N, Sumethkul V.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatology Unit, Department of Medicine, Rajavithi Hospital, 2 Rajavithi Road, Bangkok, 10400, Thailand, &lt;a href="mailto:ckittiwan@hotmail.com">ckittiwan@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a steroid hormone with pleiotropic effects. The association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level &lt;span>[25(OH) D]&lt;/span> and lupus nephritis are not clearly known. We aim to determine serum 25(OH) D levels in patients with inactive SLE, active SLE without lupus nephritis (LN) and active SLE with LN and to identify clinical predictor of vitamin D deficiency. One hundred and eight SLE patients were included. Patients were classified as Group (Gr) 1, 2 and 3 if they had SLE disease activity index (SLEDAI) &amp;lt;3, ≥3 but no LN and ≥3 with LN. Important baseline characteristics were collected. 25(OH) D was measured by high performance liquid chromatography (HPLC). SLEDAI in Gr1, Gr2 and Gr3 was 0.7 (0.9), 5.6 (2.3) and 9.2 (5.2), respectively. 43.5 % had vitamin D insufficiency and 29.6 % had vitamin D deficiency. Mean 25(OH) D in each groups was 28.3 (8.0), 26.7 (9.5) and 19.9 (7.6) ng/ml (p &amp;lt; 0.001 comparing Gr1 and 3) (p = 0.003 comparing Gr2 and 3). Vitamin D deficiency was found in 11.1, 22.2 and 55.6 % of Gr1, 2 and 3. Linear regression analysis found that 25(OH) D was significantly correlated with serum albumin (r = 0.28, p = 0.004), inversely correlated with SLEDAI (r = -0.22, p = 0.03) and urinary protein creatinine index (UPCI) (r = -0.28, p = 0.005), but not with sun exposure score, body mass index and estimated GFR. Only UPCI was significantly inversely correlated with 25(OH) D (p = 0.02) from multiple linear regression. LN was a significant predictor of vitamin D deficiency from multivariate logistic regression (OR &lt;strong>5.97&lt;/strong> ; p = 0.006). Vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency was found in 93 and 86 % of LN with proteinuria ≥ and &amp;lt;500 mg/day. We conclude that SLE patients with LN have significantly lower vitamin D level than inactive SLE and active SLE without LN. Hence, nephritis is a significant predictor of vitamin D deficiency in SLE patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis of Autoimmunity which includes Epstein-Barr Virus and Vitamin D Deficiency – 2012</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-of-autoimmunity-which-includes-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-of-autoimmunity-which-includes-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cd8-t-cell-deficiency-epstein-barr-virus-infection-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-steps-to-autoimmunity-a-unifying-hypothesis">CD8+ T-Cell Deficiency, Epstein-Barr Virus Infection, Vitamin D Deficiency, and Steps to Autoimmunity: A Unifying Hypothesis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmune Diseases, Volume 2012 (2012), Article ID 189096, 16 pages, Review Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael P. Pender 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Medicine, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD 4072, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Brisbane, QLD 4029, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 18 August 2011; Revised 3 October 2011; Accepted 16 October 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Academic Editor: Corrado Betterle&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus flares totally eliminated by loading dose then 100000 IU of vitamin D each month</title><link>/posts/lupus-flares-totally-eliminated-by-loading-dose-then-100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-each-month.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-flares-totally-eliminated-by-loading-dose-then-100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-each-month.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="restoration-of-regulatory-and-effector-t-cell-balance-and-b-cell-homeostasis-in-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-patients-through-vitamin-d-supplementation">Restoration of regulatory and effector T cell balance and B cell homeostasis in systemic lupus erythematosus patients through vitamin D supplementation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Benjamin Terrier, Nicolas Derian, Yoland Schoindre, Wahiba Chaara, Guillaume Geri, Noel Zahr, Kuberaka Mariampillai, Michelle Rosenzwajg, Wassila Carpentier, Lucile Musset, Jean-Charles Piette, Adrien Six, David Klatzmann, David Saadoun, Patrice Cacoub and Nathalie Costedoat-Chalumeau&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arthritis Research &amp;amp; Therapy 2012, 14:R221 doi:10.1186/ar4060&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 17 October 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a T and B cell-dependent autoimmune disease characterized by the appearance of autoantibodies, a global regulatory T cells (Tregs) depletion and an increase in Th17 cells. Recent studies have shown the multifaceted immunomodulatory effects of vitamin D, notably the expansion of Tregs and the decrease of Th1 and Th17 cells. A significant correlation between higher disease activity and lower serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> was also shown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus increased when whites had low vitamin D (winter)</title><link>/posts/lupus-increased-when-whites-had-low-vitamin-d-winter.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-increased-when-whites-had-low-vitamin-d-winter.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency and diabetes – rheumatoid arthritis – lupus</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-and-diabetes-rheumatoid-arthritis-lupus.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-and-diabetes-rheumatoid-arthritis-lupus.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="disease-specific-definitions-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-need-to-be-established-in-autoimmune-and-non-autoimmune-chronic-diseases-a-retrospective-comparison-of-three-chronic-diseases">Disease-specific definitions of vitamin D deficiency need to be established in autoimmune and non-autoimmune chronic diseases: a retrospective comparison of three chronic diseases&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arthritis Res Ther. 2010; 12(5): R191. 10.1186/ar3161&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anna R Broder, corresponding author1 Jonathan N Tobin,2,3 and Chaim Putterman1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Rheumatology, Albert Einstein College of Medicine/Montefiore Medical Center, 1300 Morris Park Avenue, Bronx, NY 10461, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Epidemiology and Population Health, Albert Einstein College of Medicine, 1300 Morris Park Avenue, Bronx, NY 10461, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D patent for treating immune system diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wo2008039409httpwwwwipointpatentscopesearchenwo2008039409-world-wide-patent---2008">&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/WO2008039409">(WO2008039409)&lt;/a> World-Wide patent - 2008&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="treatment-and-prevention-of-diseases-or-conditions-of-the--immune-system-or-infectious-diseases">TREATMENT AND PREVENTION OF DISEASES OR CONDITIONS OF THE &lt;strong>IMMUNE SYSTEM OR INFECTIOUS DISEASES&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>allergic rhinitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eczema,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>psoriasis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>food allergy,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>type-1 diabetes,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>ulcerative colitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>rheumatoid arthritis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>multiple sclerosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>lupus,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>tuberculosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>parasitic infection, etc,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Lupus 8X more likely to not even have 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/lupus-8x-more-likely-to-not-even-have-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-8x-more-likely-to-not-even-have-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-an-increased-autoimmune-response-in-healthy-individuals-and-in-patients-with-systemic-lupus-erythematosus">Vitamin D deficiency is associated with an increased autoimmune response in healthy individuals and in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ann Rheum Dis. 2011 May 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ritterhouse LL, Crowe SR, Niewold TB, Kamen DL, Macwana SR, Roberts VC, Dedeke AB, Harley JB, Scofield RH, Guthridge JM, James JA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Arthritis and Clinical Immunology, Oklahoma Medical Research Foundation, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is widespread and has been associated with many chronic diseases, including autoimmune disorders. A study was undertaken to explore the impact of low vitamin D levels on autoantibody production in healthy individuals, as well as B cell hyperactivity and interferon ? (IFN?) activity in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>