<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lupus on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/lupus.html</link><description>Recent content in Lupus on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/lupus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>It is time to routinely give vitamin D to Lupus patients</title><link>/posts/it-is-time-to-routinely-give-vitamin-d-to-lupus-patients.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/it-is-time-to-routinely-give-vitamin-d-to-lupus-patients.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Connective tissue disorders (Lupus, RA, etc) treated by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/connective-tissue-disorders-lupus-ra-etc-treated-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/connective-tissue-disorders-lupus-ra-etc-treated-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lupus associated with both low vitamin D and Vitamin D receptor problems</title><link>/posts/lupus-associated-with-both-low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-d-receptor-problems.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-associated-with-both-low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-d-receptor-problems.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>If Lupus in family – 5 times more likely to get Lupus if low vitamin D and poor CYP24A1</title><link>/posts/if-lupus-in-family-5-times-more-likely-to-get-lupus-if-low-vitamin-d-and-poor-cyp24a1.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-lupus-in-family-5-times-more-likely-to-get-lupus-if-low-vitamin-d-and-poor-cyp24a1.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="combined-role-of-vitamin-d-status-and-cyp24a1-in-the-transition-to-systemic-lupus-erythematosus">Combined role of vitamin D status and CYP24A1 in the transition to systemic lupus erythematosus.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Rheum Dis. 2016 Jun 9. pii: annrheumdis-2016-209157. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/annrheumdis-2016-209157.">doi: 10.1136/annrheumdis-2016-209157.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Young KA1, Munroe ME2, Guthridge JM2, Kamen DL3, Niewold TB4, Gilkeson GS3, Weisman MH5, Ishimori ML5, Kelly J2, Gaffney PM2, Sivils KH2, Lu R6, Wallace DJ5, Karp DR7, Harley JB8, James JA6, Norris JM1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Colorado School of Public Health, Aurora, Colorado, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus – vitamin D is essential in preventing and modulating it</title><link>/posts/lupus-vitamin-d-is-essential-in-preventing-and-modulating-it.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-vitamin-d-is-essential-in-preventing-and-modulating-it.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="eppur-si-muove">Eppur Si Muove:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>vitamin D is essential in preventing and modulating SLE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lupus May 2016 vol. 25 no. 6 563-572&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S Azrielant1, Y Shoenfeld1,2⇑&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1The Zabludowicz Center for Autoimmune Diseases, Sheba Medical Center, Tel-Hashomer, Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel-Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Incumbent of the Laura Schwarz-Kip Chair for Research of Autoimmune Diseases, Tel-Aviv University, Israel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yehuda Shoenfeld, Zabludowicz Center for Autoimmune Diseases, Sheba Medical Center, Tel-Hashomer 5265601, Israel. Email: &lt;a href="mailto:shoenfel@post.tau.ac.il">shoenfel@post.tau.ac.il&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2,000 IU vitamin D recommended for pediatric rheumatology</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d-recommended-for-pediatric-rheumatology.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d-recommended-for-pediatric-rheumatology.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Juvenile Lupus fatigue reduced by vitamin D ( 50,000 IU weekly for 6 months) – RCT</title><link>/posts/juvenile-lupus-fatigue-reduced-by-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly-for-6-months-rct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/juvenile-lupus-fatigue-reduced-by-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly-for-6-months-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-randomized-double-blind-placebo-controlled-trial-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-adolescents-and-young-adults-with-juvenile-onset-sle-improvement-in-disease-activity-and-fatigue-scores">A randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial of vitamin D supplementation in adolescents and young adults with Juvenile-onset SLE: Improvement in disease activity and fatigue scores&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arthritis Care and Research, DOI: 10.1002/acr.22621&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glauce L Lima1, Juliane Paupitz1, Nadia E Aikawa1,2, Liliam Takayama1, Eloisa Bonfa1 andRosa M. R. Pereira1,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Rheumatology, Faculdade de Medicina da Universidade de São Paulo, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Pediatric Rheumatology Unit, Faculdade de Medicina da Universidade de São Paulo, Brazil&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus is associated with low vitamin D (research in Southern Hemisphere concurs)</title><link>/posts/lupus-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-research-in-southern-hemisphere-concurs.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-research-in-southern-hemisphere-concurs.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-tracks-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-activityhttpwwwmedpagetodaycomrheumatologylupus5103020-medpagetoday">&lt;a href="http://www.medpagetoday.com/Rheumatology/Lupus/51030%20">Vitamin D Tracks Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Activity&lt;/a> MedPageToday&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>“Study first in Southern Hemisphere to examine role of vitamin D in SLE disease activity”&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus not treated by monthly 50,000 IU vitamin D (no surprise) – RCT</title><link>/posts/lupus-not-treated-by-monthly-50000-iu-vitamin-d-no-surprise-rct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-not-treated-by-monthly-50000-iu-vitamin-d-no-surprise-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Musculoskeletal pain reduced with 4,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/musculoskeletal-pain-reduced-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/musculoskeletal-pain-reduced-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-randomized-double-blind-placebo-controlled-study-adding-high-dose-vitamin-d-to-analgesic-regimens-in-patients-with-musculoskeletal-pain">A randomized double-blind placebo-controlled study adding high dose vitamin D to analgesic regimens in patients with musculoskeletal pain&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Lupus April 2015 vol. 24 no. 4-5 483-489, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/0961203314558676">doi: 10.1177/0961203314558676&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O Gendelman 1,2,&lt;em>; D Itzhaki 2,3,&lt;/em>; S Makarov 2,4; M Bennun 2,4; H Amital 1,2⇑&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Medicine ‘B&amp;rsquo;, Sheba Medical Center, Tel Hashomer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel-Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Central Laboratory of Clalit Health Services, Tel-Aviv, Israel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4Department of Anesthesiology, Meir Medical Center, Kfar Saba, Israel&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus is yet again strongly associated with low vitamin D (when will supplementation be tried)</title><link>/posts/lupus-is-yet-again-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-when-will-supplementation-be-tried.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-is-yet-again-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-when-will-supplementation-be-tried.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="association-of-hypovitaminosis-d-with-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-and-inflammation">Association of hypovitaminosis D with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus and inflammation.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[Article in English, Portuguese]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Bras Nefrol. 2014 Dec;36(4):430-436.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Souza VA1, Bastos MG1, Fernandes NM1, Mansur HN2, Raposo NR1, Souza DM3, Andrade LC1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Universidade Salgado de Oliveira.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Fundação Hospitalar do Estado de Minas Gerais.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Nowadays it is described a high prevalence of hypovitaminosis D in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE), which is associated with some clinical manifestations and increased inflammatory activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Antibiotic Effects of Vitamin D – 2014</title><link>/posts/the-antibiotic-effects-of-vitamin-d-2014.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-antibiotic-effects-of-vitamin-d-2014.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Endocrine, Metabolic &amp;amp; Immune Disorders-Drug Targets Vol 14, issue 4, Pages 255-266 (12)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chunxiao Guo and Adrian F. Gombart&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Linus Pauling Institute, Department of Biochemistry and Biophysics, Oregon State University, 307 Linus Pauling Science Center, Corvallis, OR 97331, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The recent discovery that vitamin D regulates expression of the cathelicidin antimicrobial peptide gene has generated renewed interest in using vitamin D to fight infectious diseases. This review describes the historical use of vitamin D or its sources to treat infections, the mechanism of action through which vitamin D mediates its “antibiotic” effects, findings from epidemiological studies associating vitamin D deficiency with increased susceptibility to infection and clinical trials with vitamin D supplementation to treat or prevent infections. Furthermore studies examining an association between vitamin D levels and cathelicidin expression are discussed. The role of cathelcidin throughout the course of infection from the initial encounter of the pathogen to the resolution of tissue damage and inflammation indicates that individuals need to maintain adequate levels of vitamin D for an optimal immune response. In addition, for treating infections, carefully designed randomized, clinical trials that are appropriately powered to detect modest effects, target populations that are severely deficient in vitamin D, and optimized dose, dosing frequency and safety are needed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus reduced with vitamin D intervention</title><link>/posts/lupus-reduced-with-vitamin-d-intervention.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-reduced-with-vitamin-d-intervention.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-cutaneous-lupus-erythematosus-effect-of-vitamin-d-replacement-on-disease-severity">Vitamin D and cutaneous lupus erythematosus: effect of vitamin D replacement on disease severity&lt;/h4>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>CLE =cutaneous lupus erythematosus = 3.5 X more chance of Vitamin D deficiency&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cutaneous Lupus Erythematosus Disease Area and Severity Index&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Before: 0.9&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After 1 year: 2.7&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Oral vitamin D3 was recommended to cases who attended our clinic in June and July 2008, and who did not present optimal levels of 25(OH)D at or above 30 ng/ml.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 did not help Lupus (no surprise, D2 was given weekly)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-did-not-help-lupus-no-surprise-d2-was-given-weekly.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-did-not-help-lupus-no-surprise-d2-was-given-weekly.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-in-sle-modest-association-with-disease-activity-and-urine-proteincreatinine-ratio">Vitamin D in SLE: Modest association with disease activity and urine protein/creatinine ratio&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Arthritis &amp;amp; Rheumatism Vol. 65 Issue 6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michelle Petri 1,†,*, Kayode J. Bello 1, Hong Fang 1, Laurence S. Magder 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: We investigated whether an increase in vitamin D levels in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus was associated with improvement in disease activity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: 1006 SLE patients were followed over 128 weeks. SLE patients with low levels of 25-hydroxy Vitamin D (&amp;lt;40 ng/mL) were supplemented with 50,000 units Vitamin D2 weekly, with Ca/D3 200 units twice daily. Longitudinal regression models were used to estimate the association between levels of vitamin D and various measures of disease activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus in blacks associated with low vitamin D AND short telomeres</title><link>/posts/lupus-in-blacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-short-telomeres.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-in-blacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-short-telomeres.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="systemic-lupus-erythematosus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-are-associated-with-shorter-telomere-length-among-african-americans-a-case-control-study">Systemic Lupus Erythematosus and Vitamin D Deficiency Are Associated with Shorter Telomere Length among African Americans: A Case-Control Study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2013 May 20;8(5):e63725. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0063725.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0063725.&lt;/a> Print 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hoffecker BM, Raffield LM, Kamen DL, Nowling TK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina, United States of America.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a chronic systemic autoimmune disease that disproportionately affects African American females. The causes of SLE are unknown but postulated to be a combination of genetic predisposition and environmental triggers. Vitamin D deficiency is one of the possible environmental triggers. In this study we evaluated relationships between vitamin D status, cellular aging (telomere length) and anti-telomere antibodies among African American Gullah women with SLE. The study population included African American female SLE patients and unaffected controls from the Sea Island region of South Carolina. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were measured using a nonchromatographic radioimmunoassay. Telomere length was measured in genomic DNA of peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) by monochrome multiplex quantitative PCR. Anti-telomere antibody levels were measured by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). Patients with SLE had significantly shorter telomeres and higher anti-telomere antibody titers compared to age- and gender-matched unaffected controls. There was a positive correlation between anti-telomere antibody levels and disease activity among patients and a significant correlation of shorter telomeres with lower 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in both patients and controls. In follow-up examination of a subset of the patients, the patients who remained vitamin D deficient tended to have shorter telomeres than those patients whose 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were repleted. Increasing 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in African American patients with SLE may be beneficial in maintaining telomere length and preventing cellular aging. Moreover, anti-telomere antibody levels may be a promising biomarker of SLE status and disease activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus biomarker ( regulatory T cell, treg) is associated with level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/lupus-biomarker-regulatory-t-cell-treg-is-associated-with-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-biomarker-regulatory-t-cell-treg-is-associated-with-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="association-between-the-low-levels-of-vitamin-d-and-treg-function-in-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-patients">Association between the low levels of vitamin d and treg function in systemic lupus erythematosus patients.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Acta Med Indones. 2013 Jan;45(1):26-31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Handono K, Marisa D, Kalim H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Pathology, Faculty of Medicine, Brawijaya University. Jl. Veteran Malang, Malang, Indonesia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aim: to determine the relationships between vitamin D and CCR4 expression on Treg, and Treg migratory capacity in SLE patients in Indonesia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: vitamin D level assesment, CCR4 expression on Treg and Treg migratory capacity were performed on 41 SLE patients and 20 healthy controls. Serum vitamin D levels were measured by ELISA (Cusabio). The expression of CCR4 on Treg was detected by flow cytometry and Treg migratory capacity was performed in chemotaxis chamber using CCR4 ligands, TARC and MDC, and subsequently analyzed by flow cytometry using FACS Calibur (Becton Dickinson). The number of migrated Treg is the ratio of CD4+CD25+CCR4+ cells number in lower chamber of chemotaxis compared to the total number of CD4+CD25+CCR4+ cells before migration, and stated in percentage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D increasingly associated with inflammation such as RA, TB, Lupus, and cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-increasingly-associated-with-inflammation-such-as-ra-tb-lupus-and-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-increasingly-associated-with-inflammation-such-as-ra-tb-lupus-and-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="there-are-two-articles-on-this-page">There are two articles on this page&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="an-update-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-risk-for-rheumatic-diseases">An Update: Vitamin D Deficiency and Risk for Rheumatic Diseases&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Paul Gatenby, Robyn Lucas, Ashwin Swaminathan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2013;25(2):184-191.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="diseases-include">Diseases include&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Lupus&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rheumatoid Arthritis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Systemic Vasculitis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Psoriatic Arthritis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Scleroderma&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Behcet&amp;rsquo;s Disease&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Spondyloarthropathies&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Connective Tissue Disease&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="further-emergent-evidence-for-the-vitamin-d-endocrine-system-involvement-in-autoimmune-rheumatic-disease-risk-and-prognosis">Further emergent evidence for the vitamin D endocrine system involvement in autoimmune rheumatic disease risk and prognosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Annals of Rheumatic Diseases EDITORIAL&lt;/strong> , April 2013 Vol 72 No 4&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus and Vitamin D: good evidence, no conclusions – Review</title><link>/posts/lupus-and-vitamin-d-good-evidence-no-conclusions-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-and-vitamin-d-good-evidence-no-conclusions-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-clinical-significance-of-vitamin-d-in-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-a-systematic-review">The Clinical Significance of Vitamin D in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus: A Systematic Review&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PLOS 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rajalingham Sakthiswary &lt;a href="mailto:sakthis5@hotmail.com">sakthis5@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azman Ali Raymond&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency is more prevalent among SLE patients than the general population. Over the past decade, many studies across the globe have been carried out to investigate the role of vitamin D in SLE from various clinical angles. Therefore, the aim of this systematic review is to summarise and evaluate the evidence from the published literature; focusing on the clinical significance of vitamin D in SLE.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus flareups cut in half by just 2,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/lupus-flareups-cut-in-half-by-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-flareups-cut-in-half-by-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-inflammatory-and-hemostatic-markers-and-disease-activity-in-patients-with-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-a-randomized-placebo-controlled-trial">The Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation on Inflammatory and Hemostatic Markers and Disease Activity in Patients with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus: A Randomized Placebo-controlled Trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Rheumatology jrheum.111594 Published online before print December 1, 2012,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anna Abou-Raya, Suzan Abou-Raya and Madihah Helmii&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Internal Medicine Department, Faculty of Medicine, University of Alexandria; the Biochemistry Department, Medical Research Institute; and the Alexandria Centre for Women’s Health, Alexandria, Egypt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. Abou-Raya, MD, Rheumatology and Immunology Department, Faculty of Medicine, University of Alexandria, and Alexandria Centre for Women’s Health; S. Abou-Raya, MD, Internal Medicine Department, Faculty of Medicine, University of Alexandria, and Alexandria Centre for Women’s Health; M. Helmii, MD, Biochemistry Department, Medical Research Institute.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When lupus affects the kidneys vitamin D levels drop even further</title><link>/posts/when-lupus-affects-the-kidneys-vitamin-d-levels-drop-even-further.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/when-lupus-affects-the-kidneys-vitamin-d-levels-drop-even-further.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-predictive-factors-of-low-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-systemic-lupus-erythematosus">The predictive factors of low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and vitamin D deficiency in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Rheumatol Int. 2012 Nov 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sumethkul K, Boonyaratavej S, Kitumnuaypong T, Angthararuk S, Cheewasat P, Manadee N, Sumethkul V.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatology Unit, Department of Medicine, Rajavithi Hospital, 2 Rajavithi Road, Bangkok, 10400, Thailand, &lt;a href="mailto:ckittiwan@hotmail.com">ckittiwan@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a steroid hormone with pleiotropic effects. The association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level &lt;span>[25(OH) D]&lt;/span> and lupus nephritis are not clearly known. We aim to determine serum 25(OH) D levels in patients with inactive SLE, active SLE without lupus nephritis (LN) and active SLE with LN and to identify clinical predictor of vitamin D deficiency. One hundred and eight SLE patients were included. Patients were classified as Group (Gr) 1, 2 and 3 if they had SLE disease activity index (SLEDAI) &amp;lt;3, ≥3 but no LN and ≥3 with LN. Important baseline characteristics were collected. 25(OH) D was measured by high performance liquid chromatography (HPLC). SLEDAI in Gr1, Gr2 and Gr3 was 0.7 (0.9), 5.6 (2.3) and 9.2 (5.2), respectively. 43.5 % had vitamin D insufficiency and 29.6 % had vitamin D deficiency. Mean 25(OH) D in each groups was 28.3 (8.0), 26.7 (9.5) and 19.9 (7.6) ng/ml (p &amp;lt; 0.001 comparing Gr1 and 3) (p = 0.003 comparing Gr2 and 3). Vitamin D deficiency was found in 11.1, 22.2 and 55.6 % of Gr1, 2 and 3. Linear regression analysis found that 25(OH) D was significantly correlated with serum albumin (r = 0.28, p = 0.004), inversely correlated with SLEDAI (r = -0.22, p = 0.03) and urinary protein creatinine index (UPCI) (r = -0.28, p = 0.005), but not with sun exposure score, body mass index and estimated GFR. Only UPCI was significantly inversely correlated with 25(OH) D (p = 0.02) from multiple linear regression. LN was a significant predictor of vitamin D deficiency from multivariate logistic regression (OR &lt;strong>5.97&lt;/strong> ; p = 0.006). Vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency was found in 93 and 86 % of LN with proteinuria ≥ and &amp;lt;500 mg/day. We conclude that SLE patients with LN have significantly lower vitamin D level than inactive SLE and active SLE without LN. Hence, nephritis is a significant predictor of vitamin D deficiency in SLE patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis of Autoimmunity which includes Epstein-Barr Virus and Vitamin D Deficiency – 2012</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-of-autoimmunity-which-includes-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-of-autoimmunity-which-includes-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cd8-t-cell-deficiency-epstein-barr-virus-infection-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-steps-to-autoimmunity-a-unifying-hypothesis">CD8+ T-Cell Deficiency, Epstein-Barr Virus Infection, Vitamin D Deficiency, and Steps to Autoimmunity: A Unifying Hypothesis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmune Diseases, Volume 2012 (2012), Article ID 189096, 16 pages, Review Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael P. Pender 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Medicine, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD 4072, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Brisbane, QLD 4029, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 18 August 2011; Revised 3 October 2011; Accepted 16 October 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Academic Editor: Corrado Betterle&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus flares totally eliminated by loading dose then 100000 IU of vitamin D each month</title><link>/posts/lupus-flares-totally-eliminated-by-loading-dose-then-100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-each-month.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-flares-totally-eliminated-by-loading-dose-then-100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-each-month.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="restoration-of-regulatory-and-effector-t-cell-balance-and-b-cell-homeostasis-in-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-patients-through-vitamin-d-supplementation">Restoration of regulatory and effector T cell balance and B cell homeostasis in systemic lupus erythematosus patients through vitamin D supplementation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Benjamin Terrier, Nicolas Derian, Yoland Schoindre, Wahiba Chaara, Guillaume Geri, Noel Zahr, Kuberaka Mariampillai, Michelle Rosenzwajg, Wassila Carpentier, Lucile Musset, Jean-Charles Piette, Adrien Six, David Klatzmann, David Saadoun, Patrice Cacoub and Nathalie Costedoat-Chalumeau&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arthritis Research &amp;amp; Therapy 2012, 14:R221 doi:10.1186/ar4060&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 17 October 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a T and B cell-dependent autoimmune disease characterized by the appearance of autoantibodies, a global regulatory T cells (Tregs) depletion and an increase in Th17 cells. Recent studies have shown the multifaceted immunomodulatory effects of vitamin D, notably the expansion of Tregs and the decrease of Th1 and Th17 cells. A significant correlation between higher disease activity and lower serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> was also shown.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>