<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Photodynamic therapy for Cancer might be helped by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/photodynamic-therapy-for-cancer-might-be-helped-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/photodynamic-therapy-for-cancer-might-be-helped-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="biomodulatory-approaches-to-photodynamic-therapy-for-solid-tumors">Biomodulatory Approaches to Photodynamic Therapy for Solid Tumors.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancer Lett. 2012 Jul 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anand S, Ortel BJ, Pereira SP, Hasan T, Maytin EV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Dermatology, Lerner Research Institute, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA; Biomedical Engineering, Lerner Research Institute, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photodynamic Therapy (PDT) uses a photosensitizing drug in combination with visible light to kill cancer cells. PDT has an advantage over surgery or ionizing radiation because PDT can eliminate tumors without causing fibrosis or scarring. Disadvantages include the dual need for drug and light, and a generally lower efficacy for PDT versus surgery. This minireview describes basic principles of PDT, photosensitizers available, and aspects of tumor biology that may provide further opportunities for treatment optimization. An emerging biomodulatory approach, using methotrexate or Vitamin D in combination with aminolevulinate-based PDT, is described. Finally, current clinical uses of PDT for solid malignancies are reviewed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D in Cancer Patients: Above All, Do No Harm – 2009</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-in-cancer-patients-above-all-do-no-harm-2009.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-in-cancer-patients-above-all-do-no-harm-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology May 1, 2009 vol. 27 no. 13 2117-2119&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pamela J. Goodwin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Samuel Lunenfeld Research Institute, Mount Sinai Hospital and Princess Margaret Hospital, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this issue of Journal of Clinical Oncology, Crew et al 1 report results of an examination of vitamin D in 103 premenopausal breast cancer patients who participated in a 1-year trial of zoledronate compared with placebo, in which all women received daily vitamin D (400 IU) and calcium (1,000 mg). Seventy-four percent of women were vitamin D deficient at study entry shortly after diagnosis; deficiency was more common in black and Hispanic women than in white women. After 1 year, less than 15% of the white women (but no Hispanic or black women) who had been vitamin D deficient at baseline achieved sufficient levels in their blood. The authors conclude, “…our study suggests that a dose of 400 IU daily is inadequate in breast cancer patients even to maintain skeletal health, and is probably too low for meaningful anticancer effects.” They go on to comment that controversy exists as to the upper safe daily limit of vitamin D supplementation and suggest “…it may be prudent to follow serum levels of 25-OHD &lt;span>[25-hydroxyvitamin D]&lt;/span>…” This carefully conducted study echoes results recently reported by Neuhouser et al 2 (that approximately three fourths of patients with breast cancer from Los Angeles had inadequate blood levels of vitamin D) and by our group3 (that the same proportion of patients with breast cancer in Toronto had inadequate levels).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>