<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Children with Cancer were 3X more likely to be vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/children-with-cancer-were-3x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-with-cancer-were-3x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-children-with-cancer">Vitamin D Deficiency in Children With Cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2013 Jul 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Helou M, Ning Y, Yang S, Irvine P, Bachmann LM, Godder K, Massey G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatric Hematology/Oncology, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Richmond, Medical College of Virginia †Department of Epidemiology and Community Health, Virginia Commonwealth University ‡Medical College of Virginia §Virginia Commonwealth University Health System, Richmond, VA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A limited number of small studies have examined the vitamin D status of pediatric oncology patients, and the results indicate an increased prevalence of hypovitaminosis. We conducted a cross-sectional study with the primary aim of describing the vitamin D status of our pediatric cancer patients and any associations with demographic characteristics. Our secondary aim was to compare this prevalence to that of a healthy population. We collected data on children seen in our clinic and determined the overall prevalence of hypovitaminosis. &lt;strong>We then compared this prevalence to that of healthy populations described in the literature&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects against many types of health problems – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-effects-on-musculoskeletal-health-immunity-autoimmunity-cardiovascular-disease-cancer-fertility-pregnancy-dementia-and-mortality-a-review-of-recent-evidence">Vitamin D effects on musculoskeletal health, immunity, autoimmunity, cardiovascular disease, cancer, fertility, pregnancy, dementia and mortality-A review of recent evidence.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmun Rev. 2013 Mar 28. pii: S1568-9972(13)00040-2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.">doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pawel Pludowski a &lt;a href="mailto:p.pludowski@czd.pl">p.pludowski@czd.pl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael F. Holick b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Pilzc, d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carol L. Wagner e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce W. Hollis e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant f,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yehuda Shoenfeld g,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elisabeth Lerchbaum c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David J. Llewellyn h,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katharina Kienreich c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maya Soni h&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Biochemistry, Radioimmunology and Experimental Medicine, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Health Institute, Warsaw, Poland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less Solar Radiation was associated with more Cancer - 1941</title><link>/posts/less-solar-radiation-was-associated-with-more-cancer-1941.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-solar-radiation-was-associated-with-more-cancer-1941.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-1941-paper-on-solar-radiation-and-cancer-references-a-1912-paper-on-the-same-subject">The 1941 paper on Solar Radiation and Cancer references a 1912 paper on the same subject&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cancer-vs-percent-of-agriculture-in-the-state">Cancer vs percent of agriculture in the state&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cancer-and-latitude">Cancer and latitude&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-1941-paper-on-solar-radiation-and-cancer-references-a-1912-paper-on-the-same-subject">The 1941 paper on Solar Radiation and Cancer references a 1912 paper on the same subject&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Relation of Solar Radiation to Cancer Mortality in North America&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frank L. Apperly, M.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(From the Department of Pathology, Medical College o [ Virginia, Richmond, Virginia)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some childhood cancer 30% less likely in parts of California with more UVB</title><link>/posts/some-childhood-cancer-30-percent-less-likely-in-parts-of-california-with-more-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-childhood-cancer-30-percent-less-likely-in-parts-of-california-with-more-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="solar-uv-radiation-and-cancer-in-young-children">Solar UV radiation and cancer in young children&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Christina A. Lombardi 1, Julia E. Heck 2, Myles Cockburn 3, and Beate Ritz 4,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Epidemiology, UCLA Fielding School of Public Health&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Public Health, University of California&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Preventive Medicine, University of Southern California&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 UCLA Fielding School of Public Health&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵* Corresponding Author: Beate Ritz, UCLA Fielding School of Public Health, United States &lt;a href="mailto:britz@ucla.edu">britz@ucla.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Studies have shown that higher UV radiation exposure (UVR) may be related to lower risk of some cancers in adults. Recently an ecological study reported lower risks of some cancers among children living in higher UVR cities and countries. In a large population-based case-control study in California we tested the hypothesis that specific childhood cancers may be influenced by UVR.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer associations, including problems with too much vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cancer-associations-including-problems-with-too-much-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-associations-including-problems-with-too-much-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-cancer-risk-in-older-adults-results-from-a-large-german-prospective-cohort-study">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Cancer Risk in Older Adults: Results from a Large German Prospective Cohort Study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiology, Biomarkers &amp;amp; Prevention, March 5, 2013; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1158/1055-9965.EPI-12-1332">doi: 10.1158/1055-9965.EPI-12-1332&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>José M. Ordóñez-Mena 1, Ben Schöttker 1, Ulrike Haug 2, Heiko Müller 1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Josef Köhrle 3, Lutz Schomburg 3, Bernd Holleczek 4, and Hermann Brenner 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors&amp;rsquo; Affiliations: Divisions of 1Clinical Epidemiology and Aging Research and 2Preventive Oncology, German Cancer Research Center, Heidelberg; 3Institut für Experimentelle Endokrinologie, Charité University Medicine Berlin, Berlin; and 4Saarland Cancer Registry, Saarbrücken, Germany&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D strongly related to death due to tobacco cancer, but not others</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-strongly-related-to-death-due-to-tobacco-cancer-but-not-others.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-strongly-related-to-death-due-to-tobacco-cancer-but-not-others.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="low-plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-risk-of-tobacco-related-cancer">Low Plasma 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Risk of Tobacco-Related Cancer&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Clinical Chemistry March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shoaib Afzal 1, Stig E. Bojesen 1,2,3 and Børge G. Nordestgaard 1,2,3,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 The Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Herlev Hospital,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 The Copenhagen City Heart study, Frederiksberg Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital, Copenhagen, Denmark;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵*Address correspondence to this author at: Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Herlev Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital, Herlev Ringvej 75, DK-2730 Herlev, Denmark. Fax +45-38683311; e-mail &lt;a href="mailto:Boerge.Nordestgaard@regionh.dk">Boerge.Nordestgaard@regionh.dk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D increasingly associated with inflammation such as RA, TB, Lupus, and cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-increasingly-associated-with-inflammation-such-as-ra-tb-lupus-and-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-increasingly-associated-with-inflammation-such-as-ra-tb-lupus-and-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="there-are-two-articles-on-this-page">There are two articles on this page&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="an-update-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-risk-for-rheumatic-diseases">An Update: Vitamin D Deficiency and Risk for Rheumatic Diseases&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Paul Gatenby, Robyn Lucas, Ashwin Swaminathan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2013;25(2):184-191.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="diseases-include">Diseases include&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Lupus&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rheumatoid Arthritis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Systemic Vasculitis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Psoriatic Arthritis&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Scleroderma&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Behcet&amp;rsquo;s Disease&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Spondyloarthropathies&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Connective Tissue Disease&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="further-emergent-evidence-for-the-vitamin-d-endocrine-system-involvement-in-autoimmune-rheumatic-disease-risk-and-prognosis">Further emergent evidence for the vitamin D endocrine system involvement in autoimmune rheumatic disease risk and prognosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Annals of Rheumatic Diseases EDITORIAL&lt;/strong> , April 2013 Vol 72 No 4&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The sun appears better at reducing incidence of some cancers than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-prevention-of-cancer-by-sun-exposure-more-than-just-the-effect-of-vitamin-d--a-systematic-review-of-epidemiological-studies">Is prevention of cancer by sun exposure more than just the effect of vitamin D? -A systematic review of epidemiological studies.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Cancer. 2012 Dec 10. pii: S0959-8049(12)00885-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.">doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van der Rhee H, Coebergh JW, de Vries E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Hagaziekenhuis, P.O. Box 40551, Leyweg 275, 2504 LN Den Haag, Zuid-Holland, The Netherlands. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:hvdrhee@casema.nl">hvdrhee@casema.nl&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The number of studies reporting on the association between sunlight exposure, vitamin D and cancer risk is steadily increasing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Relevance of Vitamin D in Bone and Muscle Health of Cancer Patients</title><link>/posts/relevance-of-vitamin-d-in-bone-and-muscle-health-of-cancer-patients.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/relevance-of-vitamin-d-in-bone-and-muscle-health-of-cancer-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.58-64 (7)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author: Heike Bischoff-Ferrari&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer patients with advanced disease frequently feel weak and fatigued, and have an increased risk of fracture. At the same time several reports describe the high prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in these patients. This review will summarize the impact of vitamin D deficiency on muscle weakness and fracture risk. While larger clinical trials of vitamin D supplementation are lacking in cancer patients, the evidence from clinical trials among older adults of the general population support a significant benefit of vitamin D on muscle strength, and fall and fracture reduction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solar UVB reduces Cancer Risk – Grant,</title><link>/posts/solar-uvb-reduces-cancer-risk-grant.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/solar-uvb-reduces-cancer-risk-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="update-on-evidence-that-support-a-role-of-solar-ultraviolet-b-irradiance-in-reducing-cancer-risk">Update on Evidence that Support a Role of Solar Ultraviolet-B Irradiance in Reducing Cancer Risk&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.140-146 (7)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author: William B. Grant&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="this-paper-was-in-a-jan-2013-issue-of-span-stylecolor090anti-cancer-agents-in-medicinal-chemistryspan">This paper was in a Jan 2013 issue of &lt;span style="color:#090;">Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h5 id="articles-copied-to-vitamindwiki-include">Articles copied to VitaminDWiki include&lt;/h5>
&lt;html xmlns:v="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:vml"
&lt;p>xmlns:o=&amp;ldquo;urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>xmlns:w=&amp;ldquo;urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:word&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>xmlns=&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40%22%3E">http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;head>
&lt;meta http-equiv=Content-Type content="text/html; charset=windows-1252">
&lt;meta name=ProgId content=Word.Document>
&lt;meta name=Generator content="Microsoft Word 10">
&lt;meta name=Originator content="Microsoft Word 10">
&lt;link rel=File-List href="Jan%202013%20Special%20Issue_files/filelist.xml">
&lt;title>• Solar UVB reduces Cancer Risk – Grant, Jan 2013&lt;/title>
&lt;!--[if gte mso 9]>&lt;xml>

&lt;/xml>&lt;![endif]-->&lt;!--[if gte mso 9]>&lt;xml>
&lt;p>&lt;/xml>&amp;lt;![endif]&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Anti-cancer Actions of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/the-anti-cancer-actions-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-anti-cancer-actions-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.126-139 (14)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Kun-Chun Chiang, Tai C. Chen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D3 is biologically inert. To become active, it requires two successive hydroxylation steps catalyzed by two cytochrome P450 enzymes, first to synthesize the pro-hormone 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 &lt;span>[25(OH)D3]&lt;/span> and then the active hormone 1α,25- dihydroxyvitamin D3 &lt;span>[1α,25(OH)2D3]&lt;/span>. 1α,25(OH)2D3 has high affinity for the vitamin D receptor (VDR), a transcription factor and a member of the steroid receptor superfamily. Through VDR, 1α,25(OH)2D3 regulates more than 200 genes in mammals, including those involved in the calcium and phosphorus homeostasis, immune function, reproduction, cardiovascular, central nerve system, inflammation, angiogenesis, and cellular proliferation, differentiation and apoptosis. Due to its versatile roles in maintaining and regulating normal cellular phenotypes and functions, 1α,25(OH)2D3 has been implicated as an anti-cancer agent. In fact, ecological and epidemiologic data have linked vitamin D deficiency with the incidence and mortality of many types of cancer. More importantly, in vitro and in vivo animal model studies have clearly demonstrated the anti-tumor effects of vitamin D. In this review, we describe the anticancer actions of vitamin D, with special emphasis on different pathways underlying the VDR-mediated genomic as well as less-defined non-genomic actions of vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Cancer Mortality – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-mortality-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-mortality-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-mortality-systematic-review-of-prospective-epidemiological-studies">Vitamin D and Cancer Mortality: Systematic Review of Prospective Epidemiological Studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.107-117 (11)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Pilz, Katharina Kienreich, Andreas Tomaschitz, Eberhard Ritz, Elisabeth Lerchbaum, Barbara Obermayer-Pietsch, Veronika Matzi, Joerg Lindenmann, Winfried Marz, Sara Gandini, Jacqueline M. Dekker&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accumulating evidence from experimental and epidemiological studies suggests that vitamin D deficiency might be a causal risk factor for cancer and therewith associated mortality. We performed a systematic review in Medline up to February 2012 to identify prospective studies on 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) and cancer mortality as well as on 25(OH)D and survival in cancer patients. Our search retrieved 13 studies on cancer-specific mortality and 20 studies on overall mortality in cancer patients. Data on 25(OH)D and cancer mortality were mainly derived from general populations. The results were inconsistent and yielded either no, inverse or positive associations. By contrast, the majority of studies in cancer patients showed that patients with higher 25(OH)D levels had a decreased risk of mortality. This relationship was particularly evident in cohorts of colorectal cancer patients. In contrast, there was no indication for increased mortality risk with higher vitamin D levels in any cancer cohort. In conclusion, the relationship of vitamin D status and cancer specific mortality is still unclear and warrants further studies. Our results provide a strong rationale to perform prospective randomized controlled studies to document a potential effect of vitamin D supplementation on survival in cancer patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Supplementation and Cancer - Review of RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-and-cancer-review-of-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-and-cancer-review-of-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-and-cancer">Vitamin D Supplementation and Cancer:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="review-of-randomized-controlled-trials">Review of Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.118-125 (8)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Matteo Lazzeroni, Davide Serrano, Stefan Pilz, Sara Gandini&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Data from experimental studies suggest that vitamin D receptor activation exerts anti-cancer effects on virtually all steps of carcinogenesis. Epidemiological data support an inverse association of vitamin D serum levels and vitamin D receptor polymorphisms with cancer incidence and mortality. Based on this promising rationale for use of vitamin D and its analogues in cancer prevention and treatment, several interventional studies have been initiated and partially published. Trials with vitamin D were mainly organized for the prevention of fracture in elderly people, usually in association with calcium supplements. Prevention studies with vitamin D have rarely been done in the context of vitamin D to evaluate a protective effect on cancer. Findings from prospective cohort studies on colorectal cancer risk and on mortality constitute pieces of evidence strong enough to consider that previous randomized controlled trials (RCTs) of vitamin D use and cancer may not have correctly addressed the question, and that new randomized trials should be organized. The reasons are due to several unsolved issues including selection of the effective dose, varying baseline levels of subjects before randomization, compliance with the intervention, contamination of the placebo group (i.e., intake of vitamin D supplements by subjects allocated to the placebo group) and unknown effective lag time between start of the intervention and disease onset. The present review summarizes the existing knowledge on vitamin D RCTs and cancer. In addition we also briefly describe the design of some ongoing trials on vitamin D supplementation and cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, Sunlight and Cancer Connection – Holick</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-sunlight-and-cancer-connection-holick.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-sunlight-and-cancer-connection-holick.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.70-82 (13)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author: Michael F. Holick&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF with ALL graphics is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been more than 100 years when it was first appreciated that increased sun exposure reduced risk of dying of cancer. The most beneficial effect of sun exposure is the production of vitamin D in the skin. Recent evidence suggests that most cells in the body not only have a vitamin D receptor but also have the capacity to convert 25-hydroxyvitamin D to 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D. Once formed 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D can inhibit cellular proliferation, induce cellular maturation, inhibit angiogenesis and ultimately cause apoptosis to prevent malignancy. A multitude of studies have associated improved vitamin D status with decreased risk for developing several deadly cancers including colon, breast, pancreatic and ovarian cancers. Patients with cancer are at high risk for vitamin D deficiency. Sensible sun exposure, vitamin D fortification and vitamin D supplementation should be encouraged to improve the vitamin D status of children and adults not only for bone health but for reducing risk of developing and dying of cancer. The goal is to achieve a blood level of 25-hydroxyvitamin D of 40-60 ng/mL. This can be accomplished by children taking 600-1000 and adults 1500-2000 international units (IU) vitamin D daily from diet and supplements along with sensible sun exposure when the sun is capable of producing vitamin D in the skin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Vitamin D prevents many cancers (c-MYC)</title><link>/posts/how-vitamin-d-prevents-many-cancers-c-myc.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-vitamin-d-prevents-many-cancers-c-myc.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-receptor-as-a-master-regulator-of-the-c-mycmxd1-network">Vitamin D receptor as a master regulator of the c-MYC/MXD1 network&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-receptor-as-a-master-regulator-of-the-c-mycmxd1-network">Vitamin D receptor as a master regulator of the c-MYC/MXD1 network&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PNAS November 13, 2012 vol. 109 no. 46 18827-18832&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reyhaneh Salehi-Tabara, Loan Nguyen-Yamamotoa, Luz E. Tavera-Mendozaa, Thomas Quailb, Vassil Dimitrovb, Beum-Soo Anb,c, Leon Glassb, David Goltzmana,b, and John H. Whitea,b, &lt;a href="mailto:john.white@mcgill.ca">john.white@mcgill.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Departments of Medicine and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Physiology, McGill University, Montreal, QC, Canada H3G 1Y6; and&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Big Pharma continues to seek a patentable form of vitamin D for Breast Cancer</title><link>/posts/big-pharma-continues-to-seek-a-patentable-form-of-vitamin-d-for-breast-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/big-pharma-continues-to-seek-a-patentable-form-of-vitamin-d-for-breast-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>A review of the evidence regarding the solar ultraviolet-B-vitamin D-cancer hypothesis</title><link>/posts/a-review-of-the-evidence-regarding-the-solar-ultraviolet-b-vitamin-d-cancer-hypothesis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-review-of-the-evidence-regarding-the-solar-ultraviolet-b-vitamin-d-cancer-hypothesis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D still appears to reduce Cancer Mortality – Systematic Review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-still-appears-to-reduce-cancer-mortality-systematic-review.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-still-appears-to-reduce-cancer-mortality-systematic-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-mortality">Vitamin D and Cancer Mortality:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="systematic-review-of-prospective-epidemiological-studies">Systematic Review of Prospective Epidemiological Studies.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Anticancer Agents Med Chem. 2012 Oct 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pilz S, Kienreich K, Tomaschitz A, Ritz E, Lerchbaum E, Obermayer-Pietsch B, Matzi V, Lindenmann J, März W, Gandini S, Dekker JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, The Netherlands. &lt;a href="mailto:stefan.pilz@meduni-graz.at">stefan.pilz@meduni-graz.at&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accumulating evidence from experimental and epidemiological studies suggests that vitamin D deficiency might be a causal risk factor for cancer and therewith associated mortality. We performed a systematic review in Medline up to February 2012 to identify prospective studies on 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) and cancer mortality as well as on 25(OH)D and survival in cancer patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CYP24A1 gene in cancer cells may actually remove vitamin D from the blood</title><link>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-in-cancer-cells-may-actually-remove-vitamin-d-from-the-blood.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-in-cancer-cells-may-actually-remove-vitamin-d-from-the-blood.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="24-hydroxylase-in-cancer-impact-on-vitamin-d-based-anticancer-therapeutics">24-Hydroxylase in Cancer: Impact on Vitamin D-based Anticancer Therapeutics.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2012 Oct 8. pii: S0960-0760(12)00200-2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2012.09.031">doi: 10.1016/j.jsbmb.2012.09.031&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luo W, Hershberger PA, Trump DL, Johnson CS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The active vitamin D hormone 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) (1,25(OH)(2)D(3)) plays a major role in regulating calcium homeostasis and bone mineralization. 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) also modulates cellular proliferation and differentiation in a variety of cell types. 24-hydroxylase, encoded by the CYP24A1 gene, is the key enzyme which converts 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) to less active calcitroic acid.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels very low for some childhood cancers, then got lower</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-very-low-for-some-childhood-cancers-then-got-lower.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-very-low-for-some-childhood-cancers-then-got-lower.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-levels-differ-by-cancer-diagnosis-and-decline-over-time-in-survivors-of-childhood-cancer">Vitamin D levels differ by cancer diagnosis and decline over time in survivors of childhood cancer†&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatric Blood &amp;amp; Cancer DOI: 10.1002/pbc.24349&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Galit P. Rosen MD1,2,*, Kristen L. Beebe MS, PA-C1,3, Gabriel Q. Shaibi PhD4,5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Center for Cancer and Blood Disorders, Phoenix Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Phoenix, Arizona&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Child Health, UA College of Medicine-Phoenix, Phoenix, Arizona&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Division of Hematology/Oncology, Mayo Clinic Arizona, Phoenix, Arizona&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Division of Endocrinology and Diabetes, Phoenix Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Phoenix, Arizona&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More US deaths due to cancer than heart if dark skinned</title><link>/posts/more-us-deaths-due-to-cancer-than-heart-if-dark-skinned.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-us-deaths-due-to-cancer-than-heart-if-dark-skinned.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and cancer: a view based of all models</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-a-view-based-of-all-models.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-a-view-based-of-all-models.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-integration-of-cellular-biology-molecular-mechanisms-and-animal-models">Vitamin D and cancer: integration of cellular biology, molecular mechanisms and animal models.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Welsh J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scand J Clin Lab Invest Suppl. 2012 Apr;243:103-11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer Research Center, University at Albany, Rensselaer, NY 12144, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:jwelsh@albany.edu">jwelsh@albany.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#090;">Probably presented at the Bermeyer Coonference in Garmishpartenkirchen (Germany) in March 2012&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiologic data suggest that the incidence and severity of many types of cancer inversely correlates with indices of vitamin D status. The vitamin D receptor (VDR) is highly expressed in epithelial cells at risk for carcinogenesis including those resident in skin, breast, prostate and colon, providing a direct molecular link by which vitamin D status impacts on carcinogenesis. Consistent with this concept, activation of VDR by its ligand 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)(2)D) triggers comprehensive genomic changes in epithelial cells that contribute to maintenance of the differentiated phenotype, resistance to cellular stresses and protection of the genome. Many epithelial cells also express the vitamin D metabolizing enzyme CYP27B1 which enables autocrine generation of 1,25(OH)(2)D from the circulating vitamin D metabolite 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D), critically linking overall vitamin D status with cellular anti-tumor actions. Furthermore, pre-clinical studies in animal models have demonstrated that dietary supplementation with vitamin D or chronic treatment with VDR agonists decreases tumor development in skin, colon, prostate and breast. Conversely, deletion of the VDR gene in mice alters the balance between proliferation and apoptosis, increases oxidative DNA damage, and enhances susceptibility to carcinogenesis in these tissues. Because VDR expression is retained in many human tumors, vitamin D status may be an important modulator of cancer progression in persons living with cancer. Collectively, these observations reinforce the need to further define the molecular actions of the VDR and the human requirement for vitamin D in relation to cancer development and progression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Cancer and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/review-of-cancer-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-cancer-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Vitamin D and Cancer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frontier Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2012; 3: 58.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2012 April 23. Prepublished online 2012 February 20. PMCID: PMC3355893&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laura Vuolo,1,* Carolina Di Somma,2 Antongiulio Faggiano,1 and Annamaria Colao1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D system is a complex pathway that includes precursors, active metabolites, enzymes, and receptors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This complex system actives several molecular pathways and mediates a multitude of functions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to the classical role in calcium and bone homeostasis, vitamin D plays “non-calcemic” effects in host defense, inflammation, immunity, and cancer processes as recognized in vitro and in vivo studies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Photodynamic therapy for Cancer might be helped by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/photodynamic-therapy-for-cancer-might-be-helped-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/photodynamic-therapy-for-cancer-might-be-helped-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="biomodulatory-approaches-to-photodynamic-therapy-for-solid-tumors">Biomodulatory Approaches to Photodynamic Therapy for Solid Tumors.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancer Lett. 2012 Jul 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anand S, Ortel BJ, Pereira SP, Hasan T, Maytin EV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Dermatology, Lerner Research Institute, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA; Biomedical Engineering, Lerner Research Institute, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photodynamic Therapy (PDT) uses a photosensitizing drug in combination with visible light to kill cancer cells. PDT has an advantage over surgery or ionizing radiation because PDT can eliminate tumors without causing fibrosis or scarring. Disadvantages include the dual need for drug and light, and a generally lower efficacy for PDT versus surgery. This minireview describes basic principles of PDT, photosensitizers available, and aspects of tumor biology that may provide further opportunities for treatment optimization. An emerging biomodulatory approach, using methotrexate or Vitamin D in combination with aminolevulinate-based PDT, is described. Finally, current clinical uses of PDT for solid malignancies are reviewed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D in Cancer Patients: Above All, Do No Harm – 2009</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-in-cancer-patients-above-all-do-no-harm-2009.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-in-cancer-patients-above-all-do-no-harm-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology May 1, 2009 vol. 27 no. 13 2117-2119&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pamela J. Goodwin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Samuel Lunenfeld Research Institute, Mount Sinai Hospital and Princess Margaret Hospital, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this issue of Journal of Clinical Oncology, Crew et al 1 report results of an examination of vitamin D in 103 premenopausal breast cancer patients who participated in a 1-year trial of zoledronate compared with placebo, in which all women received daily vitamin D (400 IU) and calcium (1,000 mg). Seventy-four percent of women were vitamin D deficient at study entry shortly after diagnosis; deficiency was more common in black and Hispanic women than in white women. After 1 year, less than 15% of the white women (but no Hispanic or black women) who had been vitamin D deficient at baseline achieved sufficient levels in their blood. The authors conclude, “…our study suggests that a dose of 400 IU daily is inadequate in breast cancer patients even to maintain skeletal health, and is probably too low for meaningful anticancer effects.” They go on to comment that controversy exists as to the upper safe daily limit of vitamin D supplementation and suggest “…it may be prudent to follow serum levels of 25-OHD &lt;span>[25-hydroxyvitamin D]&lt;/span>…” This carefully conducted study echoes results recently reported by Neuhouser et al 2 (that approximately three fourths of patients with breast cancer from Los Angeles had inadequate blood levels of vitamin D) and by our group3 (that the same proportion of patients with breast cancer in Toronto had inadequate levels).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Not enough women willing to stop taking vitamin D to permit breast cancer clinical trial</title><link>/posts/not-enough-women-willing-to-stop-taking-vitamin-d-to-permit-breast-cancer-clinical-trial.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/not-enough-women-willing-to-stop-taking-vitamin-d-to-permit-breast-cancer-clinical-trial.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>More UVB is associated with less cancer – study of 450,000 people</title><link>/posts/more-uvb-is-associated-with-less-cancer-study-of-450000-people.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-uvb-is-associated-with-less-cancer-study-of-450000-people.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prospective-study-of-ultraviolet-radiation-exposure-and-risk-of-cancer-in-the-us">Prospective study of ultraviolet radiation exposure and risk of cancer in the U.S.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Cancer. 2012 Apr 26. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ijc.27619.">doi: 10.1002/ijc.27619.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lin SW, Wheeler DC, Park Y, Cahoon EK, Hollenbeck AR, Michal Freedman D, Abne CC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer Prevention Fellowship Program, National Cancer Institute, Bethesda, MD; Division of Cancer Epidemiology &amp;amp; Genetics, National Cancer Institute, Bethesda, MD. &lt;a href="mailto:lins4@mail.nih.gov">lins4@mail.nih.gov&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ecologic studies have reported that solar ultraviolet radiation (UVR) exposure is associated with cancer, but little evidence is available from prospective studies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Blacks get more cancer than whites due to lower levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-blacks-get-more-cancer-than-whites-due-to-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-blacks-get-more-cancer-than-whites-due-to-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="differences-in-vitamin-d-status-may-account-for-unexplained-disparities-in-cancer-survival-rates-between-african-and-white-americans">Differences in vitamin D status may account for unexplained disparities in cancer survival rates between African and White Americans&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermato Endocinology Volume 4, Issue 2 April/May/June 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: William B. Grant and Alan N. Peiris&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/possible-role-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-blackwhite-health-disparities-in-the-united-states" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1096">Possible role of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D in Black–White health disparities in the United States&lt;/a> 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/low-uvb-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2287">Low UVB is associated with 15 types of Cancer – Jan 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU of vitamin D reduced fatigue of advanced cancer – RCT</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-fatigue-of-advanced-cancer-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-fatigue-of-advanced-cancer-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-supplementation-to-improve-fatigue-in-patients-with-advanced-cancer">Vitamin D3 supplementation to improve fatigue in patients with advanced cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology, 2012 ASCO Annual Meeting Proceedings (Post-Meeting Edition).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol 30, No 15_suppl (May 20 Supplement), 2012: 9097&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2012 American Society of Clinical Oncology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dragan Trivanovic, Stjepko Plestina, Renata Dobrilla-Dintinjana, Lorena Honovic, Lems Jerin and Irena Hrstic&lt;/p>
&lt;p>General Hospital Pula, Pula, Croatia; University Hospital Centre Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia; Internal Clinic, Rijeka, Croatia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Fatigue is one of the most common symptoms of patients diagnosed with cancer. Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with an increased risk of mortality in oncology patients. We conducted a prospective vitamin D (cholecalciferol) supplementation study to analyse the response to oral D3 supplementation on fatigue in this population of chemo-naïve patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The role of vitamins in cancer: a review – 2011</title><link>/posts/the-role-of-vitamins-in-cancer-a-review-2011.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-role-of-vitamins-in-cancer-a-review-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nutr Cancer. 2011;63(4):479-94.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mamede AC, Tavares SD, Abrantes AM, Trindade J, Maia JM, Botelho MF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Biophysics/Biomathematics Institute, IBILI, Faculty of Medicine, University of Coimbra, Coimbra, Portugal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamins are essential nutrients for human metabolism, playing an important role as coenzymes or enzymes in many vital processes for the normal functioning of the body. In recent years, it has become apparent that vitamins are crucial in health and human disease, due to several studies that studied this relationship. Currently, it is known that vitamins can have an important role in the prevention and treatment of cancer, but until now no conclusive results were obtained. In this review, we will present the work and more relevant conclusions obtained in recent years of investigation about the relationship between vitamins and cancer, namely vitamin A, vitamin B complex, vitamin C, vitamin D, vitamin E, and vitamin K.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 analog, 20-hydroxyvitamin D, inhibits cancer cells and is non-toxic</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-analog-20-hydroxyvitamin-d-inhibits-cancer-cells-and-is-non-toxic.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-analog-20-hydroxyvitamin-d-inhibits-cancer-cells-and-is-non-toxic.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Advanced stage cancer 3X more likely if low level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/advanced-stage-cancer-3x-more-likely-if-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/advanced-stage-cancer-3x-more-likely-if-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-widespread-in-cancer-patients-and-correlates-with-advanced-stage-disease-a-community-oncology-experience">Vitamin D Deficiency Is Widespread in Cancer Patients and Correlates With Advanced Stage Disease: A Community Oncology Experience.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nutr Cancer. 2012 Mar 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Churilla TM, Brereton HD, Klem M, Peters CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a The Commonwealth Medical College , Scranton , Pennsylvania , USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this study was to correlate serum vitamin D levels with potential clinical variables and to determine the extent of vitamin D deficiency in a large, outpatient oncology practice. One hundred ninety-five consecutive patients referred for consultation at a community radiation oncology center from October 8, 2008 to March 17, 2010 had vitamin D levels ordered. Patients who were deficient in vitamin D were treated with replacement therapy. Demographic and medical data were collected prospectively and subsequently analyzed. Pretreatment baseline patient and tumor characteristics were evaluated with respect to vitamin D concentrations. One hundred and sixty patients were analyzed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting little UV is associated with 15 types of Cancer</title><link>/posts/getting-little-uv-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/getting-little-uv-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="ecological-studies-of-the-uvbvitamin-dcancer-hypothesis">Ecological Studies of the UVB–Vitamin D–Cancer Hypothesis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Anticancer Research January 2012 vol. 32 no. 1 223-236&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WILLIAM B. GRANT, Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, P.O. Box 641603, San Francisco, CA 94164-1603, U.S.A. &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aim: This paper reviews ecological studies of the ultraviolet-B (UVB)–vitamin D–cancer hypothesis based on geographical variation of cancer incidence and/or mortality rates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Materials and Methods: The review is based largely on three ecological studies of cancer rates from the United States; one each from Australia, China, France, Japan, and Spain; and eight multicountry, multifactorial studies of cancer incidence rates from &lt;strong>more than 100 countries&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of solar UVB in US is associated with some Cancers - 2006</title><link>/posts/lack-of-solar-uvb-in-us-is-associated-with-some-cancers-2006.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-solar-uvb-in-us-is-associated-with-some-cancers-2006.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="solar-ultraviolet-b-exposure-and-cancer-incidence-and-mortality-in-the-united-states-1993-2002">Solar ultraviolet-B exposure and cancer incidence and mortality in the United States, 1993-2002.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>BMC Cancer. 2006 Nov 10;6:264.Boscoe FP, Schymura MJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, University at Albany, Rensselaer, NY 12144, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:fpb01@health.state.ny.us">fpb01@health.state.ny.us&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An inverse relationship between solar ultraviolet-B (UV-B) exposure and non-skin cancer mortality has long been reported. Vitamin D, acquired primarily through exposure to the sun via the skin, is believed to inhibit tumor development and growth and reduce mortality for certain cancers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Possible ways that vitamin D does its magic</title><link>/posts/possible-ways-that-vitamin-d-does-its-magic.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/possible-ways-that-vitamin-d-does-its-magic.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Expect that within a few years we will know that the vitamin D magic is&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>One of these ways&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Several of these ways&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Some nnumber of these ways + ways not yet proposed&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Personally, I am rooting for DNA repair&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>because it sounds so good, not because any better case has been made. Henry Lahore March 2012&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-cancer-a-review-of-molecular-mechanisms-jan-2012">Vitamin D and cancer: a review of molecular mechanisms. (Jan 2012)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cellular-and-molecular-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-carcinogenesis-nov-2011">Cellular and molecular effects of vitamin D on carcinogenesis (Nov 2011)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#does-vitamin-d-protect-against-dna-damage-feb-2012">Does vitamin D protect against DNA damage? (Feb 2012)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-a-review-of-molecular-mechanisms-jan-2012">Vitamin D and cancer: a review of molecular mechanisms. (Jan 2012)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Biochem J. 2012 Jan 1;441(1):61-76.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>800 IU Vitamin D doesn't prevent heart attack or cancer</title><link>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-doesnt-prevent-heart-attack-or-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-doesnt-prevent-heart-attack-or-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="title-of-this-page-without-800-iu--is-fromreuters-articlehttpwwwreuterscomarticle20111208us-vitamin-d-idustre7b72av2011120820">Title of this page (without 800 IU) is from&lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/12/08/us-vitamin-d-idUSTRE7B72AV20111208%20">Reuters article&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="more-precise-title-for-the-article-would-have-been">More precise title for the article would have been:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="span-stylecolorf00once-again-it-has-been-proven-that-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-not-enough-to-prevent-heart-attacks-or-reduce-cancerspan">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">&amp;ldquo;Once again it has been proven that 800 IU of vitamin D is not enough to prevent heart attacks or reduce cancer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="need-at-least-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-to-start-to-prevent-cancercategoriescancer-or-a-hrefpostsheart-attacks-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1422heart-attacksa">Need at least 2,000 IU of vitamin D to start to PREVENT &lt;a href="/categories/cancer">Cancer&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="/posts/heart-attacks" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1422">heart attacks&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="similar-article-800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart--meta-analysis-aug-2011posts800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart-meta-analysis">Similar article: &lt;a href="/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart-meta-analysis">800 IU Vitamin D does not help heart – meta-analysis Aug 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="the-following-chart-shows-how-much-vitamin-d-has-to-be-in-blood-to-prevent-many-medical-problems">The following chart shows how much vitamin D has to be in blood to prevent many medical problems&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It is virtually impossible for 800 IU to result in a 40 ng vitamin D level in the blood&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The lower the vitamin D the sooner a blood cancer needed to be treated</title><link>/posts/the-lower-the-vitamin-d-the-sooner-a-blood-cancer-needed-to-be-treated.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-lower-the-vitamin-d-the-sooner-a-blood-cancer-needed-to-be-treated.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-predicts-time-to-first-treatment-tft-in-early-chronic-lymphocytic-leukemia-cll">Vitamin D insufficiency predicts time to first treatment (TFT) in early chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Leukemia Research doi:10.1016/j.leukres.2011.10.004 |&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefano Molicaa, , , Giovanna Digiesib, Anna Antenuccib, Luciano Levatoa, Rosanna Mirabellia, Matteo Molicaa, Massimo Gentilec, Diana Giannarellid, Isabella Sperdutid, Fortunato Morabitoc, Laura Contib&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a	Dipartimento di Emato-oncologia, Azienda Ospedaliera di Catanzaro, Catanzaro, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b	Servizio di Patologia Clinica, IRCCS Regina Elena, SAFU, Rome, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c	U.O.C. di Ematologia, Azienda Ospedaliera Annunziata di Cosenza, Cosenza, Italy&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use of tanning beds would reduce associated deaths by 10X</title><link>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-sun-sunbeds-and-health">Vitamin D, sun, sunbeds and health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Oct 24:1-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moan J, Baturaite Z, Juzeniene A, Porojnicu AC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, The Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Ullernchausseen 70, Montebello N-0310 Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To review the health effects of solar radiation, sunbeds and vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DESIGN: The literature was searched in the electronic database MEDLINE to indentify published data between 1981 and 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast and other Cancer prevention - Dr. Wascher 2011</title><link>/posts/breast-and-other-cancer-prevention-dr-wascher-2011.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-and-other-cancer-prevention-dr-wascher-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-cancer-prevention-guide-for-the-human-race">A Cancer Prevention Guide for the Human Race&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Book on &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Cancer-Prevention-Guide-Human-Race/dp/1608446913/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1318595647&amp;amp;sr=8-1">Amazon&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Can look inside of the book and see 14 references to vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book in both paperback and Kindle format Sept 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="his-bloghttpwwwdoctorwaschercom">&lt;a href="http://www.doctorwascher.com/">His blog&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="the-following-appear-to-be-some-of-his-blog-posts">The following appear to be some of his blog posts&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="breast-cancer-recurrence--death--vitamin-dhttpbreastcancerawarenet201110breast-cancer-recurrence-death-vitamin-d">&lt;a href="http://breastcanceraware.net/2011/10/breast-cancer-recurrence-death-vitamin-d/">Breast Cancer Recurrence – Death &amp;amp; Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>By: admin | Date: October 12, 2011 | Categories: breast cancer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Based upon recent clinical research findings, Vitamin D is the only remaining vitamin that may have significant cancer and cardiovascular disease prevention properties. Recent large-scale prospective randomized clinical research trials have not only failed to identify a cancer prevention role (beyond a healthy balanced diet) for Vitamin E, Vitamin C, folate, and beta-carotene (a member of the Vitamin A family) supplements, but data from these trials have strongly suggested an increased risk of adverse health outcomes, at least in some sub-groups of patients, with supplements of several of these vitamins.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer in children 6X more likely if very low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cancer-in-children-6x-more-likely-if-very-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-in-children-6x-more-likely-if-very-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-paediatric-patients-with-cancer">Vitamin D status in paediatric patients with cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2011 Oct;57(4):594-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/pbc.22963.">doi: 10.1002/pbc.22963.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Feb 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sinha A, Avery P, Turner S, Bailey S, Cheetham T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Paediatric Endocrinology, Great North Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Children with malignant disease are at increased risk of bone disorders and cardiovascular disease. Vitamin D status may influence this risk and so we assessed vitamin D levels in children with malignant disease undergoing active treatment or surveillance post-therapy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D has a complex relationship with Cancer – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-has-a-complex-relationship-with-cancer-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-has-a-complex-relationship-with-cancer-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-deciphering-the-truth">Vitamin D and cancer: Deciphering the truth&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Biochimica et Biophysica Acta&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simone Mocellin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Oncological and Surgical Sciences, University ofPadova, Padova, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 16 April 2011, Accepted 4 July 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a hormone-like micronutrient involved not only in calcium metabolism but also in a variety of biological activities (e.g., cell proliferation, apoptosis, angiogenesis, inflammation) that makes it a candidate anticancer agent. Preclinical studies support the therapeutic potential of vitamin D both alone and in combination with other therapeutics. Overall, epidemiological data suggest the existence of a link between vitamin D and cancer risk, whereas the results of clinical trials are quite conflicting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancers and Vitamin D Council</title><link>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sun exposure is associated with increased survival from melanoma – 2005</title><link>/posts/sun-exposure-is-associated-with-increased-survival-from-melanoma-2005.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sun-exposure-is-associated-with-increased-survival-from-melanoma-2005.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Excessive sun increases cancer all around the body</title><link>/posts/excessive-sun-increases-cancer-all-around-the-body.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/excessive-sun-increases-cancer-all-around-the-body.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Some cancer due to low UV – Grant</title><link>/posts/some-cancer-due-to-low-uv-grant.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-cancer-due-to-low-uv-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="an-ecological-study-of-cancer-mortality-rates-in-the-united-states-with-respect-to-solar-ultraviolet-b-doses-smoking-alcohol-consumption-and-urbanrural-residence">An ecological study of cancer mortality rates in the United States with respect to solar ultraviolet-B doses, smoking, alcohol consumption and urban/rural residence.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Grant WB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight, Nutrition and Health Research Center (SUNARC); San Francisco, CA USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2010 Apr;2(2):68-76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cohort Consortium Vitamin D Polling Project of Rarer Cancers (VDPP ) study failed to find a beneficial role of prediagnostic serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels on risk of seven types of rarer cancer: endometrial, esophageal, gastric, kidney, ovarian and pancreatic cancer and non-Hodgkin&amp;rsquo;s lymphoma (NHL).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – anticancer benefits from synergy of omega-3 and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-anticancer-benefits-from-synergy-of-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-anticancer-benefits-from-synergy-of-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-anticancer-effects-of-vitamin-d-and-omega-3-pufas-in-combination-via-cod-liver-oil-one-plus-one-may-equal-more-than-two">The anticancer effects of Vitamin D and omega-3 PUFAs in combination via cod-liver oil: One plus one may equal more than two.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Med Hypotheses. 2011 May 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dyck MC, Ma DW, Meckling KA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Human Health and Nutritional Sciences, University of Guelph, Guelph, ON, Canada N1G2W1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past number of years, the anticancer activities of omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (?3-PUFAs) as well as Vitamin D have been intensively studied, but separately. Supplementation of Vitamin D and omega-3 PUFA via cod-liver oil, one of few natural sources of both of these molecules, may have additive and possibly synergistic anticancer effects. Cod-liver oil has been used effectively to treat diseases such as Rheumatism but has not been studied as an anticancer agent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Cancer Treatment and Prevention – presentations</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-treatment-and-prevention-presentations.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-treatment-and-prevention-presentations.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="click-herehttpwwwvitamindassociationorgeventshtml-uk---which-has-all-pdf-audio-and-video-recordings">&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindassociation.org/events.html">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> UK - which has all PDF, audio, and video recordings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many of the PDF files are also available on VitaminDWiki&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D &amp;amp; Cancer - Cancer overview - Oliver (777KB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1939">Vitamin D &amp;amp; Cancer - Data review - Grant&lt;/a> (871KB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1941">Vitamin D &amp;amp; Cancer - GrassRootsHealth Public Trial - Baggerly&lt;/a> (460KB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1936">Vitamin D &amp;amp; Cancer - Obesity - Lagunova&lt;/a> (3.21MB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1942">Vitamin D &amp;amp; Cancer - Oncology overview - Dalgleish&lt;/a> (101KB)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mortality and Cancer varies with latitude in France too – 2010</title><link>/posts/mortality-and-cancer-varies-with-latitude-in-france-too-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mortality-and-cancer-varies-with-latitude-in-france-too-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="an-ecological-study-of-cancer-incidence-and-mortality-rates-in-france-with-respect-to-latitude-an-index-for-vitamin-d-production">An ecological study of cancer incidence and mortality rates in France with respect to latitude, an index for vitamin D production&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2010 Apr–Dec; 2(2): 62–67. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4161/derm.2.2.13624.">doi: 10.4161/derm.2.2.13624.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B Grant &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3081677&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2010 Landes Bioscience&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight, Nutrition and Health Research Center (SUNARC); San Francisco, CA USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received July 18, 2010; Revised September 7, 2010; Accepted September 8, 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>France has unexplained &lt;strong>large latitudinal variations in cancer incidence and mortality rates&lt;/strong> . Studies of cancer rate variations in several other countries, as well as in multicountry studies, have explained such variations primarily in terms of gradients in solar ultraviolet-B (UVB) doses and vitamin D production. To investigate this possibility in France, I obtained data on&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Video on how Vitamin D reduces Cancer</title><link>/posts/video-on-how-vitamin-d-reduces-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/video-on-how-vitamin-d-reduces-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;p>In a new study, researchers at the Faculty of Medicine and Moores UCSD Cancer Center is a complex computer model for predicting dietary intake of vitamin D3 and calcium to prevent 58 000 new cases of breast cancer and use the 49,000 new cases of cancer each year in the United States and Canada. The research model also predicted that 75% of deaths from these cancers prevented by adequate intake of vitamin D3 and calcium could.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Prevention of Cancer — Is it ready for Prime Time</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-prevention-of-cancer-is-it-ready-for-prime-time.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-prevention-of-cancer-is-it-ready-for-prime-time.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-prevention-of-cancer--ready-for-prime-time">Vitamin D and Prevention of Cancer — Ready for Prime Time?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>JoAnn E. Manson, M.D., Dr.P.H., Susan T. Mayne, Ph.D., and Steven K. Clinton, M.D., Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>March 23, 2011 (10.1056/NEJMp1102022)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given that the potential role of vitamin D in cancer prevention has been widely touted, many people were surprised that cancer-related considerations didn&amp;rsquo;t figure prominently in the new Dietary Reference Intakes for vitamin D established by the Institute of Medicine (IOM).1 An IOM committee on which we served, charged with determining the population needs for vitamin D in North America, reviewed the evidence linking vitamin D with both skeletal and nonskeletal health outcomes. The committee concluded that vitamin D plays an important role in bone health and that the evidence provides a sound basis for determining the population&amp;rsquo;s needs. For outcomes beyond bone health, however, including cancer, cardiovascular disease, diabetes, and autoimmune disorders, the evidence was found to be inconsistent and inconclusive as to causality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D appears to both prevent and treat various cancers</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-appears-to-both-prevent-and-treat-various-cancers.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-appears-to-both-prevent-and-treat-various-cancers.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-as-a-promising-anticancer-agent">Vitamin D as a promising anticancer agent&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Indian Journal of Pharmacology, 2011 | Volume : 43 | Issue : 2 | Page : 113-120&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chandra Kanti Chakraborti&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Microbiology, Kanak Manjari Institute of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Rourkela, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Date of Submission	25-Feb-2010; Date of Decision	07-Sep-2010; Date of Acceptance	31-Dec-2010; Date of Web Publication	6-Mar-2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.4103/0253-7613.77335&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presence of vitamin D receptors in noncalcemic tissues and subsequent identification of its involvement in growth factor(s)-mediated cellular function suggested its probable beneficial role in genesis, progression and survival of cancerous growths. Data collected from both in vitro and in vivo studies are &lt;strong>highly optimistic regarding its potential in prevention and regression of colorectal, prostate and breast cancers&lt;/strong> . The vitamin has been found to interfere with the transduction pathways of various growth factor(s)-activated receptors (receptor tyrosine kinases) thereby modulating transcription and alteration of genomic functions resulting in inhibition of cell proliferation and angiogenesis and facilitation of cell differentiation and apoptosis. It also increases the level of an endogenous protein - cystatin D, which possesses antitumor and antimetastatic property, by facilitation of the expression of the gene coding for it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children with Cancer were 6X more likely to have less than 10ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/children-with-cancer-were-6x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-10ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-with-cancer-were-6x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-10ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-paediatric-patients-with-cancer">Vitamin D status in paediatric patients with cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Research Article&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Akash Sinha MBBS1,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Peter Avery PhD2,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Steve Turner BSc3,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Simon Bailey PhD4,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tim Cheetham MD1,5, &lt;a href="mailto:tim.cheetham@nuth.nhs.uk">tim.cheetham@nuth.nhs.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Article first published online: 3 FEB 2011; DOI: 10.1002/pbc.22963&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Paediatric Endocrinology, Great North Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Mathematics and Statistics, Newcastle University, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Great North Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Large Healthcare Org: 1500-2000 IU vitamin D to reduce cancer</title><link>/posts/large-healthcare-org-1500-2000-iu-vitamin-d-to-reduce-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/large-healthcare-org-1500-2000-iu-vitamin-d-to-reduce-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bupa-urges-everyone-to-take-vitamin-d-to-reduce-risk-of-cancer">BUPA URGES EVERYONE TO TAKE VITAMIN D TO REDUCE RISK OF CANCER&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>16 December 2009&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the winter solstice approaches, the shortest day of the year signals the start of winter when sunlight hours fall to an average of just two a day.1 Bupa, the UK&amp;rsquo;s leading healthcare company is urging people to take Vitamin D to reduce their risk of cancer as day-time no longer means sun-time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D helps protect against certain cancers such as breast, bowel, prostate and colon. For people to obtain enough Vitamin D naturally, they need either to expose their skin to lots of summer sun or eat large quantities of oily fish. Bupa&amp;rsquo;s assistant medical director, Dr Virginia Warren said: &amp;ldquo;Natural ways to get enough vitamin D aren&amp;rsquo;t realistic because our skin cannot make vitamin D from winter sunlight in the UK as it is too weak. In the summer, people are rightly concerned about risks of skin cancer. And nobody wants to eat four tins of mackerel every day to get their vitamin D from oily fish.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increase in some childhood cancers with latitude</title><link>/posts/increase-in-some-childhood-cancers-with-latitude.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increase-in-some-childhood-cancers-with-latitude.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="childhood-cancer-incidence-in-relation-to-sunlight-exposure">Childhood cancer incidence in relation to sunlight exposure.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Br J Cancer. 2010 Nov 23. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Musselman JR, Spector LG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatrics, Department of Epidemiology and Clinical Research, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:There is increasing interest in the possible association between cancer incidence and vitamin D through its role as a regulator of cell growth and differentiation. Epidemiological studies in adults and one paediatric study suggest an inverse association between sunlight exposure and cancer incidence.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>