<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The lower the vitamin D the sooner a blood cancer needed to be treated</title><link>/posts/the-lower-the-vitamin-d-the-sooner-a-blood-cancer-needed-to-be-treated.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-lower-the-vitamin-d-the-sooner-a-blood-cancer-needed-to-be-treated.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-predicts-time-to-first-treatment-tft-in-early-chronic-lymphocytic-leukemia-cll">Vitamin D insufficiency predicts time to first treatment (TFT) in early chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Leukemia Research doi:10.1016/j.leukres.2011.10.004 |&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefano Molicaa, , , Giovanna Digiesib, Anna Antenuccib, Luciano Levatoa, Rosanna Mirabellia, Matteo Molicaa, Massimo Gentilec, Diana Giannarellid, Isabella Sperdutid, Fortunato Morabitoc, Laura Contib&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a	Dipartimento di Emato-oncologia, Azienda Ospedaliera di Catanzaro, Catanzaro, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b	Servizio di Patologia Clinica, IRCCS Regina Elena, SAFU, Rome, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c	U.O.C. di Ematologia, Azienda Ospedaliera Annunziata di Cosenza, Cosenza, Italy&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use of tanning beds would reduce associated deaths by 10X</title><link>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-sun-sunbeds-and-health">Vitamin D, sun, sunbeds and health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Oct 24:1-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moan J, Baturaite Z, Juzeniene A, Porojnicu AC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, The Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Ullernchausseen 70, Montebello N-0310 Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To review the health effects of solar radiation, sunbeds and vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DESIGN: The literature was searched in the electronic database MEDLINE to indentify published data between 1981 and 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast and other Cancer prevention - Dr. Wascher 2011</title><link>/posts/breast-and-other-cancer-prevention-dr-wascher-2011.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-and-other-cancer-prevention-dr-wascher-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-cancer-prevention-guide-for-the-human-race">A Cancer Prevention Guide for the Human Race&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Book on &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Cancer-Prevention-Guide-Human-Race/dp/1608446913/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1318595647&amp;amp;sr=8-1">Amazon&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Can look inside of the book and see 14 references to vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book in both paperback and Kindle format Sept 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="his-bloghttpwwwdoctorwaschercom">&lt;a href="http://www.doctorwascher.com/">His blog&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="the-following-appear-to-be-some-of-his-blog-posts">The following appear to be some of his blog posts&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="breast-cancer-recurrence--death--vitamin-dhttpbreastcancerawarenet201110breast-cancer-recurrence-death-vitamin-d">&lt;a href="http://breastcanceraware.net/2011/10/breast-cancer-recurrence-death-vitamin-d/">Breast Cancer Recurrence – Death &amp;amp; Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>By: admin | Date: October 12, 2011 | Categories: breast cancer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Based upon recent clinical research findings, Vitamin D is the only remaining vitamin that may have significant cancer and cardiovascular disease prevention properties. Recent large-scale prospective randomized clinical research trials have not only failed to identify a cancer prevention role (beyond a healthy balanced diet) for Vitamin E, Vitamin C, folate, and beta-carotene (a member of the Vitamin A family) supplements, but data from these trials have strongly suggested an increased risk of adverse health outcomes, at least in some sub-groups of patients, with supplements of several of these vitamins.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer in children 6X more likely if very low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cancer-in-children-6x-more-likely-if-very-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-in-children-6x-more-likely-if-very-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-paediatric-patients-with-cancer">Vitamin D status in paediatric patients with cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2011 Oct;57(4):594-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/pbc.22963.">doi: 10.1002/pbc.22963.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Feb 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sinha A, Avery P, Turner S, Bailey S, Cheetham T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Paediatric Endocrinology, Great North Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Children with malignant disease are at increased risk of bone disorders and cardiovascular disease. Vitamin D status may influence this risk and so we assessed vitamin D levels in children with malignant disease undergoing active treatment or surveillance post-therapy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D has a complex relationship with Cancer – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-has-a-complex-relationship-with-cancer-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-has-a-complex-relationship-with-cancer-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-deciphering-the-truth">Vitamin D and cancer: Deciphering the truth&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Biochimica et Biophysica Acta&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simone Mocellin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Oncological and Surgical Sciences, University ofPadova, Padova, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 16 April 2011, Accepted 4 July 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a hormone-like micronutrient involved not only in calcium metabolism but also in a variety of biological activities (e.g., cell proliferation, apoptosis, angiogenesis, inflammation) that makes it a candidate anticancer agent. Preclinical studies support the therapeutic potential of vitamin D both alone and in combination with other therapeutics. Overall, epidemiological data suggest the existence of a link between vitamin D and cancer risk, whereas the results of clinical trials are quite conflicting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancers and Vitamin D Council</title><link>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sun exposure is associated with increased survival from melanoma – 2005</title><link>/posts/sun-exposure-is-associated-with-increased-survival-from-melanoma-2005.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sun-exposure-is-associated-with-increased-survival-from-melanoma-2005.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Excessive sun increases cancer all around the body</title><link>/posts/excessive-sun-increases-cancer-all-around-the-body.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/excessive-sun-increases-cancer-all-around-the-body.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Some cancer due to low UV – Grant</title><link>/posts/some-cancer-due-to-low-uv-grant.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-cancer-due-to-low-uv-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="an-ecological-study-of-cancer-mortality-rates-in-the-united-states-with-respect-to-solar-ultraviolet-b-doses-smoking-alcohol-consumption-and-urbanrural-residence">An ecological study of cancer mortality rates in the United States with respect to solar ultraviolet-B doses, smoking, alcohol consumption and urban/rural residence.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Grant WB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight, Nutrition and Health Research Center (SUNARC); San Francisco, CA USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2010 Apr;2(2):68-76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cohort Consortium Vitamin D Polling Project of Rarer Cancers (VDPP ) study failed to find a beneficial role of prediagnostic serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels on risk of seven types of rarer cancer: endometrial, esophageal, gastric, kidney, ovarian and pancreatic cancer and non-Hodgkin&amp;rsquo;s lymphoma (NHL).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – anticancer benefits from synergy of omega-3 and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-anticancer-benefits-from-synergy-of-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-anticancer-benefits-from-synergy-of-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-anticancer-effects-of-vitamin-d-and-omega-3-pufas-in-combination-via-cod-liver-oil-one-plus-one-may-equal-more-than-two">The anticancer effects of Vitamin D and omega-3 PUFAs in combination via cod-liver oil: One plus one may equal more than two.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Med Hypotheses. 2011 May 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dyck MC, Ma DW, Meckling KA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Human Health and Nutritional Sciences, University of Guelph, Guelph, ON, Canada N1G2W1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past number of years, the anticancer activities of omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (?3-PUFAs) as well as Vitamin D have been intensively studied, but separately. Supplementation of Vitamin D and omega-3 PUFA via cod-liver oil, one of few natural sources of both of these molecules, may have additive and possibly synergistic anticancer effects. Cod-liver oil has been used effectively to treat diseases such as Rheumatism but has not been studied as an anticancer agent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Cancer Treatment and Prevention – presentations</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-treatment-and-prevention-presentations.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-treatment-and-prevention-presentations.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="click-herehttpwwwvitamindassociationorgeventshtml-uk---which-has-all-pdf-audio-and-video-recordings">&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindassociation.org/events.html">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> UK - which has all PDF, audio, and video recordings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many of the PDF files are also available on VitaminDWiki&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D &amp;amp; Cancer - Cancer overview - Oliver (777KB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1939">Vitamin D &amp;amp; Cancer - Data review - Grant&lt;/a> (871KB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1941">Vitamin D &amp;amp; Cancer - GrassRootsHealth Public Trial - Baggerly&lt;/a> (460KB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1936">Vitamin D &amp;amp; Cancer - Obesity - Lagunova&lt;/a> (3.21MB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1942">Vitamin D &amp;amp; Cancer - Oncology overview - Dalgleish&lt;/a> (101KB)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mortality and Cancer varies with latitude in France too – 2010</title><link>/posts/mortality-and-cancer-varies-with-latitude-in-france-too-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mortality-and-cancer-varies-with-latitude-in-france-too-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="an-ecological-study-of-cancer-incidence-and-mortality-rates-in-france-with-respect-to-latitude-an-index-for-vitamin-d-production">An ecological study of cancer incidence and mortality rates in France with respect to latitude, an index for vitamin D production&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2010 Apr–Dec; 2(2): 62–67. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4161/derm.2.2.13624.">doi: 10.4161/derm.2.2.13624.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B Grant &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3081677&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2010 Landes Bioscience&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight, Nutrition and Health Research Center (SUNARC); San Francisco, CA USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received July 18, 2010; Revised September 7, 2010; Accepted September 8, 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>France has unexplained &lt;strong>large latitudinal variations in cancer incidence and mortality rates&lt;/strong> . Studies of cancer rate variations in several other countries, as well as in multicountry studies, have explained such variations primarily in terms of gradients in solar ultraviolet-B (UVB) doses and vitamin D production. To investigate this possibility in France, I obtained data on&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Video on how Vitamin D reduces Cancer</title><link>/posts/video-on-how-vitamin-d-reduces-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/video-on-how-vitamin-d-reduces-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;p>In a new study, researchers at the Faculty of Medicine and Moores UCSD Cancer Center is a complex computer model for predicting dietary intake of vitamin D3 and calcium to prevent 58 000 new cases of breast cancer and use the 49,000 new cases of cancer each year in the United States and Canada. The research model also predicted that 75% of deaths from these cancers prevented by adequate intake of vitamin D3 and calcium could.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Prevention of Cancer — Is it ready for Prime Time</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-prevention-of-cancer-is-it-ready-for-prime-time.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-prevention-of-cancer-is-it-ready-for-prime-time.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-prevention-of-cancer--ready-for-prime-time">Vitamin D and Prevention of Cancer — Ready for Prime Time?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>JoAnn E. Manson, M.D., Dr.P.H., Susan T. Mayne, Ph.D., and Steven K. Clinton, M.D., Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>March 23, 2011 (10.1056/NEJMp1102022)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given that the potential role of vitamin D in cancer prevention has been widely touted, many people were surprised that cancer-related considerations didn&amp;rsquo;t figure prominently in the new Dietary Reference Intakes for vitamin D established by the Institute of Medicine (IOM).1 An IOM committee on which we served, charged with determining the population needs for vitamin D in North America, reviewed the evidence linking vitamin D with both skeletal and nonskeletal health outcomes. The committee concluded that vitamin D plays an important role in bone health and that the evidence provides a sound basis for determining the population&amp;rsquo;s needs. For outcomes beyond bone health, however, including cancer, cardiovascular disease, diabetes, and autoimmune disorders, the evidence was found to be inconsistent and inconclusive as to causality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D appears to both prevent and treat various cancers</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-appears-to-both-prevent-and-treat-various-cancers.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-appears-to-both-prevent-and-treat-various-cancers.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-as-a-promising-anticancer-agent">Vitamin D as a promising anticancer agent&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Indian Journal of Pharmacology, 2011 | Volume : 43 | Issue : 2 | Page : 113-120&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chandra Kanti Chakraborti&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Microbiology, Kanak Manjari Institute of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Rourkela, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Date of Submission	25-Feb-2010; Date of Decision	07-Sep-2010; Date of Acceptance	31-Dec-2010; Date of Web Publication	6-Mar-2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.4103/0253-7613.77335&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presence of vitamin D receptors in noncalcemic tissues and subsequent identification of its involvement in growth factor(s)-mediated cellular function suggested its probable beneficial role in genesis, progression and survival of cancerous growths. Data collected from both in vitro and in vivo studies are &lt;strong>highly optimistic regarding its potential in prevention and regression of colorectal, prostate and breast cancers&lt;/strong> . The vitamin has been found to interfere with the transduction pathways of various growth factor(s)-activated receptors (receptor tyrosine kinases) thereby modulating transcription and alteration of genomic functions resulting in inhibition of cell proliferation and angiogenesis and facilitation of cell differentiation and apoptosis. It also increases the level of an endogenous protein - cystatin D, which possesses antitumor and antimetastatic property, by facilitation of the expression of the gene coding for it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children with Cancer were 6X more likely to have less than 10ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/children-with-cancer-were-6x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-10ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-with-cancer-were-6x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-10ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-paediatric-patients-with-cancer">Vitamin D status in paediatric patients with cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Research Article&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Akash Sinha MBBS1,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Peter Avery PhD2,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Steve Turner BSc3,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Simon Bailey PhD4,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tim Cheetham MD1,5, &lt;a href="mailto:tim.cheetham@nuth.nhs.uk">tim.cheetham@nuth.nhs.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Article first published online: 3 FEB 2011; DOI: 10.1002/pbc.22963&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Paediatric Endocrinology, Great North Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Mathematics and Statistics, Newcastle University, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Great North Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Large Healthcare Org: 1500-2000 IU vitamin D to reduce cancer</title><link>/posts/large-healthcare-org-1500-2000-iu-vitamin-d-to-reduce-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/large-healthcare-org-1500-2000-iu-vitamin-d-to-reduce-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bupa-urges-everyone-to-take-vitamin-d-to-reduce-risk-of-cancer">BUPA URGES EVERYONE TO TAKE VITAMIN D TO REDUCE RISK OF CANCER&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>16 December 2009&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the winter solstice approaches, the shortest day of the year signals the start of winter when sunlight hours fall to an average of just two a day.1 Bupa, the UK&amp;rsquo;s leading healthcare company is urging people to take Vitamin D to reduce their risk of cancer as day-time no longer means sun-time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D helps protect against certain cancers such as breast, bowel, prostate and colon. For people to obtain enough Vitamin D naturally, they need either to expose their skin to lots of summer sun or eat large quantities of oily fish. Bupa&amp;rsquo;s assistant medical director, Dr Virginia Warren said: &amp;ldquo;Natural ways to get enough vitamin D aren&amp;rsquo;t realistic because our skin cannot make vitamin D from winter sunlight in the UK as it is too weak. In the summer, people are rightly concerned about risks of skin cancer. And nobody wants to eat four tins of mackerel every day to get their vitamin D from oily fish.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increase in some childhood cancers with latitude</title><link>/posts/increase-in-some-childhood-cancers-with-latitude.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increase-in-some-childhood-cancers-with-latitude.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="childhood-cancer-incidence-in-relation-to-sunlight-exposure">Childhood cancer incidence in relation to sunlight exposure.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Br J Cancer. 2010 Nov 23. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Musselman JR, Spector LG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatrics, Department of Epidemiology and Clinical Research, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN 55455, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:There is increasing interest in the possible association between cancer incidence and vitamin D through its role as a regulator of cell growth and differentiation. Epidemiological studies in adults and one paediatric study suggest an inverse association between sunlight exposure and cancer incidence.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>