<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vitamin D Far From Equator on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/vitamin-d-far-from-equator.html</link><description>Recent content in Vitamin D Far From Equator on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vitamin-d-far-from-equator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Suggest more vitamin D above the Arctic Circle</title><link>/posts/suggest-more-vitamin-d-above-the-arctic-circle.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/suggest-more-vitamin-d-above-the-arctic-circle.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-adolescents-living-at-high-latitudes-are-we-missing-something-in-the-recommendations">Vitamin D deficiency in adolescents living at high latitudes: are we missing something in the recommendations?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Paediatrica, Volume 102, Issue 6, pages 569–571, June 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thomas H Casswall1,2,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Invited Commenatry for Persson K et al, Vitamin D deficiency at the Arctic circle- a study in food allergic adolescents and controls, pages 644–649.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/apa.12172/abstract">Full text on-line&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark Skinned adults need more than 45 minutes of UK summer sun daily</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-adults-need-more-than-45-minutes-of-uk-summer-sun-daily.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-adults-need-more-than-45-minutes-of-uk-summer-sun-daily.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="efficacy-of-a-dose-range-of-simulated-sunlight-exposures-in-raising-vitamin-d-status-in-south-asian-adults-implications-for-targeted-guidance-on-sun-exposure">Efficacy of a dose range of simulated sunlight exposures in raising vitamin D status in South Asian adults: implications for targeted guidance on sun exposure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr June 2013 vol. 97 no. 6 1210-1216&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mark D Farrar, Ann R Webb, Richard Kift, Marie T Durkin, Donald Allan, Annie Herbert, Jacqueline L Berry, and Lesley E Rhodes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dermatology Centre, Institute of Inflammation and Repair (MDF, MTD, DA, and LER), and the Institute of Population Health (AH), University of Manchester, Manchester Academic Health Science Centre, Salford Royal National Health Service Foundation Trust, Manchester, United Kingdom; the School of Earth, Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences, University of Manchester, Manchester, United Kingdom (ARW and RK); and the Endocrinology and Diabetes Research Group, Institute of Human Development, University of Manchester, Manchester Academic Health Science Centre, Manchester Royal Infirmary, Manchester, United Kingdom (JLB).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don’t be pregnant in Scotland</title><link>/posts/dont-be-pregnant-in-scotland.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dont-be-pregnant-in-scotland.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-at-high-latitude-in-scotland">Vitamin D in pregnancy at high latitude in Scotland.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2013 Mar 14;109(5):898-905. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0007114512002255.">doi: 10.1017/S0007114512002255.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jul 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Haggarty P, Campbell DM, Knox S, Horgan GW, Hoad G, Boulton E, McNeill G, Wallace AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Lifelong Health, Rowett Institute of Nutrition and Health, University of Aberdeen, Greenburn Road, Bucksburn, Aberdeen AB21 9SB, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="lowlights-definitely-not-highlights">Lowlights (definitely not highlights)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Only 21% of pregnant women supplement with vitamin D (median = 200 IU!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency varies with latitude in Asia, as it does elsewhere</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-varies-with-latitude-in-asia-as-it-does-elsewhere.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-varies-with-latitude-in-asia-as-it-does-elsewhere.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-sun-exposure-in-southeast-asia">Vitamin D status and sun exposure in southeast Asia&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermato Endocinology Volume 5, Issue 1 January/February/March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.4161/derm.24054">http://dx.doi.org/10.4161/derm.24054&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is more common in South Asia and Southeast Asia than in appreciated. Most studies defined 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels of less than 50 nmol/L (20 ng/mL) as vitamin D deficiency. With this cut-off level, the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency was about 70% or higher in South Asia and varied from 6–70% in Southeast Asia. The determinants for the variation of vitamin D status are skin pigmentation, aging, the sun protection behaviors such as application of a sunscreen, religious, lifestyle and nutritional differences. Advanced age is a known risk factor for vitamin D deficiency. Interestingly, elderly in countries such as Korea and Thailand, had higher 25(OH)D levels when compared with young people. This widespread vitamin D deficiency problem especially in the young generation is an urgent health issue that needs to be remedied.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schizophrenia high and increasing in Canada – lower vitamin D and more dark skin</title><link>/posts/schizophrenia-high-and-increasing-in-canada-lower-vitamin-d-and-more-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/schizophrenia-high-and-increasing-in-canada-lower-vitamin-d-and-more-dark-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="are-the-rates-of-schizophrenia-unusually-high-in-canada">Are the rates of schizophrenia unusually high in Canada?&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="a-comparison-of-canadian-and-international-data">A comparison of Canadian and international data&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Marie-José Dealberto &lt;a href="mailto:dealbert@queensu.ca">dealbert@queensu.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Community Health and Epidemiology, Carruthers Hall, Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, Ontario, Canada K7L 3N6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Psychiatry Research Received 3 March 2012; received in revised form 26 September 2012; accepted 9 January 2013. published online 25 February 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two major risk factors for schizophrenia are present in Canada, high latitude and a large and growing immigrant population. Consequently, one would expect unusually high rates of schizophrenia and an increase in these rates over time. This systematic review tests these two hypotheses. Searches of electronic databases were performed through 2011. Out of 45 studies 12 fulfilled all the inclusion criteria. The means of Canadian and international rates were compared by one-tailed unequal variance t-test. Trends with time in Canadian rates were tested by the Spearman rank correlation coefficient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Far from Equator</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-far-from-equator.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-far-from-equator.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>IBD in Finland – 3X increase in 15 years, more prevalent further from equator</title><link>/posts/ibd-in-finland-3x-increase-in-15-years-more-prevalent-further-from-equator.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ibd-in-finland-3x-increase-in-15-years-more-prevalent-further-from-equator.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="high-and-increasing-prevalence-of-inflammatory-bowel-disease-in-finland-with-a-clear-north-south-difference">High and increasing prevalence of inflammatory bowel disease in Finland with a clear North-South difference.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Crohns Colitis. 2012 Nov 6. pii: S1873-9946(12)00429-1. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.crohns.2012.10.007.">doi: 10.1016/j.crohns.2012.10.007.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jussila A, Virta LJ, Salomaa V, Mäki J, Jula A, Färkkilä MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Gastroenterology and Alimentary Tract Surgery, Tampere University Hospital, Tampere, Finland; Seinäjoki Central Hospital, Seinäjoki, Finland. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:airi.jussila@fimnet.fi">airi.jussila@fimnet.fi&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND AIM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) prevalence has increased and a North-South gradient has been reported. We estimated the nationwide prevalence of IBD, ulcerative colitis (UC) and Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease (CD) in 1993, and prevalence of IBD in 2008, and assessed the geographical distribution of IBD in Finland. In addition, we investigated the vitamin D levels in a study population from a large, nationally representative health examination survey, the Health 2000 Survey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skinned pregnant women far from equator were very vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-pregnant-women-far-from-equator-were-very-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-pregnant-women-far-from-equator-were-very-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prevalence-of-low-vitamin-d-levels-in-an-urban-midwestern-obstetric-practice">Prevalence of low vitamin d levels in an urban midwestern obstetric practice.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Midwifery Womens Health. 2012 Sep;57(5):439-44. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1542-2011.2012.00167.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1542-2011.2012.00167.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Collins-Fulea C, Klima K, Wegienka GR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: This study describes the prevalence of low vitamin D levels in pregnancy in a diverse urban population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: This was a retrospective chart review of 2839 women who gave birth at a Michigan hospital between January 1, 2008 and December 31, 2009 and had at least 1 vitamin D (25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>) measurement during their pregnancies. Race/ethnic group, wearing the hijab, and season of 25(OH)D sample collection were used in the descriptive analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mortality varies with latitude in the UK</title><link>/posts/mortality-varies-with-latitude-in-the-uk.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mortality-varies-with-latitude-in-the-uk.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="trends-in-mortality-from-1965-to-2008-across-the-english-north-south-divide-comparative-observational-study">Trends in mortality from 1965 to 2008 across the English north-south divide: comparative observational study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Epidemiologic studies Quantitative research Health policy Health service research&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Differences in sunshine duration and vitamin D production may explain much of the English north-south divide in mortality rates&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMJ 21 February 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(To) Editor:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Author) &lt;strong>William B Grant&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The paper by Hacking et al. &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup> highlights the north-south divide in&lt;/p>
&lt;p>population-wide all-cause mortality rates for England for the period 1965-&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half of the US will be people of color – wonder how many will be vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/half-of-the-us-will-be-people-of-color-wonder-how-many-will-be-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-of-the-us-will-be-people-of-color-wonder-how-many-will-be-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D from phototherapy lamps, tanning beds, and the sun</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-from-phototherapy-lamps-tanning-beds-and-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-from-phototherapy-lamps-tanning-beds-and-the-sun.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Inuits eating seal and whale meat had 25 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/inuits-eating-seal-and-whale-meat-had-25-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inuits-eating-seal-and-whale-meat-had-25-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-greenland-is-influenced-by-diet-and-ethnicity-a-population-based-survey-in-an-arctic-society-in-transition">Vitamin D status in Greenland is influenced by diet and ethnicity: a population-based survey in an Arctic society in transition.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2012 Jun 8:1-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andersen S, Laurberg P, Hvingel B, Kleinschmidt K, Heickendorff L, Mosekilde L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arctic Health Research Centre, Aalborg University Hospital, Hobrovej 42D, 9000 Aalborg, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D status as measured by plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) is important to human health. Circumpolar people rely on dietary sources and societal changes in the Arctic are having profound dietary effects. The objective of the present study was to determine plasma 25(OH)D status and factors important to plasma 25(OH)D in populations in Greenland. Inuit and non-Inuit aged 50-69 years in the capital in West Greenland (latitude 64°15&amp;rsquo;N) and in a major town and remote settlements in East Greenland (latitude 65°35&amp;rsquo;N) were surveyed. Supplement use and lifestyle factors were determined by questionnaires. Inuit food scores were computed from a FFQ of seven traditional Inuit and seven imported food items. 25(OH)D2 and 25(OH)D3 levels were measured in the plasma.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Inuit (dark skin)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-inuit-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-inuit-dark-skin.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>45 percent of Tasmanian adults vitamin D deficient in the winter</title><link>/posts/45-percent-of-tasmanian-adults-vitamin-d-deficient-in-the-winter.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/45-percent-of-tasmanian-adults-vitamin-d-deficient-in-the-winter.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-tasmania-a-whole-of-life-perspective">Vitamin D deficiency in Tasmania: A whole of life perspective.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Intern Med J. 2012 Apr 5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1445-5994.2012.02788.x">doi: 10.1111/j.1445-5994.2012.02788.x&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van der Mei IA, Dore D, Winzenberg T, Blizzard L, Jones G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Qualifications: PhD Position: Senior Research Fellow Institution or Affiliation: Menzies Research Institute Address: 17 Liverpool St, Hobart, TAS 7000 Email: &lt;a href="mailto:Ingrid.vanderMei@utas.edu.au">Ingrid.vanderMei@utas.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Qualifications: BBiotech(Hons) Position: PhD student Institution or Affiliation: Menzies Research Institute Address: 17 Liverpool St, Hobart, TAS 7000 Email: &lt;a href="mailto:Dawn.Dore@utas.edu.au">Dawn.Dore@utas.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Qualifications: MD Position: Senior Research Fellow Institution or Affiliation: Menzies Research Institute Address: 17 Liverpool St, Hobart, TAS 7000 Email: &lt;a href="mailto:Tania.Winzenberg@utas.edu.au">Tania.Winzenberg@utas.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>40 percent of Canadian children preparing for surgery had less than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/40-percent-of-canadian-children-preparing-for-surgery-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/40-percent-of-canadian-children-preparing-for-surgery-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-concentrations-among-healthy-children-in-calgary-alberta">Vitamin D concentrations among healthy children in Calgary, Alberta.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Paediatr Child Health. 2011 Feb;16(2):82-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stoian CA, Lyon M, Cox RG, Stephure DK, Mah JK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To examine the relationship between serum vitamin D concentrations, dietary intake and body mass index among healthy children living in Calgary, Alberta.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The present cross-sectional study included healthy children two to 13 years of age who presented to the Alberta Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital for elective surgery during a 12-month period. Data including the child&amp;rsquo;s weight, height, age, sex, ethnicity, dietary intake, use of vitamin supplements, physical activity and time spent outdoors were collected. Serum concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) were measured using commercial immunoradiometric assay kits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skin does not generate as much vitamin D from the same amount of UV</title><link>/posts/dark-skin-does-not-generate-as-much-vitamin-d-from-the-same-amount-of-uv.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skin-does-not-generate-as-much-vitamin-d-from-the-same-amount-of-uv.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>1700 IU vitamin D (50000 monthly) helped antarctic explorers – RCT</title><link>/posts/1700-iu-vitamin-d-50000-monthly-helped-antarctic-explorers-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1700-iu-vitamin-d-50000-monthly-helped-antarctic-explorers-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="skeletal-and-hormonal-responses-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-sunlight-deprivation-in-antarctic-expeditioners">Skeletal and hormonal responses to vitamin D supplementation during sunlight deprivation in Antarctic expeditioners.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Jan 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Iuliano-Burns S, Ayton J, Hillam S, Jones G, King K, Macleod S, Seeman E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Austin Health, University of Melbourne, Parkville, Australia, &lt;a href="mailto:sandraib@unimelb.edu.au">sandraib@unimelb.edu.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight deprivation results in vitamin D deficiency but serum vitamin D levels can be maintained above 50nmol/L when supplemented with 50,000IU at least every alternate month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Antarctic expeditioners are exposed to prolonged sunlight deprivation resulting in vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Inuit do not need as much vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-inuit-do-not-need-as-much-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-inuit-do-not-need-as-much-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Use of tanning beds would reduce associated deaths by 10X</title><link>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-sun-sunbeds-and-health">Vitamin D, sun, sunbeds and health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Oct 24:1-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moan J, Baturaite Z, Juzeniene A, Porojnicu AC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, The Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Ullernchausseen 70, Montebello N-0310 Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To review the health effects of solar radiation, sunbeds and vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DESIGN: The literature was searched in the electronic database MEDLINE to indentify published data between 1981 and 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why has the MS latitude gradient disappeared</title><link>/posts/why-has-the-ms-latitude-gradient-disappeared.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-has-the-ms-latitude-gradient-disappeared.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="why-does-the-northsouth-gradient-of-incidence-of-multiple-sclerosis-seem-to-have-disappeared-on-the-northern-hemisphere">Why does the north–south gradient of incidence of multiple sclerosis seem to have disappeared on the Northern hemisphere?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of the Neurological Sciences, doi:10.1016/j.jns.2011.09.003&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nils Koch-Henriksen a, b, Per Soelberg Sorensen c, &lt;a href="mailto:pss@rh.dk">pss@rh.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a	Department of Neurology, Aarhus University Hospital in Aalborg, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b	The Danish Multiple Sclerosis Registry, Neuroscience Centre, Copenhagen University Hospital Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c	Danish Multiple Sclerosis Center, University of Copenhagen and Department of Neurology, Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Graphs of diseases vs vitamin D levels - and D3 vs D2</title><link>/posts/graphs-of-diseases-vs-vitamin-d-levels-and-d3-vs-d2.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/graphs-of-diseases-vs-vitamin-d-levels-and-d3-vs-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="graphs-from-a-presentation-by-dr-grimes-in-london">Graphs from a presentation by Dr. Grimes in London&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PDF of the presentation is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindassociation.org/7th-april-2011-vitamin-d---experts-forum.html">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for audio and video versions on the web (Clinical Experiences)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="can-see-that-the-patients-with-east-asian-names-have-significantly-lower-vitamin-d-levels-than-those-with-british-names">Can see that the patients with East Asian Names have significantly lower vitamin D levels than those with British Names&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;735,734&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="median-east-asian--9-ng--nbsp-nbspmedian-british--19-ng">Median East Asian = 9 ng    Median British = 19 ng&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="notepatients-with-the-lowest-level-of-vitamin-d-in-their-blood-are-on-the-right">Note:patients with the lowest level of vitamin D in their blood are on the right&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="graphs-showing-the-vitamin-d-levels-for-each-disease">Graphs showing the vitamin D levels for each disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;736,737,738,739,740,741,742,743,744,745&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;250&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Disadvantaged get less sun and have poor health in the North</title><link>/posts/disadvantaged-get-less-sun-and-have-poor-health-in-the-north.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/disadvantaged-get-less-sun-and-have-poor-health-in-the-north.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>How did people used to get vitamin D when far from equator in the Winter</title><link>/posts/how-did-people-used-to-get-vitamin-d-when-far-from-equator-in-the-winter.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-did-people-used-to-get-vitamin-d-when-far-from-equator-in-the-winter.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="wondering-how-people-used-to-get-vitamin-d-in-the-winter">Wondering how people used to get vitamin D in the winter&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="note-it-appears-that-no-vitamin-d-from-the-sun-when-40-degrees-away-from-equator-in-the-winter">Note: It appears that no vitamin D from the sun when 40 degrees away from equator in the winter.&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Burn the fat &amp;amp; vitamin D in the body which had been added with summer feasting&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Winters were times of famine/fasting - and burning of fat and retrieving vitamin D stored in the fat&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Campfires? - some small amount of vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inuit and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/inuit-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inuit-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="two-articles-from-2011-and-many-links-on-this-page">Two articles from 2011 and many links on this page&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="food-insecurity-and-nutrition-transition-combine-to-affect-nutrient-intakes-in-canadian-arctic-communities-july-2011">Food Insecurity and Nutrition Transition Combine to Affect Nutrient Intakes in Canadian Arctic Communities. July 2011&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2011 Jul 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Egeland GM, Johnson-Down L, Cao ZR, Sheikh N, Weiler H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Indigenous Peoples&amp;rsquo; Nutrition and Environment and School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition, McGill University, Ste. Anne-de-Bellevue, QC, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Food insecurity and the nutrition transition have been noted in arctic communities. We therefore evaluated biomarkers of nutritional status and nutrient intakes by TF and food security status among Inuit in Canada. A cross-sectional health survey of Inuit (?18 y) in 36 arctic communities was conducted in 2007-2008. Food security was assessed by 24-h &lt;strong>dietary recalls&lt;/strong> using USDA questionnaires and nutrient intakes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Race vs vitamin D level - Veith</title><link>/posts/race-vs-vitamin-d-level-veith.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/race-vs-vitamin-d-level-veith.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>People with no UV for 6 months in the winter need at least 2000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/people-with-no-uv-for-6-months-in-the-winter-need-at-least-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-no-uv-for-6-months-in-the-winter-need-at-least-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-antarctic-winter-is-related-to-bmi">Response to vitamin D supplementation during Antarctic winter is related to BMI,&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>and supplementation can mitigate Epstein-Barr Virus Reactivation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2011 Apr 1;141(4):692-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zwart SR, Mehta SK, Ploutz-Snyder R, Bourbeau Y, Locke JP, Pierson DL, Smith SM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Universities Space Research Association, Houston, TX 77058, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maintaining vitamin D status without sunlight exposure is difficult without supplementation. This study was designed to better understand interrelationships between periodic vitamin D supplementation and immune function in Antarctic workers. The effect of 2 oral dosing regimens of vitamin D supplementation on vitamin D status and markers of immune function was evaluated in people in Antarctica with no UV light exposure for 6 mo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS is related to latitude – conclusion from 321 studies</title><link>/posts/ms-is-related-to-latitude-conclusion-from-321-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-is-related-to-latitude-conclusion-from-321-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="ms-is-significantly-associated-with-the-prevalence-of-multiple-sclerosis-a-meta-analysis">MS is significantly associated with the prevalence of multiple sclerosis: a meta-analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011 Apr 8. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simpson S Jr, Blizzard L, Otahal P, Van der Mei I, Taylor B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Menzies Research Institute Tasmania, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background There is a striking latitudinal gradient in multiple sclerosis (MS) prevalence, but exceptions in Mediterranean Europe and northern Scandinavia, and some systematic reviews, have suggested that the gradient may be an artefact. The authors sought to evaluate the association between MS prevalence and latitude by meta-regression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Latitude may not be too associated with vitamin D – Masterjohn</title><link>/posts/latitude-may-not-be-too-associated-with-vitamin-d-masterjohn.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/latitude-may-not-be-too-associated-with-vitamin-d-masterjohn.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d----problems-with-the-latitude-hypothesis">V!itamin D &amp;ndash; Problems With the Latitude Hypothesis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Posted by: Christopher Masterjohn in WAPF Blog on 12/24/10&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="virtually-everything-we-know-about-vitamin-d-and-latitude-might-be-wrong">Virtually everything we know about vitamin D and latitude might be wrong.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="click-herehttpwwwwestonapriceorgblogsvitamin-d-problems-with-the-latitude-hypothesisbloggercmasterjo-for-original-article-with-all-hyperlinks">&lt;a href="http://www.westonaprice.org/blogs/vitamin-d-problems-with-the-latitude-hypothesis/blogger/CMASTERJO/">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for original article with all hyperlinks&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When I wrote &amp;ldquo;Seafood to Sunshine: A New Understanding of Vitamin D Safety&amp;rdquo; in 2006, I took it for granted that the conventional beliefs about the effect of latitude on vitamin D synthesis were true. Here is what I wrote:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Only 18 percent of Swedes got recommended amount of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/only-18-percent-of-swedes-got-recommended-amount-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/only-18-percent-of-swedes-got-recommended-amount-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="development-of-a-diet-quality-index-assessing-adherence-to-the-swedish-nutrition-recommendations-and-dietary-guidelines-in-the-malmö-diet-and-cancer-cohort">Development of a diet quality index assessing adherence to the Swedish nutrition recommendations and dietary guidelines in the Malmö Diet and Cancer cohort.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Feb 7:1-11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drake I, Gullberg B, Ericson U, Sonestedt E, Nilsson J, Wallström P, Hedblad B, Wirfält E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Sciences in Malmö, Lund University, Skåne University Hospital, Malmö, Sweden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To develop a diet quality index (DQI) that assesses adherence to the Swedish nutrition recommendations (SNR) and the Swedish dietary guidelines (SDG).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>744 IU vitamin D needed by Northern white teens to prevent Rickets</title><link>/posts/744-iu-vitamin-d-needed-by-northern-white-teens-to-prevent-rickets.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/744-iu-vitamin-d-needed-by-northern-white-teens-to-prevent-rickets.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="estimation-of-the-dietary-requirement-for-vitamin-d-in-healthy-adolescent-white-girls">Estimation of the dietary requirement for vitamin D in healthy adolescent white girls.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jan 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cashman KD, Fitzgerald AP, Viljakainen HT, Jakobsen J, Michaelsen KF, Lamberg-Allardt C, Mølgaard C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Food and Nutritional Sciences and Departments of Medicine and Epidemiology and Public Health, and Statistics, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Knowledge gaps have contributed to considerable variation (between 0 and 15 ?g/d) between international dietary recommendations for vitamin D in adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alaskan Resolutions to increase vitamin D</title><link>/posts/alaskan-resolutions-to-increase-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alaskan-resolutions-to-increase-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="update-a-hrefpostsalaska-recommends-more-vitamin-d-infancy-800-iu-pregnancy-1400-iu-avoid-rickets-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-alaska-recommends-more-vitamin-d-infancy-800-iu-pregnancy-1400-iu-avoid-rickets-sept-2018alaska-recommends-more-vitamin-d-infancy-800-iu-pregnancy-1400-iu-avoid-rickets-sept-2018a">Update &lt;a href="/posts/alaska-recommends-more-vitamin-d-infancy-800-iu-pregnancy-1400-iu-avoid-rickets" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Alaska recommends more vitamin D: Infancy 800 IU, Pregnancy 1400 IU (avoid rickets) Sept 2018">Alaska recommends more vitamin D: Infancy 800 IU, Pregnancy 1400 IU (avoid rickets) Sept 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h3 id="update-feb-2013-alaska-house-bill-90httpwwwadncom201302232799920legislator-wants-to-test-alaskahtml-vitamin-d-newborn-testing">&lt;a href="http://www.adn.com/2013/02/23/2799920/legislator-wants-to-test-alaska.html">Update Feb 2013 Alaska House Bill 90&lt;/a> Vitamin D newborn testing&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rep. Paul Seaton, R-Homer, keeps Costco-sized bottles of vitamin D in his office for anyone who may be lacking and plans to hand them out to fellow legislators, as he&amp;rsquo;s done in the past.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schizophrenia and vitamin D have latitude-related genes</title><link>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-related-genes-could-have-been-subject-to-latitude-driven-adaptation">Schizophrenia and Vitamin D Related Genes Could Have Been Subject to Latitude-driven Adaptation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Roberto Amato email, Michele Pinelli email, Antonella Monticelli email, Gennaro Miele email and Sergio Cocozza email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Evolutionary Biology 2010, 10:351doi:10.1186/1471-2148-10-351; Published: 	11 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many natural phenomena are directly or indirectly related to latitude. Living at different latitudes, indeed, has its consequences with being exposed to different climates, diets, light/dark cycles, etc. In humans, one of the best known examples of genetic traits following a latitudinal gradient is skin pigmentation. Nevertheless, also several diseases show latitudinal clinals such as hypertension, cancer, dismetabolic conditions, schizophrenia, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease and many more.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>