<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vitamin D Far From Equator on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/vitamin-d-far-from-equator.html</link><description>Recent content in Vitamin D Far From Equator on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vitamin-d-far-from-equator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use of tanning beds would reduce associated deaths by 10X</title><link>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/use-of-tanning-beds-would-reduce-associated-deaths-by-10x.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-sun-sunbeds-and-health">Vitamin D, sun, sunbeds and health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Oct 24:1-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moan J, Baturaite Z, Juzeniene A, Porojnicu AC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, The Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Ullernchausseen 70, Montebello N-0310 Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To review the health effects of solar radiation, sunbeds and vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DESIGN: The literature was searched in the electronic database MEDLINE to indentify published data between 1981 and 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why has the MS latitude gradient disappeared</title><link>/posts/why-has-the-ms-latitude-gradient-disappeared.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-has-the-ms-latitude-gradient-disappeared.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="why-does-the-northsouth-gradient-of-incidence-of-multiple-sclerosis-seem-to-have-disappeared-on-the-northern-hemisphere">Why does the north–south gradient of incidence of multiple sclerosis seem to have disappeared on the Northern hemisphere?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of the Neurological Sciences, doi:10.1016/j.jns.2011.09.003&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nils Koch-Henriksen a, b, Per Soelberg Sorensen c, &lt;a href="mailto:pss@rh.dk">pss@rh.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a	Department of Neurology, Aarhus University Hospital in Aalborg, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b	The Danish Multiple Sclerosis Registry, Neuroscience Centre, Copenhagen University Hospital Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c	Danish Multiple Sclerosis Center, University of Copenhagen and Department of Neurology, Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Graphs of diseases vs vitamin D levels - and D3 vs D2</title><link>/posts/graphs-of-diseases-vs-vitamin-d-levels-and-d3-vs-d2.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/graphs-of-diseases-vs-vitamin-d-levels-and-d3-vs-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="graphs-from-a-presentation-by-dr-grimes-in-london">Graphs from a presentation by Dr. Grimes in London&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PDF of the presentation is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindassociation.org/7th-april-2011-vitamin-d---experts-forum.html">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for audio and video versions on the web (Clinical Experiences)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="can-see-that-the-patients-with-east-asian-names-have-significantly-lower-vitamin-d-levels-than-those-with-british-names">Can see that the patients with East Asian Names have significantly lower vitamin D levels than those with British Names&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;735,734&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="median-east-asian--9-ng--nbsp-nbspmedian-british--19-ng">Median East Asian = 9 ng    Median British = 19 ng&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="notepatients-with-the-lowest-level-of-vitamin-d-in-their-blood-are-on-the-right">Note:patients with the lowest level of vitamin D in their blood are on the right&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="graphs-showing-the-vitamin-d-levels-for-each-disease">Graphs showing the vitamin D levels for each disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;736,737,738,739,740,741,742,743,744,745&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;250&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Disadvantaged get less sun and have poor health in the North</title><link>/posts/disadvantaged-get-less-sun-and-have-poor-health-in-the-north.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/disadvantaged-get-less-sun-and-have-poor-health-in-the-north.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>How did people used to get vitamin D when far from equator in the Winter</title><link>/posts/how-did-people-used-to-get-vitamin-d-when-far-from-equator-in-the-winter.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-did-people-used-to-get-vitamin-d-when-far-from-equator-in-the-winter.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="wondering-how-people-used-to-get-vitamin-d-in-the-winter">Wondering how people used to get vitamin D in the winter&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="note-it-appears-that-no-vitamin-d-from-the-sun-when-40-degrees-away-from-equator-in-the-winter">Note: It appears that no vitamin D from the sun when 40 degrees away from equator in the winter.&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Burn the fat &amp;amp; vitamin D in the body which had been added with summer feasting&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Winters were times of famine/fasting - and burning of fat and retrieving vitamin D stored in the fat&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Campfires? - some small amount of vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inuit and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/inuit-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inuit-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="two-articles-from-2011-and-many-links-on-this-page">Two articles from 2011 and many links on this page&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="food-insecurity-and-nutrition-transition-combine-to-affect-nutrient-intakes-in-canadian-arctic-communities-july-2011">Food Insecurity and Nutrition Transition Combine to Affect Nutrient Intakes in Canadian Arctic Communities. July 2011&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2011 Jul 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Egeland GM, Johnson-Down L, Cao ZR, Sheikh N, Weiler H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Indigenous Peoples&amp;rsquo; Nutrition and Environment and School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition, McGill University, Ste. Anne-de-Bellevue, QC, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Food insecurity and the nutrition transition have been noted in arctic communities. We therefore evaluated biomarkers of nutritional status and nutrient intakes by TF and food security status among Inuit in Canada. A cross-sectional health survey of Inuit (?18 y) in 36 arctic communities was conducted in 2007-2008. Food security was assessed by 24-h &lt;strong>dietary recalls&lt;/strong> using USDA questionnaires and nutrient intakes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Race vs vitamin D level - Veith</title><link>/posts/race-vs-vitamin-d-level-veith.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/race-vs-vitamin-d-level-veith.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>People with no UV for 6 months in the winter need at least 2000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/people-with-no-uv-for-6-months-in-the-winter-need-at-least-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-no-uv-for-6-months-in-the-winter-need-at-least-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-antarctic-winter-is-related-to-bmi">Response to vitamin D supplementation during Antarctic winter is related to BMI,&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>and supplementation can mitigate Epstein-Barr Virus Reactivation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2011 Apr 1;141(4):692-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zwart SR, Mehta SK, Ploutz-Snyder R, Bourbeau Y, Locke JP, Pierson DL, Smith SM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Universities Space Research Association, Houston, TX 77058, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maintaining vitamin D status without sunlight exposure is difficult without supplementation. This study was designed to better understand interrelationships between periodic vitamin D supplementation and immune function in Antarctic workers. The effect of 2 oral dosing regimens of vitamin D supplementation on vitamin D status and markers of immune function was evaluated in people in Antarctica with no UV light exposure for 6 mo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS is related to latitude – conclusion from 321 studies</title><link>/posts/ms-is-related-to-latitude-conclusion-from-321-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-is-related-to-latitude-conclusion-from-321-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="ms-is-significantly-associated-with-the-prevalence-of-multiple-sclerosis-a-meta-analysis">MS is significantly associated with the prevalence of multiple sclerosis: a meta-analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011 Apr 8. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simpson S Jr, Blizzard L, Otahal P, Van der Mei I, Taylor B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Menzies Research Institute Tasmania, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background There is a striking latitudinal gradient in multiple sclerosis (MS) prevalence, but exceptions in Mediterranean Europe and northern Scandinavia, and some systematic reviews, have suggested that the gradient may be an artefact. The authors sought to evaluate the association between MS prevalence and latitude by meta-regression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Latitude may not be too associated with vitamin D – Masterjohn</title><link>/posts/latitude-may-not-be-too-associated-with-vitamin-d-masterjohn.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/latitude-may-not-be-too-associated-with-vitamin-d-masterjohn.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d----problems-with-the-latitude-hypothesis">V!itamin D &amp;ndash; Problems With the Latitude Hypothesis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Posted by: Christopher Masterjohn in WAPF Blog on 12/24/10&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="virtually-everything-we-know-about-vitamin-d-and-latitude-might-be-wrong">Virtually everything we know about vitamin D and latitude might be wrong.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="click-herehttpwwwwestonapriceorgblogsvitamin-d-problems-with-the-latitude-hypothesisbloggercmasterjo-for-original-article-with-all-hyperlinks">&lt;a href="http://www.westonaprice.org/blogs/vitamin-d-problems-with-the-latitude-hypothesis/blogger/CMASTERJO/">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for original article with all hyperlinks&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When I wrote &amp;ldquo;Seafood to Sunshine: A New Understanding of Vitamin D Safety&amp;rdquo; in 2006, I took it for granted that the conventional beliefs about the effect of latitude on vitamin D synthesis were true. Here is what I wrote:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Only 18 percent of Swedes got recommended amount of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/only-18-percent-of-swedes-got-recommended-amount-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/only-18-percent-of-swedes-got-recommended-amount-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="development-of-a-diet-quality-index-assessing-adherence-to-the-swedish-nutrition-recommendations-and-dietary-guidelines-in-the-malmö-diet-and-cancer-cohort">Development of a diet quality index assessing adherence to the Swedish nutrition recommendations and dietary guidelines in the Malmö Diet and Cancer cohort.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Feb 7:1-11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drake I, Gullberg B, Ericson U, Sonestedt E, Nilsson J, Wallström P, Hedblad B, Wirfält E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Sciences in Malmö, Lund University, Skåne University Hospital, Malmö, Sweden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To develop a diet quality index (DQI) that assesses adherence to the Swedish nutrition recommendations (SNR) and the Swedish dietary guidelines (SDG).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>744 IU vitamin D needed by Northern white teens to prevent Rickets</title><link>/posts/744-iu-vitamin-d-needed-by-northern-white-teens-to-prevent-rickets.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/744-iu-vitamin-d-needed-by-northern-white-teens-to-prevent-rickets.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="estimation-of-the-dietary-requirement-for-vitamin-d-in-healthy-adolescent-white-girls">Estimation of the dietary requirement for vitamin D in healthy adolescent white girls.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jan 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cashman KD, Fitzgerald AP, Viljakainen HT, Jakobsen J, Michaelsen KF, Lamberg-Allardt C, Mølgaard C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Food and Nutritional Sciences and Departments of Medicine and Epidemiology and Public Health, and Statistics, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Knowledge gaps have contributed to considerable variation (between 0 and 15 ?g/d) between international dietary recommendations for vitamin D in adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alaskan Resolutions to increase vitamin D</title><link>/posts/alaskan-resolutions-to-increase-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alaskan-resolutions-to-increase-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="update-a-hrefpostsalaska-recommends-more-vitamin-d-infancy-800-iu-pregnancy-1400-iu-avoid-rickets-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-alaska-recommends-more-vitamin-d-infancy-800-iu-pregnancy-1400-iu-avoid-rickets-sept-2018alaska-recommends-more-vitamin-d-infancy-800-iu-pregnancy-1400-iu-avoid-rickets-sept-2018a">Update &lt;a href="/posts/alaska-recommends-more-vitamin-d-infancy-800-iu-pregnancy-1400-iu-avoid-rickets" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Alaska recommends more vitamin D: Infancy 800 IU, Pregnancy 1400 IU (avoid rickets) Sept 2018">Alaska recommends more vitamin D: Infancy 800 IU, Pregnancy 1400 IU (avoid rickets) Sept 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h3 id="update-feb-2013-alaska-house-bill-90httpwwwadncom201302232799920legislator-wants-to-test-alaskahtml-vitamin-d-newborn-testing">&lt;a href="http://www.adn.com/2013/02/23/2799920/legislator-wants-to-test-alaska.html">Update Feb 2013 Alaska House Bill 90&lt;/a> Vitamin D newborn testing&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rep. Paul Seaton, R-Homer, keeps Costco-sized bottles of vitamin D in his office for anyone who may be lacking and plans to hand them out to fellow legislators, as he&amp;rsquo;s done in the past.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schizophrenia and vitamin D have latitude-related genes</title><link>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-related-genes-could-have-been-subject-to-latitude-driven-adaptation">Schizophrenia and Vitamin D Related Genes Could Have Been Subject to Latitude-driven Adaptation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Roberto Amato email, Michele Pinelli email, Antonella Monticelli email, Gennaro Miele email and Sergio Cocozza email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Evolutionary Biology 2010, 10:351doi:10.1186/1471-2148-10-351; Published: 	11 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many natural phenomena are directly or indirectly related to latitude. Living at different latitudes, indeed, has its consequences with being exposed to different climates, diets, light/dark cycles, etc. In humans, one of the best known examples of genetic traits following a latitudinal gradient is skin pigmentation. Nevertheless, also several diseases show latitudinal clinals such as hypertension, cancer, dismetabolic conditions, schizophrenia, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease and many more.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>