<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Osteoporosis on VitaminDWiki</title><link>//localhost:1313/categories/osteoporosis.html</link><description>Recent content in Osteoporosis on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/osteoporosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Osteoporosis International Vitamin D recommendation: 1,000 IU is enough, D2 or D3, by prescription only</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/osteoporosis-international-vitamin-d-recommendation-1000-iu-is-enough-d2-or-d3-by-prescription-only.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/osteoporosis-international-vitamin-d-recommendation-1000-iu-is-enough-d2-or-d3-by-prescription-only.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="optimisation-of-vitamin-d-status-in-global-populations">Optimisation of vitamin D status in global populations&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis International &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-024-07127-z">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-024-07127-z&lt;/a>     &lt;a href="https://www.deepdyve.com/lp/springer-journal/optimisation-of-vitamin-d-status-in-global-populations-bg6plG4NHj?key=springer">DeepDyve&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N.C. Harvey, K.A. Ward, D. Agnusdei, N. Binkley, E. Biver, C. Campusano, E. Cavalier, P. Clark, M. Diaz-Curiel, G.E.-H. Fuleihan, P. Khashayar, N.E. Lane, O.D. Messina, A. Mithal, R. Rizzoli, C. Sempos &amp;amp; B. Dawson-Hughes on behalf of the International Osteoporosis Foundation Vitamin D Working Group&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is important for musculoskeletal health. Concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D, the most commonly measured metabolite, vary markedly around the world and are influenced by many factors including sun exposure, skin pigmentation, covering, season and supplement use. Whilst overt vitamin D deficiency with biochemical consequences presents an increased risk of severe sequelae such as rickets, osteomalacia or cardiomyopathy and usually warrants prompt replacement treatment, the role of vitamin D supplementation in the population presents a different set of considerations. Here the issue is to keep, on average, the population at a level whereby the risk of adverse health outcomes in the population is minimised. This position paper, which complements recently published work from the European Society for Clinical and Economic Aspects of Osteoporosis, Osteoarthritis and Musculoskeletal Diseases, addresses key considerations regarding vitamin D assessment and intervention from the population perspective.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip joint destroyed in months (rare) is associated with especially low Vitamin D</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/hip-joint-destroyed-in-months-rare-is-associated-with-especially-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/hip-joint-destroyed-in-months-rare-is-associated-with-especially-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-is-frequent-in-patients-with-rapidly-destructive-osteoarthritisdata-from-a-single-center-analysis">Vitamin D Deficiency Is Frequent in Patients with Rapidly Destructive Osteoarthritis—Data from a Single-Center Analysis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-frequent-in-patients-with-rapidly-destructive-osteoarthritisdata-from-a-single-center-analysis">Vitamin D Deficiency Is Frequent in Patients with Rapidly Destructive Osteoarthritis—Data from a Single-Center Analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J. Clin. Med. 2024, 13(5), 1296; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm13051296">https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm13051296&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Konstantin Horas 1,*,†ORCID,Gerrit Maier 2,†,Maximilian Rudert 1ORCID,Axel Jakuscheit 1ORCID,Manuel Weißenberger 1,3ORCID,Ioannis Stratos 1ORCID,Tizian Heinz 1,Dominik Rak 1ORCID,Philip Mark Anderson 1ORCID andJörg Arnholdt 4&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/png/rdo.png" alt="image" width="300">
&lt;p>Background: &lt;strong>Rapidly destructive osteoarthritis (RDO) of the hip joint&lt;/strong> is characterised by the rapid destruction of the femoral head with or without acetabular involvement. There has been increasing interest in this disease over the past years; however, the entity is still poorly understood, and its pathophysiology remains unknown. Yet, there is ample evidence today that increased bone metabolism might play a role in the onset and progression of the disease. Vitamin D is of utmost importance to maintain a balanced bone metabolism. However, whether vitamin D deficiency is involved in disease development remains to be elucidated. Further, the vitamin D status of patients with RDO has not yet been analysed. For this reason, the objective of this study was to assess the vitamin D status of patients with RDO. Moreover, the aim was to clarify whether there is a difference in the vitamin D status of patients with RDO compared with patients with primary osteoarthritis (OA).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Potassium helps bones by increasing the absorption of both Calcium and Vitamin D</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/potassium-helps-bones-by-increasing-the-absorption-of-both-calcium-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/potassium-helps-bones-by-increasing-the-absorption-of-both-calcium-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#potassium-a-frontier-in-osteoporosis">Potassium: A Frontier in Osteoporosis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dietary-guidelines">Dietary Guidelines&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#chart-of-recent-decrease-in-potassium-from-crops---published-2020">Chart of recent decrease in Potassium from crops - published 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="potassium-a-frontier-in-osteoporosis">Potassium: A Frontier in Osteoporosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Horm Metab Res DOI: 10.1055/a-2254-8533&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Widhilika Singh , Poonam Kushwaha&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis is a significant public health concern, particularly in aging populations, leading to fractures, decreased mobility, and reduced quality of life. While calcium and vitamin D have long been recognized as essential for bone health, emerging research suggests that potassium may play a crucial role in maintaining bone density and preventing osteoporosis. This manuscript explores the relationship between potassium and osteoporosis, delving into the mechanisms, epidemiological evidence, and potential therapeutic implications of potassium in bone health. Furthermore, the manuscript discusses the sources of dietary potassium, its impact on bone metabolism, and the future directions in research and clinical practice regarding potassium’s role in osteoporosis management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off Topic: Xylitol reduces cavities, preterm births, osteoporosis, RTI, obesity, diabetes, etc. - several studies</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/off-topic-xylitol-reduces-cavities-preterm-births-osteoporosis-rti-obesity-diabe-several-studies.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/off-topic-xylitol-reduces-cavities-preterm-births-osteoporosis-rti-obesity-diabe-several-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#xylitol-reduced-preterm-births-40-and-cavities-in-their-infants-by-70---dec-2023">Xylitol reduced preterm births 40%, and cavities in their infants by 70% - Dec 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#oral-and-systemic-effects-of-xylitol-consumption---may-2019">Oral and Systemic Effects of Xylitol Consumption - May 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#xylitol-chewing-gums-reduced-risk-of-dental-caries-by-37x---dec-1995">Xylitol Chewing Gums reduced risk of dental caries by 3.7X - Dec 1995&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#health-benefits-of-xylitol---july-2020">Health benefits of xylitol - July 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effects-of-xylitol-chewing-gum-and-candies-on-the-accumulation-of-dental-plaque-a-systematic-review-review---oct-2021">Effects of xylitol chewing gum and candies on the accumulation of dental plaque: a systematic review Review - Oct 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-of-100s-of-xylitol-videos">Some of 100&amp;rsquo;s of Xylitol videos&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="xylitol-reduced-preterm-births-40-and-cavities-in-their-infants-by-70---dec-2023">Xylitol reduced preterm births 40%, and cavities in their infants by 70% - Dec 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Xylitol and the Gateway Microbiome&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>