<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Osteoporosis on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/osteoporosis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Osteoporosis on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/osteoporosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hip joint destroyed in months (rare) is associated with especially low Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hip-joint-destroyed-in-months-rare-is-associated-with-especially-low-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hip-joint-destroyed-in-months-rare-is-associated-with-especially-low-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-deficiency-is-frequent-in-patients-with-rapidly-destructive-osteoarthritisdata-from-a-single-center-analysis&#34;&gt;Vitamin D Deficiency Is Frequent in Patients with Rapidly Destructive Osteoarthritis—Data from a Single-Center Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J. Clin. Med. 2024, 13(5), 1296; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm13051296&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm13051296&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Konstantin Horas 1,*,†ORCID,Gerrit Maier 2,†,Maximilian Rudert 1ORCID,Axel Jakuscheit 1ORCID,Manuel Weißenberger 1,3ORCID,Ioannis Stratos 1ORCID,Tizian Heinz 1,Dominik Rak 1ORCID,Philip Mark Anderson 1ORCID andJörg Arnholdt 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background:  &lt;strong&gt;Rapidly destructive osteoarthritis (RDO) of the hip joint&lt;/strong&gt;  is characterised by the rapid destruction of the femoral head with or without acetabular involvement. There has been increasing interest in this disease over the past years; however, the entity is still poorly understood, and its pathophysiology remains unknown. Yet, there is ample evidence today that increased bone metabolism might play a role in the onset and progression of the disease. Vitamin D is of utmost importance to maintain a balanced bone metabolism. However, whether vitamin D deficiency is involved in disease development remains to be elucidated. Further, the vitamin D status of patients with RDO has not yet been analysed. For this reason, the objective of this study was to assess the vitamin D status of patients with RDO. Moreover, the aim was to clarify whether there is a difference in the vitamin D status of patients with RDO compared with patients with primary osteoarthritis (OA).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potassium helps bones by increasing the absorption of both Calcium and Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/potassium-helps-bones-by-increasing-the-absorption-of-both-calcium-and-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/potassium-helps-bones-by-increasing-the-absorption-of-both-calcium-and-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;potassium-a-frontier-in-osteoporosis&#34;&gt;Potassium: A Frontier in Osteoporosis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Horm Metab Res DOI: 10.1055/a-2254-8533&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Widhilika Singh , Poonam Kushwaha&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Osteoporosis is a significant public health concern, particularly in aging populations, leading to fractures, decreased mobility, and reduced quality of life. While calcium and vitamin D have long been recognized as essential for bone health, emerging research suggests that potassium may play a crucial role in maintaining bone density and preventing osteoporosis. This manuscript explores the relationship between potassium and osteoporosis, delving into the mechanisms, epidemiological evidence, and potential therapeutic implications of potassium in bone health. Furthermore, the manuscript discusses the sources of dietary potassium, its impact on bone metabolism, and the future directions in research and clinical practice regarding potassium’s role in osteoporosis management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off Topic: Xylitol reduces cavities, preterm births, osteoporosis, RTI, obesity, diabetes, etc. - several studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/off-topic-xylitol-reduces-cavities-preterm-births-osteoporosis-rti-obesity-diabe-several-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/off-topic-xylitol-reduces-cavities-preterm-births-osteoporosis-rti-obesity-diabe-several-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;xylitol-reduced-preterm-births-40-and-cavities-in-their-infants-by-70---dec-2023&#34;&gt;Xylitol reduced preterm births 40%, and cavities in their infants by 70% - Dec 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xylitol and the Gateway Microbiome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://petermcculloughmd.substack.com/p/xylitol-and-the-gateway-microbiome?utm_source=post-email-title&amp;amp;publication_id=1119676&amp;amp;post_id=140219879&amp;amp;utm_campaign=email-post-title&amp;amp;isFreemail=false&amp;amp;r=ofo3r&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&#34;&gt;McCullogh Substack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The oropharynx harbors thousands of bacteria and fungi that live in symbiosis with the human body. This is called the “gateway microbiome” since the nose and the mouth are the entry point for air, water, and food to the human body. &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aagaard et al conducted a large clinical study using xylitol based chewing gum in pregnant women—the results were astonishing, a 24% reduction in pre-term birth. This may have occurred due to a lesser risk of febrile infections or other factors that trigger premature labor.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Osteosarcopenia 4.5X more likely if low vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteosarcopenia-45x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteosarcopenia-45x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;Osteosarcopenia&lt;/span&gt; is a syndrome that occurs when someone has both osteoporosis and sarcopenia.%%%Osteoporosis is characterized by low bone mass and bone tissue deterioration. %%%Sarcopenia  is characterized by a loss of muscle mass, strength, and function.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;osteosarcopenia-later-in-life-prevalence-and-associated-risk-factors&#34;&gt;Osteosarcopenia later in life: Prevalence and associated risk factors&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clin Nutr ESPEN  2023 Dec:58:213-220. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnesp.2023.08.030&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.clnesp.2023.08.030&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Erika A Silveira 1, Guilherme Vinícius-Souza 2, Cristina Camargo Pereira 2, Cesar de Oliveira 3, Matias Noll 4, Valéria Pagotto 5&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Osteoporosis treatment by zoledronic acid painful if low vitamin D (nomogram)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteoporosis-treatment-by-zoledronic-acid-painful-if-low-vitamin-d-nomogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteoporosis-treatment-by-zoledronic-acid-painful-if-low-vitamin-d-nomogram/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;prediction-of-musculoskeletal-pain-after-the-first-intravenous-zoledronic-acid-injection-in-patients-with-primary-osteoporosis-development-and-evaluation-of-a-new-nomogram&#34;&gt;Prediction of musculoskeletal pain after the first intravenous zoledronic acid injection in patients with primary osteoporosis: development and evaluation of a new nomogram&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders vol 24, #: 841 (2023) &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s12891-023-06965-y&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/s12891-023-06965-y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Xiaoxia Zheng, Jiangnan Ye, Qunzhang Zhan, Weifeng Zhao, Zhongqin Liao, Xiaolin Ye &amp;amp; Chongzheng Qu&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objective&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To construct a new prediction nomogram to predict the risk of musculoskeletal pain in patients with primary osteoporosis who receive zoledronic acid intravenously for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Selenium intake cuts risk of Osteoporosis in half - meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-selenium-intake-cuts-risk-of-osteoporosis-in-half-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-selenium-intake-cuts-risk-of-osteoporosis-in-half-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-association-between-selenium-and-bone-health-a-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;The association between selenium and bone health: a meta-analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bone Joint Res . 2023 Jul 6;12(7):423-432. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1302/2046-3758.127.BJR-2022-0420.R1.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1302/2046-3758.127.BJR-2022-0420.R1.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Haibin Xie 1, Ning Wang 1, Hongyi He 1, Zidan Yang 2 3, Jing Wu 2 3, Tuo Yang 3 4, Yilun Wang 1 2 3 5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aims: Previous studies have suggested that selenium as a trace element is involved in bone health, but findings related to the specific effect of selenium on bone health remain inconclusive. Thus, we performed a meta-analysis by including all the relevant studies to elucidate the association between selenium status (dietary intake or serum selenium) and bone health indicators (bone mineral density (BMD), osteoporosis (OP), or fracture).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D Receptors in muscles decrease with age in those with Osteoporosis - 2018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-receptors-in-muscles-decrease-with-age-in-those-with-osteoporosis-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-receptors-in-muscles-decrease-with-age-in-those-with-osteoporosis-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-receptor-in-muscle-atrophy-of-elderly-patients-a-key-element-of-osteoporosis-sarcopenia-connection&#34;&gt;Vitamin D Receptor in Muscle Atrophy of Elderly Patients: A Key Element of Osteoporosis-Sarcopenia Connection&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aging and disease ›› 2018, Vol. 9 ›› Issue (6) : 952-964. DOI: 10.14336/AD.2018.0215&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this study, we investigated the relationship between sarcopenia (evaluated in term of fibers atrophy), vitamin d receptor protein expression and TaqI/Cdx2/FokI VDR genotypes in an Italian cohort of osteoporosis(n=44) and osteoarthritis (n=55) patients. Muscle biopsies were fixed and investigated by both immunohistochemistry (vitamin d receptor expression) and transmission electron microscopy (satellite stem cells niches). Vitamin d receptor polymorphisms were studied on DNA extracted from muscle paraffin sections. For the first time, we reported that aging differently affects the VDR activation in OA and OP patients. In particular, while in  &lt;strong&gt;OP patients we observed a significant reduction of VDR positive myonuclei with age&lt;/strong&gt; , no “age effect” was observed in OA patients. The frequent activation of VDR could explain the lower number of atrophic fiber that we observed in OA patients respect to OP. From genetic point of view, we showed a putative association among polymorphisms FokI and Cdx2 of VDR gene, vitamin d receptor activation and the occurrence of sarcopenia. Altogether these data open new prospective for the prevention and cure of age-related muscle disorders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Osteoporosis consensus includes Vitamin D and Calcium (Ecuador)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteoporosis-consensus-includes-vitamin-d-and-calcium-ecuador/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteoporosis-consensus-includes-vitamin-d-and-calcium-ecuador/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;first-ecuadorian-statement-consensus-for-the-evaluation-and-treatment-of-osteoporosis&#34;&gt;First Ecuadorian statement consensus for the evaluation and treatment of osteoporosis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Archives of Osteoporosis volume 18, Article number: 81 (2023) &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11657-023-01263-5&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11657-023-01263-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Carlos Rios, Genessis Maldonado, Sara Vargas, José González, Claudia Vera, Andrés Zuñiga, José Martínez, Mayra Castillo, Raúl Jervis, Rosa Ventura, Sergio Guevara, Gabriela Torres, Franklín Uguña, Osvaldo Daniel Messina, José Luis Neyro, Daniel Fernández, Roberto Guerrero &amp;amp; Mario Moreno&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;1100&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summary&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Osteoporosis management has become more relevant as the life expectancy increases. In Ecuador, approximately 19% of adults over 65 years of age have been diagnosed with osteoporosis. There is no national consensus for the management and prevention of the disease being this proposal the first Ecuadorian consensus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D during pregnancy increased child’s bone mineral density – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-increased-childs-bone-mineral-density-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-increased-childs-bone-mineral-density-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-effect-of-pregnancy-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-offspring-bone-mineral-density-in-childhood-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;The effect of pregnancy vitamin D supplementation on offspring bone mineral density in childhood: a systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Osteoporos Int. 2023 Apr 27. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-023-06751-5&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1007/s00198-023-06751-5&lt;/a&gt;   PDF is behind payeall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rebecca J Moon 1 2, Harry D Green 3, Stefania D&amp;rsquo;Angelo 3, Keith M Godfrey 3 4, Justin H Davies 5 6, Elizabeth M Curtis 3, Cyrus Cooper 3 4 7, Nicholas C Harvey 3 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Systematic review and meta-analysis of the effect of moderate- to high-dose vitamin D supplementation in pregnancy on offspring bone mineralisation found a positive effect of vitamin D supplementation on offspring bone mineral density (BMD) at age 4-6 years, with a smaller effect on bone mineral content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Osteoporosis fought by Vitamin D and Testosterone in Caucasian men</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteoporosis-fought-by-vitamin-d-and-testosterone-in-caucasian-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteoporosis-fought-by-vitamin-d-and-testosterone-in-caucasian-men/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;roles-of-sex-hormones-in-mediating-the-causal-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-osteoporosis-a-two-step-mendelian-randomization-study&#34;&gt;Roles of sex hormones in mediating the causal effect of vitamin D on osteoporosis: A two-step Mendelian randomization study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2023 Mar 30;14:1159241. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2023.1159241&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3389/fendo.2023.1159241&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yongwei Du 1, Baohui Xie 2, Maoyuan Wang 3, Yanbiao Zhong 3, Zhimai Lv 4, Yun Luo 3, Qiwei He 5, Zhen Liu 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Although 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span&gt;[25(OH)D]&lt;/span&gt; is a risk factor for osteoporosis, it is not clear whether sex hormones mediate this casual association. We aimed to explore how sex hormones affect the association between 25(OH)D and osteoporosis to provide meaningful insights on the underlying mechanisms from a genetic perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bone mineral density improvement by Vitamin D plus fluoride is augmented by laser acupuncture – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bone-mineral-density-improvement-by-vitamin-d-plus-fluoride-is-augmented-by-laser-acupuncture-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bone-mineral-density-improvement-by-vitamin-d-plus-fluoride-is-augmented-by-laser-acupuncture-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34; } --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-laser-acupuncture-on-pain-and-density-of-bone-in-osteoporotic-postmenopausal-women-a-randomized-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;Effect of laser acupuncture on pain and density of bone in osteoporotic postmenopausal women: a randomized controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Menopause. 2023 Mar 21. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1097/GME.0000000000002166&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1097/GME.0000000000002166&lt;/a&gt; Behind Paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Elham S Hassan 1, Ahmed Mohamed Maged 2, Amal Kotb 3, Mona Fouad 2, Noura El-Nassery 2, Wafaa M Kamal 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objective: This study aimed to evaluate the value of laser acupuncture (LA) on forearm bone mineral density (BMD) and wrist pain in osteoporotic postmenopausal women.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italian women taking Vitamin D (Osteoporosis, etc)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/italian-women-taking-vitamin-d-osteoporosis-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/italian-women-taking-vitamin-d-osteoporosis-etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;update-on-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-the-prevention-of-osteoporosis&#34;&gt;Update on the role of vitamin D in the prevention of osteoporosis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D - Updates 2022;5(1):4-7. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.30455/2611-2876-2022-1e&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.30455/2611-2876-2022-1e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stefano Berardi, Francesco Paolo Cantatore&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rheumatology Clinic, Department of Medical and Surgical Sciences, University of Foggia&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Packages of Vitamin D for Italian Women&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years the possible multiple positive effects of vitamin D (antineoplastic, cardioprotective, immunomodulatory, etc.) have aroused growing interest and an increase in scientific (and non-scientific) publications on the subject. However, uncertainties about its usefulness in the prevention of osteoporosis have also been raised, following discordant results in the literature, beyond any reasonable doubt on extra-skeletal effects. Osteoporosis has a burdensome impact on the healthcare system: in Italy approximately 3.5 million women and 1 million men are affected by the disease. Incidence increases with age (the steady ageing of the population leads to more cases). From age 50, the incidence of fragility fractures increases progressively, becoming comparable to that of stroke and breast cancer 1. Annual costs attributable to such fractures (acute management and longterm disability) grow with the ageing of the population. What is needed is an acceptable prevention strategy that makes the best use of available resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Osteoporosis guidelines mention vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteoporosis-guidelines-mention-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteoporosis-guidelines-mention-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;pharmacologic-treatment-of-primary-osteoporosis-or-low-bone-mass-to-prevent-fractures-in-adults-a-living-clinical-guideline-from-the-american-college-of-physicians&#34;&gt;Pharmacologic Treatment of Primary Osteoporosis or Low Bone Mass to Prevent Fractures in Adults: A Living Clinical Guideline From the American College of Physicians&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amir Qaseem, MD, PhD, MHA; Lauri A. Hicks, DO; Itziar Etxeandia-Ikobaltzeta, PharmD; Tatyana Shamliyan, MD, MS; and Thomas G. Cooney, MD; for the Clinical Guidelines Committee of the American College of Physicians*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Description: This guideline updates the 2017 American College of Physicians (ACP) recommendations on pharmacologic treatment of primary osteoporosis or low bone mass to prevent fractures in adults.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
