<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer - Ovarian on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer---ovarian.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer - Ovarian on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer---ovarian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cancers and Vitamin D Council</title><link>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ovarian Cancer is somewhat associated with a reduction in 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ovarian-cancer-is-somewhat-associated-with-a-reduction-in-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ovarian-cancer-is-somewhat-associated-with-a-reduction-in-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="meta-analysis-circulating-vitamin-d-and-ovarian-cancer-risk">Meta-analysis: Circulating vitamin D and ovarian cancer risk.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Gynecol Oncol. 2011 Feb 14&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yin L, Grandi N, Raum E, Haug U, Arndt V, Brenner H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To review and summarize evidence from longitudinal studies on the association between circulating 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and the risk of ovarian cancer (OC).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: Relevant prospective cohort studies and nested case-control studies were identified by systematically searching Ovid Medline, EMBASE, and ISI Web of Knowledge databases and by cross-referencing. The following data were extracted in a standardized manner from eligible studies: first author, publication year, country, study design, characteristics of the study population, duration of follow-up, OC incidence according to circulating vitamin D status and the respective relative risks, and covariates adjusted for in the analysis. Due to the heterogeneity of studies in categorizing circulating vitamin D levels, all results were recalculated for an increase of circulating 25(OH)D by 20ng/ml. Summary relative risks (RRs) were calculated using meta-analysis methods.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>