<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Skin - Dark on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/skin---dark.html</link><description>Recent content in Skin - Dark on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/skin---dark/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2X less prostate cancer in A-A with low Calcium is due vitamin D receptor gene</title><link>/posts/2x-less-prostate-cancer-in-a-a-with-low-calcium-is-due-vitamin-d-receptor-gene.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-less-prostate-cancer-in-a-a-with-low-calcium-is-due-vitamin-d-receptor-gene.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calcium-intake-and-prostate-cancer-among-african-americans-effect-modification-by-vitamin-d-receptor-calcium-absorption-genotype">Calcium intake and prostate cancer among African Americans: effect modification by vitamin D receptor calcium absorption genotype.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2012 Jan;27(1):187-94. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jbmr.505.">doi: 10.1002/jbmr.505.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rowland GW, Schwartz GG, John EM, Ingles SA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Preventive Medicine, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>High dietary intake of calcium has been classified as a probable cause of prostate cancer, although the mechanism underlying the association between dietary calcium and prostate cancer risk is unclear. The vitamin D receptor (VDR) is a key regulator of calcium absorption. In the small intestine, VDR expression is regulated by the CDX-2 transcription factor, which binds a polymorphic site in the VDR gene promoter. We examined VDR Cdx2 genotype and calcium intake, assessed by a food frequency questionnaire, in 533 African-American prostate cancer cases (256 with advanced stage at diagnosis, 277 with localized stage) and 250 African-American controls who participated in the California Collaborative Prostate Cancer Study. We examined the effects of genotype, calcium intake, and diet-gene interactions by conditional logistic regression. Compared with men in the lowest quartile of calcium intake, men in the highest quartile had an approximately twofold increased risk of localized and advanced prostate cancer (odds ratio &lt;span>[OR]&lt;/span> =  &lt;strong>2.20&lt;/strong> , 95% confidence interval &lt;span>[CI]&lt;/span> = 1.40, 3.46), with a significant dose-response. Poor absorbers of calcium (VDR Cdx2 GG genotype) had a significantly lower risk of advanced prostate cancer (OR = 0.41, 95% CI = 0.19, 0.90). The gene-calcium interaction was statistically significant (p = 0.03). Among men with calcium intake below the median (680 mg/day), carriers of the G allele had an approximately 50% decreased risk compared with men with the AA genotype. These findings suggest a link between prostate cancer risk and high intestinal absorption of calcium.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tuberculosis, ethnic differences, and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/tuberculosis-ethnic-differences-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tuberculosis-ethnic-differences-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ethnic-differences-affect-immune-response-to-tuberculosis-infection">Ethnic Differences Affect Immune Response To Tuberculosis Infection&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>^Comment by VitaminDWiki&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Does not appear to mention the lower vitamin D levels in those with dark skins^&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://trap.it/#!traps/id/907cd246-0855-49f4-97b4-04aaff5e62f3/articles/6HsUm3uJq0064crtMTSu%20">AsianScientist (Jul. 5, 2013) – Health &amp;amp; Medicine&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The immune response to the bacterium that causes tuberculosis (TB) varies between patients of different ethnic origin, according to a new UK study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The study, published in the journal PLOS Pathogens and led by researchers at Queen Mary, University of London, analyzed the immune response of 128 newly-diagnosed TB patients in London who were divided by ethnicity into those of African (45), European (27), Asian (55) or mixed European/Asian (1) ancestry.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breastfed Infants in Iowa got very little vitamin D, especially if winter or dark skin</title><link>/posts/breastfed-infants-in-iowa-got-very-little-vitamin-d-especially-if-winter-or-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breastfed-infants-in-iowa-got-very-little-vitamin-d-especially-if-winter-or-dark-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;p>INFANTS ARE CAPABLE of producing all of the vitamin D they need in their skin during casual exposure to sunlight, provided the sunlight is of sufficient intensity. At northern latitudes, the power of sunlight is attenuated, especially during winter, so that little or no vitamin D is formed in the skin.1 Heavy skin pigmentation reduces the amount of vitamin D formed in the skin, which is why infants with dark skin pigmentation tend to be in less satisfactory vitamin D status than infants with light skin pigmentation2 and why they are at increased risk of vitamin D deficiency rickets.3-5 Infants living at northern latitudes depend on ingestion of preformed vitamin D for the maintenance of vitamin D sufficiency during winter and possibly year round in the case of infants with darkly pigmented skin. &lt;strong>The amount of preformed vitamin D required by infants in the absence of endogenous synthesis is not exactly known but is thought to be between 100 and 200 international units (IU) per day&lt;/strong> . A daily intake of 400 IU of vitamin D is believed to prevent rickets reliably and is considered free of adverse effects.6 &lt;strong>The Institute of Medicine considers 200 IU per day to be an adequate intake for infants.7&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ricket was known to be associated with dark skin and breast feeding a century ago - 2005</title><link>/posts/ricket-was-known-to-be-associated-with-dark-skin-and-breast-feeding-a-century-ago-2005.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ricket-was-known-to-be-associated-with-dark-skin-and-breast-feeding-a-century-ago-2005.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="reemerging-nutritional-rickets-a-historical-perspective">Reemerging Nutritional Rickets: A Historical Perspective&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2005;159(4):335-341. doi:10.1001/archpedi.159.4.335.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kumaravel Rajakumar, MD; Stephen B. Thomas, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent case reports highlight the resurgence of rickets in certain groups of breastfed infants. Infants residing in the North, irrespective of skin color, and dark-skinned African American infants residing anywhere in the United States are most vulnerable to nutritional rickets if they are exclusively breastfed past age 6 months without vitamin D supplementation. &lt;strong>At the turn of the 20th century, rickets was nearly universal among African American infants living in the North&lt;/strong> . The discovery of vitamin D, the initiation of public health campaigns to fortify infant foods with vitamin D, and the supplementation of vitamin D to breastfed infants were responsible for overcoming the rickets scourge. We review a classic nutritional study by Alfred F. Hess, one of the greatest clinical nutritional researchers of the early 20th century, in the context of the resurgence of rickets, especially among dark-skinned infants. The Columbus Hill district, a black community of New York, NY, served as the setting for the study. Sixty-five infants (aged 1-17 months) entered a 6-month open-label trial of daily cod liver oil therapy. Participants were assessed for signs of rickets at recruitment and at 2, 4, and 6 months. Cod liver oil prevented the development of rickets in 34 (92%) of 37 infants treated for 6 months and in 7 (58%) of 12 treated for 4 months. Of the 16 infants who did not take the prescribed treatment, rickets progressed unremittingly in 15. Hess translated his success into a public health campaign leading to the development of the first rickets clinic in 1917. This was the first step in the conquest of the rickets epidemic of the early 20th century.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased risk of multiple sclerosis risk in African Americans due to genes</title><link>/posts/increased-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-risk-in-african-americans-due-to-genes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-risk-in-african-americans-due-to-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="genetic-risk-variants-in-african-americans-with-multiple-sclerosis">Genetic risk variants in African Americans with multiple sclerosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Neurology 10.1212/WNL.0b013e31829bfe2f&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Noriko Isobe, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pierre-Antoine Gourraud, PhD, MPH,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hanne F. Harbo, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stacy J. Caillier, BS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adam Santaniello, BS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pouya Khankhanian, BA,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martin Maiers, MS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen Spellman, MBS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nezih Cereb, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SooYoung Yang, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marcelo J. Pando, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laura Piccio, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anne H. Cross, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Philip L. De Jager, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce A.C. Cree, MD, PhD, MCR,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chart of Vitamin D levels vs race</title><link>/posts/chart-of-vitamin-d-levels-vs-race.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chart-of-vitamin-d-levels-vs-race.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="chart-had-been-from-vitamin-d-council-ceased-operation-2017">Chart had been from Vitamin D Council (ceased operation ~2017)&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"> 
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-is-a-biological-determinant-of-health-disparities">Vitamin d status is a biological determinant of health disparities.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Acad Nutr Diet. 2013 May;113(5):643-51. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jand.2012.12.011.">doi: 10.1016/j.jand.2012.12.011.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Feb 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weishaar T, &lt;a href="mailto:jtw2117@columbia.edu">jtw2117@columbia.edu&lt;/a>, Vergili JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/weishaar2013-histogram-dark-skin-vs-vitamin-d-sci-hub.pdf">Download the PDF from sci-hub via VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: In human beings, dark skin requires more exposure to ultraviolet light to synthesize the same amount of vitamin D as lighter skin. It is has been repeatedly shown that at the latitude of the United States there are vitamin D disparities related to skin color. Although inadequate vitamin D status and health disparities have been associated with many of the same diseases, neither nutrition policy nor public health policy in the United States currently recognizes any role at all for vitamin D as a determinant of health disparities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black infants had far lower vitamin D levels which did not vary with season</title><link>/posts/black-infants-had-far-lower-vitamin-d-levels-which-did-not-vary-with-season.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-infants-had-far-lower-vitamin-d-levels-which-did-not-vary-with-season.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="racial-variation-in-vitamin-d-cord-blood-concentration-in-white-and-black-male-neonates">Racial variation in vitamin D cord blood concentration in White and Black male neonates&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2013 January; 24(1): 91–98., PMCID: PMC3529856&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Monika Eichholzer,1 Elizabeth A Platz,2 Jessica L. Bienstock,3 Deborah Monsegue,4 Folasade Akereyeni,5 Bruce W Hollis,6 Ronald Horst,7 Nader Rifai,8 Michael N. Pollak,9 Aline Barbir,1 Tanya Agurs-Collins,10 and Sabine Rohrmann1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: To evaluate racial variation in umbilical cord blood concentration of vitamin D and to explore its correlation with markers of the insulin-like growth factor axis (IGFs) and sex steroid hormones in white and black male neonates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus in blacks associated with low vitamin D AND short telomeres</title><link>/posts/lupus-in-blacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-short-telomeres.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-in-blacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-short-telomeres.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="systemic-lupus-erythematosus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-are-associated-with-shorter-telomere-length-among-african-americans-a-case-control-study">Systemic Lupus Erythematosus and Vitamin D Deficiency Are Associated with Shorter Telomere Length among African Americans: A Case-Control Study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2013 May 20;8(5):e63725. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0063725.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0063725.&lt;/a> Print 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hoffecker BM, Raffield LM, Kamen DL, Nowling TK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina, United States of America.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a chronic systemic autoimmune disease that disproportionately affects African American females. The causes of SLE are unknown but postulated to be a combination of genetic predisposition and environmental triggers. Vitamin D deficiency is one of the possible environmental triggers. In this study we evaluated relationships between vitamin D status, cellular aging (telomere length) and anti-telomere antibodies among African American Gullah women with SLE. The study population included African American female SLE patients and unaffected controls from the Sea Island region of South Carolina. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were measured using a nonchromatographic radioimmunoassay. Telomere length was measured in genomic DNA of peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) by monochrome multiplex quantitative PCR. Anti-telomere antibody levels were measured by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). Patients with SLE had significantly shorter telomeres and higher anti-telomere antibody titers compared to age- and gender-matched unaffected controls. There was a positive correlation between anti-telomere antibody levels and disease activity among patients and a significant correlation of shorter telomeres with lower 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in both patients and controls. In follow-up examination of a subset of the patients, the patients who remained vitamin D deficient tended to have shorter telomeres than those patients whose 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were repleted. Increasing 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in African American patients with SLE may be beneficial in maintaining telomere length and preventing cellular aging. Moreover, anti-telomere antibody levels may be a promising biomarker of SLE status and disease activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Most immigrant women in Sweden had little vitamin D and lots of muscle pain</title><link>/posts/most-immigrant-women-in-sweden-had-little-vitamin-d-and-lots-of-muscle-pain.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/most-immigrant-women-in-sweden-had-little-vitamin-d-and-lots-of-muscle-pain.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-intake-and-status-in-immigrant-and-native-swedish-women-a-study-at-a-primary-health-care-centre-located-at-60on-in-sweden">Vitamin D intake and status in immigrant and native Swedish women: a study at a primary health care centre located at 60oN in Sweden&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Food &amp;amp; Nutrition Research eISSN 1654-661X&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Åsa Andersson, Anne Björk, Per Kristiansson, Gunnar Johansson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Immigration to Sweden from lower latitude countries has increased in recent years. Studies in the general population in other Nordic countries have demonstrated that these groups are at risk of developing vitamin D deficiency, but studies in primary health care patients are rare.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark Skinned adults need more than 45 minutes of UK summer sun daily</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-adults-need-more-than-45-minutes-of-uk-summer-sun-daily.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-adults-need-more-than-45-minutes-of-uk-summer-sun-daily.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="efficacy-of-a-dose-range-of-simulated-sunlight-exposures-in-raising-vitamin-d-status-in-south-asian-adults-implications-for-targeted-guidance-on-sun-exposure">Efficacy of a dose range of simulated sunlight exposures in raising vitamin D status in South Asian adults: implications for targeted guidance on sun exposure&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr June 2013 vol. 97 no. 6 1210-1216&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mark D Farrar, Ann R Webb, Richard Kift, Marie T Durkin, Donald Allan, Annie Herbert, Jacqueline L Berry, and Lesley E Rhodes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dermatology Centre, Institute of Inflammation and Repair (MDF, MTD, DA, and LER), and the Institute of Population Health (AH), University of Manchester, Manchester Academic Health Science Centre, Salford Royal National Health Service Foundation Trust, Manchester, United Kingdom; the School of Earth, Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences, University of Manchester, Manchester, United Kingdom (ARW and RK); and the Endocrinology and Diabetes Research Group, Institute of Human Development, University of Manchester, Manchester Academic Health Science Centre, Manchester Royal Infirmary, Manchester, United Kingdom (JLB).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis: high incidence in black women than whites (perhaps vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-high-incidence-in-black-women-than-whites-perhaps-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-high-incidence-in-black-women-than-whites-perhaps-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="incidence-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-multiple-racial-and-ethnic-groups">Incidence of multiple sclerosis in multiple racial and ethnic groups.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Neurology. 2013 May 7;80(19):1734-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182918cc2.">doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182918cc2.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Langer-Gould A, Brara SM, Beaber BE, Zhang JL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Department of Research and Evaluation (A.L.-G., J.L.Z.), Kaiser Permanente, Southern California, Pasadena; and Neurology Department (A.L.-G., S.M.B., B.E.B.), Kaiser Permanente, Southern California Los Angeles Medical Center, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To determine whether the incidence of multiple sclerosis (MS) varies by race/ethnicity in a multiethnic, population-based cohort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes in white blood cells of blacks associated with vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/genes-in-white-blood-cells-of-blacks-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-in-white-blood-cells-of-blacks-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-genome-wide-methylation-study-of-severe-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-african-american-adolescents">A Genome-Wide Methylation Study of Severe Vitamin D Deficiency in African American Adolescents&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Journal of Pediatrics. Volume 162, Issue 5 , Pages 1004-1009.e1, May 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Haidong Zhu, MD, PhD email address , Xiaoling Wang, MD, PhD , Huidong Shi, PhD ,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shaoyong Su, PhD , Gregory A. Harshfield, PhD , Bernard Gutin, PhD , Harold Snieder, PhD , Yanbin Dong, MD, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 2 July 2012; received in revised form 13 September 2012; accepted 31 October 2012. published online 10 December 2012.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sleep disorder and nonspecific pain implies low vitamin D, especially if dark skin</title><link>/posts/sleep-disorder-and-nonspecific-pain-implies-low-vitamin-d-especially-if-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sleep-disorder-and-nonspecific-pain-implies-low-vitamin-d-especially-if-dark-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="nonspecific-pain-is-a-marker-for-hypovitaminosis-d-in-patients-undergoing-evaluation-for-sleep-disorders-a-pilot-study">Nonspecific pain is a marker for hypovitaminosis D in patients undergoing evaluation for sleep disorders: a pilot study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Published Date March 2013 Volume 2013:5 Pages 37 - 42, DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.2147/NSS.S42641">http://dx.doi.org/10.2147/NSS.S42641&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David E McCarty,1 Aronkumar Reddy,1 Quinton Keigley,2 Paul Y Kim,1 Stephen Cohen,2 Andrew A Marino1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Sleep Medicine, Department of Neurology, Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Medicine, Louisiana State University, Shreveport, LA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: The purpose of this cross-sectional study was to test the hypothesis that serum vitamin D levels are abnormally low in sleep clinic patients admitting to chronic nonspecific musculoskeletal pain and to assess the associated risk factors. A secondary purpose was to identify a clinical biomarker for vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lower vitamin D if born outside of Canada or lower education</title><link>/posts/lower-vitamin-d-if-born-outside-of-canada-or-lower-education.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lower-vitamin-d-if-born-outside-of-canada-or-lower-education.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-of-vitamin-d-status-with-socio-demographic-factors-in-calgary-alberta-an-ecological-study-using-census-canada-data">Association of vitamin D status with socio-demographic factors in Calgary, Alberta: an ecological study using Census Canada data&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Public Health 2013, 13:316 doi:10.1186/1471-2458-13-316; Published: 8 April 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christopher Naugler, Jianguo Zhang, Dan Henne, Paul Woods and Brenda R Hemmelgarn&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Low 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels are a global health problem with northern countries such as Canada at particular risk. A number of sociodemographic factors have been reported to be associated with low vitamin D levels but prior studies have been limited by the ability of the researchers to gather this data directly from clinical trial participants. The purpose of this study was to use a novel methodology of inferring sociodemographic variables to evaluate the correlates of vitamin D levels in individuals dwelling in the City of Calgary, Alberta, Canada.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black women and vitamin D: Nigeria 26 ng, Chicago 12 ng</title><link>/posts/black-women-and-vitamin-d-nigeria-26-ng-chicago-12-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-women-and-vitamin-d-nigeria-26-ng-chicago-12-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-african-american-and-nigerian-women">25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in African American and Nigerian women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Hum Biol. 2013 Apr 4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ajhb.22395.">doi: 10.1002/ajhb.22395.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Durazo-Arvizu RA, Aloia JF, Dugas LR, Tayo BO, Shoham DA, Bertino AM, Yeh JK, Cooper RS, Luke A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Public Health Sciences, Loyola University Chicago, Stritch School of Medicine, Maywood, Illinois, 60153.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: African Americans (AA) have substantially lower levels of circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) than whites. We compared population-based samples of 25(OH)D in women of African descent from Nigeria and metropolitan Chicago.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dr. Holick video on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dr-holick-video-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dr-holick-video-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="holick-video-on-youtubehttpwwwyoutubecomwatchvhigbvdcbfvkfeatureyoutube">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hiGBVDcbFVk&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be">Holick Video on YouTube&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-few-images-from-another-of-his-excellent-videos">A few images from another of his excellent videos&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="other-forms-of-vitamin-d-generated">Other forms of vitamin D generated&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-other-forms-of-vitamin-d-generated.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="c-section">C-section&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-c-section.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h2 id="iguana-with-little-vitamin-d">Iguana with little vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-iguana.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="uvb-white-skin-vs-black-skin">UVB White skin vs black skin&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/hollick-uvb-white-vs-black.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;h3 id="global-deficiency-of-vitamin-d">Global deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-global-deficiency.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="psorasis-placebo-vs-vitamin-d">Psorasis placebo vs vitamin d&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-psorasis-pacelbo-vs-vitamin-d.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="navy-indoors-8x-more-death-than-outdoors---1915">Navy indoors 8X more death than outdoors - 1915&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-navy-indoors-8x-more-death-than-outdoors---1915.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="type-1-diabetes-10x-less-at-equator">Type 1 diabetes 10X less at equator&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-type-1-diabetes-10x-less-at-equator.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="perhipheral-vascular-disease-decrease-80">Perhipheral Vascular Disease decrease 80%&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-pvd-decrease-80-.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="holick-and-his-family-take-3000-iu-vitamin-d-total-daily">Holick and his family take 3000 IU vitamin D total daily&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-3000-iu-vitamin-d-total.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="holick-recommendations-vs-age">Holick recommendations vs age&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-recommendations-vs-age.jpg" alt="image" width="400"></description></item><item><title>Low Vitamin D with dark skin, even if live closer to equator and higher altitude</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-with-dark-skin-even-if-live-closer-to-equator-and-higher-altitude.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-with-dark-skin-even-if-live-closer-to-equator-and-higher-altitude.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="association-of-vitamin-d-with-glucose-levels-in-indigenous-and-mixed-population-argentinean-boys">Association of vitamin D with glucose levels in indigenous and mixed population Argentinean boys&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clinical Biochemistry, Volume 46, Issue 3, February 2013, Pages 197–201&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Valeria Hirschler a, &lt;a href="mailto:vhirschler@intramed.net">vhirschler@intramed.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gustavo Maccallini a, Claudio Aranda a, Smithius Fernando a, Claudia Molinari b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Collaborators 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a University of Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Facultad de Bioquimica, Catedra de Estadistica, University of Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: There is little information about low vitamin D concentrations in apparently healthy &lt;strong>indigenous children&lt;/strong> in South America.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Immigrants and refugees had lower vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/immigrants-and-refugees-had-lower-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/immigrants-and-refugees-had-lower-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-country-of-origin-age-and-body-mass-index-on-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-a-us-immigrant-and-refugee-population">Effect of Country of Origin, Age, and Body Mass Index on Prevalence of Vitamin D Deficiency in a US Immigrant and Refugee Population.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mayo Clin Proc. 2013 Jan;88(1):31-7. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mayocp.2012.07.027.">doi: 10.1016/j.mayocp.2012.07.027.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Campagna AM, Settgast AM, Walker PF, Defor TA, Campagna EJ, Plotnikoff GA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Minnesota Medical School, Minneapolis, MN. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:campa024@umn.edu">campa024@umn.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To determine the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency (VDD) (25-hydroxyvitamin D level &amp;lt;20 ng/mL) and severe VDD (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D level &amp;lt;10 ng/mL) in a Minnesota immigrant and refugee population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>US Minorities have poor health – how much is due to little sun</title><link>/posts/us-minorities-have-poor-health-how-much-is-due-to-little-sun.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/us-minorities-have-poor-health-how-much-is-due-to-little-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Minority Health: Recent Findings&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AHRQ Pub. No. 12(13)-P005-EF (Replaces AHRQ Pub. No. 09-P002) February 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The mission of AHRQ is to improve the quality, safety, efficiency, and effectiveness of health care by:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Using evidence to improve health care.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Improving health care outcomes through research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Transforming research into practice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The overall health of the American population has improved over the past few decades, but not all Americans have benefitted equally from these improvements. Minority populations, in particular, continue to lag behind whites in a number of areas, including quality of care, access to care, timeliness, and outcomes. Other health care problems that disproportionately affect minorities include provider biases, poor provider-patient communication, and health literacy issues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Similar response to Vitamin D supplements by senior white and black women</title><link>/posts/similar-response-to-vitamin-d-supplements-by-senior-white-and-black-women.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/similar-response-to-vitamin-d-supplements-by-senior-white-and-black-women.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-older-african-american-women">Effects of Vitamin D Supplementation in Older African American Women&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism February 5, 2013 jc.2012-3106&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. Christopher Gallagher, Munro Peacock, Vinod Yalamanchili and Lynette M. Smith&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone Metabolism Unit (J.C.G., V.Y.), Creighton University School of Medicine, Omaha, Nebraska 68131; Department of Endocrinology (M.P.), Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, Indiana 46202; and Department of Biostatistics (L.M.S.), College of Public Health, University of Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha, Nebraska 68198&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>African-Americans at high risk of obesity and diabetes - 2011</title><link>/posts/african-americans-at-high-risk-of-obesity-and-diabetes-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/african-americans-at-high-risk-of-obesity-and-diabetes-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-type-2-diabetes-in-african-americans-the-common-denominators">Vitamin D Deficiency and Type 2 Diabetes in African Americans: The Common Denominators&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Shani V. Davis, MSN, ANP-BC, CDE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetic Spectrum&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D increases risk of cardiovascular disease in African Americans – 2011</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increases-risk-of-cardiovascular-disease-in-african-americans-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increases-risk-of-cardiovascular-disease-in-african-americans-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cardiovascular-disease-potential-role-in-health-disparities">Vitamin D and cardiovascular disease: potential role in health disparities.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Health Care Poor Underserved. 2011;22(4 Suppl):23-38. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1353/hpu.2011.0161.">doi: 10.1353/hpu.2011.0161.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Artaza JN, Contreras S, Garcia LA, Mehrotra R, Gibbons G, Shohet R, Martins D, Norris KC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Charles R. Drew University of Medicine &amp;amp; Science, 1731 East 120th Street, Los Angeles, CA 90059, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:jorgeartaza@cdrewu.edu">jorgeartaza@cdrewu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular disease (CVD), which includes coronary artery disease and stroke, is the leading cause of mortality in the nation. Excess CVD morbidity and premature mortality in the African American community is one of the most striking examples of racial/ ethnic disparities in health outcomes. African Americans also suffer from increased rates of hypovitaminosis D, which has emerged as an independent risk factor for all-cause and cardiovascular mortality. This overview examines the potential role of hypovitaminosis D as a contributor to racial and ethnic disparities in cardiovascular disease (CVD). We review the epidemiology of vitamin D and CVD in African Americans and the emerging biological roles of vitamin D in key CVD signaling pathways that may contribute to the epidemiological findings and provide the foundation for future therapeutic strategies for reducing health disparities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D is a risk factor for vascular diseases in African Americans</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-is-a-risk-factor-for-vascular-diseases-in-african-americans.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-is-a-risk-factor-for-vascular-diseases-in-african-americans.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="hypovitaminosis-d-as-a-contributory-factor-to-vascular-disease-in-african-americans-a-graded-literature-review">Hypovitaminosis D as a Contributory Factor to Vascular Disease in African-Americans: A graded literature review&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>James H. Moorman MS Thesis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D different relationship between whites and blacks for bone and plaque</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-different-relationship-between-whites-and-blacks-for-bone-and-plaque.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-different-relationship-between-whites-and-blacks-for-bone-and-plaque.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-race-and-genetics-on-vitamin-d-metabolism-bone-and-vascular-health">Effect of race and genetics on vitamin D metabolism, bone and vascular health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Nephrol. 2012 Jun 12;8(8):459-66. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneph.2012.112.">doi: 10.1038/nrneph.2012.112.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Freedman BI, Register TC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Section on Nephrology, Wake Forest School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, NC 27157-1053, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:bfreedma@wakehealth.edu">bfreedma@wakehealth.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pathophysiology of chronic kidney disease-mineral and bone disorder accounts for an inverse relationship between bone mineralization and vascular calcification in progressive nephropathy. Inverse associations between bone mineral density (BMD) and calcified atherosclerotic plaque are also observed in individuals of European and African ancestry without nephropathy, suggesting a mechanistic link between these processes that is independent of kidney disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First and 2nd generation migrants 2X more likely to have psychotic disorders</title><link>/posts/first-and-2nd-generation-migrants-2x-more-likely-to-have-psychotic-disorders.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/first-and-2nd-generation-migrants-2x-more-likely-to-have-psychotic-disorders.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="ethnic-minority-position-and-risk-for-psychotic-disorders">Ethnic minority position and risk for psychotic disorders&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Current Opinion in Psychiatry:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Veling, Wim&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose of review: This article reviews the recent literature about migration, ethnic minority position and the risk of psychotic disorders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent findings: A meta-analysis found that both first and second-generation migrants have on average a two-fold increase in risk for psychotic disorders. In the Netherlands, the risk was most elevated for individuals who migrated in early childhood. Several studies investigated diagnostic ethnic bias and reported greater likelihood of schizophrenia diagnosis in ethnic minority patients at the cost of diagnosis of affective psychotic disorders. Neighbourhood ethnic density was related to prevalence of psychotic experiences in ethnic minority populations in the UK. Perceived discrimination was associated with severity of psychotic and depressive symptoms in ethnic minority patients. Both weak and strong ethnic identification, as well as experiences of social adversity, were related to risk for psychosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sickle cell and low vitamin D – 3 presentations</title><link>/posts/sickle-cell-and-low-vitamin-d-3-presentations.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sickle-cell-and-low-vitamin-d-3-presentations.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>All presented at 2012 American Society of Hematology December 8-11, 2012 Atlanta, GA&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-zinc-deficiency-associated-with-increased-pain-episodes-in-children-with-sickle-cell-disease-poster-abstract-3237">Vitamin D and Zinc Deficiency Associated with Increased Pain Episodes in Children with Sickle Cell Disease: poster, Abstract 3237&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#relationship-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-bone-fragility-in-sickle-cell-disease">Relationship Between vitamin D Deficiency and Bone Fragility in Sickle Cell Disease:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-deficiency-cd40l-and-vegf-in-a-young-population-with-sickle-cell-disease-abstract-4768">Vitamin Deficiency, CD40L and VEGF in a Young Population with Sickle Cell Disease, Abstract 4768&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-zinc-deficiency-associated-with-increased-pain-episodes-in-children-with-sickle-cell-disease-poster-abstract-3237">Vitamin D and Zinc Deficiency Associated with Increased Pain Episodes in Children with Sickle Cell Disease: poster, Abstract 3237&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Abi Vijenthira, BHSc*,1, Christine G Chretien, BSCN*,2, Sydney Harris-Janz, RD*,2 and Robert J Klaassen, MD2&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 1 Diabetes associated with low vitamin D, especially in dark skinned youths</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-especially-in-dark-skinned-youths.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-especially-in-dark-skinned-youths.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>150,000 IU vitamin D reduced pain in immigrants – RCT</title><link>/posts/150000-iu-vitamin-d-reduced-pain-in-immigrants-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/150000-iu-vitamin-d-reduced-pain-in-immigrants-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-for-nonspecific-musculoskeletal-pain-in-non-western-immigrants">Vitamin D Supplementation for Nonspecific Musculoskeletal Pain in Non-Western Immigrants:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A Randomized Controlled Trial&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ann Fam Med November/December 2012 vol. 10 no. 6 547-555&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ferdinand Schreuder , and colleagues&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many non-Western immigrants suffer musculoskeletal pain that is hard to treat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study examines the effect of high-dose vitamin D on nonspecific persistent musculoskeletal complaints in vitamin-D-deficient non-Western immigrants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What This Study Found&lt;/p>
&lt;p>High-dose vitamin D supplementation may have a positive effect on persistent musculoskeletal pain among vitamin D-deficient patients. A study of 84 non-Western immigrants in Western Europe, a population prone to vitamin D deficiency and musculoskeletal problems, revealed a small positive effect on pain 6 weeks after supplementation with 150,000 IU of Vitamin D3 on vitamin D-deficient patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autism associated with low UVB</title><link>/posts/autism-associated-with-low-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/autism-associated-with-low-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="autism-prevalence-in-the-united-states-with-respect-to-solar-uv-b-doses">Autism prevalence in the United States with respect to solar UV-B doses:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An ecological study&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.landesbioscience.com/journals/dermatoendocrinology/article/22942/%20">Dermato Endocrinology Volume 4, Issue 4&lt;/a> October/November/December 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: William B. Grant and John J. Cannell&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evidence is mounting that vitamin D deficiency is intimately involved in autism. We report on autism prevalence by US state for those aged 6–17 y in 2010 with respect to indices of solar UV-B (UVB) doses. We calculated autism prevalence rates for white, black and Asian Americans by using total prevalence and relative populations of minors for each ethnic group by state. Analyses omit AK and HI (considered extreme cases), WY (no data), along with AZ and ND for black Americans (low numbers) and DC, ME, MT, ND and SD for Asian Americans (low numbers). For white Americans, the regression coefficient for solar UVB doses and autism prevalence ranged from -0.52 in January to -0.57 in October. For black Americans, the regression coefficient for latitude was 0.61, whereas those for solar UVB ranged from -0.55 to -0.61. For Asian Americans, the values for solar UVB ranged from -0.28 to -0.38. The inverse correlation between solar UVB and autism prevalence is similar to that for many types of cancer in the US. The journal literature indicates that adverse effects on fetal brain development during pregnancy due to vitamin D deficiency can explain these findings. However, we cannot rule out a role of vitamin D deficiency in early life. These results add to the evidence that vitamin D deficiency may be an important risk factor for autism and suggest that pregnant women and autistic individuals raise their serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations above 30 ng/ml.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Receptor genes bb and BB and Osteoporosis, esp. for blacks – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-genes-bb-and-bb-and-osteoporosis-esp-for-blacks-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-genes-bb-and-bb-and-osteoporosis-esp-for-blacks-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-bsmi-polymorphism-and-osteoporosis-risk-a-meta-analysis-from-26-studies">Vitamin D Receptor BsmI Polymorphism and Osteoporosis Risk: A Meta-Analysis from 26 Studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Genetic Testing and Molecular Biomarkers – Nov 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rui-Fen Sun,2,* Qun-Hui Li,1 Da-Xing Wang,1 Feng Zhao,1 Jun-Min Li,1 Qi Pu,1 Zhong-Zi Zhang,1 Yan Jin,1 Bai-Lian Liu,1 and Ying Xiong1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Orthopedics, Kunming Medical University, National Clinical Key Specialty, Yanan Hospital, Kunming, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Central Laboratory, Yunnan University of Chinese Traditional Medicine, Kunming, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hyperglycemia in black veterans is associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hyperglycemia-in-black-veterans-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hyperglycemia-in-black-veterans-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="relationship-between-hbaic-and-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-in-african-american-and-caucasian-american-men">Relationship Between Hbaic and Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration in African American and Caucasian American Men.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2012 Nov 27:1-22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manickam B, Neagu V, Kukreja S, Barengolts E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Section of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Medicine, Jesse Brown VA and Section of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Medicine, University of Illinois Medical Centers, Chicago, IL 60612.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To examine whether (1) serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> is a risk factor for hyperglycemia, as assessed by HbA1c, in African American men (AAM) and (2) 25(OH)D is a predictor of HbA1c in AAM and Caucasian American men (CAM).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin - Dark</title><link>/posts/skin-dark.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-dark.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">&lt;/nav></description></item><item><title>Blacks had lower vitamin D and more quantifiable pain than whites with knee osteoarthritis</title><link>/posts/blacks-had-lower-vitamin-d-and-more-quantifiable-pain-than-whites-with-knee-osteoarthritis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-had-lower-vitamin-d-and-more-quantifiable-pain-than-whites-with-knee-osteoarthritis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-race-and-experimental-pain-sensitivity-in-older-adults-with-knee-osteoarthritis">Vitamin D, race, and experimental pain sensitivity in older adults with knee osteoarthritis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Arthritis &amp;amp; Rheumatism DOI: 10.1002/art.37687&lt;/p>
&lt;p>T.L. Glover1,3,*, B.R. Goodin2, A.L. Horgas3, L.L. Kindler4, C.D. King1, K.T. Sibille1, C.A. Peloquin5, J.L. Riley III1, R. Staud6, L.A. Bradley7, R.B. Fillingim1,8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 University of Florida, College of Dentistry, Community Dentistry &amp;amp; Behavioral Science&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 University of Florida, College of Dentistry, Comprehensive Center for Pain Research&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 University of Florida, College of Nursing&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Differences in black and non-black mortality and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/differences-in-black-and-non-black-mortality-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/differences-in-black-and-non-black-mortality-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>IBD surgery 5X more likely for non-caucasians with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ibd-surgery-5x-more-likely-for-non-caucasians-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ibd-surgery-5x-more-likely-for-non-caucasians-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Vitamin D is related to breast cancer racial disparities in the US</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-is-related-to-breast-cancer-racial-disparities-in-the-us.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-is-related-to-breast-cancer-racial-disparities-in-the-us.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>More US deaths due to cancer than heart if dark skinned</title><link>/posts/more-us-deaths-due-to-cancer-than-heart-if-dark-skinned.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-us-deaths-due-to-cancer-than-heart-if-dark-skinned.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>African-Americans need only 20 ng of vitamin, not 30 ng, based on iPTH</title><link>/posts/african-americans-need-only-20-ng-of-vitamin-not-30-ng-based-on-ipth.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/african-americans-need-only-20-ng-of-vitamin-not-30-ng-based-on-ipth.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">2nd study on this page disagrees - finding NO iPTH plateau&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="defining-physiologically-normal-vitamin-d-in-african-americans">Defining physiologically “normal” vitamin D in African Americans&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>OSTEOPOROSIS INTERNATIONAL; Volume 23, Number 9 (2012), 2283-2291,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N. C. Wright (1), L. Chen (2), J. Niu (3), T. Neogi (3), K. Javiad (4), M. A. Nevitt (5). C. E. Lewis (6), J. R. Curtis (2)jcurtis@uab.edu&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology, University of Alabama at Birmingham, RPHB 523, 1665 University Blvd, Birmingham, AL 35294, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skinned pregnant women far from equator were very vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-pregnant-women-far-from-equator-were-very-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-pregnant-women-far-from-equator-were-very-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prevalence-of-low-vitamin-d-levels-in-an-urban-midwestern-obstetric-practice">Prevalence of low vitamin d levels in an urban midwestern obstetric practice.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Midwifery Womens Health. 2012 Sep;57(5):439-44. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1542-2011.2012.00167.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1542-2011.2012.00167.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Collins-Fulea C, Klima K, Wegienka GR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: This study describes the prevalence of low vitamin D levels in pregnancy in a diverse urban population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: This was a retrospective chart review of 2839 women who gave birth at a Michigan hospital between January 1, 2008 and December 31, 2009 and had at least 1 vitamin D (25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>) measurement during their pregnancies. Race/ethnic group, wearing the hijab, and season of 25(OH)D sample collection were used in the descriptive analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Forearm fracture 3.5X more often in black children with low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/forearm-fracture-35x-more-often-in-black-children-with-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/forearm-fracture-35x-more-often-in-black-children-with-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="bone-mineral-density-and-vitamin-d-status-among-african-american-children-with-forearm-fractures">Bone mineral density and vitamin d status among african american children with forearm fractures.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatrics. 2012 Sep;130(3):e553-60. Epub 2012 Aug 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ryan LM, Teach SJ, Singer SA, Wood R, Freishtat R, Wright JL, McCarter R, Tosi L, Chamberlain JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Children&amp;rsquo;s National Medical Center, Division of Emergency Medicine, 111 Michigan Ave NW, Washington, DC 20010. &lt;a href="mailto:lryan@childrensnational.org">lryan@childrensnational.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine whether African American children with forearm fractures have decreased bone mineral density and an increased prevalence of vitamin D deficiency (serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level ?20 ng/mL) compared with fracture-free control patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Only 30 percent of African American children know how to swim</title><link>/posts/off-topic-only-30-percent-of-african-american-children-know-how-to-swim.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-only-30-percent-of-african-american-children-know-how-to-swim.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="reasons---first-two-reasons-from-new-york-times-articlehttpwwwnytimescom20120811opinionwater-damage-more-blacks-lack-swimming-skillshtml_r120-aug-2012">Reasons – first two reasons from &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/08/11/opinion/water-damage-more-blacks-lack-swimming-skills.html?_r=1%20">New York Times article&lt;/a> Aug 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Slave owners did not want them to learn how to swim – they could escape&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>US beaches, until recent decades, were white-only&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>African-Americans do not need a sun tan (but do need vitamin D)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="cdc-reports">CDC reports&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>African-American children aged 5-14 almost are 3X more likely to drown&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=2&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">All items in category skin color and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>83 percent of children had less than 20 ng of vitamin D – 15 ng avg for hispanic</title><link>/posts/83-percent-of-children-had-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-15-ng-avg-for-hispanic.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/83-percent-of-children-had-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-15-ng-avg-for-hispanic.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pregnant blacks 50 pcnt more likely to be depressed if 3 ng less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pregnant-blacks-50-pcnt-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-3-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnant-blacks-50-pcnt-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-3-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>98 percent of black women had less than 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/98-percent-of-black-women-had-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/98-percent-of-black-women-had-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="determination-of-vitamin-d-in-relation-to-body-mass-index-and-race-in-a-defined-population-of-black-and-white-women">Determination of vitamin D in relation to body mass index and race in a defined population of black and white women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2012 Jul 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coney P, Demers LM, Dodson WC, Kunselman AR, Ladson G, Legro RS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Meharry Medical College, Nashville, TN, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To examine the contributions of obesity and race to levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> and parathyroid hormone (PTH) in a defined cohort of black and white women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blacks with HIV were 3.5X more likely to be vitamin D deficient than whites</title><link>/posts/blacks-with-hiv-were-35x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-whites.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-with-hiv-were-35x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-whites.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="risk-factors-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-hiv-infected-patients-in-the-south-central-united-states">Risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in HIV-infected patients in the south central United States.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>AIDS Res Hum Retroviruses. 2012 May;28(5):454-9. Epub 2011 Oct 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Crutchley RD, Gathe J Jr, Mayberry C, Trieu A, Abughosh S, Garey KW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Houston, College of Pharmacy, Department of Clinical Sciences and Administration, 1441 Moursund Street, Houston, TX 77030, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:rdcrutchley@uh.edu">rdcrutchley@uh.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We evaluated the prevalence of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> deficiency and the risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in HIV-infected patients in the South-Central United States. The study consisted of a cross-sectional assessment of vitamin D levels in HIV-infected patients receiving routine clinical care from a private practice in Houston, Texas (latitude 29°N). Vitamin D deficiency was defined as 25(OH)D less than 20?ng/ml (&amp;lt;50?nmol/liter). Two-hundred enrolled patients were surveyed with a vitamin D questionnaire to determine daily supplemental vitamin D intake, dietary vitamin D intake, and average sunlight exposure (minutes/day). Multivariate logistic regression analysis was used to determine significant risk factors for vitamin D deficiency. Median 25(OH)D was 15.5?ng/ml (interquartile range 10.9-24.6) for the total population (n=200).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fair skin has lower vitamin D levels than dark skin – contrary to other studies – 2009</title><link>/posts/fair-skin-has-lower-vitamin-d-levels-than-dark-skin-contrary-to-other-studies-2009.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fair-skin-has-lower-vitamin-d-levels-than-dark-skin-contrary-to-other-studies-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pigmentation-and-vitamin-d-metabolism-in-caucasians-low-vitamin-d-serum-levels-in-fair-skin-types-in-the-uk">Pigmentation and vitamin D metabolism in Caucasians: low vitamin D serum levels in fair skin types in the UK.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2009 Aug 3;4(8):e6477.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glass D, Lens M, Swaminathan R, Spector TD, Bataille V.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Twin Research and Genetic Epidemiology, Kings College London, St Thomas&amp;rsquo; Hospital Campus, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/skin-fairness-red-hair-both-associated-with-poor-health-perhaps-low-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Skin fairness, red hair both associated with poor health (perhaps low vitamin D) – Dec 2019">Skin fairness, red hair both associated with poor health (perhaps low vitamin D) – Dec 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">RED highlight&lt;/span> for those with p value = 0.005 (very likely, normally p = 0.05)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half of the US will be people of color – wonder how many will be vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/half-of-the-us-will-be-people-of-color-wonder-how-many-will-be-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-of-the-us-will-be-people-of-color-wonder-how-many-will-be-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Survey finds that Non-Caucasians do not feel that people need sun exposure</title><link>/posts/survey-finds-that-non-caucasians-do-not-feel-that-people-need-sun-exposure.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/survey-finds-that-non-caucasians-do-not-feel-that-people-need-sun-exposure.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Extra 4,000 IU daily raised the vitamin D levels of blacks to that of whites</title><link>/posts/extra-4000-iu-daily-raised-the-vitamin-d-levels-of-blacks-to-that-of-whites.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/extra-4000-iu-daily-raised-the-vitamin-d-levels-of-blacks-to-that-of-whites.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d3-supplementation-4000-iud-for-1-y-eliminates-differences-in-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-between-african-american-and-white-men-1234">Vitamin D3 supplementation (4000 IU/d for 1 y) eliminates differences in circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D between African American and white men 1,2,3,4&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Elizabeth Garrett-Mayer, Carol L Wagner, Bruce W Hollis, Mark S Kindy, and Sebastiano Gattoni-Celli&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 From the Division of Biostatistics and Epidemiology, Department of Medicine (EG-M), and the Departments of Pediatrics (CLW and BWH), Neurosciences (MSK), and Radiation Oncology (SG-C), Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, SC, and the Ralph H Johnson VA Medical Center, Charleston, SC (MSK and SG-C).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bariatric surgery less than 30 ng of vitamin D – 82 pcnt teens, 100 pcnt of black teens</title><link>/posts/bariatric-surgery-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-82-pcnt-teens-100-pcnt-of-black-teens.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bariatric-surgery-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-82-pcnt-teens-100-pcnt-of-black-teens.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="check-vitamin-d-in-adolescents-before-bariatric-surgeryhttpwwwfamilypracticenewscomnewsmore-top-newssingle-viewcheck-vitamin-d-in-adolescents-before-bariatric-surgery9fe0deca25b9ee123ab565b28f2d1a9ehtml20-family-practice-news">&lt;a href="http://www.familypracticenews.com/news/more-top-news/single-view/check-vitamin-d-in-adolescents-before-bariatric-surgery/9fe0deca25b9ee123ab565b28f2d1a9e.html%20">Check Vitamin D in Adolescents Before Bariatric Surgery&lt;/a> Family Practice News&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>clips of paper presented by Dr. Marisa Censani at Endocrine Society. ENDO 2012&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Every kilogram increase in BMI correlated with a 0.2-ng decrease in 25OHD levels,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Roughly 80% of African American deficient , rest had insufficient levels. (100%)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Hispanics, nearly 60% deficient, close to 25% had insufficient levels (85%)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Blacks get more cancer than whites due to lower levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-blacks-get-more-cancer-than-whites-due-to-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-blacks-get-more-cancer-than-whites-due-to-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="differences-in-vitamin-d-status-may-account-for-unexplained-disparities-in-cancer-survival-rates-between-african-and-white-americans">Differences in vitamin D status may account for unexplained disparities in cancer survival rates between African and White Americans&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermato Endocinology Volume 4, Issue 2 April/May/June 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: William B. Grant and Alan N. Peiris&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/possible-role-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-blackwhite-health-disparities-in-the-united-states" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1096">Possible role of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D in Black–White health disparities in the United States&lt;/a> 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/low-uvb-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2287">Low UVB is associated with 15 types of Cancer – Jan 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Head and Neck Cancer associated with low vitamin D, especially with blacks</title><link>/posts/head-and-neck-cancer-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-especially-with-blacks.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/head-and-neck-cancer-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-especially-with-blacks.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="disparities-in-head-and-neck-cancer-a-case-for-chemoprevention-with-vitamin-d">Disparities in head and neck cancer: A case for chemoprevention with vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Amy Exum, Kristin D. Ezell, W. Jarrard Goodwin, Elizabeth J. Franzmann, Jennifer J. Hu, Laura A. Kresty. Univ. of Miami Sylvester Cancer Center, Miami, FL&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldwide head and neck cancer (HNC) is the sixth most frequently diagnosed cancer in men and is associated with significant morbidity, mortality and economic loss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>African Americans (AA) experience significantly more HNC compared to Caucasian Americans (CA)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5 out of 6 UK dark skinned kids who were vitamin D deficient had no symptoms</title><link>/posts/5-out-of-6-uk-dark-skinned-kids-who-were-vitamin-d-deficient-had-no-symptoms.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5-out-of-6-uk-dark-skinned-kids-who-were-vitamin-d-deficient-had-no-symptoms.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Seniors in North Indian: half have sore bones, 98 pcnt have less than 30 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/seniors-in-north-indian-half-have-sore-bones-98-pcnt-have-less-than-30-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-in-north-indian-half-have-sore-bones-98-pcnt-have-less-than-30-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-in-healthy-indians-aged-50-years-and-above">Vitamin D status in healthy Indians aged 50 years and above.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Assoc Physicians India. 2011 Nov;59:706-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marwaha RK, Tandon N, Garg MK, Kanwar R, Narang A, Sastry A, Saberwal A, Bandra K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Thyroid Research Centre, Institute of Nuclear Medicine and Allied Sciences, Delhi, India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: There is widespread prevalence of vitamin D deficiency from new-born to infancy, childhood and adult male and females (non-pregnant, pregnant and lactating). However, there is limited information of the vitamin D status in elderly Indians.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetics with darker skin were more vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/diabetics-with-darker-skin-were-more-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetics-with-darker-skin-were-more-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-vitamin-d-insufficiency-and-diabetes-status-in-three-ethnic-minority-groups">Serum Vitamin D Insufficiency and Diabetes Status in Three Ethnic Minority Groups.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Immigr Minor Health. 2012 May 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shaban LH, Zarini GG, Exebio JC, Sukhram SD, Huffman FG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dietetics and Nutrition, Florida International University, 11200 SW, 8th ST, AHC-1 430, Miami, FL, 33199, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this study was to investigate the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and diabetes status in three ethnicities. This cross sectional study included Cuban Americans (n = 199), Haitian Americans (n = 253) and African Americans (n = 248) with and without type 2 diabetes (T2D) from Florida, U.S. Recruitment of participants was through mailing lists (Cuban Americans and African Americans) and community based sources (Haitian Americans).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hispanics with MS had lower levels of vitamin D which did not vary seasonally</title><link>/posts/hispanics-with-ms-had-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d-which-did-not-vary-seasonally.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hispanics-with-ms-had-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d-which-did-not-vary-seasonally.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-levels-in-hispanics-with-multiple-sclerosis">Vitamin D levels in Hispanics with multiple sclerosis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Neurol. 2012 May 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amezcua L, Chung RH, Conti DV, Langer-Gould AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Keck School of Medicine, University of Southern California (USC), Los Angeles, CA, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:lamezcua@usc.edu">lamezcua@usc.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has been associated with multiple sclerosis (MS) and several markers of disease state in whites. There are limited reports of vitamin D&amp;rsquo;s influence in MS in ethnic groups, such as in Hispanics. In this study, we compared vitamin D levels in Hispanics and whites with MS and tried to determine whether season or increasing disability influence hypovitaminosis D in Hispanics with MS. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and clinical characteristics were compared in a cross-sectional sample of Hispanics (n = 80) and whites (n = 80) with MS recruited from the University of Southern California. Serum 25(OH)D levels were significantly lower in Hispanics than whites with MS (mean and standard deviation 25.1 ± 9.4 and 37.3 ± 19.8 ng/ml, respectively; p &amp;lt; 0.001). Hispanics were significantly more likely than whites to be vitamin D insufficient (?30 ng/ml; 70 vs. 41 %, respectively; p &amp;lt; 0.001) and deficient (?20 ng/ml; 40 vs. 14 %, respectively, p &amp;lt; 0.001). In Hispanics, serum 25(OH)D levels were not influenced by season (p = 0.8) or higher physical disability (EDSS ?6, p = 0.7). We found that the relationship between vitamin D and MS differs by Hispanic ethnicity. Hypovitaminosis D was significantly more common among Hispanics than among whites with MS, and the majority of Hispanics were vitamin D insufficient. Interestingly, there was no association between vitamin D levels and season or increasing disability in the Hispanics. Our findings imply that factors influencing vitamin D levels and possibly vitamin D requirements may vary by ethnicity in patients with MS. These results should be confirmed in larger, prospective multi-ethnic cohort studies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Psychosis in dark skinned people 3.5 X higher if low level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/psychosis-in-dark-skinned-people-35-x-higher-if-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/psychosis-in-dark-skinned-people-35-x-higher-if-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-psychotic-features-in-mentally-ill-adolescents-a-cross-sectional-study">Vitamin D deficiency and psychotic features in mentally ill adolescents: A cross-sectional study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Barbara L Gracious, Teresa L Finucane, Meriel Freidman-Campbell, Susan Messing and Melissa M Parkhurst&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Psychiatry 2012, 12:38 doi:10.1186/1471-244X-12-38; Published: 9 May 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency is a re-emerging epidemic, especially in minority populations. Vitamin D is crucial not only for bone health but for proper brain development and functioning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low levels of vitamin D are associated with depression, seasonal affective disorder, and &lt;strong>schizophrenia&lt;/strong> in adults but little is known about vitamin D and mental health in the pediatric population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>79 percent of TB in East London less 20 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/79-percent-of-tb-in-east-london-less-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/79-percent-of-tb-in-east-london-less-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolor00fpdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-this-pagespan">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Inuit (dark skin)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-inuit-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-inuit-dark-skin.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>80 percent of South Asian Women in UK had less than 10 ng of vitamin D in winter</title><link>/posts/80-percent-of-south-asian-women-in-uk-had-less-than-10-ng-of-vitamin-d-in-winter.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/80-percent-of-south-asian-women-in-uk-had-less-than-10-ng-of-vitamin-d-in-winter.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Black Sudanese children 350X more likely to have rickets than other Australians</title><link>/posts/black-sudanese-children-350x-more-likely-to-have-rickets-than-other-australians.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-sudanese-children-350x-more-likely-to-have-rickets-than-other-australians.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>75% of rickets cases were those were refugee children,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>63 % were born in Africa&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>47% Sudanese.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>85 %were dark-skinned,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>13 % categorised as intermediate&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>2 % were fair skinned&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>mothers who were veiled for cultural and religious reasons, contributed to low vitamin D levels&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="incidence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-rickets-among-australian-children-an-australian-paediatric-surveillance-unit-study">Incidence of vitamin D deficiency rickets among Australian children: an Australian Paediatric Surveillance Unit study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Craig F Munns &lt;a href="mailto:craigm2@chw.edu.au">craigm2@chw.edu.au&lt;/a> , Peter J Simm, Christine P Rodda, Sarah P Garnett, Margaret R Zacharin, Leanne M Ward, Janet Geddes, Sarah Cherian, Yvonne Zurynski and Christopher T Cowell, on behalf of the APSU Vitamin D Study Group&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sickle Cell Anemia: 64 percent had less than 10ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/sickle-cell-anemia-64-percent-had-less-than-10ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sickle-cell-anemia-64-percent-had-less-than-10ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Abu Dhabi 2012 - Haq</title><link>/posts/abu-dhabi-2012-haq.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/abu-dhabi-2012-haq.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="presented-at-international-symposium-on-vitamin-d-deficiency---abu-dhabi-march-2012">Presented at International Symposium on Vitamin D Deficiency - Abu Dhabi March 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;1235&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="dr-afrozul-haq">Dr. Afrozul Haq.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Qualifications: Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Position: Senior Clinical Scientist Pathology and Laboratory Medicine Institute Shaikh Khalifa Medical City, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dr. Afrozul Haq is a graduate of Aligarh Muslim University, India and trained as a postdoctoral fellow at National Institute of Health and Medical Research (INSERM), Paris, France. Dr. Haq started his professional career from All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), New Delhi in 1984. He worked as a Scientist &amp;amp; Head of Protein Chemistry Laboratory at King Faisal Specialist Hospital &amp;amp; Research Centre, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia from 1988 till 2000. Dr. Haq was invited as a visiting Professor to Pasteur Institute, Paris in 1993 and Royal Victoria Hospital, McGill University, Montreal, Canada in 1991. He has more than 25 years research experience as a basic &amp;amp; clinical scientist , published 60 research articles in peer reviewed journals, 2 book chapters, and 65 abstracts presented in the International &amp;amp; regional scientific meetings. Dr. Haq is working on several research projects on vitamin D in collaboration with clinicians and researchers at SKMC, Zayed University, Abu Dhabi and SUNARC Research Center, San Francisco, USA. Dr. Haq is the Editor of the International Journal of Medicine &amp;amp; Medical Sciences, Prime Research on Medicine, American Journal of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Asian Journal of Clinical Nutrition, International Journal of Biological Chemistry, Trends in Medical Research, International Journal of Cancer Research, member Advisory Board of International Journal of Nutrition, Pharmacology, Neurological Diseases and reviewer for Oral Oncology &amp;amp; Clinica Chimica Acta.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes may account for some of AA Breast Cancer</title><link>/posts/genes-may-account-for-some-of-aa-breast-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-may-account-for-some-of-aa-breast-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="variants-in-the-vitamin-d-pathway-serum-levels-of-vitamin-d">Variants in the vitamin D pathway, serum levels of vitamin D,&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="and-estrogen-receptor-negative-breast-cancer-among-african-american-women-a-case-control-study">and estrogen receptor negative breast cancer among African-American women: a case-control study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Song Yao, Gary Zirpoli, Dana H Bovbjerg, Lina Jandorf, Chi-Chen Hong, Hua Zhao, Lara E Sucheston, Li Tang, Michelle Roberts, Gregory Ciupak, Warren Davis, Helena Hwang, Candace S Johnson, Donald L Trump, Susan E McCann, Foluso Ademuyiwa, Karen S Pawlish, Elisa V Bandera and Christine B Ambrosone&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CDC vitamin D statistics for women: including blacks and high BMI</title><link>/posts/cdc-vitamin-d-statistics-for-women-including-blacks-and-high-bmi.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cdc-vitamin-d-statistics-for-women-including-blacks-and-high-bmi.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>CDC Nutrients: 30 percent dark skinned have less than 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cdc-nutrients-30-percent-dark-skinned-have-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cdc-nutrients-30-percent-dark-skinned-have-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;1200&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Full report and Executive report attached at bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Another urban area in a sunny climate is vitamin D deficient – Bangkok</title><link>/posts/another-urban-area-in-a-sunny-climate-is-vitamin-d-deficient-bangkok.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/another-urban-area-in-a-sunny-climate-is-vitamin-d-deficient-bangkok.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="regional-variation-and-determinants-of-vitamin-d-status-in-sunshine-abundant-thailand">Regional variation and determinants of vitamin D status in sunshine-abundant Thailand.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>BMC Public Health. 2011 Nov 10;11:853.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chailurkit LO, Aekplakorn W, Ongphiphadhanakul B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Ramathibodi Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok 10400, Thailand. &lt;a href="mailto:ralcl@mahidol.ac.th">ralcl@mahidol.ac.th&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D insufficiency is highly prevalent. Most of the studies concerning vitamin D status were generated from countries situated at temperate latitudes. It is less clear what the extent of vitamin D insufficiency is in countries situated in the tropics and how geographical regions within country would affect vitamin D status. In the present study, we investigated vitamin D status in Thais according to geographical regions and other risk factors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crohn’s Disease strongly associated with low vitamin D in South Asians</title><link>/posts/crohns-disease-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-south-asians.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/crohns-disease-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-south-asians.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-adults-with-inflammatory-bowel-disease-potential-role-of-ethnicity">Hypovitaminosis D in Adults with Inflammatory Bowel Disease: Potential Role of Ethnicity.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dig Dis Sci. 2012 Mar 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fu YT, Chatur N, Cheong-Lee C, Salh B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Gordon and Leslie Diamond Health Care Centre, University of British Columbia, 5th Floor, 2775 Laurel St, Vancouver, BC, V5Z 1M9, Canada, &lt;a href="mailto:nfu@interchange.ubc.ca">nfu@interchange.ubc.ca&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Although vitamin D deficiency occurs in inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), it is currently unclear to what extent ethnicity affects vitamin D levels. Our aim was therefore to determine the ethnic variation in serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status and its association with disease severity in adults with IBD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin color and vitamin D – Jablonski – Spring 2012</title><link>/posts/skin-color-and-vitamin-d-jablonski-spring-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-color-and-vitamin-d-jablonski-spring-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-evolution-of-human-skin-colouration-and-its-relevance-to-health-in-the-modern-world---2012">The evolution of human skin colouration and its relevance to health in the modern world - 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#human-skin-pigmentation-migration-and-disease-susceptibility---2012">Human skin pigmentation, migration and disease susceptibility - 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2009-map-by-jablonski-and-chaplin">2009 map by Jablonski and Chaplin&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/genes-for-light-skin-29000-and-900000-years-old" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Genes for light skin – 29,000 and 900,000 years old – Oct 2017">Genes for light skin – 29,000 and 900,000 years old – Oct 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtually all young Koreans had less than 30 ng of vitamin D – 2012</title><link>/posts/virtually-all-young-koreans-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/virtually-all-young-koreans-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Two articles on this page&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolorf0099-of-boys-and-100-of-korean-girls-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-dspan">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">99% of boys and 100% of Korean girls had less than 30 ng of vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="high-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-or-deficiency-in-young-adolescents-in-korea">High prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency or deficiency in young adolescents in Korea&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF PEDIATRICS 2012, DOI: 10.1007/s00431-012-1746-0 &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#090;">May 2012&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Youn Ho Shin, Ki Eun Kim, Choae Lee, Hye Jung Shin, Myung Suh Kang, Hye-Ree Lee and Yong-Jae Lee&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent studies suggest that vitamin D insufficiency or deficiency is not only a problem of older generations anymore but also an important health concern among younger generations. However, comprehensive data are lacking in Korean adolescents. We investigated the vitamin D (25-hydroxy vitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>) status, the prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency or deficiency, and the association between vitamin D levels and insulin resistance and lipid profiles in a sample of &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">188 Korean adolescents aged 12–13 years&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> who participated in a general health check-up at a tertiary hospital.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More gut problems with a dark skinned people</title><link>/posts/more-gut-problems-with-a-dark-skinned-people.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-gut-problems-with-a-dark-skinned-people.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-phenotype-and-course-of-inflammatory-bowel-disease-in-uk-patients-of-bangladeshi-descent">The phenotype and course of inflammatory bowel disease in UK patients of Bangladeshi descent.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2012 Mar 9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2036.2012.05043.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2036.2012.05043.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goodhand JR, Kamperidis N, Joshi NM, Wahed M, Koodun Y, Cantor EJ, Croft NM, Langmead FL, Lindsay JO, Rampton DS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Digestive Diseases, Blizard Institute of Cell and Molecular Science, Barts and the London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: We have tested the hypotheses that compared with local white Caucasians, UK-resident patients of Bangladeshi descent develop inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) at a younger age; more often have Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease than ulcerative colitis (UC); and have a more aggressive disease course.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perhaps optimal bioavailable vitamin D level is the same in blacks and whites</title><link>/posts/perhaps-optimal-bioavailable-vitamin-d-level-is-the-same-in-blacks-and-whites.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/perhaps-optimal-bioavailable-vitamin-d-level-is-the-same-in-blacks-and-whites.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bioavailable-vitamin-d-is-more-tightly-linked-to-mineral-metabolism-than-total-vitamin-d-in-incident-hemodialysis-patients">Bioavailable vitamin D is more tightly linked to mineral metabolism than total vitamin D in incident hemodialysis patients.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>– – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – –&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Context: Many studies have found that blacks may have a lower level of blood levels of vitamin D. Perhaps the actual bioavailable levels are the same in blacks and whites&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-dark-skin-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1064">Overview Dark Skin and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mayo clinic providing free vitamin D tests for blacks in Florida</title><link>/posts/mayo-clinic-providing-free-vitamin-d-tests-for-blacks-in-florida.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mayo-clinic-providing-free-vitamin-d-tests-for-blacks-in-florida.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Low vitamin D associated with obesity-related diseases for ethnic minorities</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-obesity-related-diseases-for-ethnic-minorities.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-obesity-related-diseases-for-ethnic-minorities.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-obesity-and-obesity-related-chronic-disease-among-ethnic-minorities-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D, obesity, and obesity-related chronic disease among ethnic minorities: a systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrition. 2011 Sep;27(9):868-79. Epub 2011 Jun 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renzaho AM, Halliday JA, Nowson C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WHO Collaborating Centre for Obesity Prevention, Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria, Australia. &lt;a href="mailto:andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au">andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="for-ethnic-minorities-this-study-has-found-that-span-stylecolor00flow-vitamin-d-diabetes-etcspan">For ethnic minorities this study has found that &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">low vitamin D==&amp;gt; diabetes etc&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="rather-than-the-conventional-hypothesis-span-stylecolor00flow-vitamin-d--obesity--diabetes-etcspan">rather than the conventional hypothesis: &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">low vitamin D ==&amp;gt; obesity ==&amp;gt; diabetes etc&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To assess the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) status and obesity, cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), the metabolic syndrome, and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in ethnic minorities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Human skin pigmentation, migration and disease susceptibility</title><link>/posts/human-skin-pigmentation-migration-and-disease-susceptibility.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/human-skin-pigmentation-migration-and-disease-susceptibility.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nina G. Jablonski &lt;a href="mailto:ngi2@psu.edu">ngi2@psu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>George Chaplin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Anthropology, The Pennsylvania State University, 409 Carpenter Building, University Park, PA 16802, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Phil. Trans. R. Soc. B 19 March 2012 vol. 367 no. 1590 785-792&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Human skin pigmentation evolved as a compromise between the conflicting physiological demands of protection against the deleterious effects of ultraviolet radiation (UVR) and photosynthesis of UVB-dependent vitamin D3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Living under high UVR near the equator, ancestral Homo sapiens had skin rich in protective eumelanin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Helps Atlanta High School Athletes</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-atlanta-high-school-athletes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-atlanta-high-school-athletes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d">Overview Sports and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-dark-skin-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1064">Overview Dark Skin and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/a-concussion-free-football-season-how-one-high-school-beat-the-odds">A Concussion-Free Football Season: How one High School beat the odds - July 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-and-sports-book-2011-at-vitamindwiki" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1907">Review of Vitamin D and Sports book - 2011 at VitaminDWiki&lt;/a> excellent on Athletics, covers vitamin D concerns well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-bone-fractures-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1344">Overview Bone Fractures and vitamin D&lt;/a> mainly seniors&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skin does not generate as much vitamin D from the same amount of UV</title><link>/posts/dark-skin-does-not-generate-as-much-vitamin-d-from-the-same-amount-of-uv.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skin-does-not-generate-as-much-vitamin-d-from-the-same-amount-of-uv.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Vitamin D will decrease CVD and diabetes in African Americans</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-will-decrease-cvd-and-diabetes-in-african-americans.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-will-decrease-cvd-and-diabetes-in-african-americans.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="does-vitamin-d-deficiency-contribute-to-increased-rates-of-cardiovascular-disease-and-type-2-diabetes-in-african-americans">Does vitamin D deficiency contribute to increased rates of cardiovascular disease and type 2 diabetes in African Americans?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 May;93(5):1175S-8S. Epub 2011 Mar 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harris SS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jean Mayer US Department of Agriculture Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging at Tufts University, Boston, MA 02111, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:susan.harris@tufts.edu">susan.harris@tufts.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>African Americans have higher rates of type 2 diabetes (T2D) and some forms of cardiovascular disease (CVD) than do European Americans. African Americans also have much higher rates of vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets in 30 percent of infants in India who had low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/rickets-in-30-percent-of-infants-in-india-who-had-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-in-30-percent-of-infants-in-india-who-had-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-healthy-breastfed-term-infants-at-3-months--their-mothers-in-india-seasonal-variation--determinants">Vitamin D deficiency in healthy breastfed term infants at 3 months &amp;amp; their mothers in India: seasonal variation &amp;amp; determinants.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Indian J Med Res. 2011 Mar;133(3):267-73.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vandana Jain, Nandita Gupta,* Mani Kalaivani,** Anurag Jain,+ Aditi Sinha, and Ramesh Agarwal&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Biostatistics, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D accounts for 25 percent of the racial differences in blood pressure</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-accounts-for-25-percent-of-the-racial-differences-in-blood-pressure.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-accounts-for-25-percent-of-the-racial-differences-in-blood-pressure.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>First vitamin D book for blacks – 2011</title><link>/posts/first-vitamin-d-book-for-blacks-2011.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/first-vitamin-d-book-for-blacks-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="correcting-the-vitamin-d-deficiency-epidemic">Correcting the Vitamin D Deficiency Epidemic&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="strategies-to-fight-diseases-and-prolong-life-for-black-people">strategies to Fight Diseases and Prolong Life for Black People&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>By Emily Allison-Francis, 2011 &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Correcting-Vitamin-Deficiency-Epidemic-Strategies/dp/0912444495/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1327423339&amp;amp;sr=8-1">Amazon&lt;/a>, can look-inside the book, $17&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is the only Vitamin D BOOK which I am aware of which starts to address concerns of Blacks&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The author felt what I said about the book was incorrect and contacted her lawyer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have always disliked confrontations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I removed my review Feb 5, 2012&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traditionally living Africans have 46 ng vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/traditionally-living-africans-have-46-ng-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/traditionally-living-africans-have-46-ng-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="43-nanograms-pregnant-maasai--59-nanograms">43 nanograms, Pregnant Maasai 59 nanograms&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D status indicators in indigenous populations in East Africa.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eur J Nutr. 2012 Aug 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luxwolda MF, Kuipers RS, Kema IP, van der Veer E, Dijck-Brouwer DA, Muskiet FA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laboratory Medicine, Room Y 3.181, University Medical Center Groningen (UMCG), P.O. Box 30.001, 9700 RB, Groningen, The Netherlands, &lt;a href="mailto:mfluxwolda@hotmail.com">mfluxwolda@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: Sufficient vitamin D status may be defined as the evolutionary established circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> matching our Paleolithic genome.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twice as many fatal strokes among whites who were low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/twice-as-many-fatal-strokes-among-whites-who-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/twice-as-many-fatal-strokes-among-whites-who-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-fatal-stroke-among-whites-but-not-blacks-the-nhanes-iii-linked-mortality-files">25-Hydroxyvitamin D deficiency is associated with fatal stroke among whites but not blacks: The NHANES-III linked mortality files.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrition. 2012 Jan 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michos ED, Reis JP, Post WS, Lutsey PL, Gottesman RF, Mosley TH, Sharrett AR, Melamed ML.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Cardiology, Johns Hopkins School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA; Department of Epidemiology, Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Deficient 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels are associated with cardiovascular disease (CVD) events and mortality. 25(OH)D deficiency and stroke are more prevalent in blacks. We examined whether low 25(OH)D contributes to the excess risk of fatal stroke in blacks compared with whites.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Even young Caucasians do not get enough time in the sun</title><link>/posts/even-young-caucasians-do-not-get-enough-time-in-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/even-young-caucasians-do-not-get-enough-time-in-the-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="solar-uv-doses-of-adult-americans-and-vitamin-d3-production">Solar UV doses of adult Americans and vitamin D(3) production.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2011 Oct;3(4):243-50. Epub 2011 Oct 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Godar DE, Pope SJ, Grant WB, Holick MF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>US Food and Drug Administration; Center for Devices and Radiological Health; Rockville, MD USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight contains UV radiation that affects human health in both detrimental (skin cancers) and beneficial (vitamin D(3)) ways. An evaluation of the vitamin D status of adult Americans (22-40, 41-59, 60+ yr) show many have deficient or insufficient serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D, indicating they are not getting enough from dietary sources or sunlight. Those findings are in conflict with calculated values from the American Academy of Dermatology who insist people make &amp;ldquo;ample&amp;rdquo; vitamin D(3) (?1,000 IU/day) from their &amp;ldquo;casual,&amp;rdquo; or everyday, outdoor UV exposures even if they use sunscreens with sun protection factor 15.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>73 percent of Australians had too little vitamin D</title><link>/posts/73-percent-of-australians-had-too-little-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/73-percent-of-australians-had-too-little-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Africans in Europe might only need 19 ng of vitamin D – estimated from PTH</title><link>/posts/africans-in-europe-might-only-need-19-ng-of-vitamin-d-estimated-from-pth.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/africans-in-europe-might-only-need-19-ng-of-vitamin-d-estimated-from-pth.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="estimation-of-the-25oh-vitamin-d-threshold-below-which-secondary-hyperparathyroidism-may-occur-among-african-migrant-women-in-paris">Estimation of the 25(OH) Vitamin D Threshold below which Secondary Hyperparathyroidism may Occur Among African Migrant Women in Paris.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Vitam Nutr Res. 2011 Jul;81(4):218-24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emilion E, Emilion R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Community Clinic, Paris, France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose: It has previously been shown that there is a threshold of serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D below which secondary hyperparathyroidism may occur. Our purpose was to estimate this threshold in a population of migrant African women living in Paris.Methods: Between February 2008 and December 2009, measurements of 25-hydroxy vitamin D and parathormone were performed in 165 African migrant women living in Paris. The estimation of 25-hydroxy vitamin D and parathormone marginal distributions as Gaussian mixtures, combined with a nonparametric kernel estimation method of the regression function of parathormone on 25-hydroxy vitamin D, provided the desired estimate of serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D threshold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VA found less testing for vitamin D resulted in increased health costs</title><link>/posts/va-found-less-testing-for-vitamin-d-resulted-in-increased-health-costs.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/va-found-less-testing-for-vitamin-d-resulted-in-increased-health-costs.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-testing-patterns-among-six-veterans-medical-centers-in-the-southeastern-united-states-links-with-medical-costs">Vitamin D Testing Patterns Among Six Veterans Medical Centers in the Southeastern United States: Links With Medical Costs&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bailey, Beth A.1; Manning, Todd2; Peiris, Alan N.3 &lt;a href="mailto:alan.peiris@va.gov">alan.peiris@va.gov&lt;/a> ==&amp;gt; &lt;a href="mailto:alan.peiris@ttuhsc.edu">alan.peiris@ttuhsc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1: Department of Family Medicine, East Tennessee State University, P.O. Box 70621, Johnson City, TN 37614.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2: Mountain Home VAMC, Johnson City, TN 37684.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3: Mountain Home VAMC, Medicine Service-111, Mountain Home, TN 37684.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Military Medicine, Volume 177, Number 1, January 2012 , pp. 70-76(7)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>28 pct of dark skinned people in UK not heard of vitamin D and 54 pct not know symptoms</title><link>/posts/28-pct-of-dark-skinned-people-in-uk-not-heard-of-vitamin-d-and-54-pct-not-know-symptoms.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/28-pct-of-dark-skinned-people-in-uk-not-heard-of-vitamin-d-and-54-pct-not-know-symptoms.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reasons for low response to vitamin D</title><link>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#detailed-reasons-for-poor-response">Detailed Reasons for poor response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reasons-for-not-getting-benefits---span-stylecolorf00even-if-blood-tests-are-okspan">Reasons for not getting benefits - &lt;span style="color:#F00;">even if blood tests are OK&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsuv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual--2010big-differences-in-uvb-responsesa-20-to-36-ng-after-6-weeks">&lt;a href="/posts/uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: UV production of Vitamin D varies with the individual – 2010">Big differences in UVB responses&lt;/a>: 20 to 36 ng after 6 weeks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#alternate-sources-of-vitamin-d">Alternate sources of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/h4>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>~ 50% of all people have a low response to vitamin D3&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20 ng of vitamin D is enough for African American PTH</title><link>/posts/20-ng-of-vitamin-d-is-enough-for-african-american-pth.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/20-ng-of-vitamin-d-is-enough-for-african-american-pth.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="defining-physiologically-normal-vitamin-d-in-african-americans">Defining physiologically &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; vitamin D in African Americans.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Dec 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wright NC, Chen L, Niu J, Neogi T, Javiad K, Nevitt MA, Lewis CE, Curtis JR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology, University of Alabama at Birmingham, RPHB 523, 1665 University Blvd, Birmingham, AL, 35294, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between serum 25(OH)D and intact parathyroid hormone (iPTH) was evaluated in the Multicenter Osteoarthritis Study (MOST). No further change in iPTH was observed for African Americans with 25(OH)D levels above 20 ng/ml, suggesting that compared to Caucasians, lower vitamin D targets for sufficiency may be appropriate for African Americans.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genetic differences explain some of vitamin D variation in African-Americans</title><link>/posts/genetic-differences-explain-some-of-vitamin-d-variation-in-african-americans.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genetic-differences-explain-some-of-vitamin-d-variation-in-african-americans.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="common-variation-in-vitamin-d-pathway-genes-predicts-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-among-african-americans">Common Variation in Vitamin D Pathway Genes Predicts Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels among African Americans&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Lisa B. Signorello 1, 2*, Jiajun Shi 2, Qiuyin Cai 2, Wei Zheng 2, Scott M. Williams 3, Jirong Long 2, Sarah S. Cohen 1, Guoliang Li 2, Bruce W. Hollis 4, Jeffrey R. Smith5, William J. Blot1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International Epidemiology Institute, Rockville, Maryland, United States of America, Division of Epidemiology, Department of Medicine, Vanderbilt Epidemiology Center, Vanderbilt University School of Medicine and the Vanderbilt-Ingram Cancer Center, Nashville, Tennessee, United States of America, Division of Human Genomics, Department of Molecular Physiology and Biophysics, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, United States of America, Department of Pediatrics, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina, United States of America, Division of Genetic Medicine, Department of Medicine, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville, Tennessee, United States of America&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Immigrant vitamin D deficiency in Europe</title><link>/posts/immigrant-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-europe.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/immigrant-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-europe.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Striking ethnic health disparity – blacks dying due to lack of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/striking-ethnic-health-disparity-blacks-dying-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/striking-ethnic-health-disparity-blacks-dying-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-cardiovascular-disease-potential-role-in-health-disparities">Vitamin D and Cardiovascular Disease: Potential Role in Health Disparities&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Health Care for the Poor and Underserved&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 22, Number 4, November 2011, Supplement; E-ISSN: 1548-6869 Print ISSN: 1049-2089; DOI: 10.1353/hpu.2011.0161&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorge N. Artaza, Sandra Contreras, Leah A. Garcia, Rajnish Mehrotra, Gary Gibbons, Ralph Shohet, David Martins, Keith C. Norris&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Johns Hopkins University Press&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular disease (CVD), which includes coronary artery disease and stroke, is the leading cause of mortality in the nation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blacks living in urban area vs rural have less vitamin D if older than 50</title><link>/posts/blacks-living-in-urban-area-vs-rural-have-less-vitamin-d-if-older-than-50.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-living-in-urban-area-vs-rural-have-less-vitamin-d-if-older-than-50.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blacks may need less vitamin D than whites – PTH</title><link>/posts/blacks-may-need-less-vitamin-d-than-whites-pth.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-may-need-less-vitamin-d-than-whites-pth.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The 25(OH)D/PTH Threshold in Black Women&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2010 November; 95(11): 5069–5073. Received March 15, 2010; Accepted July 2, 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2010 August 4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2010-0610">doi: 10.1210/jc.2010-0610&lt;/a>; PMCID: PMC2968726&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John F. Aloia, Ding-Geng Chen, and Henian Chen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone Mineral Research Center, Winthrop-University Hospital, Mineola, New York 11501&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address all correspondence and requests for reprints to: Dr. John F. Aloia, Winthrop University Hospital, Academic Affairs, 222 Station Plaza North, Mineola, New York 11501. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:jaloia@winthrop.org">jaloia@winthrop.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diseases of obesity strongly associated with vitamin D deficiency in ethnic minorities</title><link>/posts/diseases-of-obesity-strongly-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-ethnic-minorities.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diseases-of-obesity-strongly-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-ethnic-minorities.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-obesity-and-obesity-related-chronic-disease-among-ethnic-minorities-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D, obesity, and obesity-related chronic disease among ethnic minorities: A systematic review&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrition, Volume 27, Issue 9, September 2011, Pages 868-879&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.nut.2010.12.014 | How to Cite or Link Using DOI&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andre M.N. Renzaho Ph.D.a &lt;a href="mailto:andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au">andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jennifer A. Halliday B.H.Sci. (Hons)a, Caryl Nowson Ph.D.b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a	WHO Collaborating Centre for Obesity Prevention, Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b	Centre for Physical Activity and Nutrition Research, School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Second generation dark skinned immigrants live shorter lives</title><link>/posts/second-generation-dark-skinned-immigrants-live-shorter-lives.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/second-generation-dark-skinned-immigrants-live-shorter-lives.html</guid><description>&lt;p>A chart in by Dr. Grimes in the UK &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TIo9a56nOwI">Video June 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;861&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="note-that-children-from-bangladesh-do-not-die-as-much-as-those-from-pakistan---with-similar-skin-color">Note that children from Bangladesh do not die as much as those from Pakistan - with similar skin color&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>They do not have such concealing clothes - thus getting more vitamin D from the sun&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>They eat far more fish (which contain vitamin D)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/cse?cx=001215644404345293668%3A3di8vufs_m4&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=grimes&amp;amp;sa=Search&amp;amp;siteurl=www-open-opensocial.googleusercontent.com%2Fgadgets%2Fifr%3Furl%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fwww.google.com%252Fcse%252Fapi%252F001215644404345293668%252Fcse%252F3di8vufs_m4%252Fgadget%26container%3Dopen%26view%3Dhome%26lang%3Dall%26country%3DALL%26debug%3D0%26nocache%3D0%26sanitize%3D0%26v%3Dafb6168a5fba69bc%26source%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fwww.VitaminDWiki.com%252Ftiki-index.php%253Fpage%253DVitaminDSearch%26parent%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fwww.VitaminDWiki.com%252Ftiki-index.php%253Fpage%253DVitaminDSearch%26libs%3Dcore%253Acore.io%253Arpc%23st%3D%2525st%2525%26rpctoken%3D2060229812#gsc.tab=0&amp;amp;gsc.q=grimes&amp;amp;gsc.page=1">Google search VitaminDWiki for Grimes&lt;/a> 25 items as of Oct 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>97 percent of Native American children have less than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/97-percent-of-native-american-children-have-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/97-percent-of-native-american-children-have-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-is-associated-with-diabetes-risk-in-native-american-children">Vitamin D Insufficiency Is Associated With Diabetes Risk in Native American Children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2011 Oct 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nsiah-Kumi PA, Erickson JM, Beals JL, Ogle EA, Whiting M, Brushbreaker C, Borgeson CD, Qui F, Yu F, Larsen JL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha, NE, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aims/Hypothesis. Vitamin D insufficiency has not been well studied in Native American (NA) children, who are at risk for obesity and diabetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The authors examined vitamin D insufficiency and its association with body mass index (BMI) and insulin resistance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Telomeres improved when obese blacks took 2000 IU of vitamin D daily</title><link>/posts/telomeres-improved-when-obese-blacks-took-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/telomeres-improved-when-obese-blacks-took-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Black seniors near equator: increased vitamin D decreases bone density</title><link>/posts/black-seniors-near-equator-increased-vitamin-d-decreases-bone-density.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-seniors-near-equator-increased-vitamin-d-decreases-bone-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-association-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-with-indicators-of-bone-quality-in-men-of-caucasian-and-african-ancestry">The association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D with indicators of bone quality in men of Caucasian and African ancestry.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Sep;22(9):2475-85. Epub 2010 Nov 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbour KE, Zmuda JM, Horwitz MJ, Strotmeyer ES, Boudreau R, Evans RW, Ensrud KE, Gordon CL, Petit MA, Patrick AL, Cauley JA; Osteoporotic Fractures in Men (MrOS) Research Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology, Graduate School of Public Health, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:barbourk@edc.pitt.edu">barbourk@edc.pitt.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We examined the association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> with indices of bone quality in older men. Positive associations for 25(OH)D and bone mineral density, content, cortical thickness, and axial and polar strength strain indices were observed among Caucasians; however, among men of African descent findings were either null or negative.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black veterans have worse health and low vitamin D, yet are not tested as much</title><link>/posts/black-veterans-have-worse-health-and-low-vitamin-d-yet-are-not-tested-as-much.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-veterans-have-worse-health-and-low-vitamin-d-yet-are-not-tested-as-much.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="race-and-vitamin-d-status-and-monitoring-in-male-veterans">Race and vitamin D status and monitoring in male veterans.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Natl Med Assoc. 2011 Jun;103(6):492-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peiris AN, Bailey BA, Peiris P, Copeland RJ, Manning T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, East Tennessee State University, Johnson City, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:alan.peiris@va.gov">alan.peiris@va.gov&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>African Americans have lower vitamin D levels and reduced health outcomes compared to white Americans. Vitamin D deficiency may contribute to adverse health outcomes in African Americans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We hypothesized that race would be associated with vitamin D status and testing in African Americans veterans, and that vitamin D status is a major contributor to health care costs in African American veterans compared to white veterans.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark Skinned youths and vitamin D in Southern Canada - Dissertation 2011</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-youths-and-vitamin-d-in-southern-canada-dissertation-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-youths-and-vitamin-d-in-southern-canada-dissertation-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-metabolites-in-young-adults-of-diverse-ancestry-living-in-the-greater-toronto-area">Vitamin D Metabolites in Young Adults of Diverse Ancestry Living in the Greater Toronto Area&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>By Agnes Gozdzik&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A thesis submitted in conformity with the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Anthropology University of Toronto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© Copyright by Agnes Gozdzik 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor00fpdf-is-attached-at-the-bottom-of-this-pagespan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D plays a critical role in bone metabolism and many cellular and immunological processes, and low vitamin D levels have been associated with several chronic and infectious diseases. Previous studies have reported that many otherwise healthy adults of European ancestry living in Canada have low vitamin D concentrations during the wintertime. However, individuals of non-European ancestry are at a higher risk of having low vitamin D levels. This thesis examined vitamin D status in a sample of young adults of diverse ancestry living in the Greater Toronto Area. In my research I found that:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Vitamin D Deficiencies in developing countries</title><link>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-deficiencies-in-developing-countries.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-deficiencies-in-developing-countries.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>14000 IU vitamin D (50000 twice a week) often stops Sickle Cell pain</title><link>/posts/14000-iu-vitamin-d-50000-twice-a-week-often-stops-sickle-cell-pain.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/14000-iu-vitamin-d-50000-twice-a-week-often-stops-sickle-cell-pain.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="several-items-on-this-page">Several items on this page&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - &lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="can-sometimes-stop-sickle-cell-pain-with-vitamin-d---oct-2011">Can sometimes stop sickle cell pain with vitamin D - Oct 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="complete-resolution-of-sickle-cell-chronic-pain-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-therapy">Complete Resolution of Sickle Cell Chronic Pain With High Dose Vitamin D Therapy:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A Case Report and Review of the Literature&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Pediatric Hematology/Oncology: October 2011 - Volume 33 - Issue 7 - p 549–551, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/MPH.0b013e31821ed3ea">doi: 10.1097/MPH.0b013e31821ed3ea&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blacks have low vitamin D and have 50 percent more kidney failure</title><link>/posts/blacks-have-low-vitamin-d-and-have-50-percent-more-kidney-failure.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-have-low-vitamin-d-and-have-50-percent-more-kidney-failure.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-racial-disparity-in-albuminuria-nhanes-20012006">Vitamin D and Racial Disparity in Albuminuria: NHANES 2001–2006&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>American Journal of Hypertension 2011; 24 10, 1114–1120. doi:10.1038/ajh.2011.108&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kevin A. Fiscella1,2, Paul C. Winters1 and Gbenga Ogedegbe3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Family Medicine, University of Rochester School of Medicine, Rochester, New York, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Community &amp;amp; Preventive Medicine, University of Rochester School of Medicine, Rochester, New York, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Medicine, Division of General Internal Medicine, Center for Healthful Behavior Change, New York University School of Medicine, New York, New York, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Graphs of diseases vs vitamin D levels - and D3 vs D2</title><link>/posts/graphs-of-diseases-vs-vitamin-d-levels-and-d3-vs-d2.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/graphs-of-diseases-vs-vitamin-d-levels-and-d3-vs-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="graphs-from-a-presentation-by-dr-grimes-in-london">Graphs from a presentation by Dr. Grimes in London&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PDF of the presentation is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindassociation.org/7th-april-2011-vitamin-d---experts-forum.html">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for audio and video versions on the web (Clinical Experiences)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="can-see-that-the-patients-with-east-asian-names-have-significantly-lower-vitamin-d-levels-than-those-with-british-names">Can see that the patients with East Asian Names have significantly lower vitamin D levels than those with British Names&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;735,734&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="median-east-asian--9-ng--nbsp-nbspmedian-british--19-ng">Median East Asian = 9 ng    Median British = 19 ng&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="notepatients-with-the-lowest-level-of-vitamin-d-in-their-blood-are-on-the-right">Note:patients with the lowest level of vitamin D in their blood are on the right&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="graphs-showing-the-vitamin-d-levels-for-each-disease">Graphs showing the vitamin D levels for each disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;736,737,738,739,740,741,742,743,744,745&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;250&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast cancer worse for black women</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-worse-for-black-women.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-worse-for-black-women.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="breast-cancer-spreads-significantly-different-in-black-women">Breast cancer spreads significantly different in Black women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>By Jimmie Davis, Jr., BlackPressUSA, &lt;a href="http://www.thewestsidegazette.com/news/Article/Article.asp?NewsID=110573&amp;amp;sID=20&amp;amp;ItemSource=L%20">Originally posted 9/15/2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it comes to the way breast cancer spreads throughout the body of African American women are in comparison to white women, there significant differences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These disparities have led the National Cancer Institute &lt;span>[NCI]&lt;/span> to award a $19.3 million research grant to Roswell Park Cancer Institute &lt;span>[RPCI]&lt;/span>, the University of North Carolina Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center &lt;span>[UNC]&lt;/span> and Slone Epidemiology Center at Boston University &lt;span>[BU]&lt;/span> to study why breast cancer in African American women is distributed out of the ordinary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blacks have more pre-term births due to low nutrients such as vitamin D</title><link>/posts/blacks-have-more-pre-term-births-due-to-low-nutrients-such-as-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-have-more-pre-term-births-due-to-low-nutrients-such-as-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="racial-disparities-in-preterm-birth-an-overview-of-the-potential-role-of-nutrient-deficiencies">Racial disparities in preterm birth: an overview of the potential role of nutrient deficiencies.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dunlop AL, Kramer M, Hogue CJ, Menon R, Ramakrishan U.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2011 Sep 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emory University School of Medicine, Department of Family and Preventive Medicine, Emory University Rollins School of Public Health, Women and Children&amp;rsquo;s Center,Department of Epidemiology, and Emory University Rollins School of Public Health, Department of Global Health, Atlanta, Georgia, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>88 percent of African immigrants to Melborne had less than 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/88-percent-of-african-immigrants-to-melborne-had-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/88-percent-of-african-immigrants-to-melborne-had-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-and-risk-factors-for-type-2-diabetes-and-cardiovascular-disease-among-african-migrant-and-refugee-adults-in-melbourne---a-pilot-study">Prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency and risk factors for type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease among African migrant and refugee adults in Melbourne - A pilot study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Asia Pac J Clin Nutr. 2011;20(3):397-403.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renzaho AM, Nowson C, Kaur A, Halliday JA, Fong D, Desilva J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WHO Collaborating Centre for Obesity Prevention, Deakin Population Health Strategic Research Centre, Faculty of Health, Deakin University, 221 Burwood Highway, Burwood, 3125, Victoria, Australia. &lt;a href="mailto:andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au">andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Migration to industrialised countries poses a &amp;ldquo;double whammy&amp;rdquo; for type 2 diabetes among sub-Saharan African migrant and refugee adults. This population group has been found to be at an increased risk of obesity and type 2 diabetes, which may be further aggravated by inadequate vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Disadvantaged get less sun and have poor health in the North</title><link>/posts/disadvantaged-get-less-sun-and-have-poor-health-in-the-north.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/disadvantaged-get-less-sun-and-have-poor-health-in-the-north.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Black women lacking Calcium and Vitamin D weighed more</title><link>/posts/black-women-lacking-calcium-and-vitamin-d-weighed-more.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-women-lacking-calcium-and-vitamin-d-weighed-more.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="higher-amounts-of-body-fat-are-associated-with-inadequate-intakes-of-calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-african-american-women">Higher amounts of body fat are associated with inadequate intakes of calcium and vitamin D in African American women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrition Research; Volume 31, Issue 7, July 2011, Pages 527-536; doi:10.1016/j.nutres.2011.06.005&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diane K. Tidwell a, &lt;a href="mailto:ditdwell@fsnhp.msstate.edu">ditdwell@fsnhp.msstate.edu&lt;/a> and Melinda W. Valliant b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Food Science, Nutrition and Health Promotion, PO Box 9805, Mississippi State, MS 39762&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Nutrition and Hospitality Management, The University of Mississippi&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 11 October 2010; revised 22 June 2011; accepted 23 June 2011, online 12 August 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D insufficiency in UK youths – 37X more likely if dark skin</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-uk-youths-37x-more-likely-if-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-uk-youths-37x-more-likely-if-dark-skin.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Diabetic neuropathy and low vitamin D, especially in blacks</title><link>/posts/diabetic-neuropathy-and-low-vitamin-d-especially-in-blacks.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetic-neuropathy-and-low-vitamin-d-especially-in-blacks.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-between-vitamin-d-and-diabetic-neuropathy-in-a-nationally-representative-sample-results-from-20012004-nhanes">Association between vitamin D and diabetic neuropathy in a nationally representative sample: results from 2001–2004 NHANES&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>L. H. Soderstrom1, S. P. Johnson2, V. A. Diaz2, A. G. Mainous III2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1111/j.1464-5491.2011.03379.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal compilation © 2011 Diabetes UK, Vol. 28 Issue 7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aims:? To evaluate the association between vitamin D insufficiency and peripheral neuropathy in a nationally representative sample of adults with diagnosed diabetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods:? Vitamin D concentrations, medical examination variables and questionnaire results from the 2001–2004 National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey were analysed for adults ? 40 years old with diagnosed diabetes (unweighted n = 591, weighted n = 8.82 million). Neuropathy was defined as self report of peripheral neuropathy symptoms of painful sensation, tingling, numbness or loss of feeling in hands or feet. Additionally, Semmes–Weinstein monofilament test results were used as an indicator of neuropathy. Insufficient vitamin D was characterized as &lt;strong>&amp;lt; 30 ng/ml.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black members of Adventist church defy health disparities</title><link>/posts/black-members-of-adventist-church-defy-health-disparities.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-members-of-adventist-church-defy-health-disparities.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="medical-expresshttpmedicalxpresscomnews2011-06-black-members-adventist-church-defyhtml">&lt;a href="http://medicalxpress.com/news/2011-06-black-members-adventist-church-defy.html">Medical Express&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>mproved Quality of Life – answering such question as&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;During the past four weeks, how much did pain interfere with your normal work?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;How much time during the past four weeks have you felt downhearted and depressed?”&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Overall, black Adventist study participants reported better physical and mental quality of life than the U.S. norm,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>in some cases by as much as 4.5 percentage points.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;This difference is particularly pronounced in older age groups, who progressively demonstrate&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Council vs FDA concerning vitamin D deficiency in blacks and others</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-council-vs-fda-concerning-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-blacks-and-others.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-council-vs-fda-concerning-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-blacks-and-others.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="following-email-was-sent-end-of-june-2011---no-action-was-taken">Following email was sent end of June 2011 - no action was taken&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dear Vitamin D Council Member,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We need your help! This summer, the Vitamin D Council is set to file a 17-page complaint against Commissioner Margaret Hamburg, M.D. and the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) regarding their vitamin D food fortification policies and how they disparately afflict African Americans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through a combination of mandated and encouraged practices, the FDA depends upon milk to deliver virtually all supplemental dietary vitamin D to Americans. The FDA knows African Americans consume little milk, particularly relative to Caucasian Americans. The FDA, in effect, chooses to fortify a food that does not target a population who most need vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Studies linked low vitamin D and dark skin to Obesity, Diabetes, and heart</title><link>/posts/studies-linked-low-vitamin-d-and-dark-skin-to-obesity-diabetes-and-heart.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/studies-linked-low-vitamin-d-and-dark-skin-to-obesity-diabetes-and-heart.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-obesity-and-obesity-related-chronic-disease-among-ethnic-minorities-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D, obesity, and obesity-related chronic disease among ethnic minorities: A systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrition. 2011 Jun 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renzaho AM, Halliday JA, Nowson C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WHO Collaborating Centre for Obesity Prevention, Deakin University, Burwood , Victoria, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To assess the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) status and obesity, cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), the metabolic syndrome, and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in ethnic minorities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Databases searched were CINHAL with full text, Global Health, MEDLINE with full text, and PsycINFO from 1980 through 2010 (February). Studies were included if they 1) targeted immigrants from low- to high-income countries or ethnic minorities, 2) focused primarily on 25(OH)D and its relation to obesity, T2DM, and/or CVDs, and 3) were published in peer-reviewed journals. The influences of key confounders such as age, gender, and ethnicity on any observed relations were also assessed. Due to the heterogeneity of study characteristics, only a narrative synthesis was undertaken.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skinned teens use media much more</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-teens-use-media-much-more.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-teens-use-media-much-more.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="clipped-from-good-website-kids-of-color-consume-a-lot-more-media-than-white-kidshttpwwwgoodispostkids-of-color-consume-a-lot-more-media-than-white-kids-june-2011">Clipped from Good website: &lt;a href="http://www.good.is/post/kids-of-color-consume-a-lot-more-media-than-white-kids/">Kids of Color Consume a Lot More Media Than White Kids&lt;/a> June 2011&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A &lt;a href="http://www.northwestern.edu/newscenter/stories/2011/06/media-usa-youth-wartella.html">new study&lt;/a> at Northwestern University found a huge difference between the amount of media white and nonwhite kids consume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Minority children ages 8 to 18 consume an average of 13 hours of media content a day—about 4-and-a-half hours more than their white counterparts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In the last ten years, this number has doubled for black children and quadrupled for Hispanics&lt;/strong> .&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blacks not taking mulitvitamins were 5X more likely to be vitamin D insufficient</title><link>/posts/blacks-not-taking-mulitvitamins-were-5x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-insufficient.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-not-taking-mulitvitamins-were-5x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-insufficient.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="correlates-and-prevalence-of-insufficient-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-in-black-and-white-older-adults-the-health-aging-and-body-composition-study">Correlates and Prevalence of Insufficient 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Status in Black and White Older Adults: The Health, Aging and Body Composition Study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Am Geriatr Soc. 2011 Jun 13. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-5415.2011.03476.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2011.03476.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shea MK, Houston DK &lt;a href="mailto:dhausman@uga.edu">dhausman@uga.edu&lt;/a>, Tooze JA, Davis CC, Johnson MA, Hausman DB, Cauley JA, Bauer DC, Tylavsky F, Harris TB, Kritchevsky SB; for the Health, Aging and Body Composition Study.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, School of Medicine, Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, North Carolina;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis - 40 ng is enough vitamin D if high latitude or dark skin</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-40-ng-is-enough-vitamin-d-if-high-latitude-or-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-40-ng-is-enough-vitamin-d-if-high-latitude-or-dark-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="a-hrefpostsrecommendations-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1293recommendationsa-of-amount-of-vitamin-d-to-have-generally-vary-between-30ngml-and-60-ngml">&lt;a href="/posts/recommendations" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1293">Recommendations&lt;/a> of amount of vitamin D to have generally vary between 30ng/ml and 60 ng/ml&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpoststhe-institute-of-medicine-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1193the-institute-of-medicinea-proposed-20-ngml-in-nov-2010">&lt;a href="/posts/the-institute-of-medicine" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1193">The Institute of Medicine&lt;/a> proposed 20 ng/ml in Nov 2010]&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="dr-veith-presented-an-interesting-hypothesis-in-may-2011">Dr. Veith presented an interesting hypothesis in May 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="some-people-caucasians-living-in-high-latitudes-which-have-a-large-variation-in-uv-during-the-year">Some people (Caucasians?) living in high latitudes (which have a large variation in UV during the year)&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="get-adverse-reactions-to-high-50-ng-levels-of-vitamin-d-for-the-entire-year">get adverse reactions to high (50 ng+) levels of vitamin D for the entire year&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="it-might-be-ok-to-have-higher-levels-during-the-summer">It MIGHT be OK to have higher levels during the summer.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="the-data-only-hints-that-having--50ngml-all-year-long-might-be-a-problem">The data only hints that having &amp;gt; 50NG/ml all year long might be a problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="a-hrefpostscick-here-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1660cick-herea-to-get-to-reference---pdf-and-soon-audio-and-video">&lt;a href="/posts/cick-here" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1660">CICK HERE&lt;/a> to get to reference - PDF and soon audio and video&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="humans-evolved-to-have-a-constant-amount-of-vitamin-d">Humans evolved to have a constant amount of vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"> 
&lt;h2 id="u-shaped-risk-curve-only-where-uv-varies-a-lot-with-season---veith">U shaped risk curve only where UV varies a lot with season - Veith&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"> 
&lt;h2 id="pancreatic-cancer-increases-with-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-only-where-uv-varies-a-lot-with-season">Pancreatic Cancer increases with high levels of vitamin D only where UV varies a lot with season&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"> 
&lt;h1 id="prostate-cancer-u-shaped-curve-from-a-hrefpostslappe-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1659lappe-may-2011a">Prostate Cancer U-shaped curve from &lt;a href="/posts/lappe" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1659">Lappe May 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="note-this-shows-having-24-ngml-all-year-long-increases-prostate-cancer">Note: this shows having 24 ng/ml all year long increases prostate cancer&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"> 
&lt;h1 id="concerning-people-with-dark-skins">Concerning people with dark skins&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="there-have-been-various-reports-in-2009-2010-and-2011-which-seem-to-indicate-that-dark-skinned-people-do-not-need-as-much-as-those-with-light-skins">There have been various reports in 2009, 2010, and 2011 which seem to indicate that dark skinned people do not need as much as those with light skins&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="unknown-so-far">Unknown so far&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Does this apply only to dark skinned people living far from the equator&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="see-in-vitamindwiki">See in VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1795">Dark skin need more vitamin D - Mar 2010.pdf&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Race vs vitamin D level - Veith</title><link>/posts/race-vs-vitamin-d-level-veith.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/race-vs-vitamin-d-level-veith.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Canadian Vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/canadian-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/canadian-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-vitamin-d-status-of-canadians-relative-to-the-2011-dietary-reference-intakes-an-examination-in-children-and-adults-with-and-without-supplement-use">The vitamin D status of Canadians relative to the 2011 Dietary Reference Intakes: an examination in children and adults with and without supplement use.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 May 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whiting SJ, Langlois KA, Vatanparast H, Greene-Finestone LS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>College of Pharmacy and Nutrition, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 2011 Dietary Reference Intakes (DRIs) for vitamin D use 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations to define vitamin D deficiency (&amp;lt;30 nmol/L), the Estimated Average Requirement (40 nmol/L), and the Recommended Dietary Allowance (RDA; 50 nmol/L). The Canadian population has not yet been assessed according to these recommendations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skinned obese not helped much by weekly 50000 IU dose of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-obese-not-helped-much-by-weekly-50000-iu-dose-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-obese-not-helped-much-by-weekly-50000-iu-dose-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-status-among-obese-adolescents-prevalence-and-response-to-treatment">Low Vitamin D Status Among Obese Adolescents: Prevalence and Response to Treatment&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Adolescent Health, Volume 48, Issue 5 , Pages 448-452, May 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zeev Harel, M.D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patricia Flanagan, M.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michelle Forcier, M.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dalia Harel, M.Sc. Received 19 September 2010; accepted 20 January 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Adolescent Medicine, Hasbro Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Providence, Rhode Island&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Warren Alpert Medical School of Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corresponding Author InformationAddress correspondence to: Zeev Harel, M.D., Division of Adolescent Medicine, Hasbro Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, 593 Eddy Street, Providence, RI 02903&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin pigmentation predicted bone mineral content in Hawaii</title><link>/posts/skin-pigmentation-predicted-bone-mineral-content-in-hawaii.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-pigmentation-predicted-bone-mineral-content-in-hawaii.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="tanning-predicts-bone-mass-but-not-structure-in-adolescent-females-living-in-hawaii">Tanning predicts bone mass but not structure in adolescent females living in Hawaii.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Hum Biol. 2011 Apr 14. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ajhb.21158.">doi: 10.1002/ajhb.21158.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osborne DL, Weaver CM, McAbe LD, McCabe GM, Novotny R, Boushey C, Savaiano DA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Anthropology, University of Nebraska-Lincoln, Lincoln, Nebraska 68588. &lt;a href="mailto:dosborne2@unl.edu">dosborne2@unl.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: To evaluate the relationship between facultative skin pigmentation, which predicts circulating levels of plasma 25-hydroxymitamin D, and several measures of bone mass and structure in a cross sectional sample of adolescent females living in Hawaii.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skinned Caribbean seniors have enough vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-caribbean-seniors-have-enough-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-caribbean-seniors-have-enough-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-elderly-afro-caribbean-men">Low prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in elderly Afro-Caribbean men.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ethn Dis. 2011 Winter;21(1):79-84.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Miljkovic I, Bodnar LM, Cauley JA, Bunker CH, Patrick AL, Wheeler VW, Kuller LH, Zmuda JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology, Graduate School of Public Health, Pittsburgh, University of Pittsburgh, PA 15213, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:miljkovici@edc.pitt.edu">miljkovici@edc.pitt.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is highly prevalent worldwide, and is linked to several major chronic, inflammatory and autoimmune diseases. Vitamin D deficiency has not been evaluated in dark skinned individuals living in areas of high sun exposure utilizing more reliable mass spectrometry assay techniques. We determined the prevalence of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) deficiency in Afro-Caribbean men on the tropical island of Tobago, where there is a high level of sunshine year round. Serum 25(OH)D2 and 25(OH)D3 metabolites were measured following extraction and purification using liquid chromatography and tandem mass spectrometry in 424 Afro-Caribbean men aged &amp;gt; 65 years from a larger population-based cohort study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skin pregnancies and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/dark-skin-pregnancies-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skin-pregnancies-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary">Summary&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#statistics-for-african-american-vs-white-births-in-the-us">Statistics for African-American vs white births in the US:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostschart-shows-that-blacks-are-almost-4x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1560chart-shows-that-blacks-are-almost-4x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-da">&lt;a href="/posts/chart-shows-that-blacks-are-almost-4x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1560">Chart shows that blacks are almost 4X more likely to have less than 20ng of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#left-curve--blacks-indoors-15-ng--right-curve--blacks-outdoors-46ng">Left curve = blacks indoors (15 ng) /// Right curve = blacks outdoors (46ng)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#on-the-web">On the web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> Avoiding the sun reduces your vitamin D intake&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> Can avoid the sun by use of sunscreen, not going outdoors, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30 percent of US had less than 20 ng of vitamin D - CDC</title><link>/posts/30-percent-of-us-had-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-cdc.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/30-percent-of-us-had-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-cdc.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="very-different-than-the-a-hrefposts10-percent-deficiency-reported-by-the-iom-just-4-months-before-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-119310-deficiency-reported-by-the-iom-just-4-months-beforea">Very different than the &lt;a href="/posts/10-percent-deficiency-reported-by-the-iom-just-4-months-before" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1193">10% deficiency reported by the IoM just 4 months before&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="a-few-of-the-charts-from-vitamin-d-status-united-states-20012006">A few of the charts from: Vitamin D Status: United States, 2001–2006&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;519&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolorc00note-very-few-organizations-consider-levels--50-ngram-125-nmol-to-be-possibly-harmfulspan">&lt;span style="color:#C00;">Note: Very few organizations consider levels &amp;gt; 50 ngram (125 nmol) to be &amp;ldquo;possibly harmful&amp;rdquo;&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;520&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="span-stylecolorc0071-of-blacks-had-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-dspan">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#C00;">71% of blacks had less than 20 ng of vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;521&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="click-herehttpswwwvitamindwikicomtiki-download_filephpfileid1827-for-pdf">&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1827">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for PDF&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 889">Overview Deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>42 percent of US adults less than 20 ng of vitamin D and 82 percent of blacks</title><link>/posts/42-percent-of-us-adults-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-and-82-percent-of-blacks.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/42-percent-of-us-adults-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-and-82-percent-of-blacks.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prevalence-and-correlates-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-us-adults">Prevalence and correlates of vitamin D deficiency in US adults.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutr Res. 2011 Jan;31(1):48-54.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forrest KY, Stuhldreher WL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Public Health &amp;amp; Social Work, Slippery Rock University of Pennsylvania, Slippery Rock, PA 16057, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:kimberly.forrest@sru.edu">kimberly.forrest@sru.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mounting evidence suggests that vitamin D deficiency could be linked to several chronic diseases, including cardiovascular disease and cancer. The purpose of this study was to examine the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency and its correlates to test the hypothesis that vitamin D deficiency was common in the US population, especially in certain minority groups. The National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2005 to 2006 data were analyzed for vitamin D levels in adult participants (N = 4495). Vitamin D deficiency was defined as a serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations ?20 ng/mL (50 nmol/L). The overall prevalence rate of vitamin D deficiency was 41.6%, with the highest rate seen in blacks (82.1%), followed by Hispanics (69.2%). Vitamin D deficiency was significantly more common among those who had no college education, were obese, with a poor health status, hypertension, low high-density lipoprotein cholesterol level, or not consuming milk daily (all P &amp;lt; .001). Multivariate analyses showed that&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>50000 IU vitamin D2 weekly helped blacks with heart problems</title><link>/posts/50000-iu-vitamin-d2-weekly-helped-blacks-with-heart-problems.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/50000-iu-vitamin-d2-weekly-helped-blacks-with-heart-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="supplemental-vitamin-d-and-calcium-in-the-management-of-african-americans-with-heart-failure-having-hypovitaminosis-d">Supplemental vitamin D and calcium in the management of African Americans with heart failure having hypovitaminosis D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Med Sci. 2011 Feb;341(2):113-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zia AA, Komolafe BO, Moten M, Ahokas RA, McGee JE, William Rosenberg E, Bhattacharya SK, Weber KT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, 38163, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: A dyshomeostasis of macro- and micronutrients, including vitamin D and oxidative stress, are common pathophysiologic features in patients with congestive heart failure (CHF). In African Americans (AA) with CHF, reductions in plasma 25(OH)D are of moderate-to-marked severity (&amp;lt;20 ng/mL) and may be accompanied by ionized hypocalcemia with compensatory increases in serum parathyroid hormone (PTH). The management of hypovitaminosis D in AA with CHF has not been established.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels in Israel vs skin type and age</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-in-israel-vs-skin-type-and-age.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-in-israel-vs-skin-type-and-age.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25ohd-concentrations-in-sunny-israel">Serum 25(OH)D concentrations in sunny Israel.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Mar 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saliba W, Rennert HS, Kershenbaum A, Rennert G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Community Medicine and Epidemiology, Carmel Medical Center, Clalit Health Services, and Bruce Rappaport Faculty of Medicine, Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, 7 Michal St., Haifa, 34362, Israel, &lt;a href="mailto:saliba_wa@clalit.org.il">saliba_wa@clalit.org.il&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study assesses vitamin D status in Israel. Serum 25(OH)D levels &amp;lt;25 and &amp;lt;50 nmol/L are common in Israel with noted differences between Arabs and Jews, Arab females were particularly at high risk. These findings may require public health intervention at the population level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Not yet certain that vitamin D reduces cardiovascular and diabetes in blacks</title><link>/posts/not-yet-certain-that-vitamin-d-reduces-cardiovascular-and-diabetes-in-blacks.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/not-yet-certain-that-vitamin-d-reduces-cardiovascular-and-diabetes-in-blacks.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="does-vitamin-d-deficiency-contribute-to-increased-rates-of-cardiovascular-disease-and-type-2-diabetes-in-african-americans">Does vitamin D deficiency contribute to increased rates of cardiovascular disease and type 2 diabetes in African Americans?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Mar 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harris SS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jean Mayer US Department of Agriculture Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging at Tufts University, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>African Americans have higher rates of type 2 diabetes (T2D) and some forms of cardiovascular disease (CVD) than do European Americans. African Americans also have much higher rates of vitamin D deficiency. There is emerging evidence that vitamin D deficiency may be a risk factor for hypertension, T2D, and CVD, but the extent to which racial disparities in disease rates are explained by racial differences in vitamin D status is uncertain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black obese children had low vitamin D and more fat under skin than whites</title><link>/posts/black-obese-children-had-low-vitamin-d-and-more-fat-under-skin-than-whites.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-obese-children-had-low-vitamin-d-and-more-fat-under-skin-than-whites.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-adiposity-and-lipids-in-black-american-and-caucasian-children">Vitamin D Status, Adiposity, and Lipids in Black American and Caucasian Children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Mar 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rajakumar K, de Las Heras J, Chen TC, Lee S, Holick MF, Arslanian SA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics (K.R.), Division of General Academic Pediatrics, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Department of Pediatrics (J.d.l.H., S.L., S.A.A.), Division of Weight Management and Wellness, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Division of Pediatric Endocrinology, Metabolism, and Diabetes Mellitus (S.A.A.), University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Department of Pediatrics and Endocrinology and Diabetes Research Group (J.d.l.H.), Cruces Hospital, 48903 Barakaldo, Vizcaya, Spain; and Department of Medicine (T.C.C., M.F.H.), Boston University School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts 02118.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Alert – one in three pre-teens in Tehran had less than 5 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/red-alert-one-in-three-pre-teens-in-tehran-had-less-than-5-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/red-alert-one-in-three-pre-teens-in-tehran-had-less-than-5-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-school-age-children-in-tehran-2008-a-red-alert">High prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in school-age children in Tehran, 2008: a red alert.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Feb 28:1-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neyestani TR, Hajifaraji M, Omidvar N, Eshraghian MR, Shariatzadeh N, Kalayi A, Gharavi A, Khalaji N, Haidari H, Zowghi T, Nikooyeh B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Laboratory of Nutrition Research, National Research Institute, Faculty of Nutritional Science and Food Technology, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, PO Box 19395-4741, Tehran, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To assess the vitamin D status of 9-12-year-old primary-school children in Tehran during autumn and winter 2007-2008.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and fertility and birth problems with dark skin</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-fertility-and-birth-problems-with-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-fertility-and-birth-problems-with-dark-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="racial-and-ethnic-disparities-in-assisted-reproductive-technology-pregnancy-and-live-birth-rates-within-body-mass-index-categories--fertility-and-sterility">Racial and ethnic disparities in assisted reproductive technology pregnancy and live birth rates within body mass index categories Fertility and Sterility&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.fertnstert.2010.12.035 | How to Cite or Link Using DOI&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara Luke Sc.D., M.P.H.a, b, Corresponding Author Contact Information, E-mail The Corresponding Author, Morton B. Brown Ph.D.c, Judy E. Stern Ph.D.d, Stacey A. Missmer Sc.D.e, f, g, Victor Y. Fujimoto M.D.h and Richard Leach M.D.a&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology, and Reproductive Biology, Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improved blood flow in blacks with just 2000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/improved-blood-flow-in-blacks-with-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/improved-blood-flow-in-blacks-with-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Vitamin D(3) Supplementation for 16 Weeks Improves Flow-Mediated Dilation in Overweight African-American Adults.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am J Hypertens. 2011 Feb 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harris RA, Pedersen-White J, Guo DH, Stallmann-Jorgensen IS, Keeton D, Huang Y, Shah Y, Zhu H, Dong Y.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Georgia Prevention Institute, Department of Pediatrics, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta, Georgia, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background A growing body of evidence has linked vitamin D deficiency to increased risk of cardiovascular disease. Vitamin D deficiency is also more common in African Americans for whom an increased cardiovascular disease risk exists. This study sought to test the hypothesis that 16 weeks of 60,000 IU monthly supplementation of oral vitamin D(3) would improve flow-mediated dilation (FMD) in African Americans, whereas no change would be observed in the placebo group.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>South African white children 48 ng vitamin D – black 37 ng</title><link>/posts/south-african-white-children-48-ng-vitamin-d-black-37-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/south-african-white-children-48-ng-vitamin-d-black-37-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="factors-influencing-the-vitamin-d-status-of-10-year-old-urban-south-african-children">Factors influencing the vitamin D status of 10-year-old urban South African children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Feb;14(2):334-339. Epub 2010 Aug 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Poopedi MA, Norris SA, Pettifor JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MRC Mineral Metabolism Research Unit &amp;amp; Birth to Twenty Research Programme, Faculty of Health Sciences, Department of Paediatrics and Child Health, Chris Hani Baragwanath Hospital, The University of the Witwatersrand, PO Bertsham, 2013 Johannesburg, South Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Assessment of vitamin D status in a cohort of healthy 10-year-old urban children and the factors that influence vitamin D status in these children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D bed used 4 minutes daily by dark skin members of UK sports team</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-bed-used-4-minutes-daily-by-dark-skin-members-of-uk-sports-team.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-bed-used-4-minutes-daily-by-dark-skin-members-of-uk-sports-team.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="manchester-uniteds-ryan-giggs-and-rio-ferdinand-buy-into-cutting-edge-methods-at-carrington">Manchester United&amp;rsquo;s Ryan Giggs and Rio Ferdinand buy into cutting-edge methods at Carrington&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Manchester United’s attempt to &lt;strong>reclaim the Premier League title&lt;/strong> is being bolstered by cutting-edge technology which includes GPS tracking of the players, zero-gravity rehabilitation and vitamin D beds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/sport/football/teams/manchester-united/8275326/Manchester-Uniteds-Ryan-Giggs-and-Rio-Ferdinand-buy-into-cutting-edge-methods-at-Carrington.html">By Mark Ogden 21 Jan 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a revelatory access-all-areas documentary by MUTV, the club’s in-house television channel, Ryan &amp;amp; Rio — Carrington Revealed, sheds light on the behind-the-scenes operation at Manchester United’s 108-acre Carrington training centre.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anemia associated with lower than 20 ng vitamin D among elderly</title><link>/posts/anemia-associated-with-lower-than-20-ng-vitamin-d-among-elderly.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/anemia-associated-with-lower-than-20-ng-vitamin-d-among-elderly.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-deficiency-in-subgroups-of-elderly-persons-with-anemia-association-with-anemia-of-inflammation">Prevalence of 25-hydroxyvitamin D deficiency in subgroups of elderly persons with anemia: association with anemia of inflammation.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Blood. 2011 Jan 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perlstein TS, Pande R, Berliner N, Vanasse GJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anemia and vitamin D deficiency are conditions that both result in significant morbidity and increase with age. The potential relationship between them remains poorly understood, particularly in the elderly. We utilized the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES III) to examine the association of vitamin D deficiency with anemia subtypes in individuals aged &amp;gt; 60 years. Vitamin D deficiency was defined as serum levels &lt;strong>&amp;lt; 20 ng/mL&lt;/strong> and anemia was defined according to World Health Organization criteria.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium with Vitamin D2 then D3 helps A-A after heart failure</title><link>/posts/calcium-with-vitamin-d2-then-d3-helps-a-a-after-heart-failure.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-with-vitamin-d2-then-d3-helps-a-a-after-heart-failure.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="supplemental-vitamin-d-and-calcium-in-the-management-of-african-americans-with-heart-failure-having-hypovitaminosis-d">Supplemental Vitamin D and Calcium in the Management of African Americans With Heart Failure Having Hypovitaminosis D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Med Sci. 2011 Jan 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zia AA, Komolafe BO, Moten M, Ahokas RA, McGee JE, William Rosenberg E, Bhattacharya SK, Weber KT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Division of Cardiovascular Diseases (aaz, mm, jem, skb, ktw), Department of Medicine, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; Department of Medicine (bok), Graduate Medical Education, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology (raa), University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; Division of Dermatology(ewr), Department of Medicine, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; and Veterans Affairs Medical Center (mm, jem), Memphis, Tennessee.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autism more frequent from mothers who are dark skinned or veiled</title><link>/posts/autism-more-frequent-from-mothers-who-are-dark-skinned-or-veiled.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/autism-more-frequent-from-mothers-who-are-dark-skinned-or-veiled.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prevalence-of-autism-according-to-maternal-immigrant-status-and-ethnic-origin">Prevalence of autism according to maternal immigrant status and ethnic origin.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2011 Jan 11. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0447.2010.01662.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0447.2010.01662.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dealberto MJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Community Health and Epidemiology, Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, ON, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective:? To examine the rates of autism separately according to maternal immigrant status and ethnic origin in respect to the vitamin D insufficiency hypothesis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Method:? Articles were identified by electronic searches. Studies were selected when they analysed autism rates according to maternal immigrant status and/or ethnic origin using multivariate techniques.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Very low vitamin D for first pregnancies and those with dark skin</title><link>/posts/very-low-vitamin-d-for-first-pregnancies-and-those-with-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/very-low-vitamin-d-for-first-pregnancies-and-those-with-dark-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-insufficiency-is-common-during-pregnancy">Vitamin D Deficiency and Insufficiency is Common during Pregnancy.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Perinatol. 2011 Jan;28(1):7-12. Epub 2010 Jul 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johnson DD, Wagner CL, Hulsey TC, McNeil RB, Ebeling M, Hollis BW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Maternal Fetal Medicine, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>– – – – – – – – – –&lt;/p>
&lt;p>^~~#F00:Average ng/ml during pregnancy: Blacks 15, Hispanic 24, Caucasian 29&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Percentage with less than 20ng/ml: Blacks 97%, Hispanic 81%, Caucasian 67%~~^&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blacks are still not getting enough vitamin D</title><link>/posts/blacks-are-still-not-getting-enough-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-are-still-not-getting-enough-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>By Consuelo H. Wilkins, M.D., December 16, 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From &lt;a href="http://www.stlamerican.com/articles/2010/12/16/your_health_matters/health_news/health02.txt">http://www.stlamerican.com/articles/2010/12/16/your_health_matters/health_news/health02.txt&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past 5 years, the messages regarding vitamin D have been both confusing and conflicting and the Institute of Medicine’s (IOM) recent report has only made it more complex. Last month, the IOM, which sets the dietary reference intakes for nutrients, published new guidelines for calcium and vitamin D. Although the recommended dietary allowances (600-800 IUs, depending on age) and the upper limit of the vitamin D intake (4,000 IUs) are higher than the IOM’s 1997 recommendations, it is not as high as some experts, researchers and other health professionals had anticipated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many possible associations of increased asthma in black children</title><link>/posts/many-possible-associations-of-increased-asthma-in-black-children.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-possible-associations-of-increased-asthma-in-black-children.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="racial-disparities-in-pediatric-asthma-a-review-of-the-literature">Racial Disparities in Pediatric Asthma: A Review of the Literature.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Allergy Asthma Rep. 2010 Nov 24. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hill TD, Graham LM, Divgi V.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Georgia Pediatric Pulmonology Associates, 1100 Lake Hearn Drive, Suite 450, Atlanta, GA, 30342, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:tdhill@gppa.net">tdhill@gppa.net&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The burden of asthma disproportionately affects children living in economically disadvantaged urban communities. The relationships between ethnicity, genetic differences, lower socioeconomic status, poor medication adherence, greater exposure to environmental triggers, and absence of regular asthma care all contribute to this disparity. This review aims to identify and discuss recent studies on additional factors that may also impact to pediatric asthma disparity. The body of work examined in this review suggests that these disparities are the result of&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU raised black teens vitamin D level to 34 ng and they lost fat</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-raised-black-teens-vitamin-d-level-to-34-ng-and-they-lost-fat.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-raised-black-teens-vitamin-d-level-to-34-ng-and-they-lost-fat.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-16-week-randomized-clinical-trial-of-2000-international-units-daily-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-black-youth-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-adiposity-and-arterial-stiffness">A 16-week randomized clinical trial of 2000 international units daily vitamin D3 supplementation in black youth: 25-hydroxyvitamin D, adiposity, and arterial stiffness.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2010 Oct;95(10):4584-91. Epub 2010 Jul 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dong Y, Stallmann-Jorgensen IS, Pollock NK, Harris RA, Keeton D, Huang Y, Li K, Bassali R, Guo DH, Thomas J, Pierce GL, White J, Holick MF, Zhu H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Georgia Prevention Institute, Department of Pediatrics, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta, Georgia 30912, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:ydong@mail.mcg.edu">ydong@mail.mcg.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>End stage kidney disease almost 3X more likely for blacks – 2009</title><link>/posts/end-stage-kidney-disease-almost-3x-more-likely-for-blacks-2009.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/end-stage-kidney-disease-almost-3x-more-likely-for-blacks-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-race-and-the-progression-of-kidney-disease">25-hydroxyvitamin D levels, race, and the progression of kidney disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Am Soc Nephrol. 2009 Dec;20(12):2631-9. Epub 2009 Oct 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Melamed ML, Astor B, Michos ED, Hostetter TH, Powe NR, Muntner P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Albert Einstein College of Medicine, 1300 Morris Park Avenue, Bronx, NY 10461, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:mmelamed@aecom.yu.edu">mmelamed@aecom.yu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Black individuals have lower 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and experience a disproportionate burden of ESRD compared with white individuals. Animal studies suggest that vitamin D has renoprotective effects. We evaluated the contribution of low 25(OH)D levels on incidence of ESRD using data from the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey-linked Medicare claims files (n = 13,328). We included baseline (1988 through 1994) measurements of 25(OH)D and assessed the incidence of ESRD through July 31, 2001.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>