<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HIV on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/hiv.html</link><description>Recent content in HIV on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/hiv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blacks with HIV were 3.5X more likely to be vitamin D deficient than whites</title><link>/posts/blacks-with-hiv-were-35x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-whites.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-with-hiv-were-35x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-whites.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="risk-factors-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-hiv-infected-patients-in-the-south-central-united-states">Risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in HIV-infected patients in the south central United States.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>AIDS Res Hum Retroviruses. 2012 May;28(5):454-9. Epub 2011 Oct 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Crutchley RD, Gathe J Jr, Mayberry C, Trieu A, Abughosh S, Garey KW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Houston, College of Pharmacy, Department of Clinical Sciences and Administration, 1441 Moursund Street, Houston, TX 77030, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:rdcrutchley@uh.edu">rdcrutchley@uh.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We evaluated the prevalence of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> deficiency and the risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in HIV-infected patients in the South-Central United States. The study consisted of a cross-sectional assessment of vitamin D levels in HIV-infected patients receiving routine clinical care from a private practice in Houston, Texas (latitude 29°N). Vitamin D deficiency was defined as 25(OH)D less than 20?ng/ml (&amp;lt;50?nmol/liter). Two-hundred enrolled patients were surveyed with a vitamin D questionnaire to determine daily supplemental vitamin D intake, dietary vitamin D intake, and average sunlight exposure (minutes/day). Multivariate logistic regression analysis was used to determine significant risk factors for vitamin D deficiency. Median 25(OH)D was 15.5?ng/ml (interquartile range 10.9-24.6) for the total population (n=200).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>