<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cystic Fibrosis on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cystic-fibrosis.html</link><description>Recent content in Cystic Fibrosis on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cystic-fibrosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Might use Vitamin D for cystic fibrosis and topically on skin</title><link>/posts/might-use-vitamin-d-for-cystic-fibrosis-and-topically-on-skin.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/might-use-vitamin-d-for-cystic-fibrosis-and-topically-on-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2011/06/110617185105.htm?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+sciencedaily+%28ScienceDaily%3A+Latest+Science+News%29&amp;amp;utm_content=Google+Reader">(June 18, 2011) &lt;/a>— Laboratory-grown gingival cells treated with vitamin D boosted their production of an endogenous antibiotic, and killed more bacteria than untreated cells, according to a paper in the June 2011 issue of the journal Infection and Immunity. The research suggests that vitamin D can help protect the gums from bacterial infections that lead to gingivitis and periodontitis. Periodontitis affects up to 50 percent of the US population, is a major cause of tooth loss, and can also contribute to heart disease. Most Americans are deficient in vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>People with Cystic Fibrosis should have more than 35 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/people-with-cystic-fibrosis-should-have-more-than-35-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-cystic-fibrosis-should-have-more-than-35-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="appropriate-goal-level-for-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-cystic-fibrosis">Appropriate Goal Level for 25-Hydroxyvitamin D in Cystic Fibrosis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Chest. 2011 Mar 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>West NE, Lechtzin N, Merlo CA, Turowski JB, Davis ME, Ramsay MZ, Watts SL, Stenner SP, Boyle MP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johns Hopkins University, Department of Medicine, Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine. &lt;a href="mailto:nwest5@jhmi.edu">nwest5@jhmi.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D deficiency is common in Cystic Fibrosis (CF), and guidelines recommend 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) levels ?30ng/ml. This threshold was selected because parathyroid hormone (PTH) rises in healthy individuals when 25OHD falls below 30ng/ml. PTH levels &amp;gt;50pg/ml are associated with an increased risk of bone loss. However, the relationship between 25OHD and PTH has not been studied in CF. We sought to determine the appropriate goal 25OHD level in CF by identifying the level below which the risk of PTH &amp;gt;50 begins to increase.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cystic Fibrosis - vitamin D level in blood varies with UV</title><link>/posts/cystic-fibrosis-vitamin-d-level-in-blood-varies-with-uv.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cystic-fibrosis-vitamin-d-level-in-blood-varies-with-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sunlight-is-an-important-determinant-of-vitamin-d-serum-concentrations-in-cystic-fibrosis">Sunlight is an important determinant of vitamin D serum concentrations in cystic fibrosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jan 19. doi:10.1038/ejcn.2010.280&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robberecht E, Vandewalle S, Wehlou C, Kaufman JM, De Schepper J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CF Centre Ghent University Hospital, Ghent, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/sunlight-is-an-important-determinant-of-vitamin-d-.pdf">Download the PDF from Research Gate via VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Objectives:The increase of bone disease in adult cystic fibrosis (CF) patients is partly attributed to inadequate serum concentrations of 25-OH cholecalciferol (25 (OH) D) blamed on fat malabsorption. Based on physiological, clinical and biochemical observations this pathogenesis is debatable. The objective was to ascertain the relative importance of different 25 (OH) D sources.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>