<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dental on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/dental.html</link><description>Recent content in Dental on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/dental/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>More sunshine: more teeth (1862), fewer cavities (1934)</title><link>/posts/more-sunshine-more-teeth-1862-fewer-cavities-1934.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-sunshine-more-teeth-1862-fewer-cavities-1934.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Missing molar and 12X increase in breast cancer – probable vitamin D link</title><link>/posts/missing-molar-and-12x-increase-in-breast-cancer-probable-vitamin-d-link.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/missing-molar-and-12x-increase-in-breast-cancer-probable-vitamin-d-link.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Strontium and vitamin D patented in 2008 for periodontitis, gingivitis</title><link>/posts/strontium-and-vitamin-d-patented-in-2008-for-periodontitis-gingivitis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/strontium-and-vitamin-d-patented-in-2008-for-periodontitis-gingivitis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="wo2008061535httpwwwwipointpatentscopesearchendetailjsfdocidwo2008061535recnum1tabpctclaimsmaxrecofficeprevfiltersortoptionquerystring20-world-patent-office">&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/detail.jsf?docId=WO2008061535&amp;amp;recNum=1&amp;amp;tab=PCTClaims&amp;amp;maxRec=&amp;amp;office=&amp;amp;prevFilter=&amp;amp;sortOption=&amp;amp;queryString=%20">(WO2008061535)&lt;/a> World Patent Office&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="for-periodontitis--gingivitis-does-not-mention-how-much-vitamin-d">For Periodontitis , gingivitis: Does not mention how much Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="any-of-the-following-forms-of-strontium">Any of the following forms of Strontium:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Strontium camphorate, strontium carbonate, strontium chloride, strontium citrate, strontium ethanesulfonate strontium fumarate, strontium gluconate, strontium lactate, strontium malate, strontium maleate, strontium malonate, strontium methanesulfonate, strontium nitrate, strontium oxalate, strontium phosphate, &lt;span style="color:#F33;">strontium ranelate (patented)&lt;/span>, strontium silicate, strontium succinate, strontium sulphate and strontium tartrate.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor00flots-span-of-strontium-not-just-a-trace">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Lots &lt;/span>&lt;/strong> of strontium (not just a trace)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>“Therefore the weight ratio of strontium to calcium should not be less than 1 .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Might use Vitamin D for cystic fibrosis and topically on skin</title><link>/posts/might-use-vitamin-d-for-cystic-fibrosis-and-topically-on-skin.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/might-use-vitamin-d-for-cystic-fibrosis-and-topically-on-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2011/06/110617185105.htm?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+sciencedaily+%28ScienceDaily%3A+Latest+Science+News%29&amp;amp;utm_content=Google+Reader">(June 18, 2011) &lt;/a>— Laboratory-grown gingival cells treated with vitamin D boosted their production of an endogenous antibiotic, and killed more bacteria than untreated cells, according to a paper in the June 2011 issue of the journal Infection and Immunity. The research suggests that vitamin D can help protect the gums from bacterial infections that lead to gingivitis and periodontitis. Periodontitis affects up to 50 percent of the US population, is a major cause of tooth loss, and can also contribute to heart disease. Most Americans are deficient in vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin Deficiency Underlies Tooth Decay – 2009 and 1931</title><link>/posts/vitamin-deficiency-underlies-tooth-decay-2009-and-1931.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-deficiency-underlies-tooth-decay-2009-and-1931.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>800 IU vitamin D helped periodontal surgery</title><link>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-helped-periodontal-surgery.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-helped-periodontal-surgery.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-impact-of-vitamin-d-status-on-periodontal-surgery-outcomes">The Impact of Vitamin D Status on Periodontal Surgery Outcomes.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Dent Res. 2011 May 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bashutski JD, Eber RM, Kinney JS, Benavides E, Maitra S, Braun TM, Giannobile WV, McCauley LK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D regulates calcium and immune function. While vitamin D deficiency has been associated with periodontitis, little information exists regarding its effect on wound healing and periodontal surgery outcomes. This longitudinal clinical trial assessed outcomes of periodontal surgery and teriparatide administration in vitamin-D-sufficient and -insufficient individuals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB and Vitamin D might decrease dental caries better than fluoride</title><link>/posts/uvb-and-vitamin-d-might-decrease-dental-caries-better-than-fluoride.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-and-vitamin-d-might-decrease-dental-caries-better-than-fluoride.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-review-of-the-role-of-solar-ultraviolet-b-irradiance-and-vitamin-d-in-reducing-risk-of-dental-caries">A review of the role of solar ultraviolet-B irradiance and vitamin D in reducing risk of dental caries&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dermato Endrocrenology Volume 3, Issue 3 July/August/September 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Large geographical variations in dental health and tooth loss among U.S. adolescents and young adults have been reported since the mid-1800s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Studies in the 1920s and 1930s noted that vitamin D and ultraviolet-B (UVB) irradiance reduced caries formation, the proposed mechanism being improved calcium absorption and metabolism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Periodontal disease is related to vitamin D – 2010</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-periodontal-disease-is-related-to-vitamin-d-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-periodontal-disease-is-related-to-vitamin-d-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="are-hills-criteria-for-causality-satisfied-for-vitamin-d-and-periodontal-disease">Are Hill&amp;rsquo;s criteria for causality satisfied for vitamin D and periodontal disease?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2010 Jan–Mar; 2(1): 30–36. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4161/derm.2.1.12488.">doi: 10.4161/derm.2.1.12488.&lt;/a> PMCID: PMC3084963&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B Grant 1 &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a> and Barbara J Boucher 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Sunlight, Nutrition; and Health Research Center (SUNARC); San Francisco, CA USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Centre for Diabetes; Bart&amp;rsquo;s and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry; Queen Mary University of London; Blizard Institute of Cell and Molecular Science; London, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is mounting evidence that periodontal disease (PD) is linked to low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations in addition to recognized risk factors like diet and smoking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dental and breast cancer might be linked by Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dental-and-breast-cancer-might-be-linked-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dental-and-breast-cancer-might-be-linked-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="unfortunately-no-abstact-this-side-of-a-paywall">Unfortunately no abstact this side of a paywall&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-status-likely-contributes-to-the-link-between-periodontal-disease-and-breast-cancer">Low vitamin D status likely contributes to the link between periodontal disease and breast cancer.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2011 Mar 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grant WB, Boucher BJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center (SUNARC), P.O. Box 641603, San Francisco, CA, 94164-1603, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMID: 21437609&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pregnant women 2X more dental problems when vitamin D less than 30ng</title><link>/posts/pregnant-women-2x-more-dental-problems-when-vitamin-d-less-than-30ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnant-women-2x-more-dental-problems-when-vitamin-d-less-than-30ng.html</guid><description>&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code class="language-!Vitamin" data-lang="!Vitamin">
J Periodontol. 2011 Feb;82(2):195-200. Epub 2010 Sep 1.

Boggess KA, Espinola JA, Moss K, Beck J, Offenbacher S, Camargo CA Jr.

Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC.

Background: Maternal periodontal disease is found in ?40% of pregnant women and is associated with adverse pregnancy outcomes. 

Vitamin D deficiency may play a role in periodontal disease and tooth loss, and insufficient vitamin D status is common among pregnant women. 

The objective of this study is to examine the relationship between maternal vitamin D status and periodontal disease. 

Methods: A case-control study was conducted. Cases were defined as pregnant women with clinical moderate to severe periodontal disease; controls were pregnant women who were periodontally healthy. Maternal data were chart abstracted and serum was collected between 14 and 26 weeks of gestation. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;[OH]&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;D) levels were measured using liquid chromatography?tandem mass spectrometry. Median serum 25(OH)D levels and prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency (defined as &amp;lt;75 nmol/l) were compared between cases and controls. The odds ratio and 95% confidence interval for moderate to severe periodontal disease among women with vitamin D insufficiency was calculated using multivariable logistic regression, adjusting for maternal race, season of blood draw, and other potential confounders. 

Results: A total of 117 cases were compared to 118 controls. 

Cases had lower median 25(OH)D levels than controls (59 versus 100 nmol/l; P &amp;lt;0.001) and were more likely to have vitamin D insufficiency (65% versus 29%; P &amp;lt;0.001). 

The adjusted odds ratio (95% confidence interval) for moderate to severe periodontal disease among women with vitamin D insufficiency was **2.1** (0.99 to 4.5). 

Conclusions: Vitamin D insufficiency (serum 25&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;[OH]&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;D &amp;lt;75 nmol/l) is associated with maternal periodontal disease during pregnancy. Vitamin D

---

#### See also VitaminDWiki

* &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;/posts/pregnant-women-low-on-vitamin-d-had-2x-more-periodontal-disease&amp;#34; style=&amp;#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;This link has an unknown page_id: 932&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Pregnant women low on vitamin D had 2X more periodontal disease&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; with 2000 IU in Hollis slides #27, #29
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Even 1000 IU vitamin D reduced periodontitis</title><link>/posts/even-1000-iu-vitamin-d-reduced-periodontitis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/even-1000-iu-vitamin-d-reduced-periodontitis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and minimum cereal minimized tooth decay – in 1932</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-minimum-cereal-minimized-tooth-decay-in-1932.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-minimum-cereal-minimized-tooth-decay-in-1932.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dr-mellanbys-tooth-decay-reversal-diet---from-ethiopian-review">Dr. Mellanby’s Tooth Decay Reversal Diet - from Ethiopian Review&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ethiopianreview.com/health/201002/?p=146829">http://www.ethiopianreview.com/health/201002/?p=146829&lt;/a> December 11th, 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a lot of admiration for Drs. Edward and May Mellanby. A husband-and-wife team, **** they discovered vitamin D, and determined that rickets is caused by poor calcium (or phosphorus) status, typically due to vitamin D deficiency. They believed that an ideal diet is omnivorous, based on whole foods, and offers an adequate supply of fat-soluble vitamins and easily absorbed minerals. They also felt that grain intake should be modest, as their research showed that unsoaked whole grains antagonize the effect of vitamins D and A.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>