<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dental on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/dental.html</link><description>Recent content in Dental on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/dental/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dental implant failure 4 times more likely if low vitamin D (not statistically significant)</title><link>/posts/dental-implant-failure-4-times-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-not-statistically-significant.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dental-implant-failure-4-times-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-not-statistically-significant.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Periodontal disease 1.5 times more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/periodontal-disease-15-times-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/periodontal-disease-15-times-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chronic Periodontitis 9.6 times more likely if smoke and have poor Vitamin D Receptor</title><link>/posts/chronic-periodontitis-96-times-more-likely-if-smoke-and-have-poor-vitamin-d-receptor.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-periodontitis-96-times-more-likely-if-smoke-and-have-poor-vitamin-d-receptor.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dental caries associated with poor Vitamin D receptor – 2016</title><link>/posts/dental-caries-associated-with-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-2016.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dental-caries-associated-with-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-2016.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dental implants more successful if higher level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dental-implants-more-successful-if-higher-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dental-implants-more-successful-if-higher-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wisdom tooth (3rd molar) extraction helped by Vitamin D loading dose – RCT</title><link>/posts/wisdom-tooth-3rd-molar-extraction-helped-by-vitamin-d-loading-dose-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wisdom-tooth-3rd-molar-extraction-helped-by-vitamin-d-loading-dose-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="does-vitamin-d3-have-an-impact-on-clinical-and-biochemical-parameters-related-to-third-molar-surgery">Does Vitamin D3 Have an Impact on Clinical and Biochemical Parameters Related to Third Molar Surgery.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Craniofac Surg. 2016 Mar;27(2):469-76. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/SCS.0000000000002389.">doi: 10.1097/SCS.0000000000002389.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oteri G1, Cicciù M, Peditto M, Catalano A, Loddo S, Pisano M, Lasco A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1*Department of Experimental Medical-Surgical Sciences and Dentistry †Department of Odontostomatology, School of Dentistry ‡Department of Clinical and Experimental Medicine, University of Messina, Messina, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this study was to evaluate the clinical effect on the biochemical inflammatory markers of a single oral high dose of cholecalciferol in vitamin D-deficient patients undergoing the surgical removal of lower third molars. A randomized, split-mouth, single-blind study was conducted on 25 vitamin D-deficient patients ranging between 18 and 40 years of age requiring lower third molars extraction and referred at the Oral Surgery Unit of the School of Dentistry of the University of Messina. All patients, with vitamin D3 blood levels ?30?ng/mL, underwent bilateral surgical removal. The first extraction (control group) being conducted with the administration of a placebo, the second one (test group) being conducted with the preliminary administration of &lt;strong>300,000 IU&lt;/strong> of cholecalciferol 4 days before the procedure. At each surgery, clinical indexes, such as pain, edema and any functional limitation have been recorded. Clinical and biochemical parameters were registered 4 days before, immediately after, 3 and 7 days after the surgical procedure. The data obtained were processed using paired t-test. The clinical outcome parameters showed a slight to moderate improvement between the control and the vitamin-D treatment group, with statistical significance being obtained regarding the &lt;strong>edema&lt;/strong> at defined time points. Interleukin-1-beta, interleukin-6, and tumor necrosis factor-alpha values were significantly lower (P?&amp;lt;?0.01) for the test group after the surgery. The increase of vitamin D serum levels showed an impact on the outcome of the third molar surgery, eliciting a &lt;strong>reduced inflammatory response and leading to a more favorable clinical course.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes associated with low vitamin D also associated with childhood tooth decay</title><link>/posts/genes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-also-associated-with-childhood-tooth-decay.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-also-associated-with-childhood-tooth-decay.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="re-examining-the-association-between-vitamin-d-and-childhood-caries">Re-Examining the Association between Vitamin D and Childhood Caries&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLOS ONE December 21, 2015DOI: 10.1371/journal.pone.0143769&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tom Dudding, Steve J. Thomas, Karen Duncan, Debbie A. Lawlor, Nicholas J. Timpson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Previous studies have reported an inverse association between vitamin D and childhood dental caries, but whether this is causal is unclear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective:To determine the causal effect of circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration on dental caries experience, early caries onset and the requirement for a dental general anesthetic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dental Caries risk in children cut in half if more than 20 nanogram of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dental-caries-risk-in-children-cut-in-half-if-more-than-20-nanogram-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dental-caries-risk-in-children-cut-in-half-if-more-than-20-nanogram-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-dental-caries-in-children">Vitamin D and Dental Caries in Children.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Dent Res. 2015 Nov 9. pii: 0022034515616335. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schroth RJ1, Rabbani R2, Loewen G3, Moffatt ME4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 The University of Manitoba, Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada The Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Research Institute of Manitoba, Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada &lt;a href="mailto:umschrot@cc.umanitoba.ca">umschrot@cc.umanitoba.ca&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 The University of Manitoba, Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada George Fay Yee Centre for Healthcare Innovation, Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 The University of Manitoba, Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dental implants 10 percent better with topical vitamin D (in dogs)</title><link>/posts/dental-implants-10-percent-better-with-topical-vitamin-d-in-dogs.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dental-implants-10-percent-better-with-topical-vitamin-d-in-dogs.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="topical-applications-of-vitamin-d-on-implant-surface-for-bone-to-implant-contact-enhance-a-pilot-study-in-dogs-part-ii">Topical applications of vitamin D on implant surface for bone-to-implant contact enhance: a pilot study in dogs part II.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Oral Implants Res. 2015 Sep 30. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.12707">doi: 10.1111/clr.12707&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Salomó-Coll O1, Maté-Sánchez de Val JE2, Ramírez-Fernandez MP2, Hernández-Alfaro F1, Gargallo-Albiol J1, Calvo-Guirado JL2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery, International University of Catalonia, Barcelona, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2International Dentistry Research Cathedra, Universidad Católica San Antonio de Murcia (UCAM), Murcia, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study was to evaluate the effect of topical application of vitamin D over implant surface, placed immediately to the extraction, throughout histological and histomorphometric analysis of peri-implant tissue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Teeth enamel problems (MIH) 11 percent less likely with just 4 ng more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/teeth-enamel-problems-mih-11-percent-less-likely-with-just-4-ng-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/teeth-enamel-problems-mih-11-percent-less-likely-with-just-4-ng-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="elevated-serum-25oh-vitamin-d-levels-are-negatively-correlated-with-molar-incisor-hypomineralization">Elevated Serum 25(OH)-Vitamin D Levels Are Negatively Correlated with Molar-Incisor Hypomineralization.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Dent Res. 2014 Dec 10. pii: 0022034514561657. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kühnisch J1, Thiering E2, Kratzsch J3, Heinrich-Weltzien R4, Hickel R5, Heinrich J6; for the GINIplus study group; the LISAplus study group; for the GINIplus study group. Collaborators (49)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Conservative Dentistry and Periodontology, School of Dentistry, Ludwig-Maximilians-University of Munich, Munich, Germany &lt;a href="mailto:jkuehn@dent.med.uni-muenchen.de">jkuehn@dent.med.uni-muenchen.de&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Institute of Epidemiology I, Helmholtz Zentrum Munich, German Research Centre for Environmental Health, Neuherberg, Germany Dr. von Hauner Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Ludwig-Maximilians-University Munich, Munich, Germany.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poor oral health for young women with low Ca and low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/poor-oral-health-for-young-women-with-low-ca-and-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poor-oral-health-for-young-women-with-low-ca-and-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="oral-health-in-young-women-having-a-low-calcium-and-vitamin-d-nutritional-status">Oral health in young women having a low calcium and vitamin D nutritional status.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Clin Oral Investig. 2014 Oct 31. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antonenko O1, Bryk G, Brito G, Pellegrini G, Zeni SN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Metabolic Bone Diseases Laboratory, Clinical Hospital, Immunology, Genetic and Metabolism Institute (INIGEM), National Council for Scientific and Technologic Research (CONICET), Buenos Aires University (UBA), Av. Córdoba 2351-8vo Piso, 1120, Buenos Aires, Argentina, &lt;a href="mailto:olgaaliona@yahoo.com.ar">olgaaliona@yahoo.com.ar&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oral health plays an important role in an individual&amp;rsquo;s eating choices, which in turn ensure good nutrition throughout life. The deterioration in diet quality may partially explain the association between tooth loss and several systemic diseases, including osteoporosis. The study evaluated the association between oral health and calcium (Ca) and vitamin D nutritional status. The effect of several dietary and lifestyle habits was also evaluated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tooth loss reduction by 15 percent associated with 10 ng higher vitamin D</title><link>/posts/tooth-loss-reduction-by-15-percent-associated-with-10-ng-higher-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tooth-loss-reduction-by-15-percent-associated-with-10-ng-higher-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="prospective-study-of-serum-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-and-tooth-loss">Prospective Study of Serum 25-hydroxy Vitamin D and Tooth Loss.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Dent Res. 2014 May 14. pii: 0022034514534985. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhan Y1, Samietz S2, Holtfreter B1, Hannemann A3, Meisel P1, Nauck M3, Völzke H4, Wallaschofski H3, Dietrich T5, Kocher T6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Unit of Periodontology, University Medicine, Ernst-Moritz-Arndt University Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Prosthetic Dentistry, Gerodontology, and Biomaterials, Center of Oral Health, University Medicine, Ernst-Moritz-Arndt University Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X fewer infant dental caries if good level of vitamin D while pregnant</title><link>/posts/3x-fewer-infant-dental-caries-if-good-level-of-vitamin-d-while-pregnant.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-fewer-infant-dental-caries-if-good-level-of-vitamin-d-while-pregnant.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dental-carries-35-x-more-likely-if--20-ng-in-3rd-trimester---feb-2022">Dental Carries 3.5 X more likely if &amp;lt; 20 ng in 3rd trimester - Feb 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="dental-carries-35-x-more-likely-if--20-ng-in-3rd-trimester---feb-2022">Dental Carries 3.5 X more likely if &amp;lt; 20 ng in 3rd trimester - Feb 2022&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dental Consequences of Vitamin D Deficiency during Pregnancy and Early Infancy—An Observational Study&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/dental-carries-with-low-d-during-gestation.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Severe tooth decay in children unless supplemented with Vitamin D drops</title><link>/posts/severe-tooth-decay-in-children-unless-supplemented-with-vitamin-d-drops.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/severe-tooth-decay-in-children-unless-supplemented-with-vitamin-d-drops.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-of-children-with-severe-early-childhood-cariesa-case--control-study">Vitamin D status of children with severe early childhood caries:a case&amp;ndash;control study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>BMC Pediatrics 2013, 13:174 doi:10.1186/1471-2431-13-174&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robert J Schroth, Jeremy A Levi, Elizabeth A Sellers, James Friel, Eleonore Kliewer and Michael EK Moffatt&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 25 October 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Severe Early Childhood Caries (S-ECC) affects the health and well-being of young children. There is limited research in this area, though evidence suggests that children with S-ECC are at an increased risk of malnutrition. The purpose of this study was to determine the association between vitamin D (25(OH)D) levels and S-ECC.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gingivitis inflammation (retracted)</title><link>/posts/gingivitis-inflammation-retracted.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gingivitis-inflammation-retracted.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="anti-inflammatory-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-gingivitis-a-dose-response-randomised-controlled-trial">Anti-inflammatory effect of vitamin D on gingivitis: a dose response randomised controlled trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Indian J Public Health. 2013 Jan-Mar;57(1):29-32. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4103/0019-557X.111365.">doi: 10.4103/0019-557X.111365.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hiremath VP, Rao CB, Naiak V, Prasad KV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Public Health Dentistry, Maratha Mandal Dental College, Belgaum, India. &lt;a href="mailto:Vishbu123@hotmail.com">Vishbu123@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a randomized controlled trial, a daily Oral Vitamin D supplementation was given in dose of 2000 IU for Group A, 1000 IU for Group B , 500 IU for Group C and placebo for Group D over 3 months period to assess the anti-inflammatory effect of vitamin D on gingivitis at various doses. The changes in gingival scores were measured at the period of 1 st , 2 nd and 3 rd month. Gingivitis score changed in direct proportion to the dose of vitamin D supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dental health improved with more than 800 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dental-health-improved-with-more-than-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dental-health-improved-with-more-than-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-and-periodontal-health-in-older-men">Vitamin D and Periodontal Health in Older Men&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Journal of Dental Research June 20, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E.N. Alshouibi1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E.K. Kaye2,3, &lt;a href="mailto:kralle@bu.edu">kralle@bu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>H.J. Cabral4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C.W. Leone5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R.I. Garcia2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Preventive Sciences, King Abdulaziz University Faculty of Dentistry, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Health Policy &amp;amp; Health Services Research, Boston University Henry M. Goldman School of Dental Medicine, Boston, MA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3VA Boston Healthcare System, Boston, MA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4Department of Biostatistics, Boston University School of Public Health, Boston, MA, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tooth decay and bleeding gums associated with low vitamin D in postmenopausal women</title><link>/posts/tooth-decay-and-bleeding-gums-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-postmenopausal-women.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tooth-decay-and-bleeding-gums-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-postmenopausal-women.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-and-periodontal-disease-in-postmenopausal-women">Plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D Concentrations and Periodontal Disease in Postmenopausal Women.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Periodontol. 2012 Dec 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Millen AE, Hovey KM, Lamonte MJ, Swanson M, Andrews CA, Kluczynski MA, Genco RJ, Wactawski-Wende J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Social and Preventive Medicine, School of Public Health and Health Professions, University at Buffalo, The State University of New York, Buffalo, NY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D has anti-inflammatory and anti-microbial properties that, together with its influence on bone health, may confer periodontal benefit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB added in classroom reduced cavities, increased height, increased academics. etc</title><link>/posts/uvb-added-in-classroom-reduced-cavities-increased-height-increased-academics-etc.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-added-in-classroom-reduced-cavities-increased-height-increased-academics-etc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Periodontal Disease – continuing education</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-periodontal-disease-continuing-education.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-periodontal-disease-continuing-education.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-review-of-vitamin-d-as-it-relates-to-periodontal-disease">A Review of Vitamin D as It Relates to Periodontal Disease&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Suellan Go Yao, DMD; Clinical Instructor, Columbia University College of Dental Medicine, Department of Periodontics, New York, New York; Private Practice; New York, New York&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>James Burke Fine, DMD; Associate Dean for Postdoctoral Education, Professor of Clinical Dentistry and Postdoctoral Director of the Division of Periodontics, Attending Dental Surgeon, Presbyterian Hospital Dental Service; New York, New York; Private Practice limited to Periodontics; Hoboken, New Jersey; faculty practice, Columbia University&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poor kidneys result in lower vitamin D level result in 7X more tooth loss</title><link>/posts/poor-kidneys-result-in-lower-vitamin-d-level-result-in-7x-more-tooth-loss.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poor-kidneys-result-in-lower-vitamin-d-level-result-in-7x-more-tooth-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="association-between-low-renal-function-and-tooth-loss-over-5-years">Association between low renal function and tooth loss over 5 years.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Gerodontology. 2012 Nov 26. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/ger.12015.">doi: 10.1111/ger.12015.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yoshihara A, Iwasaki M, Miyazaki H, Nakamura K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Oral Health and Welfare, Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences, Niigata University, Niigata, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This longitudinal study evaluated the relationship between low renal function and tooth loss in elderly subjects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MATERIAL AND METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Subjects comprised 406 female subjects (55-74 years old) who agreed to participate in a baseline examination and a follow-up examination after 5 years. Serum cystatin C levels were used to assess renal function. Multiple logistic regression analysis was used to evaluate the relationship between tooth loss and change in serum cystatin C levels over 5 years. Tooth loss over 5 years (0: no, 1: yes) was used as the dependent variable. Seven variables were used as independent variables, including change in serum cystatin C levels over 5 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dental caries cut in half by vitamin D, review of 24 old clinical trials</title><link>/posts/dental-caries-cut-in-half-by-vitamin-d-review-of-24-old-clinical-trials.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dental-caries-cut-in-half-by-vitamin-d-review-of-24-old-clinical-trials.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-dental-caries-in-controlled-clinical-trials-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D and dental caries in controlled clinical trials: systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrition Reviews Dec 2012, DOI: 10.1111/j.1753-4887.2012.00544.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Philippe P Hujoel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Oral Health Sciences, School of Dentistry, Department of Epidemiology, School of Public Health, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>PP Hujoel, Oral Health Sciences, Box 357475, School of Dentistry, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington 98195-7475, USA. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:hujoel@uw.edu">hujoel@uw.edu&lt;/a>, Phone: +1-206-543-2034,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="relative-rate-of-dental-caries-associated-with-vitamin-d-supplementation">Relative rate of dental caries associated with vitamin D supplementation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Half as many caries if supplement with vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB and vitamin D decrease dental problems</title><link>/posts/uvb-and-vitamin-d-decrease-dental-problems.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-and-vitamin-d-decrease-dental-problems.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Children with severe caries were 2X more likely to have inadequate vitamin D</title><link>/posts/children-with-severe-caries-were-2x-more-likely-to-have-inadequate-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-with-severe-caries-were-2x-more-likely-to-have-inadequate-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>