<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Middle East on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/middle-east.html</link><description>Recent content in Middle East on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/middle-east/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Diabetes in Saudi women improved with just 2,000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetes-in-saudi-women-improved-with-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-in-saudi-women-improved-with-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-as-an-adjuvant-therapy-for-patients-with-t2dm-an-18-month-prospective-interventional-study">Vitamin D supplementation as an adjuvant therapy for patients with T2DM: an 18-month prospective interventional study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nasser M Al-Daghri, Khalid M Alkharfy, Abdulaziz Al-Othman, Emad El-Kholie, Osama Moharram, Majed S Alokail, Yousef Al-Saleh, Shaun Sabico, Sudhesh Kumar and George Chrousos&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular Diabetology 2012, 11:85 doi:10.1186/1475-2840-11-85; Published: 18 July 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with impaired human insulin action, suggesting a role in the pathogenesis of diabetes mellitus type 2 (T2DM). In this prospective interventional study we investigated the effects of vitamin D3 supplementation on the metabolic profiles of Saudi T2DM subjects pre- and post-vitamin D supplementation over an 18-month period.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic dermatitis dramatically reduced in Iran with 1600 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-dramatically-reduced-in-iran-with-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-dramatically-reduced-in-iran-with-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-the-treatment-of-atopic-dermatitis-a-clinical-trial-study">Vitamin D supplementation in the treatment of atopic dermatitis: a clinical trial study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Amestejani M, Salehi BS, Vasigh M, Sobhkhiz A, Karami M, Alinia H, Kamrava SK, Shamspour J Drugs Dermatol. 2012 Mar;11(3):327-30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N, Ghalehbaghi B, Behzadi AH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Orumieh University of Medical Science, Orumieh, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of vitamin D in Atopic Dermatitis (AD) is ambiguous and clinical trials are needed to assess the role of vitamin D in the treatment of AD. The aim of this clinical trial study to evaluate the effect of vitamin D supplementation on patients with AD.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>