<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cognitive on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cognitive.html</link><description>Recent content in Cognitive on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cognitive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Concussions (traumatic brain injury) getting big press coverage, vitamin D might be both a cause and a solution</title><link>/posts/concussions-traumatic-brain-injury-getting-big-press-coverage-vitamin-d-might-be--and-a-solution.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/concussions-traumatic-brain-injury-getting-big-press-coverage-vitamin-d-might-be--and-a-solution.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="reasons-to-associate-concussion-with-low-vitamind">Reasons to associate concussion with low vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Those people having concussions have lower vitamin D levels&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Increase in the number of concussions as vitamin D levels have dropped&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Giving vitamin D (and other supplements) shortens recovery time from concussions&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Giving vitamin D resulted in fewer concussions (football players)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="researchers-tie-gulf-war-illness-to-brain-damagehttpmusatodaycomarticlenewsnation1982817preferredarticleviewmodesingle-usa-today-march2013">&lt;a href="http://m.usatoday.com/article/news/nation/1982817?preferredArticleViewMode=single">Researchers tie Gulf War illness to brain damage&lt;/a> USA Today March 2013&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Using fMRI machines, the Georgetown University researchers could see anomalies in the bundle of nerve fibers that interpret pain signals in the brain in 31 Gulf War veterans. The research will be published Wednesday in PLOS ONE journal.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>CAUTION: The FMRI magnetic fields MAY substantially reduce the vitamin D levels - &lt;a href="/posts/update" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 4093">Update May 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Link between diabetes and Alzheimers is probably low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/link-between-diabetes-and-alzheimers-is-probably-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/link-between-diabetes-and-alzheimers-is-probably-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.whec.com/news/stories/S2291815.shtml?cat=566">Study: Adults with diabetes more prone to dementia&lt;/a> Sept 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For 11 years, Japanese researchers followed more than 1,000 people, ages 60 and older.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They found that those with diabetes at the outset were 35 percent more likely to develop Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Those with the most severe diabetes had more than triple the risk.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deficiency-of-vitamin-dcategoriesdeficiency-of-vitamin-d-has-the-following-graph">&lt;a href="/categories/deficiency-of-vitamin-d">Deficiency of Vitamin D&lt;/a> has the following graph&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h2 id="diabetes-is-in-a-vicious-circle-with-vitamin-d">Diabetes is in a vicious circle with vitamin D.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="low-vitamin-d-increases-diabetes-and-diabetes-decreased-vitamin-d-even-more">Low vitamin D increases diabetes, and diabetes decreased vitamin D even more.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-spirals-lower-and-lower">Vitamin D spirals lower and lower&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpostsoverview-cognition-and-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-584overview-cognition-and-vitamin-da">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-cognition-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 584">Overview Cognition and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cognitive decline, dementia, and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Disease are all associated with low vitamin D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Risk of Cognitive Decline in Elderly Persons</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-risk-of-cognitive-decline-in-elderly-persons.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-risk-of-cognitive-decline-in-elderly-persons.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Obstetrical &amp;amp; Gynecological Survey:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>June 2011 - Volume 66 - Issue 6 - pp 354-355&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/OGX.0b013e31822c1957">doi: 10.1097/OGX.0b013e31822c1957&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gynecology: Menopause&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Llewellyn, David J.; Lang, Iain A.; Langa, Kenneth M.; Muniz-Terrera, Graciela; Phillips, Caroline L.; Cherubini, Antonio; Ferrucci, Luigi; Melzer, David&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The findings of a report published in 2007 suggested that over 40% of older, community-living adults in the United States and Europe were vitamin D deficient. There is clinical evidence for a relationship between low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels and cognitive dysfunction with aging. Although data in several small clinical studies showing such an association were equivocal, 3 of 4 large population-based cross-sectional studies reported a relationship between levels of serum 25(OH)D and cognitive dysfunction in the elderly. No prior prospective population-based studies have investigated the possible association between vitamin D status and incident dementia or cognitive decline.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Risk of cognitive decline 50 percent higher if low amount of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/risk-of-cognitive-decline-50-percent-higher-if-low-amount-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/risk-of-cognitive-decline-50-percent-higher-if-low-amount-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-cognitive-dysfunction-and-dementia-in-older-adults">Vitamin d, cognitive dysfunction and dementia in older adults.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>CNS Drugs. 2011 Aug 1;25(8):629-39. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2165/11593080-000000000-00000.">doi: 10.2165/11593080-000000000-00000.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dickens AP, Lang IA, Langa KM, Kos K, Llewellyn DJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peninsula Collaboration for Leadership in Applied Health Research and Care, Peninsula College of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The physiologically active form of vitamin D, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3), is a fat-soluble steroid hormone with a well established role in skeletal health. A growing body of evidence suggests low vitamin D levels also play a role in the pathogenesis of a wide range of non-skeletal, age-associated diseases including cancer, heart disease, type 2 diabetes mellitus and stroke. Low levels of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>, a stable marker of vitamin D status, are also associated with increased odds of prevalent cognitive dysfunction, Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease and all-cause dementia in a number of studies, raising the possibility that vitamin D plays a role in the aetiology of cognitive dysfunction and dementia. To date, the majority of human studies reporting associations between vitamin D and cognition or dementia have been cross-sectional or case-control designs that do not permit us to exclude the possibility that such associations are a result of disease progression rather than being causal. Animal and in vitro experiments have identified a number of neuroprotective mechanisms that might link vitamin D status to cognitive dysfunction and dementia, including vasoprotection and amyloid phagocytosis and clearance, but the clinical relevance of these mechanisms in humans is not currently clear. Two recent, large, prospective studies go some way to establish the temporal relationship with cognitive decline.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5X fewer hip fractures from Parkinson – Alzheimer – Stroke with enough sun</title><link>/posts/5x-fewer-hip-fractures-from-parkinson-alzheimer-stroke-with-enough-sun.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5x-fewer-hip-fractures-from-parkinson-alzheimer-stroke-with-enough-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sunlight-exposure-is-important-for-preventing-hip-fractures-in-patients-with-alzheimers-disease-parkinsons-disease-or-stroke">Sunlight exposure is important for preventing hip fractures in patients with Alzheimer’s disease, Parkinson’s disease, or stroke&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Neurologica Scandinavica, Article first published online: 18 JUN 2011; DOI: 10.1111/j.1600-0404.2011.01555.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. Iwamoto, T. Takeda, H. Matsumoto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives?–? Hypovitaminosis D as a result of malnutrition or sunlight deprivation, increased bone resorption, low bone mineral density (BMD), or an increased risk of falls may contribute to an increased risk of hip fractures in patients with neurological diseases, including Alzheimer’s disease, Parkinson’s disease, and stroke. The purpose of this study was to clarify the efficacy of sunlight exposure for reducing the risk of hip fractures in patients with such neurological diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D might might reduce dementia</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-might-might-reduce-dementia.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-might-might-reduce-dementia.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-value-of-physiologic-vitamin-d-as-a-biomarker-of-dementia">The value of physiologic vitamin D as a biomarker of dementia.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Drugs Today (Barc). 2011 Mar;47(3):223-31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Buell JS, Tucker KL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harvard Clinical Research Institute, Boston, Massachusetts, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:kl.tucker@neu.edu">kl.tucker@neu.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has been investigated in association with cognitive function in healthy and multimorbid elderly patients. Whether higher physiologic concentrations of vitamin D may be neuroprotective is not yet known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiological investigations have suggested a protective effect of physiologic vitamin D concentrations (circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D) on neurocognitive dysfunction and cerebrovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis -10 percent increased schizophrenia in winter births due to vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-10-percent-increased-schizophrenia-in-winter-births-due-to-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-10-percent-increased-schizophrenia-in-winter-births-due-to-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="season-of-birth-in-schizophrenia-a-maternal-fetal-chronobiological-hypothesis">Season of birth in schizophrenia: A maternal-fetal chronobiological hypothesis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Med Hypotheses. 2011 Mar 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schwartz PJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Psychiatry, Wright State University, Boonshoft School of Medicine, Dayton, OH, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being born in the winter and spring significantly increases one&amp;rsquo;s risk for developing schizophrenia. This birth seasonality may account for as many as 10% of all cases of schizophrenia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maternal third trimester infections or vitamin D deficiencies are hypothesized to be the most likely cause and can account for many of the important features of schizophrenia, although each hypothesis has limitations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mental Illness and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mental-illness-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mental-illness-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-role-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-mental-illness---mercola-dec-2024">The Role of Vitamin D Deficiency in Mental Illness - Mercola Dec 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-vitamin-d-when-indoors-most-of-the-time---fromvitamindwiki">Low vitamin D when indoors most of the time - from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsoweb">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#fact-1-smoking-decreases-vitamind">Fact 1 Smoking decreases vitamin D.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#fact-2-low-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-mentalillness">Fact 2 Low vitamin D is associated with mental illness&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#update-some-mental-hospitals-are-no-longer-encouraging-smoking-bypatients">Update: Some mental hospitals are no longer encouraging smoking by patients&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sesame-street-mental-disorders--2018httpswwwpinterestcompin7107311886643729">&lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/7107311886643729/">Sesame Street Mental Disorders - 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-role-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-mental-illness---mercola-dec-2024">The Role of Vitamin D Deficiency in Mental Illness - Mercola Dec 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2024/12/23/vitamin-d-deficiency-mental-illness.aspx?ui=d738e3df52a8a14aea9298fe6ec5bc113ed0d6d7922f31861727d54a43cbe29d&amp;amp;sd=20121119&amp;amp;cid_source=dnl&amp;amp;cid_medium=email&amp;amp;cid_content=art1HL&amp;amp;cid=20241223Z1_NB&amp;amp;foDate=false&amp;amp;mid=DM1673328&amp;amp;rid=190128122">2 videos&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poorer teen cognition due to lower vitamin D or race</title><link>/posts/poorer-teen-cognition-due-to-lower-vitamin-d-or-race.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poorer-teen-cognition-due-to-lower-vitamin-d-or-race.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Elderly with more than 257 IU vitamin D daily had less cognitive impairment</title><link>/posts/elderly-with-more-than-257-iu-vitamin-d-daily-had-less-cognitive-impairment.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/elderly-with-more-than-257-iu-vitamin-d-daily-had-less-cognitive-impairment.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dietary-intake-of-vitamin-d-and-cognition-in-older-women-a-large-population-based-study">Dietary intake of vitamin D and cognition in older women: A large population-based study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>by: C. Annweiler, A. M. Schott, Y. Rolland, H. Blain, F. R. Herrmann, O. Beauchet&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neurology, Vol. 75, No. 20. (16 November 2010), pp. 1810-1816.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Serum vitamin D concentrations are associated with global cognitive function among older adults. The benefits of vitamin D intake to treat or prevent cognitive impairment remain unknown. The objective of this cross-sectional study was to determine whether weekly dietary intake of vitamin D could be associated with global cognitive performance among older adults.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schizophrenia and vitamin D have latitude-related genes</title><link>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-related-genes-could-have-been-subject-to-latitude-driven-adaptation">Schizophrenia and Vitamin D Related Genes Could Have Been Subject to Latitude-driven Adaptation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Roberto Amato email, Michele Pinelli email, Antonella Monticelli email, Gennaro Miele email and Sergio Cocozza email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Evolutionary Biology 2010, 10:351doi:10.1186/1471-2148-10-351; Published: 	11 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many natural phenomena are directly or indirectly related to latitude. Living at different latitudes, indeed, has its consequences with being exposed to different climates, diets, light/dark cycles, etc. In humans, one of the best known examples of genetic traits following a latitudinal gradient is skin pigmentation. Nevertheless, also several diseases show latitudinal clinals such as hypertension, cancer, dismetabolic conditions, schizophrenia, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease and many more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cognitive impairment 4X more likely when vitamin D less than 10 ng</title><link>/posts/cognitive-impairment-4x-more-likely-when-vitamin-d-less-than-10-ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cognitive-impairment-4x-more-likely-when-vitamin-d-less-than-10-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cognitive-impairment-in-the-elderly-us-population">Vitamin D and Cognitive Impairment in the Elderly U.S. Population.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2010 Nov 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Llewellyn DJ, Lang IA, Langa KM, Melzer D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiology &amp;amp; Public Health Group, Peninsula Medical School, Barrack Road, Exeter, EX2 5DW, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:david.llewellyn@pms.ac.uk">david.llewellyn@pms.ac.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Recent European studies suggest that vitamin D deficiency may be associated with increased odds of cognitive impairment in older persons, although findings from the United States are equivocal. Our objective was to investigate the association between vitamin D deficiency and cognitive impairment in the elderly U.S. population.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>