<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cognitive on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cognitive.html</link><description>Recent content in Cognitive on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cognitive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cognitive Impairment 2.4X more likely if low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cognitive-impairment-24x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cognitive-impairment-24x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-cognitive-impairment-and-dementia-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D Deficiency, Cognitive Impairment and Dementia: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord 2012 Vol. 33, No. 5, 2012 ;33:297-305&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thorleif Etgena,b &lt;a href="mailto:thorleif.etgen@klinikum-traunstein.de">thorleif.etgen@klinikum-traunstein.de&lt;/a>, Dirk Sanderc,d, Horst Bickela, Kerstin Sanderd, Hans Förstla&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Technische Universität München,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Department of Neurology, Kliniken Südostbayern – Klinikum Traunstein,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Department of Neurology, Benedictus Krankenhaus Tutzing, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D Department of Neurology, Technische Universität München, Munich, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Recent preventive strategies for patients with cognitive impairment include the identification of modifiable somatic risk factors like vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Concussion-Free Football Season: How one High School beat the odds</title><link>/posts/a-concussion-free-football-season-how-one-high-school-beat-the-odds.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-concussion-free-football-season-how-one-high-school-beat-the-odds.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-hrefpostshigh-school-in-atlanta-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-2378high-school-in-atlantaa-added-vitamin-d-in-2011-to-their-sports-teams">&lt;a href="/posts/high-school-in-atlanta" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2378">High School in Atlanta&lt;/a> added vitamin D in 2011 to their sports teams&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Martin Luther King Jr. High School in Lithonia, Georgia has reduced its concussions and sports injuries by almost 100%. What was their secret? In 2011, the school started a parent-led nutrition program that included a daily regimen of vitamin D. The program was instituted by Dr. L. Ray Matthews, one of the nation’s leading researchers in vitamin D and assistant professor of surgery and director of surgical care at Grady Memorial Hospital in Atlanta,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Schizophrenia and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>15 reasons to think that schizophrenia is associated with low vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>97% of patients with schizophrenia are vitamin D deficient&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Schizophrenia varies with latitude (UVB) by 10X (controversy)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Schizophrenia is more common in those with dark skin (when away from the equator)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Schizophrenia is associated with low natal vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Schizophrenia has been increasing around the world when vitamin D has been decreasing (controversy)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Schizophrenia is associated with low birth rate, which is associated with low vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>