<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cognitive on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cognitive.html</link><description>Recent content in Cognitive on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cognitive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alzheimer's disease 30 percent more likely in the 30 years after a low vitamin D test</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-disease-30-percent-more-likely-in-the-30-years-after-a-low-vitamin-d-test.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-disease-30-percent-more-likely-in-the-30-years-after-a-low-vitamin-d-test.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="reduced-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-risk-of-alzheimers-disease-and-vascular-dementia">Reduced 25-hydroxyvitamin D and risk of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease and vascular dementia.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Alzheimers Dement. 2013 Jul 18. pii: S1552-5260(13)02425-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jalz.2013.05.1765.">doi: 10.1016/j.jalz.2013.05.1765.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Afzal S, Bojesen SE, Nordestgaard BG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Herlev Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital, Herlev, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D deficiency has been implicated as a risk factor for dementia in several cross-sectional studies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We tested the hypothesis that reduced plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) is associated with increased risk of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) and vascular dementia in the general population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and MS, ALS, Autism, Alzheimer’s and other nervous system diseases – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-ms-als-autism-alzheimers-and-other-nervous-system-diseases-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-ms-als-autism-alzheimers-and-other-nervous-system-diseases-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="review-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-nervous-system-health-and-disease">Review: The role of vitamin D in nervous system health and disease&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Neuropathology and Applied Neurobiology. Volume 39, Issue 5, pages 458–484, August 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G. C. DeLuca 1,gabriele.deluca@ndcn.ox.ac.uk&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. M. Kimball 3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. Kolasinski 1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. V. Ramagopalan 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G. C. Ebers 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Nuffield Department of Clinical Neurosciences (Clinical Neurology), University of Oxford, Oxford&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Blizard Institute of Cell and Molecular Science, Queen Mary University of London, Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brain (Alzheimer’s) worked better with Vitamin D intervention – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/brain-alzheimers-worked-better-with-vitamin-d-intervention-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/brain-alzheimers-worked-better-with-vitamin-d-intervention-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="meta-analysis-of-memory-and-executive-dysfunctions-in-relation-to-vitamin-d">Meta-Analysis of Memory and Executive Dysfunctions in Relation to Vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Disease, Online Date	Wednesday, July 03, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cedric Annweiler 1, 2, 3, Manuel Montero-Odasso2, David J. Llewellyn4, Stéphane Richard-Devantoy5, Gustavo Duque, Olivier Beauchet1&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1 Department of Neuroscience, Division of Geriatric Medicine and Memory Clinic, UPRES EA, UNAM, Angers University Hospital, Angers, France&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>2 Department of Medicine, Division of Geriatric Medicine, Parkwood Hospital, St. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s Health Care London; Gait and Brain Lab, Lawson Health Research Institute, the University of Western Ontario, London, ON, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s and Vitamins D, B, C, E, as well as Omega-3, metals, etc.</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-and-vitamins-d-b-c-e-as-well-as-omega-3-metals-etc.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-and-vitamins-d-b-c-e-as-well-as-omega-3-metals-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Importance and management of micronutrient deficiencies in patients with Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara Rita Cardoso1 Cristiane Cominetti2 Silvia Maria Franciscato Cozzolino1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Sao Paulo (USP), Sao Paulo, Brazil; 2Faculty of Nutrition, Federal University of Goias, Goias, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Barbara Rita Cardoso; Av Prof Lineu Prestes, 580 - Bloco &amp;lsquo;4 - CEP: 05508-900 – Sao Paulo - SP - Brazil Tel +55 3 09&amp;rsquo; 3625, +55 8 353 8223 Email &lt;a href="mailto:barbaracardoso@usp.br">barbaracardoso@usp.br&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinal cord problems more likely if TBI if little Omega-3 in diet</title><link>/posts/spinal-cord-problems-more-likely-if-tbi-if-little-omega-3-in-diet.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-cord-problems-more-likely-if-tbi-if-little-omega-3-in-diet.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dietary-omega-3-deficiency-from-gestation-increases-spinal-cord-vulnerability-to-traumatic-brain-injury-induced-damage">Dietary omega-3 deficiency from gestation increases spinal cord vulnerability to traumatic brain injury-induced damage.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(12):e52998. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0052998.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0052998.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Dec 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ying Z, Feng C, Agrawal R, Zhuang Y, Gomez-Pinilla F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Integrative Biology &amp;amp; Physiology, University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although traumatic brain injury (TBI) is often associated with gait deficits, the effects of TBI on spinal cord centers are poorly understood. We seek to determine the influence of TBI on the spinal cord and the potential of dietary omega-3 (n-3) fatty acids to counteract these effects. Male rodents exposed to diets containing adequate or deficient levels of n-3 since gestation received a moderate fluid percussion injury when becoming 14 weeks old. TBI reduced levels of molecular systems important for synaptic plasticity (BDNF, TrkB, and CREB) and plasma membrane homeostasis (4-HNE, iPLA2, syntaxin-3) in the lumbar spinal cord. These effects of TBI were more dramatic in the animals exposed to the n-3 deficient diet. Results emphasize the comprehensive action of TBI across the neuroaxis, and the critical role of dietary n-3 as a means to build resistance against the effects of TBI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is important for the central nervous system and cognition</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-important-for-the-central-nervous-system-and-cognition.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-important-for-the-central-nervous-system-and-cognition.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-the-central-nervous-system">Vitamin D and the central nervous system&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Pharmacological Reports, 2013, 65, 271-278 ISSN 1734-1140&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matgorzata Wrzosek1, Jacek tukaszkiewicz2, Michat Wrzosek3, Andrzej Jakubczyk4, Halina Matsumoto4, Pawet Piatkiewicz3, Maria Radziwoh-Zaleska4, Marcin Wojnar4,5, Grazyna Nowicka1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>department of Pharmacogenomics, department of Biochemistry and Clinical Chemistry,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>department of Internal Medicine and Diabetology, department of Psychiatry, Medical University of Warsaw, Zwirki i Wigury 61, PL 02-091 Warszawa, Poland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>department of Psychiatry, University of Michigan, 4250 Plymouth Rd., Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA Correspondence: Grazyna Nowicka, e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:grazyna.nowicka@wum.edu.p">grazyna.nowicka@wum.edu.p&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dementia associated with low vitamin D in two thirds of studies – systematic review</title><link>/posts/dementia-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-two-thirds-of-studies-systematic-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dementia-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-two-thirds-of-studies-systematic-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-association-between-vitamin-d-and-cognition-a-systematic-review">The association between vitamin D and cognition: a systematic review.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ageing Res Rev. 2013 May 29. pii: S1568-1637(13)00026-3. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arr.2013.05.004.">doi: 10.1016/j.arr.2013.05.004.&lt;/a> van der Schaft J, Koek HL, Dijkstra E, Verhaar HJ, van der Schouw YT, Emmelot-Vonk MH. &lt;a href="mailto:m.h.emmelotvonk@umcutrecht.nl">m.h.emmelotvonk@umcutrecht.nl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Geriatrics, University Medical Center Utrecht.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>We conducted a systematic literature review in Pubmed and Embase.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>We examine the association between levels of vitamin D and cognition.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Lower vitamin D levels are associated with worse cognitive function tests.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer's disease most likely will need more than monotherapy such as vitamin D</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-disease-most-likely-will-need-more-than-monotherapy-such-as-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-disease-most-likely-will-need-more-than-monotherapy-such-as-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s diseases associated with low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-levels-in-alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-a-meta-analysis">Vitamin D levels in Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s diseases: A meta-analysis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-levels-in-alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-a-meta-analysis">Vitamin D levels in Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s diseases: A meta-analysis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nutrition, Volume 29, Issue 6 , Pages 828-832, June 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yan Zhao, B.Sc., Yan Sun, B.Sc., Hong-Fang Ji, Ph.D. &lt;a href="mailto:jhf@sdut.edu.cn">jhf@sdut.edu.cn&lt;/a>, Liang Shen, Ph.D.email address&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shandong Provincial Research Center for Bioinformatic Engineering and Technique, Shandong University of Technology, Zibo, P. R. China&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 6 July 2012; accepted 25 November 2012. published online 15 February 2013.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traumatic brain injury treated by Vitamin D Progesterone Omega-3 and glutamine</title><link>/posts/traumatic-brain-injury-treated-by-vitamin-d-progesterone-omega-3-and-glutamine.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/traumatic-brain-injury-treated-by-vitamin-d-progesterone-omega-3-and-glutamine.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="combination-therapy-with-vitamin-d3-progesterone-omega-3-fatty-acids-and-glutamine-reverses-coma-and-improves-clinical-outcomes-in-patients-with-severe-traumatic-brain-injuries-a-case-series-of-three-patients">Combination therapy with vitamin D3, progesterone, omega-3 fatty acids, and glutamine reverses coma and improves clinical outcomes in patients with severe traumatic brain injuries: A case series of three patients&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>IJCRI - International Journal of Case Reports and Images, Vol. No. 2013. ISSN - &lt;span>[0976-3198]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Leslie R Matthews&lt;/strong> 1, Omar K Danner1, Y A Ahmed2, Diane M Dennis-Griggs1, Alexis Frederick1, Clarence Clark1, Ronald Moore1, Wilson DuMornay1, Ed W Childs1, Kenneth L Wilson1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fewest Google searches for Mental Health when there is lots of vitamin D from the sun</title><link>/posts/fewest-google-searches-for-mental-health-when-there-is-lots-of-vitamin-d-from-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fewest-google-searches-for-mental-health-when-there-is-lots-of-vitamin-d-from-the-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="seasonality-in-seeking-mental-health-information-on-google">Seasonality in Seeking Mental Health Information on Google&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>American Journal of Preventive Medicine. Volume 44, Issue 5 , Pages 520-525, May 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John W. Ayers, PhD, MA. Benjamin M. Althouse, ScM , Jon-Patrick Allem, MA , J. Niels Rosenquist, MD, PhD , Daniel E. Ford, MD, MPH&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background” Population mental health surveillance is an important challenge limited by resource constraints, long time lags in data collection, and stigma. One promising approach to bridge similar gaps elsewhere has been the use of passively generated digital data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Infectious burden linked to cognitive decline (both linked to low vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/infectious-burden-linked-to-cognitive-decline-both-linked-to-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/infectious-burden-linked-to-cognitive-decline-both-linked-to-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="infectious-burden-and-cognitive-function-the-northern-manhattan-study">Infectious burden and cognitive function, The Northern Manhattan Study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Neurology March 26, 2013 vol. 80 no. 13 1209-1215; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182896e79">doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182896e79&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mira Katan, MD, &lt;a href="mailto:mk3270@columbia.edu">mk3270@columbia.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeseon Park Moon, MS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Myunghee Cho Paik, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ralph L. Sacco, MD, MS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinton B. Wright, MD and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mitchell S.V. Elkind, MD, MS&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology (M.K., Y.P.M., M.S.V.E.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Gertrude Sergievsky Center (M.S.V.E.), Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, New York;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Biostatistics (M.C.P.), Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University, New York, NY;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s patients 3X more likely to have a malfunctioning vitamin D receptor gene – 2012</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-patients-3x-more-likely-to-have-a-malfunctioning-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-2012.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-patients-3x-more-likely-to-have-a-malfunctioning-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-gene-haplotype-is-associated-with-late-onset-alzheimers-disease">Vitamin D receptor gene haplotype is associated with late-onset Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Tohoku J Exp Med. 2012;228(3):189-96.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gezen-Ak D, Dursun E, Bilgiç B, Hanağasi H, Ertan T, Gürvit H, Emre M, Eker E, Ulutin T, Uysal O, Yilmazer S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medical Biology, Cerrahpasa Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D(3) is a neurosteroid that mediates its effects via the vitamin D receptor (VDR). The VDR gene is located on chromosome 12q13 and consists of 9 exons. VDR contains the DNA-binding site encoded by exons 2 and 3 and the ligand-binding site encoded by exons 4 - 9. Our earlier study showed that the ApaI polymorphic site of the VDR gene is associated with late-onset Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD). Here, we investigated the association between additional polymorphisms of the VDR gene and AD using the same samples. Two single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in intron 8 (BsmI and Tru9I polymorphisms) and one in exon 2 (FokI polymorphism) of the VDR gene were examined in up to 108 AD patients and 115 age-matched controls. Genotypes were determined with polymerase chain reaction (PCR) and restriction fragment length polymorphism (RFLP) methods. Haplotype analysis also included the previously studied polymorphic sites that were recognized by TaqI (in exon 9) and ApaI (in intron 8) restriction enzymes. There was no significant difference between AD patients and controls when their genotypes for BsmI, Tru9I and FokI polymorphic sites were compared. However, the frequency of &amp;ldquo;TaubF&amp;rdquo; haplotype (alleles of TaqI, ApaI, Tru9I, BsmI and FokI, respectively), which was determined by analyzing 5 polymorphisms together, was significantly higher in the AD patient group, suggesting that this haplotype is a risk factor in AD. Our results point out a possible link between AD and certain VDR polymorphisms and indicate that individuals with these polymorphisms might be vulnerable to AD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schizophrenia high and increasing in Canada – lower vitamin D and more dark skin</title><link>/posts/schizophrenia-high-and-increasing-in-canada-lower-vitamin-d-and-more-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/schizophrenia-high-and-increasing-in-canada-lower-vitamin-d-and-more-dark-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="are-the-rates-of-schizophrenia-unusually-high-in-canada">Are the rates of schizophrenia unusually high in Canada?&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="a-comparison-of-canadian-and-international-data">A comparison of Canadian and international data&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Marie-José Dealberto &lt;a href="mailto:dealbert@queensu.ca">dealbert@queensu.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Community Health and Epidemiology, Carruthers Hall, Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, Ontario, Canada K7L 3N6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Psychiatry Research Received 3 March 2012; received in revised form 26 September 2012; accepted 9 January 2013. published online 25 February 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two major risk factors for schizophrenia are present in Canada, high latitude and a large and growing immigrant population. Consequently, one would expect unusually high rates of schizophrenia and an increase in these rates over time. This systematic review tests these two hypotheses. Searches of electronic databases were performed through 2011. Out of 45 studies 12 fulfilled all the inclusion criteria. The means of Canadian and international rates were compared by one-tailed unequal variance t-test. Trends with time in Canadian rates were tested by the Spearman rank correlation coefficient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Brain Plasticity (best way to exercise your brain) – Interview</title><link>/posts/off-topic-brain-plasticity-best-way-to-exercise-your-brain-interview.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-brain-plasticity-best-way-to-exercise-your-brain-interview.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor00fupdatespan-a-hrefpostsdementia-risk-reduced-29-percent-by-just-10-hours-of-computer-brain-plasticity-training-rct-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-dementia-risk-reduced-29-percent-by-just-10-hours-of-computer-brain-plasticity-training--rct-dec-2017dementia-risk-reduced-29-percent-by-just-10-hours-of-computer-brain-plasticity-training--rct-dec-2017a">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Update:&lt;/span> &lt;a href="/posts/dementia-risk-reduced-29-percent-by-just-10-hours-of-computer-brain-plasticity-training-rct" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Dementia risk reduced 29 percent by just 10 hours of computer brain plasticity training – RCT Dec 2017">Dementia risk reduced 29 percent by just 10 hours of computer brain plasticity training – RCT Dec 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>I have now used Posit Science for about a decade&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Initially ~5 hours a week, recent years ~1/2 hour a week&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I cannot remember where I last left an item in &amp;lt;10 seconds&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Long term rat memory aided by optimal level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/long-term-rat-memory-aided-by-optimal-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/long-term-rat-memory-aided-by-optimal-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hippocampal-long-term-potentiation-in-rats-under-different-regimens-of-vitamin-d-an-in-vivo-study">Hippocampal long term potentiation in rats under different regimens of vitamin D: an in vivo study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Neurosci Lett. 2012 Feb 10;509(1):56-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2011.12.050.">doi: 10.1016/j.neulet.2011.12.050.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Dec 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Salami M, Talaei SA, Davari S, Taghizadeh M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Physiology Research Center, Kashan University of Medical Sciences, Kashan, Islamic Republic of Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evidence indicates that vitamin D involves in development of brain as well as its function. This study assesses occurrence of long term potentiation (LTP), as an experimental form of synaptic plasticity, in adult rats under the normal regimen (CON), and the regimens without vitamin D (CON-D) or with a supplement of 1,25(OH)2D3 (CON+D). Stimulating the Schaffer collaterals pre- and post-tetanus excitatory postsynaptic potentials (EPSPs) were recorded in the CA1 area of hippocampus in anesthetized animals. Amplitude change of the EPSPs was considered for comparisons. Our results indicated that the basic EPSPs were similar in the three groups. Tetanization elicited a considerable LTP in both the CON and CON+D rats but a moderate potentiation in the CON-D group. We concluded that optimal level of vitamin D is required for induction of LTP.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnesium may be an important way to treat brain trauma</title><link>/posts/magnesium-may-be-an-important-way-to-treat-brain-trauma.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/magnesium-may-be-an-important-way-to-treat-brain-trauma.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="your-bones-are-21-calciummagnesium-ratio-while-your-brain-is-more-like-21-mgca">Your bones are 2:1 calcium/magnesium ratio while your brain is more like 2:1 Mg:Ca&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-magnesium-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Magnesium and vitamin D">Overview Magnesium and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>which shows major decrease in Magnesium around the world during past 40 years&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There is a lot of interaction between Magnesiuma and Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/concussions-traumatic-brain-injury-getting-big-press-coverage-vitamin-d-might-be--and-a-solution">Concussions (traumatic brain injury) getting big press coverage, vitamin D might be both a cause and a solution&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces Alzheimer’s disease in at least 11 ways</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-alzheimers-disease-in-at-least-11-ways.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-alzheimers-disease-in-at-least-11-ways.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-alzheimers-disease-possible-genetic-and-cell-signaling-mechanisms">The Role of Vitamin D in Alzheimer’s disease: Possible Genetic and Cell Signaling Mechanisms&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>AM J ALZHEIMERS DIS OTHER DEMEN January 15, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Khanh Vinh Quốc Lu&amp;rsquo;o&amp;rsquo;ng, MD &lt;a href="mailto:lng2687765@aol.com">lng2687765@aol.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lan Thi Hoàng Nguyễn, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alzheimer’s disease (AD) is the most common form of dementia in the elderly individuals and is associated with progressive memory loss and cognitive dysfunction. A significant association between AD and low levels of vitamin D has been demonstrated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D aided progesterone in reducing traumatic brain injury – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-aided-progesterone-in-reducing-traumatic-brain-injury-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-aided-progesterone-in-reducing-traumatic-brain-injury-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="comparison-of-the-administration-of-progesterone-versus-progesterone-and-vitamin-d-in-improvement-of-outcomes-in-patients-with-traumatic-brain-injury-a-randomized-clinical-trial-with-placebo-group">Comparison of the administration of progesterone versus progesterone and vitamin D in improvement of outcomes in patients with traumatic brain injury: A randomized clinical trial with placebo group&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Adv Biomed Res 2012, 1:58&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bahram Aminmansour 1, Hossein Nikbakht 1, Abbas Ghorbani 2, Majid Rezvani 1, Paiman Rahmani 1, Mostaffa Torkashvand 1, Mohammadamin Nourian1, Mehran Moradi 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Neurosurgery, Isfahan University Of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Neurology, Al-zahra Hospital, Isfahan University Of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Psychiatric disorders in a few elderly associated with insufficient vitamin D</title><link>/posts/psychiatric-disorders-in-a-few-elderly-associated-with-insufficient-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/psychiatric-disorders-in-a-few-elderly-associated-with-insufficient-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-a-contributor-to-psychiatric-disorders-in-elderly">Hypovitaminosis d: a contributor to psychiatric disorders in elderly?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Can Geriatr J. 2012 Sep;15(3):80-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5770/cgj.15.39.">doi: 10.5770/cgj.15.39.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Sep 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ford J, Hategan A, Bourgeois JA &lt;a href="mailto:james.bourgeois@ucsf.edu">james.bourgeois@ucsf.edu&lt;/a>, Tisi DK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioural Neurosciences, Michael G. DeGroote School of Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypovitaminosis D is unrecognized and remarkably common in geriatric patients, with various clinical manifestations. The purpose of this study was to prospectively assess the vitamin D (VD) status in newly admitted psychogeriatric patients, and to study the correlation of VD status with indicators of calcium metabolism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>400 IU vitamin D was not enough to stop cognitive impairment</title><link>/posts/400-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-stop-cognitive-impairment.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/400-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-stop-cognitive-impairment.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="see-calcium-and-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-cognitive-impairment-in-the-womens-health-initiativehttpwwwncbinlmnihgovpubmed23176129doptabstract">See &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23176129?dopt=Abstract">Calcium and Vitamin D Supplementation and Cognitive Impairment in the Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Initiative.&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Random Controlled Trial with 1000 mg of Calcium, Nov 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="comment-by-vitamindwiki">Comment by VitaminDWiki&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>2,000IU might have shown some benefit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dementia risk increases 60 percent if have low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dementia-risk-increases-60-percent-if-have-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dementia-risk-increases-60-percent-if-have-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="association-between-serum-25oh-vitamin-d-and-the-risk-of-cognitive-decline-in-older-women">Association between serum 25(OH) vitamin D and the risk of cognitive decline in older women.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2012 Oct;67(10):1092-8. Epub 2012 Mar 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Slinin Y, Paudel M, Taylor BC, Ishani A, Rossom R, Yaffe K, Blackwell T, Lui LY, Hochberg M, Ensrud KE; Study of Osteoporotic Fractures Research Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Chronic Disease Outcomes Research, VA Medical Center, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:slini001@umn.edu">slini001@umn.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Results of prospective studies examining the association between 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels and cognitive decline have been inconsistent. We tested the hypothesis that lower 25(OH)D levels are associated with a greater likelihood of cognitive impairment and risk of cognitive decline.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s patients not on medication have very low levels of Vitamin D2</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-patients-not-on-medication-have-very-low-levels-of-vitamin-d2.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-patients-not-on-medication-have-very-low-levels-of-vitamin-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-25oh-vitamin-d2-levels-found-in-untreated-alzheimers-patients-compared-to-acetylcholinesterase-inhibitor-treated-and-controls">Low 25OH Vitamin D2 Levels Found in Untreated Alzheimer’s Patients Compared to Acetylcholinesterase Inhibitor Treated and Controls,&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Published in &lt;a href="http://www.hindawi.com/journals/ijad/%20">International Journal Current Alzheimer Research&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As of Nov 10, the abstract and paper is not on that website&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2012/11/121108131452.htm">Vitamin D Could Hold Vital Key to Arresting Development of Alzheimer’s Disease&lt;/a> Science Daily&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Age-related cognitive decline in rats mitigated by Vitamin D intervention – RCT</title><link>/posts/age-related-cognitive-decline-in-rats-mitigated-by-vitamin-d-intervention-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/age-related-cognitive-decline-in-rats-mitigated-by-vitamin-d-intervention-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dementia less likely with increased levels of Magnesium etc.</title><link>/posts/dementia-less-likely-with-increased-levels-of-magnesium-etc.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dementia-less-likely-with-increased-levels-of-magnesium-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#4-dementia-risk-factors-cancelled-if-have-enough-magnesium---june-2021">4 Dementia risk factors cancelled if have enough Magnesium - June 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dementia-risk-cut-in-half-in-those-taking-magnesium-as-a-laxative--jan-2018">Dementia risk cut in half in those taking Magnesium (as a laxative) – Jan 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="4-dementia-risk-factors-cancelled-if-have-enough-magnesium---june-2021">4 Dementia risk factors cancelled if have enough Magnesium - June 2021&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Plasma Concentrations of Magnesium and Risk of Dementia: A General Population Study of 102 648 Individuals&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical Chemistry, Volume 67, Issue 6, June 2021, Pages 899–911, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvab041">https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvab041&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jesper Qvist Thomassen, Janne S Tolstrup, Børge G Nordestgaard, Anne Tybjærg-Hansen, Ruth Frikke-Schmidt&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer's Disease more likely with low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-disease-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-disease-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lewy Body Dementia (Robin Williams) and low Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/lewy-body-dementia-robin-williams-and-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lewy-body-dementia-robin-williams-and-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="robins-wish---movie-sept-2020">Robin&amp;rsquo;s Wish - Movie Sept 2020&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90543401/robins-wish-erases-the-sad-clown-trope-around-robin-williamss-death?partner=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+fastcompany%2Fheadlines+%28Fast+Company%29">‘Robin’s Wish’ erases the sad clown trope around Robin Williams’s death&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Includes link to the video trailer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;“He never got bitter,” Norwood continues. “He never got angry. Robin Williams wasn’t the guy who was going to go burn down the neighborhood the last night he was alive because he felt like things were unfair. He went and asked for a hug from one of his close friends. He said goodnight to his wife. And he realized that there just wasn’t much left on the earth for him. &lt;strong>He was about two weeks from going into an inpatient program that he likely never would have come out of&lt;/strong> . And that’s just not how the guy wanted to live.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Role of vitamin D in insulin resistance</title><link>/posts/role-of-vitamin-d-in-insulin-resistance.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/role-of-vitamin-d-in-insulin-resistance.html</guid><description>&lt;p>J Biomed Biotechnol. 2012;2012:634195. Epub 2012 Sep 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sung CC, Liao MT, Lu KC, Wu CC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, Tri-Service General Hospital, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei 114, Taiwan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is characterized as a regulator of homeostasis of bone and mineral metabolism, but it can also provide nonskeletal actions because vitamin D receptors have been found in various tissues including the brain, prostate, breast, colon, pancreas, and immune cells.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer disease associated with 2.5 ng less vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/alzheimer-disease-associated-with-25-ng-less-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimer-disease-associated-with-25-ng-less-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>80 year olds had better cognition and stood better if high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/80-year-olds-had-better-cognition-and-stood-better-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/80-year-olds-had-better-cognition-and-stood-better-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-physical-and-cognitive-performance-in-older-people-with-chronic-conditions">25-hydroxyvitamin D and physical and cognitive performance in older people with chronic conditions.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pol Arch Med Wewn. 2012;122(4):162-9. Epub 2012 Feb 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skalska A, Ga?a? A, Grodzicki T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine and Gerontology, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Kraków, Poland. &lt;a href="mailto:anskal@su.krakow.pl">anskal@su.krakow.pl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and various pathologies as well as functional decline has been reported.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of the study was to assess the relationship between 25-hydroxyvitamin D, 25(OH)D, levels and functional status in elderly patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deliurium in ICU not associated with daily vitamin measurements</title><link>/posts/deliurium-in-icu-not-associated-with-daily-vitamin-measurements.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/deliurium-in-icu-not-associated-with-daily-vitamin-measurements.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-and-delirium-in-critically-ill-patients-a-preliminary-investigationhttpwwwsciencedirectcomsciencearticlepiis0883944112001864-aug-2012">&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0883944112001864">Vitamin D and delirium in critically ill patients: a preliminary investigation&lt;/a> Aug 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The study did not take vitamin D measurements at the time of the confusion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cognitive Impairment 2.4X more likely if low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cognitive-impairment-24x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cognitive-impairment-24x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-cognitive-impairment-and-dementia-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D Deficiency, Cognitive Impairment and Dementia: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord 2012 Vol. 33, No. 5, 2012 ;33:297-305&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thorleif Etgena,b &lt;a href="mailto:thorleif.etgen@klinikum-traunstein.de">thorleif.etgen@klinikum-traunstein.de&lt;/a>, Dirk Sanderc,d, Horst Bickela, Kerstin Sanderd, Hans Förstla&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Technische Universität München,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Department of Neurology, Kliniken Südostbayern – Klinikum Traunstein,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Department of Neurology, Benedictus Krankenhaus Tutzing, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D Department of Neurology, Technische Universität München, Munich, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Recent preventive strategies for patients with cognitive impairment include the identification of modifiable somatic risk factors like vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Concussion-Free Football Season: How one High School beat the odds</title><link>/posts/a-concussion-free-football-season-how-one-high-school-beat-the-odds.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-concussion-free-football-season-how-one-high-school-beat-the-odds.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-hrefpostshigh-school-in-atlanta-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-2378high-school-in-atlantaa-added-vitamin-d-in-2011-to-their-sports-teams">&lt;a href="/posts/high-school-in-atlanta" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2378">High School in Atlanta&lt;/a> added vitamin D in 2011 to their sports teams&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Martin Luther King Jr. High School in Lithonia, Georgia has reduced its concussions and sports injuries by almost 100%. What was their secret? In 2011, the school started a parent-led nutrition program that included a daily regimen of vitamin D. The program was instituted by Dr. L. Ray Matthews, one of the nation’s leading researchers in vitamin D and assistant professor of surgery and director of surgical care at Grady Memorial Hospital in Atlanta,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Schizophrenia and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>15 reasons to think that schizophrenia is associated with low vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>97% of patients with schizophrenia are vitamin D deficient&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Schizophrenia varies with latitude (UVB) by 10X (controversy)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Schizophrenia is more common in those with dark skin (when away from the equator)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Schizophrenia is associated with low natal vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Schizophrenia has been increasing around the world when vitamin D has been decreasing (controversy)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Schizophrenia is associated with low birth rate, which is associated with low vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes reduces vitamin D levels which reduces cognition</title><link>/posts/diabetes-reduces-vitamin-d-levels-which-reduces-cognition.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-reduces-vitamin-d-levels-which-reduces-cognition.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="diabetes-linked-to-memory-problems-in-older-adultshttpwellblogsnytimescom20120619diabetes-linked-to-memory-problems-in-older-adults20-ny-times-june-2012">&lt;a href="http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/06/19/diabetes-linked-to-memory-problems-in-older-adults/%20">Diabetes Linked to Memory Problems in Older Adults&lt;/a> NY Times June 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By ANAHAD O&amp;rsquo;CONNOR&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="snips">Snips&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“What we’ve shown is a clear association with diabetes and cognitive aging in terms of the slope and the rate of decline on these cognitive tests,” said Dr. Kristine Yaffe, a professor of psychiatry and neurology at the University of California, San Francisco. “That’s very powerful.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous studies have shown that Type 2 diabetes correlates with a higher risk of Alzheimer’s disease and dementia later in life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer's probability decreased 77 percent with just 51 IU more vitamin D daily</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-probability-decreased-77-percent-with-just-51-iu-more-vitamin-d-daily.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-probability-decreased-77-percent-with-just-51-iu-more-vitamin-d-daily.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="higher-vitamin-d-dietary-intake-is-associated-with-lower-risk-of-alzheimers-disease-a-7-year-follow-up">Higher Vitamin D Dietary Intake Is Associated With Lower Risk of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Disease: A 7-Year Follow-up.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2012 Apr 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annweiler C, Rolland Y, Schott AM, Blain H, Vellas B, Herrmann FR, Beauchet O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neuroscience, Division of Geriatric Medicine, Angers University Hospital, 49933 Angers, France. &lt;a href="mailto:ceannweiler@chu-angers.fr">ceannweiler@chu-angers.fr&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypovitaminosis D is associated with cognitive decline among older adults. The relationship between vitamin D intakes and cognitive decline is not well understood. Our objective was to determine whether the dietary intake of vitamin D was an independent predictor of the onset of dementia within 7 years among women aged 75 years and older.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s 4X less likely with high level of vitamin D – 2 studies</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-4x-less-likely-with-high-level-of-vitamin-d-2-studies.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-4x-less-likely-with-high-level-of-vitamin-d-2-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#two-studies-with-the-same-conclusion">Two studies with the same conclusion&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#higher-vitamin-d-dietary-intake-is-associated-with-lower-risk-of-alzheimers-disease-a-7-year-follow-up">Higher Vitamin D Dietary Intake Is Associated With Lower Risk of Alzheimer’s Disease: A 7-Year Follow-up&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-cognitive-function">Vitamin D and cognitive function&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="two-studies-with-the-same-conclusion">Two studies with the same conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="higher-vitamin-d-dietary-intake-is-associated-with-lower-risk-of-alzheimers-disease-a-7-year-follow-up">Higher Vitamin D Dietary Intake Is Associated With Lower Risk of Alzheimer’s Disease: A 7-Year Follow-up&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cédric Annweiler1, Yves Rolland 2, Anne M Schott 3, Hubert Blain 4, Bruno Vellas 2, François R Herrmann 5 and Olivier Beauchet 1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cognition in young adults not improved with vitamin D if already have enough</title><link>/posts/cognition-in-young-adults-not-improved-with-vitamin-d-if-already-have-enough.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cognition-in-young-adults-not-improved-with-vitamin-d-if-already-have-enough.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-cognitive-and-emotional-functioning-in-young-adults--a-randomised-controlled-trial">Effects of vitamin D supplementation on cognitive and emotional functioning in young adults&amp;ndash;a randomised controlled trial.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2011;6(11):e25966. Epub 2011 Nov 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dean AJ &lt;a href="mailto:a.dean@uq.edu.au">a.dean@uq.edu.au&lt;/a> , Bellgrove MA, Hall T, Phan WM, Eyles DW, Kvaskoff D, McGrath JJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Queensland Brain Institute, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiological research links vitamin D status to various brain-related outcomes. However, few trials examine whether supplementation can improve such outcomes and none have examined effects on cognition. This study examined whether Vitamin D supplementation led to improvements in diverse measures of cognitive and emotional functioning, and hypothesised that supplementation would lead to improvements in these outcomes compared to placebo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s may be treated by vitamin D3 and curcumin</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-may-be-treated-by-vitamin-d3-and-curcumin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-may-be-treated-by-vitamin-d3-and-curcumin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="scientists-pinpoint-how-vitamin-d-may-help-clear-amyloid-plaques-found-in-alzheimershttpnewsroomuclaeduportaluclascientists-pinpoint-how-vitamin-229702aspx20">&lt;a href="http://newsroom.ucla.edu/portal/ucla/scientists-pinpoint-how-vitamin-229702.aspx%20">Scientists pinpoint how vitamin D may help clear amyloid plaques found in Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>UCLA Press Release By Rachel Champeau March 06, 2012&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A team of academic researchers has identified the intracellular mechanisms regulated by vitamin D3 that may help the body clear the brain of amyloid beta, the main component of plaques associated with Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published in the March 6 issue of the Journal of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Disease, the early findings show that vitamin D3 may activate key genes and cellular signaling networks to help stimulate the immune system to clear the amyloid-beta protein.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s patients are genetically 70 percent more likely to be vitamin D in-efficient</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-patients-are-genetically-70-percent-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-in-efficient.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-patients-are-genetically-70-percent-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-in-efficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="so-people-with-that-gene-need-more-vitamin-d-than-others-who-do-not-have-the-gene">So, people with that gene need more vitamin D than others who do not have the gene.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-receptor-and-alzheimers-disease-a-genetic-and-functional-study">Vitamin D receptor and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease: a genetic and functional study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Neurobiology of Aging, Available online 3 February 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liyong Wanga, #, Kenju Haraa, d, #, Jessica M. Van Baaren a, Justin C. Price a, Gary W. Beecham a,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paul J. Gallins a, Patrice L. Whitehead a, Gaofeng Wang a, Chunrong Lu a, Michael A. Slifer a,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>\"Senior moment\" 25X more likely with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/senior-moment-25x-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/senior-moment-25x-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-and-mild-cognitive-impairment-cross-sectional-association">Vitamin D insufficiency and mild cognitive impairment: cross-sectional association&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>C. &lt;strong>Annweiler&lt;/strong> 1,2,3, &lt;a href="mailto:ceannweiler@chu-angers.fr">ceannweiler@chu-angers.fr&lt;/a>, B. Fantino2,3; A. M. Schott4; P. Krolak-Salmon5; G. Allali6; O. Beauchet1,2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Article first published online: 16 FEB 2012 European Journal of Neurology © 2012 EFNS&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Neuroscience, Division of Geriatric Medicine, Angers University Hospital, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Angers University Memory Center, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 UPRES EA 2646, University of Angers, UNAM, Angers, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Hospices Civils de Lyon, Pôle IMER; EA 4129, RECIF, Université de Lyon; INSERM U1033, Lyon, France&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Helps Atlanta High School Athletes</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-atlanta-high-school-athletes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-atlanta-high-school-athletes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d">Overview Sports and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-dark-skin-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1064">Overview Dark Skin and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/a-concussion-free-football-season-how-one-high-school-beat-the-odds">A Concussion-Free Football Season: How one High School beat the odds - July 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-and-sports-book-2011-at-vitamindwiki" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1907">Review of Vitamin D and Sports book - 2011 at VitaminDWiki&lt;/a> excellent on Athletics, covers vitamin D concerns well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-bone-fractures-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1344">Overview Bone Fractures and vitamin D&lt;/a> mainly seniors&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dementia 19X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dementia-19x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dementia-19x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-predictor-of-incident-non-alzheimer-dementias-a-7-year-longitudinal-study">Serum Vitamin D Deficiency as a Predictor of Incident Non-Alzheimer Dementias: A 7-Year Longitudinal Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord. 2012 Jan 19;32(4):273-278.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annweiler C, Rolland Y, Schott AM, Blain H, Vellas B, Beauchet O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neuroscience, Division of Geriatric Medicine, Angers University Hospital, Angers University Memory Center, UPRES EA 2646, University of Angers, UNAM, Angers, France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Hypovitaminosis D has been cross-sectionally associated with dementia and stroke. The objective of this longitudinal study was to determine whether serum vitamin D deficiency at baseline could predict the onset of non-Alzheimer dementias (NAD) within 7 years among older women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Concussions (traumatic brain injury) getting big press coverage, vitamin D might be both a cause and a solution</title><link>/posts/concussions-traumatic-brain-injury-getting-big-press-coverage-vitamin-d-might-be--and-a-solution.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/concussions-traumatic-brain-injury-getting-big-press-coverage-vitamin-d-might-be--and-a-solution.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="reasons-to-associate-concussion-with-low-vitamind">Reasons to associate concussion with low vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Those people having concussions have lower vitamin D levels&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Increase in the number of concussions as vitamin D levels have dropped&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Giving vitamin D (and other supplements) shortens recovery time from concussions&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Giving vitamin D resulted in fewer concussions (football players)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="researchers-tie-gulf-war-illness-to-brain-damagehttpmusatodaycomarticlenewsnation1982817preferredarticleviewmodesingle-usa-today-march2013">&lt;a href="http://m.usatoday.com/article/news/nation/1982817?preferredArticleViewMode=single">Researchers tie Gulf War illness to brain damage&lt;/a> USA Today March 2013&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Using fMRI machines, the Georgetown University researchers could see anomalies in the bundle of nerve fibers that interpret pain signals in the brain in 31 Gulf War veterans. The research will be published Wednesday in PLOS ONE journal.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>CAUTION: The FMRI magnetic fields MAY substantially reduce the vitamin D levels - &lt;a href="/posts/update" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 4093">Update May 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Link between diabetes and Alzheimers is probably low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/link-between-diabetes-and-alzheimers-is-probably-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/link-between-diabetes-and-alzheimers-is-probably-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.whec.com/news/stories/S2291815.shtml?cat=566">Study: Adults with diabetes more prone to dementia&lt;/a> Sept 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For 11 years, Japanese researchers followed more than 1,000 people, ages 60 and older.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They found that those with diabetes at the outset were 35 percent more likely to develop Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Those with the most severe diabetes had more than triple the risk.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deficiency-of-vitamin-dcategoriesdeficiency-of-vitamin-d-has-the-following-graph">&lt;a href="/categories/deficiency-of-vitamin-d">Deficiency of Vitamin D&lt;/a> has the following graph&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h2 id="diabetes-is-in-a-vicious-circle-with-vitamin-d">Diabetes is in a vicious circle with vitamin D.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="low-vitamin-d-increases-diabetes-and-diabetes-decreased-vitamin-d-even-more">Low vitamin D increases diabetes, and diabetes decreased vitamin D even more.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-spirals-lower-and-lower">Vitamin D spirals lower and lower&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpostsoverview-cognition-and-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-584overview-cognition-and-vitamin-da">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-cognition-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 584">Overview Cognition and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cognitive decline, dementia, and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Disease are all associated with low vitamin D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Risk of Cognitive Decline in Elderly Persons</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-risk-of-cognitive-decline-in-elderly-persons.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-risk-of-cognitive-decline-in-elderly-persons.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Obstetrical &amp;amp; Gynecological Survey:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>June 2011 - Volume 66 - Issue 6 - pp 354-355&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/OGX.0b013e31822c1957">doi: 10.1097/OGX.0b013e31822c1957&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gynecology: Menopause&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Llewellyn, David J.; Lang, Iain A.; Langa, Kenneth M.; Muniz-Terrera, Graciela; Phillips, Caroline L.; Cherubini, Antonio; Ferrucci, Luigi; Melzer, David&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The findings of a report published in 2007 suggested that over 40% of older, community-living adults in the United States and Europe were vitamin D deficient. There is clinical evidence for a relationship between low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels and cognitive dysfunction with aging. Although data in several small clinical studies showing such an association were equivocal, 3 of 4 large population-based cross-sectional studies reported a relationship between levels of serum 25(OH)D and cognitive dysfunction in the elderly. No prior prospective population-based studies have investigated the possible association between vitamin D status and incident dementia or cognitive decline.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Risk of cognitive decline 50 percent higher if low amount of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/risk-of-cognitive-decline-50-percent-higher-if-low-amount-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/risk-of-cognitive-decline-50-percent-higher-if-low-amount-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-cognitive-dysfunction-and-dementia-in-older-adults">Vitamin d, cognitive dysfunction and dementia in older adults.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>CNS Drugs. 2011 Aug 1;25(8):629-39. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2165/11593080-000000000-00000.">doi: 10.2165/11593080-000000000-00000.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dickens AP, Lang IA, Langa KM, Kos K, Llewellyn DJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peninsula Collaboration for Leadership in Applied Health Research and Care, Peninsula College of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The physiologically active form of vitamin D, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3), is a fat-soluble steroid hormone with a well established role in skeletal health. A growing body of evidence suggests low vitamin D levels also play a role in the pathogenesis of a wide range of non-skeletal, age-associated diseases including cancer, heart disease, type 2 diabetes mellitus and stroke. Low levels of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>, a stable marker of vitamin D status, are also associated with increased odds of prevalent cognitive dysfunction, Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease and all-cause dementia in a number of studies, raising the possibility that vitamin D plays a role in the aetiology of cognitive dysfunction and dementia. To date, the majority of human studies reporting associations between vitamin D and cognition or dementia have been cross-sectional or case-control designs that do not permit us to exclude the possibility that such associations are a result of disease progression rather than being causal. Animal and in vitro experiments have identified a number of neuroprotective mechanisms that might link vitamin D status to cognitive dysfunction and dementia, including vasoprotection and amyloid phagocytosis and clearance, but the clinical relevance of these mechanisms in humans is not currently clear. Two recent, large, prospective studies go some way to establish the temporal relationship with cognitive decline.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5X fewer hip fractures from Parkinson – Alzheimer – Stroke with enough sun</title><link>/posts/5x-fewer-hip-fractures-from-parkinson-alzheimer-stroke-with-enough-sun.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5x-fewer-hip-fractures-from-parkinson-alzheimer-stroke-with-enough-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sunlight-exposure-is-important-for-preventing-hip-fractures-in-patients-with-alzheimers-disease-parkinsons-disease-or-stroke">Sunlight exposure is important for preventing hip fractures in patients with Alzheimer’s disease, Parkinson’s disease, or stroke&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Neurologica Scandinavica, Article first published online: 18 JUN 2011; DOI: 10.1111/j.1600-0404.2011.01555.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. Iwamoto, T. Takeda, H. Matsumoto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives?–? Hypovitaminosis D as a result of malnutrition or sunlight deprivation, increased bone resorption, low bone mineral density (BMD), or an increased risk of falls may contribute to an increased risk of hip fractures in patients with neurological diseases, including Alzheimer’s disease, Parkinson’s disease, and stroke. The purpose of this study was to clarify the efficacy of sunlight exposure for reducing the risk of hip fractures in patients with such neurological diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D might might reduce dementia</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-might-might-reduce-dementia.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-might-might-reduce-dementia.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-value-of-physiologic-vitamin-d-as-a-biomarker-of-dementia">The value of physiologic vitamin D as a biomarker of dementia.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Drugs Today (Barc). 2011 Mar;47(3):223-31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Buell JS, Tucker KL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harvard Clinical Research Institute, Boston, Massachusetts, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:kl.tucker@neu.edu">kl.tucker@neu.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has been investigated in association with cognitive function in healthy and multimorbid elderly patients. Whether higher physiologic concentrations of vitamin D may be neuroprotective is not yet known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiological investigations have suggested a protective effect of physiologic vitamin D concentrations (circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D) on neurocognitive dysfunction and cerebrovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis -10 percent increased schizophrenia in winter births due to vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-10-percent-increased-schizophrenia-in-winter-births-due-to-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-10-percent-increased-schizophrenia-in-winter-births-due-to-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="season-of-birth-in-schizophrenia-a-maternal-fetal-chronobiological-hypothesis">Season of birth in schizophrenia: A maternal-fetal chronobiological hypothesis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Med Hypotheses. 2011 Mar 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schwartz PJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Psychiatry, Wright State University, Boonshoft School of Medicine, Dayton, OH, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being born in the winter and spring significantly increases one&amp;rsquo;s risk for developing schizophrenia. This birth seasonality may account for as many as 10% of all cases of schizophrenia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maternal third trimester infections or vitamin D deficiencies are hypothesized to be the most likely cause and can account for many of the important features of schizophrenia, although each hypothesis has limitations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mental Illness and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mental-illness-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mental-illness-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-role-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-mental-illness---mercola-dec-2024">The Role of Vitamin D Deficiency in Mental Illness - Mercola Dec 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-vitamin-d-when-indoors-most-of-the-time---fromvitamindwiki">Low vitamin D when indoors most of the time - from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsoweb">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#fact-1-smoking-decreases-vitamind">Fact 1 Smoking decreases vitamin D.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#fact-2-low-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-mentalillness">Fact 2 Low vitamin D is associated with mental illness&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#update-some-mental-hospitals-are-no-longer-encouraging-smoking-bypatients">Update: Some mental hospitals are no longer encouraging smoking by patients&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sesame-street-mental-disorders--2018httpswwwpinterestcompin7107311886643729">&lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/7107311886643729/">Sesame Street Mental Disorders - 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-role-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-mental-illness---mercola-dec-2024">The Role of Vitamin D Deficiency in Mental Illness - Mercola Dec 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2024/12/23/vitamin-d-deficiency-mental-illness.aspx?ui=d738e3df52a8a14aea9298fe6ec5bc113ed0d6d7922f31861727d54a43cbe29d&amp;amp;sd=20121119&amp;amp;cid_source=dnl&amp;amp;cid_medium=email&amp;amp;cid_content=art1HL&amp;amp;cid=20241223Z1_NB&amp;amp;foDate=false&amp;amp;mid=DM1673328&amp;amp;rid=190128122">2 videos&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poorer teen cognition due to lower vitamin D or race</title><link>/posts/poorer-teen-cognition-due-to-lower-vitamin-d-or-race.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poorer-teen-cognition-due-to-lower-vitamin-d-or-race.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Elderly with more than 257 IU vitamin D daily had less cognitive impairment</title><link>/posts/elderly-with-more-than-257-iu-vitamin-d-daily-had-less-cognitive-impairment.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/elderly-with-more-than-257-iu-vitamin-d-daily-had-less-cognitive-impairment.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dietary-intake-of-vitamin-d-and-cognition-in-older-women-a-large-population-based-study">Dietary intake of vitamin D and cognition in older women: A large population-based study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>by: C. Annweiler, A. M. Schott, Y. Rolland, H. Blain, F. R. Herrmann, O. Beauchet&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neurology, Vol. 75, No. 20. (16 November 2010), pp. 1810-1816.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Serum vitamin D concentrations are associated with global cognitive function among older adults. The benefits of vitamin D intake to treat or prevent cognitive impairment remain unknown. The objective of this cross-sectional study was to determine whether weekly dietary intake of vitamin D could be associated with global cognitive performance among older adults.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schizophrenia and vitamin D have latitude-related genes</title><link>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-related-genes-could-have-been-subject-to-latitude-driven-adaptation">Schizophrenia and Vitamin D Related Genes Could Have Been Subject to Latitude-driven Adaptation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Roberto Amato email, Michele Pinelli email, Antonella Monticelli email, Gennaro Miele email and Sergio Cocozza email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Evolutionary Biology 2010, 10:351doi:10.1186/1471-2148-10-351; Published: 	11 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many natural phenomena are directly or indirectly related to latitude. Living at different latitudes, indeed, has its consequences with being exposed to different climates, diets, light/dark cycles, etc. In humans, one of the best known examples of genetic traits following a latitudinal gradient is skin pigmentation. Nevertheless, also several diseases show latitudinal clinals such as hypertension, cancer, dismetabolic conditions, schizophrenia, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease and many more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cognitive impairment 4X more likely when vitamin D less than 10 ng</title><link>/posts/cognitive-impairment-4x-more-likely-when-vitamin-d-less-than-10-ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cognitive-impairment-4x-more-likely-when-vitamin-d-less-than-10-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cognitive-impairment-in-the-elderly-us-population">Vitamin D and Cognitive Impairment in the Elderly U.S. Population.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2010 Nov 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Llewellyn DJ, Lang IA, Langa KM, Melzer D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiology &amp;amp; Public Health Group, Peninsula Medical School, Barrack Road, Exeter, EX2 5DW, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:david.llewellyn@pms.ac.uk">david.llewellyn@pms.ac.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Recent European studies suggest that vitamin D deficiency may be associated with increased odds of cognitive impairment in older persons, although findings from the United States are equivocal. Our objective was to investigate the association between vitamin D deficiency and cognitive impairment in the elderly U.S. population.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>