<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ankle Fractures on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/ankle-fractures.html</link><description>Recent content in Ankle Fractures on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ankle-fractures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Foot and Ankle Fracture Healing – vitamin D appears promising for everyone– review</title><link>/posts/foot-and-ankle-fracture-healing-vitamin-d-appears-promising-for-everyone-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/foot-and-ankle-fracture-healing-vitamin-d-appears-promising-for-everyone-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-in-foot-and-ankle-fracture-healing-a-literature-review-and-research-design">Vitamin D in Foot and Ankle Fracture Healing: A Literature Review and Research Design.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Foot Ankle Spec. 2015 May 11. pii: 1938640015585958. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bernhard A1, Matuk J2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a generic name for a group of essential vitamins, or secosteroids, important in calcium homeostasis and bone metabolism. Specifically, efficacy of vitamin D with regard to bone healing is in question. A literature review was performed, finding mostly large studies involving vitamin D effects on prevention of fractures and randomized animal model studies consisting of controlled fractures with vitamin D interventions. The prevention articles generally focus on at-risk populations, including menopausal women and osteoporotic patients, and also most often include calcium in the treatment group. Few studies look at vitamin D specifically. The animal model studies often focus more on vitamin D supplementation; however the results are still largely inconclusive. While recent case reports &lt;strong>appear promising&lt;/strong> , the ambiguity of results on the topic of fracture healing suggests a need for more, higher level research. A novel study design is proposed to help determine the efficacy on vitamin D in fracture healing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ankle fractures associated with low vitamin D, smoking etc.</title><link>/posts/ankle-fractures-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-smoking-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ankle-fractures-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-smoking-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-foot-and-ankle-injuries">Prevalence of Vitamin D Deficiency in Patients With Foot and Ankle Injuries&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ankle.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Foot &amp;amp; Ankle International January 2014 vol. 35 no. 1 8-13&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jeremy T. Smith, MD1, Kareem Halim, AB1, David A. Palms, AB1, Kanu Okike, MD, MPH2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eric M. Bluman, MD, PhD1, Christopher P. Chiodo, MD1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Brigham Foot and Ankle Center at the Faulkner, Jamaica Plain, MA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Orthopaedics, Shock Trauma Center, Baltimore, MD, USA&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>