<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Parkinson on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/parkinson.html</link><description>Recent content in Parkinson on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/parkinson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5X fewer hip fractures from Parkinson – Alzheimer – Stroke with enough sun</title><link>/posts/5x-fewer-hip-fractures-from-parkinson-alzheimer-stroke-with-enough-sun.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5x-fewer-hip-fractures-from-parkinson-alzheimer-stroke-with-enough-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sunlight-exposure-is-important-for-preventing-hip-fractures-in-patients-with-alzheimers-disease-parkinsons-disease-or-stroke">Sunlight exposure is important for preventing hip fractures in patients with Alzheimer’s disease, Parkinson’s disease, or stroke&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Neurologica Scandinavica, Article first published online: 18 JUN 2011; DOI: 10.1111/j.1600-0404.2011.01555.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. Iwamoto, T. Takeda, H. Matsumoto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives?–? Hypovitaminosis D as a result of malnutrition or sunlight deprivation, increased bone resorption, low bone mineral density (BMD), or an increased risk of falls may contribute to an increased risk of hip fractures in patients with neurological diseases, including Alzheimer’s disease, Parkinson’s disease, and stroke. The purpose of this study was to clarify the efficacy of sunlight exposure for reducing the risk of hip fractures in patients with such neurological diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Parkinson disease increased in Israel by 50 percent in 7 years</title><link>/posts/parkinson-disease-increased-in-israel-by-50-percent-in-7-years.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/parkinson-disease-increased-in-israel-by-50-percent-in-7-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="new-method-for-measuring-parkinsons-disease-prevalence-reveals-sharp-increase-in-israel">New method for measuring Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease prevalence reveals sharp increase in Israel&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://medicalxpress.com/news/2011-06-method-parkinson-disease-prevalence-reveals.html%20">June 9, 2011 Medical Xpress&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a new study published today in the inaugural issue of the Journal of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease, Israeli researchers report that by tracking pharmacy purchases of anti-Parkinson drugs they could estimate the number of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) cases in a large population. The study identified a sharp rise in PD prevalence from 170/100,000 in 2000 to 256/100,000 in 2007 in Israel, which warrants further investigation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>9 minutes a day of sun improved BMD Parkinsons disease patients</title><link>/posts/9-minutes-a-day-of-sun-improved-bmd-parkinsons-disease-patients.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/9-minutes-a-day-of-sun-improved-bmd-parkinsons-disease-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="amelioration-of-osteoporosis-and-hypovitaminosis-d-by-sunlight-exposure-in-parkinsons-disease">Amelioration of osteoporosis and hypovitaminosis D by sunlight exposure in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2011 Jan;17(1):22-6. Epub 2010 Nov 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sato Y, Iwamoto J, Honda Y.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Mitate Hospital, 3237 Yugeta, Tagawa 826-0041, Japan. &lt;a href="mailto:y-sato@ktarn.or.jp">y-sato@ktarn.or.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A high incidence of fractures, particularly of the hip, represents an important problem in patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD), who are prone to falls and have osteoporosis. We previously showed that 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) deficiency due to sunlight deprivation with compensatory hyperparathyroidism causes reduced bone mineral density (BMD) in elderly patients with PD. The present study was undertaken to address the possibility that sunlight exposure may maintain BMD and reduce the incidence of hip fracture in elderly patients with PD. In a prospective study, PD patients were assigned to regular sunlight exposure (n=162) or usual lifestyle (n=162), and followed for 2 years. BMD of the second metacarpal bone was measured using a computed X-ray densitometer. Incidence of hip fracture in the two patient groups during the 2 year follow-up period was assessed. At baseline, patients of both groups showed vitamin D deficiency due to sunlight deprivation with compensatory hyperparathyroidism. The exposed group patients were exposed to sunlight (3231 min/year).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels were low at start of Parkinson Disease – but did not drop lower</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-were-low-at-start-of-parkinson-disease-but-did-not-drop-lower.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-were-low-at-start-of-parkinson-disease-but-did-not-drop-lower.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-levels-may-precede-parkinsons-symptoms">Low Vitamin D Levels May Precede Parkinson’s Symptoms&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.pdf.org/en/science_news/release/pr_1302025378">Parkinson’s Disease Foundation&lt;/a> - Apr 05 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People with a recent diagnosis of Parkinson’s disease (PD) were found to have low blood levels of vitamin D in a study published in the March 2011 issue of Neurology. The study authors suggest that people with PD may not have been getting enough vitamin D for a long time before Parkinson’s symptoms developed, and that vitamin D deficiency may play a role in causing the disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reduced vitamin D and BMD and Neurological Conditions</title><link>/posts/reduced-vitamin-d-and-bmd-and-neurological-conditions.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reduced-vitamin-d-and-bmd-and-neurological-conditions.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-mineral-density-in-adults-disabled-through-acquired-neurological-conditions-a-review">Bone Mineral Density in Adults Disabled Through Acquired Neurological Conditions: A Review&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Densitometry&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 14, Issue 2 , Pages 85-94, April 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone Mineral Density in Adults Disabled Through Acquired Neurological Conditions: A Review&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Áine Carroll&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 10 June 2010; received in revised form 12 December 2010; accepted 13 December 2010. published online 07 April 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article is a review of the changes in bone mineral density (BMD), which occur in a number of acquired neurological conditions resulting in disability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 instead of 11 fractures with Parkinson disease when have enough sun</title><link>/posts/3-instead-of-11-fractures-with-parkinson-disease-when-have-enough-sun.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-instead-of-11-fractures-with-parkinson-disease-when-have-enough-sun.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>