<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Parkinson on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/parkinson.html</link><description>Recent content in Parkinson on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/parkinson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D and MS, ALS, Autism, Alzheimer’s and other nervous system diseases – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-ms-als-autism-alzheimers-and-other-nervous-system-diseases-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-ms-als-autism-alzheimers-and-other-nervous-system-diseases-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="review-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-nervous-system-health-and-disease">Review: The role of vitamin D in nervous system health and disease&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Neuropathology and Applied Neurobiology. Volume 39, Issue 5, pages 458–484, August 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G. C. DeLuca 1,gabriele.deluca@ndcn.ox.ac.uk&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. M. Kimball 3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. Kolasinski 1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. V. Ramagopalan 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G. C. Ebers 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Nuffield Department of Clinical Neurosciences (Clinical Neurology), University of Oxford, Oxford&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Blizard Institute of Cell and Molecular Science, Queen Mary University of London, Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s diseases associated with low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-levels-in-alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-a-meta-analysis">Vitamin D levels in Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s diseases: A meta-analysis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-levels-in-alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-a-meta-analysis">Vitamin D levels in Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s diseases: A meta-analysis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nutrition, Volume 29, Issue 6 , Pages 828-832, June 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yan Zhao, B.Sc., Yan Sun, B.Sc., Hong-Fang Ji, Ph.D. &lt;a href="mailto:jhf@sdut.edu.cn">jhf@sdut.edu.cn&lt;/a>, Liang Shen, Ph.D.email address&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shandong Provincial Research Center for Bioinformatic Engineering and Technique, Shandong University of Technology, Zibo, P. R. China&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 6 July 2012; accepted 25 November 2012. published online 15 February 2013.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Parkinson's disease stabilized with just 1200 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/parkinsons-disease-stabilized-with-just-1200-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/parkinsons-disease-stabilized-with-just-1200-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="randomized-double-blind-placebo-controlled-trial-of-vitamin-d-supplement-in-parkinsons-disease">Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of vitamin D supplement in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr May 2013 ajcn.051664&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Masahiko Suzuki, Masayuki Yoshioka, Masaya Hashimoto, Maiko Murakami, Miki Noya, Daisuke Takahashi, and Mitsuyoshi Urashima; &lt;a href="mailto:urashima@jikei.ac.jp">urashima@jikei.ac.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 From the Department of Neurology, Katsushika Medical Center (MS, MY, MH, MM, and MN) and the Division of Molecular Epidemiology (MN, DT, and MU), Jikei University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Author Notes&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵2 Funders had no role in the study design, data collection and analysis, decision to publish, or preparation of the manuscript.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20 percent less chance of Parkinson’s disease if work outdoors some – Thesis</title><link>/posts/20-percent-less-chance-of-parkinsons-disease-if-work-outdoors-some-thesis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/20-percent-less-chance-of-parkinsons-disease-if-work-outdoors-some-thesis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="outdoor-occupational-history-and-risk-of-parkinson-disease-a-case-control-study">Outdoor Occupational History and Risk of Parkinson Disease: a Case-Control Study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Kwon, Elena Hindh Noor&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: A role for antioxidants in prevention of Parkinson disease has been proposed, however, epidemiologic evidence supporting this assertion has been inconclusive. Ninety percent of vitamin D in adults is produced in vivo related to ultraviolet type B exposure. This creates a plausible role for outdoor work as a strong surrogate for vitamin D in studies related to neurodegenerative disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fractures greatly reduced by sunshine, vitamin D, and vitamin K – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-greatly-reduced-by-sunshine-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-greatly-reduced-by-sunshine-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="strategy-for-prevention-of-hip-fractures-in-patients-with-parkinsons-disease">Strategy for prevention of hip fractures in patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>World J Orthop. 2012 Sep 18;3(9):137-41. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5312/wjo.v3.i9.137.">doi: 10.5312/wjo.v3.i9.137.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Iwamoto J, Sato Y, Takeda T, Matsumoto H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jun Iwamoto, Tsuyoshi Takeda, Hideo Matsumoto, Institute for Integrated Sports Medicine, Keio University School of Medicine, Tokyo 160-8582, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypovitaminosis D and K due to malnutrition or sunlight deprivation, increased bone resorption due to immobilization, low bone mineral density (BMD) and an increased risk of falls may contribute to an increased risk of hip fractures in patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease. The purpose of the present study was to clarify the efficacy of interventions intended to prevent hip fractures in elderly patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease. PubMed was used to search the literature for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) regarding Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease and hip fractures. The inclusion criteria were 50 or more subjects per group and a study period of 1 year or longer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Parkinson's disease and vitamin D recommends use of active form</title><link>/posts/review-of-parkinsons-disease-and-vitamin-d-recommends-use-of-active-form.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-parkinsons-disease-and-vitamin-d-recommends-use-of-active-form.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-parkinsons-disease">Vitamin D and Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Neuroscience Research, 28 AUG 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Khanh vinh quôc Luong*, Lan Thi Hoàng Nguyên&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) is the second most common form of neurodegeneration among the elderly population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PD is clinically characterized by&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>tremors,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>rigidity,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>slowness of movement, and&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>postural imbalance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Interestingly, a significant association has been demonstrated between PD and low levels of vitamin D in the serum, and vitamin D supplement appears to have a beneficial clinical effect on PD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Role of vitamin D in Parkinson's disease</title><link>/posts/role-of-vitamin-d-in-parkinsons-disease.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/role-of-vitamin-d-in-parkinsons-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;p>ISRN Neurol. 2012;2012:134289. Epub 2012 Mar 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>L Ng K, Nguy?n L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vietnamese American Medical Research Foundation, Westminster, CA 92683, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) is the second most common form of neurodegeneration in the elderly population. Clinically, it is characterized by tremor, rigidity, slowness of movement, and postural imbalance. A significant association between low serum vitamin D and PD has been demonstrated, suggesting that elevated vitamin D levels might provide protection against PD. Genetic studies have helped identify a number of proteins linking vitamin D to PD pathology, including the major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class II, the vitamin D receptor (VDR), cytochrome P450 2D6 (CYP2D6), chromosome 22, the renin-angiotensin system (RAS), heme oxygenase-1 (HO-1), poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase-1 gene (PARP-1), neurotrophic factor (NTF), and Sp1 transcription factor. Vitamin D has also been implicated in PD through its effects on L-type voltage-sensitive calcium channels (L-VSCC), nerve growth factor (NGF), matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs), prostaglandins (PGs) and cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2), reactive oxygen species (ROS), and nitric oxide synthase (NOS).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5X fewer hip fractures from Parkinson – Alzheimer – Stroke with enough sun</title><link>/posts/5x-fewer-hip-fractures-from-parkinson-alzheimer-stroke-with-enough-sun.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5x-fewer-hip-fractures-from-parkinson-alzheimer-stroke-with-enough-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sunlight-exposure-is-important-for-preventing-hip-fractures-in-patients-with-alzheimers-disease-parkinsons-disease-or-stroke">Sunlight exposure is important for preventing hip fractures in patients with Alzheimer’s disease, Parkinson’s disease, or stroke&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Neurologica Scandinavica, Article first published online: 18 JUN 2011; DOI: 10.1111/j.1600-0404.2011.01555.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. Iwamoto, T. Takeda, H. Matsumoto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives?–? Hypovitaminosis D as a result of malnutrition or sunlight deprivation, increased bone resorption, low bone mineral density (BMD), or an increased risk of falls may contribute to an increased risk of hip fractures in patients with neurological diseases, including Alzheimer’s disease, Parkinson’s disease, and stroke. The purpose of this study was to clarify the efficacy of sunlight exposure for reducing the risk of hip fractures in patients with such neurological diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Parkinson disease increased in Israel by 50 percent in 7 years</title><link>/posts/parkinson-disease-increased-in-israel-by-50-percent-in-7-years.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/parkinson-disease-increased-in-israel-by-50-percent-in-7-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="new-method-for-measuring-parkinsons-disease-prevalence-reveals-sharp-increase-in-israel">New method for measuring Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease prevalence reveals sharp increase in Israel&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://medicalxpress.com/news/2011-06-method-parkinson-disease-prevalence-reveals.html%20">June 9, 2011 Medical Xpress&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a new study published today in the inaugural issue of the Journal of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease, Israeli researchers report that by tracking pharmacy purchases of anti-Parkinson drugs they could estimate the number of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) cases in a large population. The study identified a sharp rise in PD prevalence from 170/100,000 in 2000 to 256/100,000 in 2007 in Israel, which warrants further investigation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>9 minutes a day of sun improved BMD Parkinsons disease patients</title><link>/posts/9-minutes-a-day-of-sun-improved-bmd-parkinsons-disease-patients.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/9-minutes-a-day-of-sun-improved-bmd-parkinsons-disease-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="amelioration-of-osteoporosis-and-hypovitaminosis-d-by-sunlight-exposure-in-parkinsons-disease">Amelioration of osteoporosis and hypovitaminosis D by sunlight exposure in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2011 Jan;17(1):22-6. Epub 2010 Nov 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sato Y, Iwamoto J, Honda Y.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Mitate Hospital, 3237 Yugeta, Tagawa 826-0041, Japan. &lt;a href="mailto:y-sato@ktarn.or.jp">y-sato@ktarn.or.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A high incidence of fractures, particularly of the hip, represents an important problem in patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD), who are prone to falls and have osteoporosis. We previously showed that 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) deficiency due to sunlight deprivation with compensatory hyperparathyroidism causes reduced bone mineral density (BMD) in elderly patients with PD. The present study was undertaken to address the possibility that sunlight exposure may maintain BMD and reduce the incidence of hip fracture in elderly patients with PD. In a prospective study, PD patients were assigned to regular sunlight exposure (n=162) or usual lifestyle (n=162), and followed for 2 years. BMD of the second metacarpal bone was measured using a computed X-ray densitometer. Incidence of hip fracture in the two patient groups during the 2 year follow-up period was assessed. At baseline, patients of both groups showed vitamin D deficiency due to sunlight deprivation with compensatory hyperparathyroidism. The exposed group patients were exposed to sunlight (3231 min/year).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels were low at start of Parkinson Disease – but did not drop lower</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-were-low-at-start-of-parkinson-disease-but-did-not-drop-lower.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-were-low-at-start-of-parkinson-disease-but-did-not-drop-lower.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-levels-may-precede-parkinsons-symptoms">Low Vitamin D Levels May Precede Parkinson’s Symptoms&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.pdf.org/en/science_news/release/pr_1302025378">Parkinson’s Disease Foundation&lt;/a> - Apr 05 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People with a recent diagnosis of Parkinson’s disease (PD) were found to have low blood levels of vitamin D in a study published in the March 2011 issue of Neurology. The study authors suggest that people with PD may not have been getting enough vitamin D for a long time before Parkinson’s symptoms developed, and that vitamin D deficiency may play a role in causing the disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reduced vitamin D and BMD and Neurological Conditions</title><link>/posts/reduced-vitamin-d-and-bmd-and-neurological-conditions.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reduced-vitamin-d-and-bmd-and-neurological-conditions.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-mineral-density-in-adults-disabled-through-acquired-neurological-conditions-a-review">Bone Mineral Density in Adults Disabled Through Acquired Neurological Conditions: A Review&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Densitometry&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 14, Issue 2 , Pages 85-94, April 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone Mineral Density in Adults Disabled Through Acquired Neurological Conditions: A Review&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Áine Carroll&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 10 June 2010; received in revised form 12 December 2010; accepted 13 December 2010. published online 07 April 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article is a review of the changes in bone mineral density (BMD), which occur in a number of acquired neurological conditions resulting in disability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 instead of 11 fractures with Parkinson disease when have enough sun</title><link>/posts/3-instead-of-11-fractures-with-parkinson-disease-when-have-enough-sun.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-instead-of-11-fractures-with-parkinson-disease-when-have-enough-sun.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>