<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gut on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/gut/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gut on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/gut/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fat-soluble Vitamins go thru the slow lymph system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fat-soluble-vitamins-go-thru-the-slow-lymph-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fat-soluble-vitamins-go-thru-the-slow-lymph-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;some-vitamin-d-in-gut-goes-thru-the-lymph-system-radioactive-tracing---may-1984&#34;&gt;Some Vitamin D in gut goes thru the lymph system (radioactive tracing) - May 1984&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lymphatic absorption and transport of retinol and vitamin D-3 from rat intestine. Evidence for different pathways&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biochim Biophys Acta. 1984 May 16;772(2):109-16. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/0005-2736&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/0005-2736&lt;/a&gt;(84)90033-6.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;R Blomhoff, P Helgerud, S Dueland, T Berg, J I Pedersen, K R Norum, C A Drevon&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lymphatic absorption and transport of retinol and vitamin D-3 from rat intestine has been studied. When rats were cannulated in the intestinal lymph duct and given an intraduodenal bolus of &lt;span&gt;[3H]&lt;/span&gt;retinol and 14C-labelled vitamin D-3, 14C-labeled vitamin D-3 appeared later in the intestinal lymph than &lt;span&gt;[3H]&lt;/span&gt;retinol and the rate of absorption of vitamin D-3 was still maximal at a time when that of retinol had declined. Both vitamins were absorbed via the lymphatic route in association with  &lt;strong&gt;chylomicrons&lt;/strong&gt; . Almost all the retinol was esterified, while vitamin D-3 appeared in the chylomicrons as free vitamin D-3. In vitro incubations and in vivo studies using hepatectomized and normal rats showed that the retinyl ester was a relatively nonexchangeable component of the chylomicrons and their remnants. Hence, all the vitamin A followed the remnants in their clearance from plasma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celiac Disease 2.2X higher risk if low vitamin D, Gluten Free Diet slightly increases D – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/celiac-disease-22x-higher-risk-if-low-vitamin-d-gluten-free-diet-slightly-increases-d-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/celiac-disease-22x-higher-risk-if-low-vitamin-d-gluten-free-diet-slightly-increases-d-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Celiac disease is reduced by%%% Vitamin D (esp. gut-friendly), Prebioitics, Zinc, Gluten Free Diet, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;relationship-between-vitamin-d-levels-and-pediatric-celiac-disease-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;Relationship between vitamin D levels and pediatric celiac disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BMC Pediatr . 2024 Mar 16;24(1):185. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s12887-024-04688-0.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1186/s12887-024-04688-0.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yanhong Sun # 1, Qingxue Zhou # 2, Dandan Tian 1, Jianming Zhou 1, Shilei Dong 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: The relationship between Vitamin D levels and pediatric celiac disease (CD) remains controversial. In this study, we conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis to examine the relationship between Vitamin D and pediatric CD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celiac Disease: Vitamin D levels do not change with season (not outdoors much)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/celiac-disease-vitamin-d-levels-do-not-change-with-season-not-outdoors-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/celiac-disease-vitamin-d-levels-do-not-change-with-season-not-outdoors-much/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;differences-in-plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-at-diagnosis-of-celiac-disease-and-type-1-diabetes&#34;&gt;Differences in Plasma 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels at Diagnosis of Celiac Disease and Type 1 Diabetes&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients. 2024 Mar 5;16(5):743. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu16050743.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/nu16050743.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Monica Marino 1, Tiziana Galeazzi 2, Rosaria Gesuita 3, Salima Ricci 4, Carlo Catassi 4, Valentino Cherubini 1, Elena Lionetti 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;700&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aim: The aim of this work is to assess the vitamin D levels, evaluated as plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D of children with a new diagnosis of celiac disease (CD), of children with a new onset of type 1 diabetes (T1D) and in children with CD at diagnosis of T1D (T1D&amp;amp;CD).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children with IBD are treated with Vitamin D (Australia and NZ)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/children-with-ibd-are-treated-with-vitamin-d-australia-and-nz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/children-with-ibd-are-treated-with-vitamin-d-australia-and-nz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;patterns-of-vitamin-d-testing-and-supplementation-for-children-with-inflammatory-bowel-disease-in-australasia&#34;&gt;Patterns of vitamin D testing and supplementation for children with inflammatory bowel disease in Australasia&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JGH Open . 2024 Mar 4;8(3):e13041. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/jgh3.13041&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1002/jgh3.13041&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Angharad Vernon-Roberts 1, Andrew S Day 1; PEDiatric Australasian Gastroenterology REsearch NEtwork (PEDAGREE)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background and aim: For children with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), optimal levels of vitamin D are ascribed anti-inflammatory and essential immune system roles that are associated with reduced disease activity, lower postoperative recurrence, and higher quality of life. International guidelines for vitamin D testing and supplementation provide inconsistent recommendations. The aim of this study was to survey Australasian pediatric gastroenterologists to ascertain current practices of vitamin D testing and supplementation for children with IBD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diarrhea and Vitamin D - several studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/diarrhea-and-vitamin-d-several-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/diarrhea-and-vitamin-d-several-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange9span-vitamindwiki-pages-have-diarrhea-in-the-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;9+&lt;/span&gt; VitaminDWiki pages have DIARRHEA in the title&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{list max=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34; DIARRHEA&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;NOT \&#34; piglet\&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; shownbitems=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xA;&#xA;{column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=title format=&amp;ldquo;objectlink&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;childhood-diarrhea-7x-higher-risk-if-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d---meta-analysis--2024&#34;&gt;Childhood diarrhea 7X higher risk if less than 20 ng of Vitamin D - meta-analysis – 2024&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The relationship of vitamin D deficiency and childhood diarrhea: a systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People with new fecal incontinence are 1.9 X more likely to have low Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/people-with-new-fecal-incontinence-are-19-x-more-likely-to-have-low-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/people-with-new-fecal-incontinence-are-19-x-more-likely-to-have-low-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-association-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-fecal-incontinence&#34;&gt;The association between vitamin-D deficiency and fecal incontinence&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neurogastroenterol Motil 2024 Feb 5:e14753. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/nmo.14753&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1111/nmo.14753&lt;/a&gt;  PDF can be viewed at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deepdyve.com/lp/wiley/the-association-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-fecal-incontinence-xlf9tCjSOL?articleList=%2Fsearch%3Fquery%3D%2522The%2Bassociation%2Bbetween%2Bvitamin-D%2Bdeficiency%2Band%2Bfecal%2Bincontinence%2522&#34;&gt;DeepDyve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leila Neshatian 1, Gabrielle Grant 2, Nielsen Fernandez-Becker 1, Ye Yuan 3, Patricia Garcia 1, Laren Becker 1, Brooke Gurland 4, George Triadafilopoulos 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Vitamin-D is essential for musculoskeletal health. We aimed to determine whether patients with fecal incontinence (FI): (1) are more likely to have vitamin-D deficiency and, (2) have higher rates of comorbid medical conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bariatric Surgery in Adolescents: 41% vitamin D deficient - meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bariatric-surgery-in-adolescents-41-percent-vitamin-d-deficient-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bariatric-surgery-in-adolescents-41-percent-vitamin-d-deficient-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;nutrient-deficiency-after-bariatric-surgery-in-adolescents-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;Nutrient Deficiency After Bariatric Surgery in Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obes Surg  2023 Nov 22. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11695-023-06955-y&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1007/s11695-023-06955-y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Faraneh Zolfaghari 1, Yasaman Khorshidi 1, Nazanin Moslehi 2, Mahdieh Golzarand 3, Golaleh Asghari 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objective: This systematic review and meta-analysis study aimed to estimate changes in blood nutrient concentrations and nutrient deficiencies in adolescents following bariatric surgery.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Methods: We searched PubMed, Scopus, and the Web of Science to find studies published between January 2000 and August 2023. Observational studies reporting the mean blood concentration of nutrients before and after bariatric surgery or the proportion of nutrient deficiencies after the surgery in healthy adolescents were selected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBS - Vitamin D was the only micronutrient under DRV - meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ibs-vitamin-d-was-the-only-micronutrient-under-drv-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ibs-vitamin-d-was-the-only-micronutrient-under-drv-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-diet-and-nutrient-intake-in-adults-with-irritable-bowel-syndrome&#34;&gt;A systematic review and meta-analysis of diet and nutrient intake in adults with irritable bowel syndrome&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neurogastroenterology &amp;amp; Motility. 2023;00:e14698. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/nmo.14698&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/nmo.14698&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Numerous individual and environmental factors including diet may play an important role in the pathophysiology of irritable bowel syndrome (IBS). It is un­clear to what degree dietary intake is affected in individuals with IBS. We aimed to perform a systematic review and meta-analysis to summarize dietary intake of adults with IBS and to compare dietary intake between adults with IBS and non-IBS controls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBD associated with low vitamin D again (they need to take a gut-friendly form of Vitamin D)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ibd-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-again-they-need-to-take-a-gut-friendly-form-of-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ibd-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-again-they-need-to-take-a-gut-friendly-form-of-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;lower-vitamin-d-levels-are-associated-with-the-pathogenesis-of-inflammatory-bowel-diseases&#34;&gt;Lower vitamin D levels are associated with the pathogenesis of inflammatory bowel diseases&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Medicine (Baltimore). 2023 Oct 13;102(41):e35505. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000035505.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000035505.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Antonia Topalova-Dimitrova 1 2, Ivan Valentinov Dimitrov 2 3, Rosen Nikolov 1 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D plays a role in regulating immune homeostasis, inflammation and has an impact on the pathogenesis of inflammatory bowel diseases (IBD). IBD has a multifactorial pathogenesis primarily associated with immune dysregulation, dysbiosis, structurally altered intestinal mucosa, and genetic factors. The immunomodulatory function of this vitamin is linked to its control over innate and adaptive immunity, facilitated through its nuclear vitamin D receptor, leading to the inhibition of nuclear factor kappa-B. This study aimed to investigate serum vitamin D levels in patients with IBD compared to healthy individuals and to evaluate the relationship between vitamin D and inflammatory markers. Cross-sectional study. The study included 106 participants divided into 2 groups: patients with IBD (92), and healthy controls (14). The diagnosis of IBD was based on clinical, laboratory, fecal, endoscopic, and histological findings, following the European guidelines for diagnosis and follow-up ECCO-ESGAR guidelines for diagnostic assessment of IBD from 2019. Serum vitamin D levels were measured along with laboratory tests, imaging, and endoscopic examinations. IBD activity was evaluated using the Montreal classification and clinical and endoscopic indices. Data analysis involved calculating the mean, minimum, and maximum values, standard deviation, and Pearson coefficient. The level of statistical significance for this study was set at P &amp;lt; .05. The study found a prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in 32.6% of patients with IBD, while 66.3% had insufficiency, as compared with healthy individuals. The mean levels of vitamin D in UC and CD were 16 ± 8.6 ng/mL, whereas in the control healthy group, they were 26 ± 9.73 ng/mL. A statistically significant reverse correlation was observed between lower vitamin D levels and higher levels of the inflammatory markers. The study concluded that IBD patients exhibit lower levels of vitamin D, which is associated with inflammation and may contribute to the pathogenesis of the disease.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBS reduced by 50,000 IU of Vitamin D (weekly or bi-weekly) – Meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ibs-reduced-by-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly-or-bi-weekly-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ibs-reduced-by-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly-or-bi-weekly-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-improves-irritable-bowel-syndrome-symptoms-a-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;Vitamin D improves irritable bowel syndrome symptoms: A meta-analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Heliyon. 2023 May 25;9(6):e16437. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e1643&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e1643&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chenxi Yan 1, Chenmin Hu 1, Xiaolong Chen 1, Xinyi Jia 1, Zhenya Zhu 1, Diya Ye 1, Yuhao Wu 1, Rui Guo 1, Mizu Jiang 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background &amp;amp; aims: Approximately 5%-10% of the population in most geographical regions suffer from irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), which creates a significant burden on individual patients, their families, and society. Recent advances in IBS therapies have indicated that vitamin D supplementation is potential to relieve its symptoms, but evidence of this is lacking. This meta-analysis aimed to estimate the effect of vitamin D on gastrointestinal (GI) symptoms in IBS patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/irritable-bowel-syndrome-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/irritable-bowel-syndrome-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange18span--vitamindwiki-pages-with-ibs-etc--in-the-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;18+&lt;/span&gt;  VitaminDWiki pages with IBS etc.  in the title&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;s&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;\&#34;Irritable bowel syndrome\&#34; OR “\&#34;IBS\&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; shownbitems=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xA;&#xA;{column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=title format=&amp;ldquo;objectlink&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;role-of-in-vitamin-d-in-irritable-bowel-syndrome---april-2023&#34;&gt;Role of in vitamin D in irritable bowel syndrome - April 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;World J Clin Cases. 2023 Apr 26; 11(12): 2677–2683. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.12998/wjcc.v11.i12.2677&#34;&gt;doi: 10.12998/wjcc.v11.i12.2677&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nutrients, Microbiome, and Chronic Diseases</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nutrients-microbiome-and-chronic-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nutrients-microbiome-and-chronic-diseases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-microbiome-as-a-major-function-of-the-gastrointestinal-tract-and-its-implication-in-micronutrient-metabolism-and-chronic-diseases&#34;&gt;The microbiome as a major function of the gastrointestinal tract and its implication in micronutrient metabolism and chronic diseases&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutr Res . 2023 Mar 4;112:30-45. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nutres.2023.02.007&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2023.02.007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dingbo Lin 1, Denis M Medeiros 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;pdf-table-of-contents&#34;&gt;PDF Table of Contents&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Small intestine in nutrient digestion and absorption&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 Large intestine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4 Overview of the intestinal microbiome&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5 Vitamin C and other redox-active food compounds on the gut microbiome&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6 Gut microbiome-derived folate does not meet human needs&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D interactions with poor gut (Celiac, IBD, and Bariatric surgery) – several studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-interactions-with-poor-gut-celiac-ibd-and-bariatric-surgery-several-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-interactions-with-poor-gut-celiac-ibd-and-bariatric-surgery-several-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;ibd-best-practice-advice-includes-vitamin-d---jan-2024&#34;&gt;IBD best practice advice includes Vitamin D - Jan 2024&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AGA Clinical Practice Update on Diet and Nutritional Therapies in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease: Expert Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gastroenterology. 2024 Jan 23:S0016-5085(23)05597-X. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2023.11.303&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1053/j.gastro.2023.11.303&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jana G Hashash 1, Jaclyn Elkins 2, James D Lewis 3, David G Binion 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Description: Diet plays a critical role in human health, but especially for patients with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). Guidance about diet for patients with IBD are often controversial and a source of uncertainty for many physicians and patients. The role of diet has been investigated as a risk factor for IBD etiopathogenesis and as a therapy for active disease. Dietary restrictions, along with the clinical complications of IBD, can result in malnutrition, an underrecognized condition among this patient population. The aim of this American Gastroenterological Association (AGA) Clinical Practice Update (CPU) is to provide best practice advice statements, primarily to clinical gastroenterologists, covering the topics of diet and nutritional therapies in the management of IBD, while emphasizing identification and treatment of malnutrition in these patients. We provide guidance for tailored dietary approaches during IBD remission, active disease, and intestinal failure. A healthy Mediterranean diet will benefit patients with IBD, but may require accommodations for food texture in the setting of intestinal strictures or obstructions. New data in Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease supports the use of enteral liquid nutrition to help induce remission and correct malnutrition in patients heading for surgery. Parenteral nutrition plays a critical role in patients with IBD facing acute and/or chronic intestinal failure. Registered dietitians are an essential part of the interdisciplinary team approach for optimal nutrition assessment and management in the patient population with IBD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
