<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gut on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/gut.html</link><description>Recent content in Gut on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/gut/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crohn's Disease patients normalizing their Vitamin D levels decreased risk of surgery by 44 percent</title><link>/posts/crohns-disease-patients-normalizing-their-vitamin-d-levels-decreased-risk-of-surgery-by-44-percent.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/crohns-disease-patients-normalizing-their-vitamin-d-levels-decreased-risk-of-surgery-by-44-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="normalization-of-plasma-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-reduced-risk-of-surgery-in-crohns-disease">Normalization of Plasma 25-Hydroxy Vitamin D Is Associated with Reduced Risk of Surgery in Crohn&amp;rsquo;s Disease.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2013 Aug;19(9):1921-1927.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ananthakrishnan AN, Cagan A, Gainer VS, Cai T, Cheng SC, Savova G, Chen P, Szolovits P, Xia Z, De Jager PL, Shaw SY, Churchill S, Karlson EW, Kohane I, Plenge RM, Murphy SN, Liao KP.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Division of Gastroenterology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts; †Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts; ‡Research Computing, Partners HealthCare, Charlestown, Massachusetts; §Department of Biostatistics, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, Massachusetts; | | Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Boston, Boston, Massachusetts; ¶Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts; **Department of Neurology, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts; ††Center for Systems Biology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts; ‡‡i2b2 National Center for Biomedical Computing, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts; §§Division of Rheumatology, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts; and | | | |Department of Neurology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D may have an immunologic role in Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease (CD) and ulcerative colitis (UC). Retrospective studies suggested a weak association between vitamin D status and disease activity but have significant limitations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Probiotics increased vitamin D levels 22 percent in those with excess cholesterol</title><link>/posts/probiotics-increased-vitamin-d-levels-22-percent-in-those-with-excess-cholesterol.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/probiotics-increased-vitamin-d-levels-22-percent-in-those-with-excess-cholesterol.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="oral-supplementation-with-probiotic-l-reuteri-ncimb-30242-increases-mean-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-a-post-hoc-analysis-of-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Oral supplementation with probiotic L. reuteri NCIMB 30242 increases mean circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D: a post-hoc analysis of a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013 Apr 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jones ML, Martoni CJ, Prakash S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Biomedical Technology and Cell Therapy Research Laboratory, Department of Biomedical Engineering and Physiology, Artificial Cells and Organs Research Centre, Faculty of Medicine, McGill University, 3775 University St, Montreal, QC, H3A 2B4, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Context:Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D is a risk factor for osteoporosis, cardiovascular disease, diabetes and cancer. Disruption of non-cholesterol sterol absorption due to cholesterol lowering therapies may result in reduced fat soluble vitamin absorption.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crohn’s helped by 5000 IU vitamin D</title><link>/posts/crohns-helped-by-5000-iu-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/crohns-helped-by-5000-iu-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="therapeutic-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-a-pilot-study-of-crohns-patients">Therapeutic Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation in a Pilot Study of Crohn’s Patients&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Clinical and Translational Gastroenterology (2013) 4, e33; doi:10.1038/ctg.2013.1, Published online 18 April 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Linlin Yang PhD1, Veronika Weaver1, Jill P Smith MD2, Sandra Bingaman RN2, Terryl J Hartman MPH/PhD3 and Margherita T Cantorna PhD1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Veterinary and Biomedical Science, Center for Molecular Immunology and Infectious Disease, University Park, Pennsylvania, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Medicine, Hershey, Pennsylvania, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>88 percent of Intestinal failures had both low vitamin D and low bone density</title><link>/posts/88-percent-of-intestinal-failures-had-both-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/88-percent-of-intestinal-failures-had-both-low-vitamin-d-and-low-bone-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="high-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-osteoporosis-in-out-patients-with-intestinal-failure">High prevalence of vitamin D deficiency and osteoporosis in out-patients with intestinal failure.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clin Nutr. 2013 Feb 21. pii: S0261-5614(13)00051-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnu.2013.02.005">doi: 10.1016/j.clnu.2013.02.005&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ellegård L, Kurlberg G, Bosaeus I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Nutrition, Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Göteborg, Sweden. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:lasse.ellegard@nutrition.gu.se">lasse.ellegard@nutrition.gu.se&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: In intestinal failure, specific nutrient deficiencies especially for fat-soluble vitamins can be expected in addition to energy-protein malnutrition. We report serum levels of fat soluble vitamins, and bone density in out-patients with intestinal failure (IF).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active Crohn's disease is associated with low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/active-crohns-disease-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-crohns-disease-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;p>J Crohns Colitis. 2013 Feb 8. pii: S1873-9946(13)00032-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.crohns.2013.01.012.">doi: 10.1016/j.crohns.2013.01.012.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jørgensen SP, Hvas CL, Agnholt J, Christensen LA, Heickendorff L, Dahlerup JF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine V, Hepatology and Gastroenterology, Aarhus University Hospital, Denmark. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:soerjoer@rm.dk">soerjoer@rm.dk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND AIMS: Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease prevalence increases with increasing latitude. Because most vitamin D comes from sunlight exposure and murine models of intestinal inflammation have demonstrated beneficial effects of 1,25-(OH)(2) vitamin D treatment, we hypothesised that Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease activity is associated with low vitamin D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Having celiac disease and low vitamin D only predicted psoriasis and anemia</title><link>/posts/having-celiac-disease-and-low-vitamin-d-only-predicted-psoriasis-and-anemia.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/having-celiac-disease-and-low-vitamin-d-only-predicted-psoriasis-and-anemia.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-concomitant-autoimmunity-in-celiac-disease">Vitamin D Status and Concomitant Autoimmunity in Celiac Disease&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Gastroenterology: 16 January 2013,&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/MCG.0b013e318266f81b">doi: 10.1097/MCG.0b013e318266f81b&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tavakkoli, Anna MD; DiGiacomo, Daniel MS; Green, Peter H. MD; Lebwohl, Benjamin MD, MS&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goals: To determine whether patients with celiac disease (CD) and low vitamin D levels also have a higher prevalence of other autoimmune diseases (AD) as compared with patients with normal vitamin D levels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Patients with CD carry a higher risk of other autoimmune disorders. Because of its immunoregulatory properties, vitamin D deficiency has been proposed in the pathogenesis of a variety of AD. Whether low vitamin D levels in patients with CD can predict concomitant AD is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>70 percent of people with IBS had symptoms relieved with high dose vitamin D – 2012</title><link>/posts/70-percent-of-people-with-ibs-had-symptoms-relieved-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-2012.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/70-percent-of-people-with-ibs-had-symptoms-relieved-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-as-a-novel-treatment-for-irritable-bowel-syndrome-single-case-leads-to-critical-analysis-of-patient-centred-data">Vitamin D3 as a novel treatment for irritable bowel syndrome: single case leads to critical analysis of patient-centred data&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMJ Case Reports 2012; doi:10.1136/bcr-2012-007223&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eleanor F Sprake,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vicky A Grant,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bernard M Corfe &lt;a href="mailto:b.m.corfe@sheffield.ac.uk">b.m.corfe@sheffield.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Molecular Gastroenterology Research Group, Academic Unit of Surgical Oncology, Department of Oncology, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is a chronic and debilitating functional disorder of the gastrointestinal tract with serious and detrimental impacts on quality of life. Its aetiology is largely unknown and the identification of effective management strategies remains far from complete. This paper first reports, a case of a 41-year-old woman IBS sufferer who reported significant symptom improvements with high-dose vitamin D3 supplementation. The sufferer identified a &lt;strong>substantial body of patient data surrounding this potential therapy on social media sites&lt;/strong> , and this paper, therefore, also reports the findings from a systematic analysis of patient-centred, internet-based data surrounding this phenomenon. Data from 37 IBS sufferers commenting on the effect of vitamin D supplementation on their condition were located; approximately &lt;strong>70% of these reported that high-dose supplementation improved their IBS symptoms.&lt;/strong> A randomised controlled trial into the effect of vitamin D supplementation on IBS symptomatology to test this association scientifically is merited.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis of Autoimmunity which includes Epstein-Barr Virus and Vitamin D Deficiency – 2012</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-of-autoimmunity-which-includes-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-of-autoimmunity-which-includes-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cd8-t-cell-deficiency-epstein-barr-virus-infection-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-steps-to-autoimmunity-a-unifying-hypothesis">CD8+ T-Cell Deficiency, Epstein-Barr Virus Infection, Vitamin D Deficiency, and Steps to Autoimmunity: A Unifying Hypothesis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmune Diseases, Volume 2012 (2012), Article ID 189096, 16 pages, Review Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael P. Pender 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Medicine, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD 4072, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Brisbane, QLD 4029, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 18 August 2011; Revised 3 October 2011; Accepted 16 October 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Academic Editor: Corrado Betterle&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IBD in Finland – 3X increase in 15 years, more prevalent further from equator</title><link>/posts/ibd-in-finland-3x-increase-in-15-years-more-prevalent-further-from-equator.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ibd-in-finland-3x-increase-in-15-years-more-prevalent-further-from-equator.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="high-and-increasing-prevalence-of-inflammatory-bowel-disease-in-finland-with-a-clear-north-south-difference">High and increasing prevalence of inflammatory bowel disease in Finland with a clear North-South difference.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Crohns Colitis. 2012 Nov 6. pii: S1873-9946(12)00429-1. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.crohns.2012.10.007.">doi: 10.1016/j.crohns.2012.10.007.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jussila A, Virta LJ, Salomaa V, Mäki J, Jula A, Färkkilä MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Gastroenterology and Alimentary Tract Surgery, Tampere University Hospital, Tampere, Finland; Seinäjoki Central Hospital, Seinäjoki, Finland. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:airi.jussila@fimnet.fi">airi.jussila@fimnet.fi&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND AIM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) prevalence has increased and a North-South gradient has been reported. We estimated the nationwide prevalence of IBD, ulcerative colitis (UC) and Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease (CD) in 1993, and prevalence of IBD in 2008, and assessed the geographical distribution of IBD in Finland. In addition, we investigated the vitamin D levels in a study population from a large, nationally representative health examination survey, the Health 2000 Survey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IBD surgery 5X more likely for non-caucasians with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ibd-surgery-5x-more-likely-for-non-caucasians-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ibd-surgery-5x-more-likely-for-non-caucasians-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Obese children with celiac disease had lower levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/obese-children-with-celiac-disease-had-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-children-with-celiac-disease-had-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-vitamin-d-deficiency-a-feature-of-pediatric-celiac-disease">Is vitamin D deficiency a feature of pediatric celiac disease?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab. 2012;25(5-6):607-10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Villanueva J, Maranda L, Nwosu BU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Massachusetts Medical School, Worcester, 01655, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Celiac disease (CD) is an autoimmune enteropathy characterized by villus atrophy and malabsorption of essential nutrients. Vitamin D deficiency has been described in autoimmune diseases, but its status in prepubertal children with CD has not been adequately studied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine the vitamin D status of prepubertal children with CD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More than half those with Crohn’s disease have less than 20ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/more-than-half-those-with-crohns-disease-have-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-half-those-with-crohns-disease-have-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D as a therapy for colitis: A systematic review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-as-a-therapy-for-colitis-a-systematic-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-as-a-therapy-for-colitis-a-systematic-review.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Journal of Crohn’s and ColitisVolume 6, Issue 4, May 2012, Pages 405–411&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Imogen Nicholsona, A. Mark Dalzella, Wael El-Mataryb, c, ,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Division of Paediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Nutrition, Alder Hey Children’s NHS Foundation Trust, Liverpool, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Section of Paediatric Gastroenterology, Department of Paediatrics, Faculty of Medicine, University of Manitoba, Winnipeg, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 20 November 2011. Revised 5 January 2012. Accepted 5 January 2012. Available online 27 January 2012.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gut doctors becoming aware of importance of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/gut-doctors-becoming-aware-of-importance-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gut-doctors-becoming-aware-of-importance-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="many-items-in-the-journal-gut-and-the-journal-of-crohns-and-colitis--spring-2012">Many items in the journal Gut and the Journal of Crohn&amp;rsquo;s and Colitis Spring 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="oc-037-vitamin-d-deficiency-is-common-in-intestinal-failure-patients">OC-037? Vitamin D deficiency is common in intestinal failure patients&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Gut 2012;61:A16 doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2012-302514a.37&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bapen symposium: “original communications”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Culkin, B Rye, C Hanson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>St Mark&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Harrow, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction Vitamin D is essential due to its role in bone health and its immunomodulatory propeties.1 Patients with intestinal failure (IF) are at risk of Vitamin D deficiency due to inadequate absorption and lack of exposure to UVB light. Deficiency has been demonstrated in IF patients dependent on home parenteral nutrition.2 We aimed to determine the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in hospital patients with IF and the efficacy of subsequent prescribed treatment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About 40 percent more likely to get Crohn’s Disease or UC if have low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/about-40-percent-more-likely-to-get-crohns-disease-or-uc-if-have-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/about-40-percent-more-likely-to-get-crohns-disease-or-uc-if-have-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gallbladder removal and vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/gallbladder-removal-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gallbladder-removal-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary">Summary&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-level-was-25-percent-lower-if-lack-a-gall-bladder--march2018">Vitamin D level was 25 percent lower if lack a gall bladder – March 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#demographics-overweight-middle-agedfemales">Demographics: Overweight, middle-aged females&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#strong-geneticcorrelation">Strong genetic correlation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#diarrhea-and-poor-digestion-of-vitamin-d-magnesium-etc-after-gallbladder-removal-varies-from-1-in-3-to-1-in100">Diarrhea (and poor digestion of Vitamin D, Magnesium, etc.) after gallbladder removal varies from 1 in 3 to 1 in 100&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#rats-without-any-bile-had-virtually-zero-vitamin-d-absorption--1987">Rats without any bile had virtually zero vitamin D absorption - 1987&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsoverview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-889overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-da-has-a-chart---the-following-is-a-portion-of-that-chart---showing-viciouscycles">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 889">Overview Deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/a> has a chart - the following is a portion of that chart - showing vicious cycles&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsoweb">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Gallbladder surgery is very common: 500,000 - 750,000 in the US each year&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>roughly 3% of adults have had gallbladder surgery&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crohn's disease kids are 2X more likely to have low vitamin D, intervention helps</title><link>/posts/crohns-disease-kids-are-2x-more-likely-to-have-low-vitamin-d-intervention-helps.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/crohns-disease-kids-are-2x-more-likely-to-have-low-vitamin-d-intervention-helps.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="changes-in-vitamin-d-and-parathyroid-hormone-metabolism-in-incident-pediatric-crohns-disease">Changes in vitamin D and parathyroid hormone metabolism in incident pediatric Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Aaron R. Prosnitz MD1, Mary B. Leonard MD, MSCE2,3, Justine Shults PhD3, Babette S. Zemel PhD2, Bruce W. Hollis PhD4, Lee A. Denson MD5, Robert N. Baldassano MD2, Aaron B. Cohen BS2, Meena Thayu MD, MSCE2,3,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Pediatrics, Yale-New Haven Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, New Haven, Connecticut&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Pediatrics, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Philadelphia, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crohn’s Disease strongly associated with low vitamin D in South Asians</title><link>/posts/crohns-disease-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-south-asians.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/crohns-disease-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-south-asians.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-adults-with-inflammatory-bowel-disease-potential-role-of-ethnicity">Hypovitaminosis D in Adults with Inflammatory Bowel Disease: Potential Role of Ethnicity.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dig Dis Sci. 2012 Mar 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fu YT, Chatur N, Cheong-Lee C, Salh B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Gordon and Leslie Diamond Health Care Centre, University of British Columbia, 5th Floor, 2775 Laurel St, Vancouver, BC, V5Z 1M9, Canada, &lt;a href="mailto:nfu@interchange.ubc.ca">nfu@interchange.ubc.ca&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Although vitamin D deficiency occurs in inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), it is currently unclear to what extent ethnicity affects vitamin D levels. Our aim was therefore to determine the ethnic variation in serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status and its association with disease severity in adults with IBD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More gut problems with a dark skinned people</title><link>/posts/more-gut-problems-with-a-dark-skinned-people.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-gut-problems-with-a-dark-skinned-people.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-phenotype-and-course-of-inflammatory-bowel-disease-in-uk-patients-of-bangladeshi-descent">The phenotype and course of inflammatory bowel disease in UK patients of Bangladeshi descent.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2012 Mar 9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2036.2012.05043.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2036.2012.05043.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goodhand JR, Kamperidis N, Joshi NM, Wahed M, Koodun Y, Cantor EJ, Croft NM, Langmead FL, Lindsay JO, Rampton DS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Digestive Diseases, Blizard Institute of Cell and Molecular Science, Barts and the London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: We have tested the hypotheses that compared with local white Caucasians, UK-resident patients of Bangladeshi descent develop inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) at a younger age; more often have Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease than ulcerative colitis (UC); and have a more aggressive disease course.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IBD less costly when treated with vitamin D3 compared to D2</title><link>/posts/ibd-less-costly-when-treated-with-vitamin-d3-compared-to-d2.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ibd-less-costly-when-treated-with-vitamin-d3-compared-to-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="differences-in-outcomes-between-cholecalciferol-and-ergocalciferol-supplementation-in-veterans-with-inflammatory-bowel-disease">Differences in outcomes between cholecalciferol and ergocalciferol supplementation in veterans with inflammatory bowel disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2012 Jan 10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1447-0594.2011.00798.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1447-0594.2011.00798.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Youssef D, Bailey B, Atia A, El-Abbassi A, Manning T, Peiris AN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Infectious Diseases Department of Family Medicine Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Gastroenterology Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology, East Tennessee State University Department of Medicine, Mountain Home VAMC, Johnson City, Tennessee, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reasons for low response to vitamin D</title><link>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#detailed-reasons-for-poor-response">Detailed Reasons for poor response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reasons-for-not-getting-benefits---span-stylecolorf00even-if-blood-tests-are-okspan">Reasons for not getting benefits - &lt;span style="color:#F00;">even if blood tests are OK&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsuv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual--2010big-differences-in-uvb-responsesa-20-to-36-ng-after-6-weeks">&lt;a href="/posts/uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: UV production of Vitamin D varies with the individual – 2010">Big differences in UVB responses&lt;/a>: 20 to 36 ng after 6 weeks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#alternate-sources-of-vitamin-d">Alternate sources of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/h4>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>~ 50% of all people have a low response to vitamin D3&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogs – like humans – with IBD were low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dogs-like-humans-with-ibd-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dogs-like-humans-with-ibd-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-dogs-with-inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-hypoalbuminaemia">Hypovitaminosis D in dogs with inflammatory bowel disease and hypoalbuminaemia.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>A G Gow, R Else, H Evans, J L Berry, M E Herrtage and R J Mellanby J Small Anim Pract 52(8):411-418 (2011) PMID 21797872&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To compare serum vitamin D metabolites and plasma parathyroid hormone concentrations in dogs with inflammatory bowel disease and normal albumin concentration, dogs with inflammatory bowel disease and hypoalbuminaemia, healthy dogs and hospitalised ill dogs with non-gastrointestinal illness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IBD UC and CD at risk of being vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/ibd-uc-and-cd-at-risk-of-being-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ibd-uc-and-cd-at-risk-of-being-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D might reduce military costs for UC and CD</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-might-reduce-military-costs-for-uc-and-cd.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-might-reduce-military-costs-for-uc-and-cd.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-veterans-with-inflammatory-bowel-disease-relationship-to-health-care-costs-and-services">Vitamin D Status in Veterans With Inflammatory Bowel Disease: Relationship to Health Care Costs and Services&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Military Medicine, Volume 176, Number 6, June 2011 , pp. 711-714(4)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Atia, Antwan1; Murthy, Ravindra2; Bailey, Beth A.3; Manning, Todd4; Garrett, Linda L.5; Youssef, Dima4; Peiris, Alan N.1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1: Department of Internal Medicine, East Tennessee State University, PO Box 70622, Johnson City, TN 37614.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2: Department of Internal Medicine, Mountain Home VAMC, Mountain Home, TN 37684.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IBD and Crohn but not Colitis associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ibd-and-crohn-but-not-colitis-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ibd-and-crohn-but-not-colitis-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-inflammatory-bowel-disease-association-with-disease-activity-and-quality-of-life">Vitamin d deficiency in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: association with disease activity and quality of life.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2011 May-Jun;35(3):308-16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ulitsky A, Ananthakrishnan AN, Naik A, Skaros S, Zadvornova Y, Binion DG, Issa M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Department of Medicine, Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, Wisconsin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency is common in inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). The aim of the study was to determine the prevalence and predictors of vitamin D deficiency in an IBD cohort. It was hypothesized that vitamin D deficiency is associated with increased disease activity and &lt;strong>lower health-related quality of life (HRQOL)&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crohn’s disease deficient in vitamin K – IBD deficient in vitamins K and D</title><link>/posts/crohns-disease-deficient-in-vitamin-k-ibd-deficient-in-vitamins-k-and-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/crohns-disease-deficient-in-vitamin-k-ibd-deficient-in-vitamins-k-and-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="association-of-vitamin-k-deficiency-with-bone-metabolism-and-clinical-disease-activity-in-inflammatory-bowel-disease">Association of vitamin K deficiency with bone metabolism and clinical disease activity in inflammatory bowel disease&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.nut.2010.10.021 Applied nutritional investigation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sachiko Nakajima M.D.a, Hideki Iijima M.D., Ph.D.a, Corresponding Author Contact Information, E-mail The Corresponding Author, Satoshi Egawa M.D., Ph.D.a, Shinichiro Shinzaki M.D., Ph.D.a, Jumpei Kondo M.D.a, Takahiro Inoue M.D.a, Yoshito Hayashi M.D.a, Jin Ying M.D.a, Akira Mukai M.D.a, Tomofumi Akasaka M.D.a, Tsutomu Nishida M.D., Ph.D.a, Tatsuya Kanto M.D., Ph.D.a, b, Masahiko Tsujii M.D., Ph.D.a and Norio Hayashi M.D., Ph.D.a&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>People with gut problems are low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/people-with-gut-problems-are-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-gut-problems-are-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-supplementation-in-pediatric-gastrointestinal-disease">Vitamin D status and supplementation in pediatric gastrointestinal disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Spec Pediatr Nurs. 2011 Apr;16(2):140-50. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1744-6155.2011.00280.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1744-6155.2011.00280.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O&amp;rsquo;Malley T, Heuberger R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tarah O&amp;rsquo;Malley MS, RD, was a Student, Central Michigan University, and is currently a Pediatric Dietitian, Clinical Dietitian, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Denver, Aurora, Colorado; and Roschelle Heuberger, PhD, RD, CWMS, is Associate Professor and Graduate Program Coordinator, Central Michigan University, Mount Pleasant, Michigan, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose.? To evaluate vitamin D status and supplementation in the pediatric population with common gastrointestinal diseases. The literature was searched for studies on vitamin D status in children with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), celiac disease, and liver disease. Vitamin D supplementation in healthy children was also reviewed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gastric bypass reduces vitamin D by at least 25 percent</title><link>/posts/gastric-bypass-reduces-vitamin-d-by-at-least-25-percent.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gastric-bypass-reduces-vitamin-d-by-at-least-25-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-absorption-consequences-of-gastric-bypass-surgery">Vitamin D Absorption: Consequences of Gastric Bypass Surgery.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Endocrinol. 2011 Feb 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aarts E, van Groningen L, Horst R, Telting D, van Sorge A, Janssen I, de Boer H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E Aarts, Surgery, Rijnstate Hospital, Arnhem, Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To develop a test that quantifies the changes in intestinal cholecalciferol absorption induced by Roux-en-Y gastric bypass (RYGB) surgery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Severe vitamin D deficiency is a common finding in morbid obesity, and the incidence increases markedly after RYGB. Normalisation of vitamin D levels after RYGB is difficult to achieve because the degree of surgery-induced malabsorption is not known.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IBD colorectal Cancer and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ibd-colorectal-cancer-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ibd-colorectal-cancer-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-gastrointestinal-diseases-inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-colorectal-cancer">Vitamin D and gastrointestinal diseases: inflammatory bowel disease and colorectal cancer&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Therap Adv Gastroenterol. 2011 January; 4(1): 49–62.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/1756283X10377820.">doi: 10.1177/1756283X10377820.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3036961&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maitreyi Raman; Division of Gastroenterology, University of Calgary, 6D26, Teaching, Research and Wellness Building, 3280 Hospital Drive N.W., Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 4N1; &lt;a href="mailto:mkothand@ucalgary.ca">mkothand@ucalgary.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andrew N. Milestone; St. Marks Hospital, Harrow, Middlesex, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Julian R.F. Walters; Division of Medicine, Imperial College Healthcare, London, Hammersmith Hospital, Imperial College London, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gut-Friendly Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/gut-friendly-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gut-friendly-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-article-at-the-bottom-of-this-page-got-vitamindwiki-interested-in-gut-friendly-forms-of-vitamin-d">The article at the bottom of this page got VitaminDWiki interested in gut-friendly forms of Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="bio-d-mulsion-forte-from-biotics-research-corporation-the-first-one-on-the-market">Bio-D-Mulsion Forte® from Biotics Research Corporation (The first one on the market)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>supplies 2,000 IU per drop of vitamin D3 as a micro-emulsion for enhanced absorption and utilization, which is particularly important for those with &lt;strong>malabsorption conditions&lt;/strong> . &amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$21 Amazon Sept 2018&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.bioticsresearch.com/node/1570">Biotics Research Description fo the 2,000 IU/ drop FORTE&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/click-here-for-details-and-updates" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 120">CLICK HERE for details and updates&lt;/a> on Bio-D-Mulsion Forte&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gluten Intolerance - with notes on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/gluten-intolerance-with-notes-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gluten-intolerance-with-notes-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="gluten-intolerance-a-growing-epidemic">Gluten Intolerance: A Growing Epidemic&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Strong hints of intolerance with low vitamin D, vitamin k2, and Magnesium&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Many people around the world have become deficient in all three during the past 4 decades&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Roundup is also suspected (which is used a few days before wheat is harvested)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="gluten-intolerance-disease-charthttpdrmarkrussellcomgluten-intolerance-lubbock-tx">&lt;a href="http://drmarkrussell.com/gluten-intolerance-lubbock-tx">Gluten Intolerance Disease Chart&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;584&amp;rdquo; max=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="natural-news-june-2011httpwwwnaturalnewscom032823_gluten_intolerance_celiac_diseasehtml-gluten-then-and-now">&lt;a href="http://www.naturalnews.com/032823_gluten_intolerance_celiac_disease.html">Natural News June 2011&lt;/a> Gluten then and now&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>CD is four times more common today that it was five decades ago&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>