<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trauma and Surgery on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/trauma-and-surgery.html</link><description>Recent content in Trauma and Surgery on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/trauma-and-surgery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chance of dying within 1 month of entering hospital is 45 percent higher if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chance-of-dying-within-1-month-of-entering-hospital-is-45-percent-higher-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chance-of-dying-within-1-month-of-entering-hospital-is-45-percent-higher-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="pre-hospital-vitamin-d-concentration-mortality-and-bloodstream-infection-in-a-hospitalized-patient-population">Pre-hospital Vitamin D Concentration, Mortality, and Bloodstream Infection in a Hospitalized Patient Population&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The American Journal of Medicine; Volume 126, Issue 7, July 2013, Pages 640.e19–640.e27&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nancy Lange, MD, MPHa,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Augusto A. Litonjua, MD, MPHb,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fiona K. Gibbons, MDc,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Edward Giovannucci, MD, ScDd,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kenneth B. Christopher, MDe, &lt;a href="mailto:kbchristopher@partners.org">kbchristopher@partners.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Pulmonary Division, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Boston, Mass&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Channing Laboratory and Pulmonary and Critical Care Division, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Boston, Mass&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No association of cardiac surgery outcome with vitamin D level – they were all low</title><link>/posts/no-association-of-cardiac-surgery-outcome-with-vitamin-d-level-they-were-all-low.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-association-of-cardiac-surgery-outcome-with-vitamin-d-level-they-were-all-low.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="low-vitamin-d-concentration-is-not-associated-with-increased-mortality-and-morbidity-after-cardiac-surgery">Low vitamin d concentration is not associated with increased mortality and morbidity after cardiac surgery.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2013 May 28;8(5):e63831. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0063831.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0063831.&lt;/a> Print 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turan A, Grady M, You J, Mascha EJ, Keeyapaj W, Komatsu R, Bashour CA, Sessler DI, Saager L, Kurz A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Outcomes Research, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, United States of America.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To determine the effect of vitamin D on postoperative outcomes in cardiac surgical patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One issue of Inflammation and Allergy-Drug Targets has vitamin D items behind paywall</title><link>/posts/one-issue-of-inflammation-and-allergy-drug-targets-has-vitamin-d-items-behind-paywall.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/one-issue-of-inflammation-and-allergy-drug-targets-has-vitamin-d-items-behind-paywall.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Studies are behind a &lt;a href="http://www.benthamdirect.org/pages/content.php?iadt%20">paywall&lt;/a> and the abstracts do no have much content&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Editorial: Vitamin D deficiency and Critical Illness.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christopher KB. No abstract available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D and Sepsis: From Associations to Causal Connections.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kempker JA, Martin GS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D in acute kidney injury.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Braun AB, Christopher KB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Efficacy of high-dose vitamin D supplementation in the critically ill.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perron RM, Lee P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D Intervention Trials in the Critically Ill.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schnedl C, Pieber TR, Amrein K.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Congenital heart surgery dropped vitamin D levels by 40 percent</title><link>/posts/congenital-heart-surgery-dropped-vitamin-d-levels-by-40-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/congenital-heart-surgery-dropped-vitamin-d-levels-by-40-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="impact-of-anesthesia-and-surgery-for-congenital-heart-disease-on-the-vitamin-d-status-of-infants-and-children">Impact of Anesthesia and Surgery for Congenital Heart Disease on the Vitamin D Status of Infants and Children:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A Prospective Longitudinal Study&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anesthesiology: July 2013 - Volume 119 - Issue 1 - p 71-80. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/ALN.0b013e31828ce817">doi: 10.1097/ALN.0b013e31828ce817&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>McNally, J. Dayre M.D., Ph.D.*; Menon, Kusum M.D., M.Sc.†; Chakraborty, Pranesh M.D.‡; Fisher, Lawrence B.Sc., A.R.T.§; Williams, Kathryn A. M.S.‖; Al-Dirbashi, Osama Y. Ph.D.#; Girolamo, Tara B.Sc.N.**; Maharajh, Gyaandeo M.D., C.M.††; Doherty, Dermot R. M.B., B.Ch., B.A.O., M.D.‡‡&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More sepsis deaths when active vitamin D (Calcitrol) was low</title><link>/posts/more-sepsis-deaths-when-active-vitamin-d-calcitrol-was-low.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-sepsis-deaths-when-active-vitamin-d-calcitrol-was-low.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-an-outcome-prognosticator-in-human-sepsis">Serum 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D: An Outcome Prognosticator in Human Sepsis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(5): e64348. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0064348&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nguyen HB, Eshete B, Lau KHW, Sai A, Villarin M, Baylink D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In sepsis, the vitamin D active metabolite 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)2D) may play a crucial role by its action to produce cathelicidin and improve endothelial barrier function, such that a deficiency in 1,25(OH)2D is associated with poor outcome. To test our hypothesis, we performed analysis of stored plasma samples from a prospective observational study in 91 patients with sepsis, age of 59.1+/−2.0 years, 52.7% females, and 11.0% deaths at 30 days. Vitamin D status, including 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D), 1,25(OH)2D, 24,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (24,25(OH)2D), and parathyroid hormone (PTH), were measured daily over 3 days after hospital admission. At baseline, 1,25(OH)2D was significantly different between survivors vs. non-survivors. But there was no significant difference in 25(OH)D, 24,25(OH)2D, and PTH. In a multivariable binomial logistic regression model, age, total calcium and 1,25(OH)2D were significant predictors of 30-day mortality. Kaplan Meier analysis showed that patients with mean 1,25(OH)2D measured over 3 days of &amp;lt; = 13.6 pg/mL had 57.1% 30-day survival compared to 91.7% in patients with 1,25 (OH)2D level &amp;gt;13.6 pg/mL (p&amp;lt;0.01). From repeated measures regression analysis, there was significant increase in 1,25(OH)2D for increases in 25(OH)D in both survivors and non-survivors. However, compared to survivors, the low 25(OH)D in non-survivors was insufficient to account for the larger decrease in 1,25(OH)2D, indicating a dysfunctional 1α-hydroxylase. Additionally, there was a significant negative correlation between PTH and 1,25(OH)2D in both survivors and non-survivors, suggesting a severe impairment in the effect of PTH to increase renal 1α-hydroxylase activity. In conclusion, low 1,25(OH)2D levels are associated with increased 30-day mortality in sepsis patients, likely due to impaired 25(OH)D hydroxylation and PTH insensitivity. Our data also suggest that the active metabolite 1,25(OH)2D may be an important therapeutic target in the design of sepsis clinical trials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low levels of vitamin D prior to spine surgery</title><link>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-prior-to-spine-surgery.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-prior-to-spine-surgery.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="preoperative-vitamin-d-status-of-adults-undergoing-surgical-spinal-fusion">Preoperative Vitamin D Status of Adults Undergoing Surgical Spinal Fusion&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Spine: 15 March 2013 - Volume 38 - Issue 6 - p 507–515&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stoker, Geoffrey E. BS; Buchowski, Jacob M. MD, MS; Bridwell, Keith H. MD; Lenke, Lawrence G. MD; Riew, K. Daniel MD; Zebala, Lukas P. MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Study Design. Retrospective investigation of cross-sectional data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective. To define the prevalence and determinants of preoperative vitamin D deficiency among adults undergoing spinal fusion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Use of ICU in month before death has increased to almost 30 pcnt</title><link>/posts/off-topic-use-of-icu-in-month-before-death-has-increased-to-almost-30-pcnt.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-use-of-icu-in-month-before-death-has-increased-to-almost-30-pcnt.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="change-in-end-of-life-care-for-medicare-beneficiariessite-of-death-place-of-care-and-health-care-transitions-in-2000-2005-and-2009">Change in End-of-Life Care for Medicare BeneficiariesSite of Death, Place of Care, and Health Care Transitions in 2000, 2005, and 2009&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>JAMA. 2013;309(5):470-477. doi:10.1001/jama.2012.207624. February 6, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joan M. Teno, MD, MS; Pedro L. Gozalo, PhD; Julie P. W. Bynum, MD, MPH; Natalie E. Leland, PhD; Susan C. Miller, PhD, MBA; Nancy E. Morden, MD, MPH; Thomas Scupp, BS; David C. Goodman, MD; Vincent Mor, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Importance A recent Centers for Disease Control and Prevention report found that more persons die at home. This has been cited as evidence that persons dying in the United States are using more supportive care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20 percent of Critically ill in India had undetectable vitamin D, and 62 percent died</title><link>/posts/20-percent-of-critically-ill-in-india-had-undetectable-vitamin-d-and-62-percent-died.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/20-percent-of-critically-ill-in-india-had-undetectable-vitamin-d-and-62-percent-died.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-critical-illness-and-its-influence-on-outcome-experience-from-tertiary-care-centre-in-north-india">Vitamin D Deficiency in Critical Illness and Its Influence on Outcome: Experience From Tertiary Care Centre in North India&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Critical Care Medicine: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/01.ccm.0000424989.62300.45">doi: 10.1097/01.ccm.0000424989.62300.45&lt;/a>, Oral Abstract Session: ABSTRACT Only, 774:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azim, Afzal; Ahmed, Armeen; Baronia, Arvind; Yadav, Subhash&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Vitamin D deficiency can range from 50% to 90% in select general population and has been associated with increased mortality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Limited studies are available on vitamin D deficiency in critically ill population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sepsis bacteria can be killed by blue as well as UV light</title><link>/posts/sepsis-bacteria-can-be-killed-by-blue-as-well-as-uv-light.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sepsis-bacteria-can-be-killed-by-blue-as-well-as-uv-light.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="blue-light-rescues-mice-from-potentially-fatal-pseudomonas-aeruginosa-burn-infection-efficacy-safety-and-mechanism-of-action">Blue light rescues mice from potentially fatal Pseudomonas aeruginosa burn infection: efficacy, safety, and mechanism of action.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2012 Dec 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dai T, Gupta A, Huang YY, Yin R, Murray CK, Vrahas MS, Sherwood M, Tegos GP, Hamblin MR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wellman Center for Photomedicine, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Blue light has attracted increasing attention due to its intrinsic antimicrobial effect without the addition of exogenous photosensitizers. However, the use of blue light for wound infections has not been established yet. In this study, we demonstrated the efficacy of blue light at &lt;strong>415 nm&lt;/strong> for treatment of acute, potentially lethal Pseudomonas aeruginosa burn infections in mice. In vitro studies demonstrated that the inactivation rate of P. aeruginosa cells by blue light was approximately 35-fold faster than that of keratinocytes (P=0.0014). Transmission electron microscopy revealed blue light mediated intracellular damage to P. aeruginosa cells. Fluorescence spectroscopy suggested that coproporphyrin III or/and uroporphyrin III are possibly the intracellular photosensitive chromophores associated with the blue light inactivation of P. aeruginosa. In vivo studies using an in vivo bioluminescence imaging technique and the area-under-the-bioluminescence-time-curve (AUBC) analysis showed that a single exposure of blue light at 55.8 J/cm(2), applied 30 min after bacterial inoculation to the infected mouse burns, reduced the AUBC by an approximately 100-fold in comparison with untreated and infected mouse burns (P&amp;lt;0.0001). Histological analysis and TUNEL assay indicated no significant damages in the mouse skin exposed to blue light at the effective antimicrobial dose. Survival analysis revealed that blue light increased the survival rate of infected mice from &lt;strong>18.2% to 100%&lt;/strong> (P&amp;lt;0.0001). In conclusion, blue light therapy may offer an effective and safe alternative to conventional antimicrobial therapy for P. aeruginosa burn infections.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Almost 6X more likely to die after coronary bypass if vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/almost-6x-more-likely-to-die-after-coronary-bypass-if-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/almost-6x-more-likely-to-die-after-coronary-bypass-if-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="pre-hospital-serum-vitamin-d-levels-and-mortality-following-coronary-artery-bypass-grafting">Pre-Hospital Serum Vitamin D Levels and Mortality Following Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Critical Care Medicine: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/01.ccm.0000424294.93940.c5">doi: 10.1097/01.ccm.0000424294.93940.c5&lt;/a>, Oral Abstract Session&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moromizato, Takuhiro; Litonjua, Augusto; Braun, Andrea; Gibbons, Fiona; Giovannucci, Edward; Christopher, Kenneth&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Whether the degree of vitamin D deficiency affects survival following coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) is not clear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypothesis: We hypothesize that pre-hospital vitamin D deficiency is associated with mortality following CABG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: We performed a retrospective cohort study between 2001 and 2010 in two teaching hospitals in Boston, Massachusetts utilizing an institutional Research Patient Data Registry. We studied 322 patients, age = 18 years, in whom 25(OH)D was measured prior to hospitalization. The exposure of interest was pre-admission 25(OH)D categorized a priori as deficiency in 25(OH)D (=15ng/mL), insufficiency (15-30 ng/mL) and sufficiency (=30ng/mL). The primary outcome was all cause mortality 90 days following CABG. Vital status was obtained from the Social Security Administration Death Master File. Associations between vitamin D groups and mortality were estimated by bivariable and multivariable logistic regression models.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypomagnesemia (low Magnesium) is very prevalent in ICU – 1999</title><link>/posts/hypomagnesemia-low-magnesium-is-very-prevalent-in-icu-1999.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypomagnesemia-low-magnesium-is-very-prevalent-in-icu-1999.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypomagnesemia">Hypomagnesemia&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of the American Society of Nephrology July 1, 1999 vol. 10 no. 7 1616-1622&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ZALMAN S. AGUS&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emeritus Professor of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence to Dr. Zalman S Agus, Medical Research Service (151), VA Medical Center, University and Woodland Avenues, Philadelphia, PA 19104. Phone: 215-823-4297; Fax: 215-823-4336; E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:agus@mail.med.upenn.edu">agus@mail.med.upenn.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypomagnesemia is a common entity occurring in up to 12% of hospitalized patients (1). The incidence rises to as high as 60 to 65% in patients in intensive care settings in which nutrition, diuretics, hypoalbuminemia, and aminoglycosides may play important roles (2,3,4).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D decrease during inflammation is probably due to interferons</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-decrease-during-inflammation-is-probably-due-to-interferons.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-decrease-during-inflammation-is-probably-due-to-interferons.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="circulating-interferon-γ-correlates-with-125ohd-and-the-125ohd-to-25ohd-ratio">Circulating interferon-γ correlates with 1,25(OH)D and the 1,25(OH)D-to-25(OH)D ratio.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cytokine. 2012 Oct;60(1):23-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cyto.2012.05.015.">doi: 10.1016/j.cyto.2012.05.015.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jun 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barker T, Martins TB, Kjeldsberg CR, Trawick RH, Hill HR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Orthopedic Specialty Hospital, Murray, UT 84107, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:tyler.barker@imail.org">tyler.barker@imail.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The mechanism responsible for the decrease in vitamin D status (i.e., plasma or serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentration) during inflammatory stress is unknown in humans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interferon (IFN)-γ is an inflammatory cytokine that regulates vitamin D metabolism in isolated immune cells, but data suggesting this regulation exists in vivo is lacking. The purpose of this study, therefore, was to associate circulating IFN-γ perturbations with 25(OH)D and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)D) alterations during inflammatory stress in young adults recovering from anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnesium may be an important way to treat brain trauma</title><link>/posts/magnesium-may-be-an-important-way-to-treat-brain-trauma.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/magnesium-may-be-an-important-way-to-treat-brain-trauma.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="your-bones-are-21-calciummagnesium-ratio-while-your-brain-is-more-like-21-mgca">Your bones are 2:1 calcium/magnesium ratio while your brain is more like 2:1 Mg:Ca&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-magnesium-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Magnesium and vitamin D">Overview Magnesium and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>which shows major decrease in Magnesium around the world during past 40 years&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There is a lot of interaction between Magnesiuma and Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/concussions-traumatic-brain-injury-getting-big-press-coverage-vitamin-d-might-be--and-a-solution">Concussions (traumatic brain injury) getting big press coverage, vitamin D might be both a cause and a solution&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D aided progesterone in reducing traumatic brain injury – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-aided-progesterone-in-reducing-traumatic-brain-injury-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-aided-progesterone-in-reducing-traumatic-brain-injury-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="comparison-of-the-administration-of-progesterone-versus-progesterone-and-vitamin-d-in-improvement-of-outcomes-in-patients-with-traumatic-brain-injury-a-randomized-clinical-trial-with-placebo-group">Comparison of the administration of progesterone versus progesterone and vitamin D in improvement of outcomes in patients with traumatic brain injury: A randomized clinical trial with placebo group&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Adv Biomed Res 2012, 1:58&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bahram Aminmansour 1, Hossein Nikbakht 1, Abbas Ghorbani 2, Majid Rezvani 1, Paiman Rahmani 1, Mostaffa Torkashvand 1, Mohammadamin Nourian1, Mehran Moradi 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Neurosurgery, Isfahan University Of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Neurology, Al-zahra Hospital, Isfahan University Of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>After bone fracture, vitamin D unchanged but 1,25(OH)(2) D decreased</title><link>/posts/after-bone-fracture-vitamin-d-unchanged-but-125oh2-d-decreased.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/after-bone-fracture-vitamin-d-unchanged-but-125oh2-d-decreased.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="longitudinal-study-of-vitamin-d-metabolites-following-long-bone-fracture">Longitudinal study of vitamin D metabolites following long bone fracture.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2012 Dec 21. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jbmr.1855.">doi: 10.1002/jbmr.1855.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Briggs AD, Kuan V, Greiller CL, Maclaughlin BD, Ramachandran M, Harris T, Timms PM, Venton TR, Vieth R, Norman AW, Griffiths CJ, Martineau AR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Primary Care and Public Health, Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London E1 2AB, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Animal models suggest a key role for dihydroxylated vitamin D metabolites in fracture healing, as evidenced by increases in serum concentration of 24R,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (24R,25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>(2) D) following long bone fracture. Human studies investigating the kinetics of serum concentrations of 24R,25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>(2) D, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>(2) D) and their parent metabolite 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) are lacking. We therefore conducted a longitudinal study to determine whether &lt;strong>total, free or bioavailable&lt;/strong> concentrations of these vitamin D metabolites fluctuate in humans following long bone fracture.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deadly amount of vitamin D speeds up recovery of crushed muscles in rats</title><link>/posts/deadly-amount-of-vitamin-d-speeds-up-recovery-of-crushed-muscles-in-rats.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/deadly-amount-of-vitamin-d-speeds-up-recovery-of-crushed-muscles-in-rats.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-increases-cellular-turnover-and-functionally-restores-the-skeletal-muscle-after-crush-injury-in-rats">Vitamin D Increases Cellular Turnover and Functionally Restores the Skeletal Muscle after Crush Injury in Rats&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The American Journal of Pathology] Dec 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ioannis Stratos∗, †, Zhengdong Li∗, Philipp Herlyn∗, Robert Rotter∗, Ann-Kathrin Behrendt∗, Thomas Mittlmeier†, Brigitte Vollmar∗, ,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∗ Institute for Experimental Surgery, University of Rostock, Rostock, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>† Department of Trauma and Reconstructive Surgery, University of Rostock, Rostock, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ajpath.2012.11.006">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ajpath.2012.11.006&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Insufficient skeletal muscle regeneration after injury often impedes the healing process and is accompanied by functional deficiencies or pain. The aim of our study was to provide evidence that vitamin D improves muscle healing after muscle injury. Therefore, we used male rats and induced an injury of the soleus muscle. After crush injury, animals received either 8.3 mg/kg (332,000 IU/kg) body weight vitamin D or vehicle solution, s.c. After assessment of muscle force at days 1, 4, 14, and 42 after injury, sampling of muscle tissue served for analysis of proliferation (5-bromo-2′-deoxyuridine IHC), apoptosis (ApopTag kit), satellite cells (paired-box protein 7 IHC), and prolyl-4-hydroxylase-β expression (Western blot analysis). Vitamin D application caused a significant increase in cell proliferation and a significant inhibition of apoptosis at day 4 after injury compared to control animals. The numbers of satellite cells were not influenced by the vitamin D application, but there was an increase in prolyl-4-hydroxylase-β expression, indicative of increased extracellular matrix proteins. This cellular turnover resulted in a faster recovery of contraction forces at day 42 in the vitamin D group. Current data support the hypothesis that vitamin D promotes the regenerative process in injured muscle. Thus, vitamin D treatment may represent a promising therapy to optimize recovery after injury.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Higher vitamin D levels associated with fewer vein clots decades later</title><link>/posts/higher-vitamin-d-levels-associated-with-fewer-vein-clots-decades-later.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/higher-vitamin-d-levels-associated-with-fewer-vein-clots-decades-later.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-and-risk-of-venous-thromboembolism-in-the-general-population-with-18791-participants">25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations and risk of venous thromboembolism in the general population with 18,791 participants.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Brøndum-Jacobsen P, Benn M, Tybjaerg-Hansen A, Nordestgaard BG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Herlev Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital, Denmark; The Copenhagen General Population Study, Herlev Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital, Denmark; The Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/blood-clot.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has potential antithrombotic effects suggesting that vitamin D analogs could be used as adjunctive antithrombotic agents. However, epidemiological evidence of an association between reduced 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations and risk of venous thromboembolism is lacking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficient children stayed in ICU almost 2 days longer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficient-children-stayed-in-icu-almost-2-days-longer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficient-children-stayed-in-icu-almost-2-days-longer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Extensive burns reduce vitamin D, which increase bone loss</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-extensive-burns-reduce-vitamin-d-which-increase-bone-loss.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-extensive-burns-reduce-vitamin-d-which-increase-bone-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="does-vitamin-d-deficiency-contribute-to-post-burn-bone-loss">Does vitamin D deficiency contribute to post-burn bone loss?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://f1000research.com/articles/does-vitamin-d-deficiency-contribute-to-post-burn-bone-loss/%20">URL&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gordon L Klein &lt;a href="mailto:gordonklein@ymail.com">gordonklein@ymail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation and Shriners Burns Hospital, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, Texas 77555, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burn injury results in the acute loss of bone as well as the development of progressive vitamin D deficiency. Bone loss occurs acutely due to resorption, which is then followed by apoptosis of osteoblasts preventing repair of the bone loss. The acute resorption is due to a combination of the inflammatory response and the stress response to the burn injury. The resultant production of inflammatory cytokines and endogenous glucocorticoids initially stimulate the osteoblasts to produce RANK ligand, which stimulates marrow stem cell differentiation into osteoclasts. As the stress response persists for approximately one year post-burn the glucocorticoids produced by the body will cause osteoblast apoptosis and adynamic bone, impairing the ability of bone to recover its resorptive losses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trauma and surgery</title><link>/posts/trauma-and-surgery.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/trauma-and-surgery.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#high-dose-vitamin-d-in-the-covid-icu---video-may-2023">High Dose Vitamin D in the (COVID) ICU - video May 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="high-dose-vitamin-d-in-the-covid-icu---video-may-2023">High Dose Vitamin D in the (COVID) ICU - video May 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n0aKls6AbME&amp;amp;ab_channel=Dr.EduardoBeltran">Dr. Eduardo Beltran&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this video, we shall talk about HLD (600K IU of vitamin D3) that was used in the intensive care unit (Brazil &amp;amp; Bolivia) used in patients who were diagnosed with SCV-2. Patients received their D3 via an NG tube while being intubated and connected to a ventilator. 26 out of 28 patients survived. The results speak for themselves.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Will lots of vitamin D help in ICU – RCT protocol</title><link>/posts/will-lots-of-vitamin-d-help-in-icu-rct-protocol.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/will-lots-of-vitamin-d-help-in-icu-rct-protocol.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Plasma exchange cut vitamin D levels in half</title><link>/posts/plasma-exchange-cut-vitamin-d-levels-in-half.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/plasma-exchange-cut-vitamin-d-levels-in-half.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Loss of muscle strength –sarcopenia – one of the suspects is vitamin D</title><link>/posts/loss-of-muscle-strength-sarcopenia-one-of-the-suspects-is-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/loss-of-muscle-strength-sarcopenia-one-of-the-suspects-is-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="sarcopenia-pharmacology-today-and-tomorrow">Sarcopenia: Pharmacology today and tomorrow&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Pharocology and Experimental Theraputics August 28, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marco P Brotto &lt;a href="mailto:brottom@umkc.edu">brottom@umkc.edu&lt;/a>, and Eduardo L Abreu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Missouri-Kansas City&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarcopenia remains largely undiagnosed and undertreated, because of the lack of a universally accepted definition, effective ways to measure it, and identification of the outcomes that should guide treatment efficacy. An ever growing number of clinicians and researchers along with funding and regulatory agencies have gradually recognized that sarcopenia is a human condition that requires both prevention and treatment. In this &amp;ldquo;Pharmacology in Perspective: article, we briefly reviewed sarcopenia; its common and less known pharmacological treatments, and attempted to define sarcopenia in its broader context, and presented some new ideas for potential future treatment for this devastating condition. ?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>With just 200 IU vitamin D in intravenous feeds, deficiency results</title><link>/posts/with-just-200-iu-vitamin-d-in-intravenous-feeds-deficiency-results.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/with-just-200-iu-vitamin-d-in-intravenous-feeds-deficiency-results.html</guid><description>&lt;p>!!Recommendations for Changes in Commercially Available Parenteral Multivitamin and Multi–Trace Element Products
&lt;strong>A.S.P.E.N. Position Paper&lt;/strong>
Nutr Clin Pract August 2012 vol. 27 no. 4 440-491
Vincent W. Vanek, MD, FACS, FASPEN (Chair)1
Peggy Borum, PhD, FASPEN2
Alan Buchman, MD, MSPH, FACP, FACG, FACN, AGAF3
Theresa A. Fessler, MS, RD, CNSC4
Lyn Howard, MB, FRCP5
Khursheed Jeejeebhoy, MBBS, PhD, FRCPC6
Marty Kochevar, MS, RPh, BCNSP7
Alan Shenkin, MB, ChB, PhD, FRCP, FRCPath8
Christina J. Valentine, MD, MS, RD9
&lt;strong>Novel Nutrient Task Force, Parenteral Multi-Vitamin and Multi–Trace Element Working Group&lt;/strong>
American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition (A.S.P.E.N.) Board of Directors
1 St. Elizabeth Health Center, Youngstown, Ohio
2 University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida
3 Northwestern University School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois
4 University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia
5 Albany Medical College, Albany, New York
6 Polyclinic, Toronto, Ontario
7 A.S.P.E.N., Silver Spring, Maryland
8 Royal Liverpool University Hospital, Liverpool, England
9 University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, Ohio
Vincent W. Vanek, St. Elizabeth Health Center, 1044 Belmont Ave, PO Box 1790, Youngstown, OH 44501-1790; e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:vince_vanek@hmis.org">vince_vanek@hmis.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Highest vitamin D increases after spine surgery associated with best outcomes</title><link>/posts/highest-vitamin-d-increases-after-spine-surgery-associated-with-best-outcomes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/highest-vitamin-d-increases-after-spine-surgery-associated-with-best-outcomes.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="changes-in-vitamin-d-status-after-surgery-in-female-patients-with-lumbar-spinal-stenosis-and-its-clinical-significance">Changes in Vitamin D Status After Surgery in Female Patients With Lumbar Spinal Stenosis and its Clinical Significance.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Kim TH, Yoon JY, Lee BH, Jung HS, Park MS, Park JO, Moon ES, Kim HS, Lee HM, Moon SH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Medical College of Hallym University, Anyang, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2012 Jul 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ABSTRACT: Study Design. Prospective cohort study&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D supplementation did not decrease LDL lipids – Ha!</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-did-not-decrease-ldl-lipids-ha.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-did-not-decrease-ldl-lipids-ha.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-may-not-improve-lipid-levels-a-serial-clinical-laboratory-data-studyhttpcircahajournalsorgcontentearly20120618circulationaha111077875abstract-circulation-june-2012">&lt;a href="http://circ.ahajournals.org/content/early/2012/06/18/CIRCULATIONAHA.111.077875.abstract">Vitamin D May Not Improve Lipid Levels: A Serial Clinical Laboratory Data Study&lt;/a> Circulation June 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Of the 108,000 people who had multiple vitamin D tests, 6,620 increased vitamin D levels from &amp;lt; 20 ng to &amp;gt;30 ng.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These increased vitamin D levels did not decrease the LDL levels.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="reasons-for-vitamin-d-levels-increasing-from-20-ng-to--30-ng-include">Reasons for vitamin D levels increasing from &amp;lt;20 ng to &amp;gt; 30 ng include:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Have recovered from surgery&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Have recovered from &lt;a href="/posts/trauma" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2042">trauma&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moderate and severe strokes 2X associated with low vitamin D – 2012</title><link>/posts/moderate-and-severe-strokes-2x-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-2012.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/moderate-and-severe-strokes-2x-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-2012.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D's potential to reduce the risk of hospital-acquired infections</title><link>/posts/vitamin-ds-potential-to-reduce-the-risk-of-hospital-acquired-infections.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-ds-potential-to-reduce-the-risk-of-hospital-acquired-infections.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="health-careassociated-and-hospital-acquired-infections-are-two-entities-associated-with-increased-morbidity-and-mortality-dermato-endrocinology-volume-4-issue-2---aprilmayjune-2012">Health care–associated and hospital-acquired infections are two entities associated with increased morbidity and mortality. Dermato Endrocinology Volume 4, Issue 2 April/May/June 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dima A. Youssef &lt;a href="mailto:estecina@hotmail.com">estecina@hotmail.com&lt;/a>, Tamra Ranasinghe, William B. Grant and Alan N. Peiris&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They are highly costly and constitute a great burden to the health care system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency (&amp;lt; 20 ng/ml) is prevalent and may be a key contributor to both acute and chronic ill health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is associated with decreased innate immunity and increased risk for infections.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5 days longer in ICU if low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/5-days-longer-in-icu-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5-days-longer-in-icu-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>If you are getting a lung transplant you must have vitamin D</title><link>/posts/if-you-are-getting-a-lung-transplant-you-must-have-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-you-are-getting-a-lung-transplant-you-must-have-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="press-release-april-2012httpwwwloyolamedicineorgnewsnews_releasesnews_release_detailcfmvar_news_release_id973441757">&lt;a href="http://www.loyolamedicine.org/News/News_Releases/news_release_detail.cfm?var_news_release_id=973441757">Press Release April 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="summary-lung-transplant-poor-if-vitamin-d-deficient">Summary: Lung transplant poor if vitamin D deficient&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2.4X more likely to reject the transplant&lt;br>
1.5X more likely to have infection&lt;br>
4.8X more likely to die within one year&lt;br>
      &amp;quot; The vitamin D supplementation most commonly utilized&lt;br>
     included ergocalciferol or cholecalciferol,&lt;br>
     which ranged from 1,000 IU daily to 50,000 IU once or twice weekly.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-shown-to-increase-rejection-rates-in-lung-transplant-patients">VITAMIN D DEFICIENCY SHOWN TO INCREASE REJECTION RATES IN LUNG TRANSPLANT PATIENTS&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>MAYWOOD, Ill. &amp;ndash; Vitamin D deficiency is associated with an increase in lung transplant rejection and infections, according to research conducted at Loyola University Health System (LUHS). Researchers also found that recipients who &lt;strong>remained deficient&lt;/strong> for one year following the transplant had a higher mortality rate than those who had normal vitamin D levels. These data were published in the latest issue of The Journal of Heart and Lung Transplantation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to reduce hospital infections with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/how-to-reduce-hospital-infections-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-reduce-hospital-infections-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sepsis associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/sepsis-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sepsis-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="there-are-two-items-on-this-page">There are two items on this page&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/icu-surgical-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-stayed-longer-and-had-more-sepsis">ICU surgical patients with low vitamin D stayed longer and had more sepsis – Dec 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-might-reduce-sepsis" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1855">Vitamin D might reduce sepsis&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/span-stylecolor00fmrsa-span-inpatient-cost-2x-higher-if-less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1753"> &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">MRSA &lt;/span>&lt;/strong> inpatient cost 2X higher if less than 20 ng vitamin D – June 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/staph-infection-reduced-50-percent-when-have-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d">Staph infection reduced 50 percent when have more than 30 ng of vitamin D – Aug 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shorter time in ICU if have higher level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/shorter-time-in-icu-if-have-higher-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shorter-time-in-icu-if-have-higher-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>ICU patients with pneumonia stay 7 days longer if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/icu-patients-with-pneumonia-stay-7-days-longer-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/icu-patients-with-pneumonia-stay-7-days-longer-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Many Organ transplants cause skin cancer – what is the role of UV</title><link>/posts/many-organ-transplants-cause-skin-cancer-what-is-the-role-of-uv.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-organ-transplants-cause-skin-cancer-what-is-the-role-of-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="photoprotection-in-transplant-recipients">Photoprotection in transplant recipients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Curr Probl Dermatol. 2012;43:171-96. Epub 2012 Feb 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Surber C, Pittelkow M, Lautenschlager S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, University Hospital of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skin cancers remain the most commonly diagnosed neoplasms among organ transplant recipients (OTRs), comprising nearly 40% of all posttransplant malignancies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The occurrence of skin tumors has a considerable impact on the quality of life and the overall survival of OTRs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet radiation (UVR) is the major environmental cause of nonmelanoma skin cancers, and it is therefore pivotal to protect the skin from UVR in order to prevent de novo and progression of preinvasive and invasive malignancies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Being vitamin D deficient in the ICU is not good</title><link>/posts/being-vitamin-d-deficient-in-the-icu-is-not-good.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/being-vitamin-d-deficient-in-the-icu-is-not-good.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Elderly surgical rehab in Germany - 67 pct have less than 10 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/elderly-surgical-rehab-in-germany-67-pct-have-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/elderly-surgical-rehab-in-germany-67-pct-have-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="epidemic-vitamin-d-deficiency-among-patients-in-an-elderly-care-rehabilitation-facility">Epidemic Vitamin D Deficiency Among Patients in an Elderly Care Rehabilitation Facility&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dtsch Arztebl Int 2012; 109(3): 33-8; DOI: 10.3238/arztebl.2012.0033&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schilling, S&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Geriatrische Rehabilitationsklinik St. Irminen, Trier: Dr. med. Schilling&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-seniors-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 28">Overview Seniors and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=64&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">All items in After Surgery or Trauma&lt;/a> 58 items Feb 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1765">Rehab patients vitamin D deficient - with chart Nov 2010.pdf&lt;/a> file&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/icu-needs-vitamin-d-vitamin-d-council">ICU needs vitamin D - Vitamin D Council Sept 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nursing home residents 2X more likely to die of some surgeries – perhaps lack vitamin D</title><link>/posts/nursing-home-residents-2x-more-likely-to-die-of-some-surgeries-perhaps-lack-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nursing-home-residents-2x-more-likely-to-die-of-some-surgeries-perhaps-lack-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="major-abdominal-surgery-in-nursing-home-residents-a-national-study">Major Abdominal Surgery in Nursing Home Residents: A National Study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Annals of Surgery: December 2011 - Volume 254 - Issue 6 - p 921–926&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/SLA.0b013e3182383a78">doi: 10.1097/SLA.0b013e3182383a78&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finlayson, Emily MD &lt;a href="mailto:emily.finlayson@ucsfmedctr.org">emily.finlayson@ucsfmedctr.org&lt;/a> &lt;em>,†; Wang, Li PhD‡; Landefeld, C. Seth MD§,¶; Dudley, R. Adams MD†,&lt;/em>*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To determine surgical risk in nursing home residents undergoing major abdominal surgery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Recent studies suggest that surgery can be performed safely in the very old. Surgical risk in nursing home residents is poorly understood.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels of critically ill patients reduced 35 pct after blood dilution</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-of-critically-ill-patients-reduced-35-pct-after-blood-dilution.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-of-critically-ill-patients-reduced-35-pct-after-blood-dilution.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="acute-fluid-shifts-influence-the-assessment-of-serum-vitamin-d-status-in-critically-ill-patients">Acute fluid shifts influence the assessment of serum vitamin D status in critically ill patients.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Crit Care. 2010;14(6):R216. Epub 2010 Nov 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Krishnan A, Ochola J, Mundy J, Jones M, Kruger P, Duncan E, Venkatesh B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Intensive Care Unit, Princess Alexandra Hospital, University of Queensland, Ipswich Road, Woolloongabba, QLD 4102, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Recent reports have highlighted the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency and suggested an association with excess mortality in critically ill patients. Serum vitamin D concentrations in these studies were measured following resuscitation. It is unclear whether aggressive fluid resuscitation independently influences serum vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20 percent change in vitamin D levels of critically ill during a 24 hour period</title><link>/posts/20-percent-change-in-vitamin-d-levels-of-critically-ill-during-a-24-hour-period.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/20-percent-change-in-vitamin-d-levels-of-critically-ill-during-a-24-hour-period.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Critical Care patients need vitamin D</title><link>/posts/critical-care-patients-need-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/critical-care-patients-need-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="summary-of-studies-of-icu-and-vitamin-d-levels-as-of-jan-2012">Summary of studies of ICU and Vitamin D levels as of Jan 2012&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Year&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>ICU problem&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>If vitamin D less than&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2011 this page&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>85 % increased death&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>20 ng&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;a href="/posts/2011" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2018">2011&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>85 % increased death&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>15 ng&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;a href="/posts/2011" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1326">2011&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>70 % increased death&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>15ng&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;a href="/posts/2011" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1428">2011&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>2X more likely to stay 2 days&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>20 ng&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="future-icu-vitamin-d-options-seem-to-include-opinion-by-vitamindwiki">Future ICU Vitamin D Options seem to include (opinion by VitaminDWiki)&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Give every ICU patient vitamin D3 orally&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>-Perhaps faster if sub-lingual or IV (is sublingual D3 as available as IV?)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Give D3 daily vs a single dose as was done for the RCT&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Septic shock and low vitamin D in children</title><link>/posts/septic-shock-and-low-vitamin-d-in-children.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/septic-shock-and-low-vitamin-d-in-children.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="septic-shock-and-vasopressor-requirement-is-associated-with-lower-vitamin-d-levels-in-critically-ill-children">Septic shock and vasopressor requirement is associated with lower vitamin D levels in critically ill children&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>K Madden1,2*, HA Feldman3,4,5, E Smith1, CM Gordon3,5,6, S Keisling1, R Sullivan1, BW Hollis7, AA Agan1 and AG Randolph1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Corresponding author: K Madden&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Author Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Anesthesia, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Boston, MA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Anaesthesia, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Division of Endocrinology, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Boston, MA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 The Clinical Research Program, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Boston, MA, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ICU surgical patients with low vitamin D stayed longer and had more sepsis</title><link>/posts/icu-surgical-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-stayed-longer-and-had-more-sepsis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/icu-surgical-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-stayed-longer-and-had-more-sepsis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-critically-ill-surgical-patients">Effects of vitamin D deficiency in critically ill surgical patients&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Presented at the 2011 annual meeting of the Midwest Surgical Association, Galena, Illinois.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The American Journal of Surgery; doi:10.1016/j.amjsurg.2011.09.012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lisa Flynn M.D.a, Lisa Hall Zimmerman Pharm.D.b, Kelly McNorton Pharm.D.b, Mortimer Dolman M.D.c, James Tyburski M.D.a, Alfred Baylor M.D.a, Robert Wilson M.D.a, Heather Dolman M.D.a, &lt;a href="mailto:hdolman@med.wayne.edu">hdolman@med.wayne.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a	Department of Surgery, Wayne State University, School of Medicine, Detroit Receiving Hospital, Detroit Medical Center, Detroit, MI, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels low both before and after organ transplant</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-low-both-before-and-after-organ-transplant.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-low-both-before-and-after-organ-transplant.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-in-organ-transplantation">Vitamin D in organ transplantation.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Jul;22(7):2107-18. Epub 2011 Jan 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stein EM, Shane E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Columbia University Medical Center, 630 West 168th Street, PH8-864, New York, NY 10032, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:es2029@columbia.edu">es2029@columbia.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is prevalent among patients with end-stage organ failure awaiting transplant. Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) levels in these patients may be related to many disease-specific factors, as well as decreased sunlight exposure and limited intake of foods containing vitamin D. Low serum 25-OHD levels are also extremely common following solid organ transplantation, both during the immediate postoperative period and in long-term graft recipients. Demographic and lifestyle factors are important in determining D status in transplant recipients. Worse vitamin D status is associated with poorer general health, lower albumin, and even decreased survival among these patients. Although several studies have demonstrated that active forms of vitamin D and its analogues prevent bone loss following transplantation, the data do not show consistent benefit. These therapies may have particular utility after renal transplantation. However, given the narrow therapeutic window with respect to hypercalcemia and hypercalciuria, and the demonstrated efficacy of bisphosphonates to prevent post-transplantation bone loss, we regard these agents as adjunctive rather than primary therapy for transplantation osteoporosis. The effects of 1,25(OH)(2)D on the immune system, which are still being elucidated, may have potential for reducing infections and preventing allograft rejection after transplantation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Survive surgery 3X better if overweight – Hypothesis - due to vitamin D released from fat</title><link>/posts/survive-surgery-3x-better-if-overweight-hypothesis-due-to-vitamin-d-released-from-fat.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/survive-surgery-3x-better-if-overweight-hypothesis-due-to-vitamin-d-released-from-fat.html</guid><description>&lt;p>190,000 surgeries; 3,200 died within 30 days&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chance of dying – which ranged from 14% to 0.1% depending on surgery type&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2.8 % for BMI &amp;lt; 23&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;1 % for BMI &amp;gt; 35&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact:&lt;/strong> Surgery reduces vitamin D levels&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact:&lt;/strong> Higher level of Vitamin D after surgery reduces chance of death&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Suspect:&lt;/strong> Vitamin D stored in the fat becomes available to post-surgery&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Recommend:&lt;/strong> Take lots of vitamin D before and after surgery&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinal fusion patients often low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/spinal-fusion-patients-often-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-fusion-patients-often-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="lower-levels-of-vitamin-d-may-put-spinal-fusion-patients-at-risk-study-findshttpwwwjsonlinecomfeatureshealthlower-levels-of-vitamin-d-may-put-spinal-fusion-patients-at-risk-study-finds-133155178html">&lt;a href="http://www.jsonline.com/features/health/lower-levels-of-vitamin-d-may-put-spinal-fusion-patients-at-risk-study-finds-133155178.html">Lower levels of vitamin D may put spinal fusion patients at risk, study finds&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>57% inadequate (&amp;lt; 30 ng)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>27% deficient (20 ng)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4% severe deficient (&amp;lt; 10 ng)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The paper, presented Thursday at the North American Spine Society annual meeting,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Buchowski said the idea of checking vitamin D levels of patients first occurred to him in 2008.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A woman in her 40s who had undergone cervical fusion surgery and did not get an adequate fusion told him that she had been treated for a vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CV event 56 percent more likely after vascular surgery if low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cv-event-56-percent-more-likely-after-vascular-surgery-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cv-event-56-percent-more-likely-after-vascular-surgery-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-boosts-postsurgical-cv-events">Low Vitamin D Boosts Postsurgical CV Events&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Volume 9, Issue 10, Page 32 (October 2011) Cardiology News&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Annual Congress of the European Society of Cardiology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MITCHEL L. ZOLER&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Major Finding: During the 30 days following vascular surgery, patients with severe vitamin D deficiency at baseline had a statistically significant, 56% increased rate of cardiovascular events, compared with patients with sufficient plasma levels of vitamin D in a multivariate analysis that controlled for baseline differences in demographics, medical history, and medication.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ICU needs vitamin D - Vitamin D Council</title><link>/posts/icu-needs-vitamin-d-vitamin-d-council.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/icu-needs-vitamin-d-vitamin-d-council.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-critical-illness">Vitamin D and critical illness&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>clips from a post September 30, 2011 by Dr John Cannell&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="you-can-subscribe-to-his-vitamin-d-posts-for-5-a-monthhttpwwwvitamindcouncilorg">You can &lt;a href="http://www.vitamindcouncil.org/">subscribe to his Vitamin D posts for $5 a month&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Lee P. Vitamin D metabolism and deficiency in critical illness. - see below&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“Collectively these results provide unequivocal evidence that vitamin D insufficiency and deficiency are highly prevalent among critically ill patients.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“These results demonstrate current replacement regimes are grossly inadequate.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>He ends by citing studies showing death in the ICU and the CCU is 2-3 times higher for the vitamin D deficient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces lung damage due to radiotherapy</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-lung-damage-due-to-radiotherapy.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-lung-damage-due-to-radiotherapy.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-prophylaxis-on-radiation-induced-pulmonary-damage">The effect of vitamin d prophylaxis on radiation induced pulmonary damage.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Radiat Res (Tokyo). 2011;52(5):616-21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yazici G, Yildiz F, Iskit A, Erdemli E, Surucu S, Firat P, Hayran M, Ozyigit G, Cengiz M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Radiation Oncology, Hacettepe University, Faculty of Medicine.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolor00fpdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-this-pagespan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has a selective radio and chemosensitizing effect on tumor cells. In vitro and in vivo studies have shown that vitamin D inhibits collagen gel construction, induces type II pneumocyte proliferation and surfactant synthesis in the lungs, and decreases vascular permeability caused by radiation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fat soluable vitamins decrease quickly after trauma</title><link>/posts/fat-soluable-vitamins-decrease-quickly-after-trauma.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fat-soluable-vitamins-decrease-quickly-after-trauma.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="in-letter-to-editor-doi-103945ajcn111019539httpsdoiorg103945ajcn111019539">In Letter to editor &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3945/ajcn.111.019539.">doi: 10.3945/ajcn.111.019539.&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-is-a-reliable-indicator-of-vitamin-d-status">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D is a reliable indicator of vitamin D status&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Dear Sir:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reid et al (1) reported a decrease in plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>, both total and free, after knee arthroplasty (1). Baseline 25(OH)D values in their patients averaged 40 nmol/L, well below even the most conservative lower limit of adequacy (2). By5dpost-surgery, this concentration had dropped by more than 25%; and by 3 mo, that deficit had still not been repaired. The authors concluded that serum 25(OH)D is thus not a reliable measure of vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Critical Care patients with less than 15 ng vitamin D were 85 percent more likely to die</title><link>/posts/critical-care-patients-with-less-than-15-ng-vitamin-d-were-85-percent-more-likely-to-die.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/critical-care-patients-with-less-than-15-ng-vitamin-d-were-85-percent-more-likely-to-die.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Active form of vitamin D (calcitriol) cut in half the fractures following organ transplant – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/active-form-of-vitamin-d-calcitriol-cut-in-half-the-fractures-following-organ-tr-t-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-form-of-vitamin-d-calcitriol-cut-in-half-the-fractures-following-organ-tr-t-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Staph infection reduced 50 percent when have more than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/staph-infection-reduced-50-percent-when-have-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/staph-infection-reduced-50-percent-when-have-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="staphylococcus-aureus-nasal-carriage-is-associated-with-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-gender-and-smoking-status-the-tromsø-staph-and-skin-study">Staphylococcus aureus nasal carriage is associated with serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels, gender and smoking status. The Tromsø Staph and Skin Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2011 Aug 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olsen K, Falch BM, Danielsen K, Johannessen M, Ericson Sollid JU, Thune I, Grimnes G, Jorde R, Simonsen GS, Furberg AS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Microbiology and Infection Control, University Hospital of North Norway, 9038, Tromsø, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:karina.olsen@unn.no">karina.olsen@unn.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D induces the expression of antimicrobial peptides with activity against Staphylococcus aureus. Thus, we studied the association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and S. aureus nasal colonization and carriage. Nasal swabs, blood samples and clinical data from 2,115 women and 1,674 men, aged 30-87 years, were collected in the Tromsø Staph and Skin Study 2007-08, as part of the population-based sixth Tromsø Study. Multivariate logistic regression analyses were stratified by recognized risk factors for S. aureus carriage: sex, age and smoking. In non-smoking men, we observed a 6.6% and 6.7% decrease in the probability of S. aureus colonization and carriage, respectively, by each 5 nmol/l increase in serum 25(OH)D concentration (P?&lt;?0.001 and P?=?0.001), and serum 25(OH)D?>?59 nmol/l and ?75 nmol/l as thresholds for ~30% and ~50% reduction in S. aureus colonization and carriage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Higher vitamin D helps regain muscle strength after knee surgery</title><link>/posts/higher-vitamin-d-helps-regain-muscle-strength-after-knee-surgery.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/higher-vitamin-d-helps-regain-muscle-strength-after-knee-surgery.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-vitamin-d-impairs-strength-recovery-after-anterior-cruciate-ligament-surgery">Low Vitamin D Impairs Strength Recovery After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Surgery&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="low-vitamin-d-impairs-strength-recovery-after-anterior-cruciate-ligament-surgery">Low Vitamin D Impairs Strength Recovery After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Surgery&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Tyler Barker, PhD &lt;a href="mailto:tyler.barker@imail.org">tyler.barker@imail.org&lt;/a>; The Orthopedic Specialty Hospital, Murray, UT, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thomas B. Martins, MS; ARUP Laboratories, Institute for Clinical and Experimental Pathology, Salt Lake City, UT, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harry R. Hill, MD; ARUP Laboratories, Institute for Clinical and Experimental Pathology, Salt Lake City, UT, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carl R. Kjeldsberg; ARUP Laboratories, Institute for Clinical and Experimental Pathology, Salt Lake City, UT, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sepsis is both prevented and treated by Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/sepsis-is-both-prevented-and-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sepsis-is-both-prevented-and-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary-of-sepsis-and-vitamin-d">Summary of Sepsis and Vitamin D&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki-recommendations-for-vitamin-d-treatment-of-sepsis-in-icu">VitaminDWiki recommendations for Vitamin D treatment of sepsis in ICU&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#people-with-sepis-have-poor-guts-vitamin-d-less-bio-available---perplexity-ai-june-2024">People with Sepis have poor guts (Vitamin D less bio-available) - Perplexity AI June 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#69100-hits-for-sepsis-vitamin-d---feb-2025-google-scholar">69,100 hits for sepsis &amp;ldquo;vitamin d&amp;rdquo; - Feb 2025 (Google Scholar)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#is-sepsis-treated-by-vitamin-d---asked-httpssearchsciphiai-jan-2024">Is sepsis treated by &amp;ldquo;Vitamin d&amp;rdquo;? - asked &lt;a href="https://search.sciphi.ai/">https://search.sciphi.ai/&lt;/a> Jan 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-in-icu-43-less-likely-to-die-in-30-days-if-happened-to-have-been-taking-vitamin-d--jan-2025">Sepsis in ICU: 43% less likely to die in 30 days if happened to have been taking vitamin D – Jan 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#no-consensus-on-sepsis-and-vitamin-d-type-amount-when-how-often---july-2023">No Consensus on Sepsis and Vitamin D: Type, Amount, When, How Often - July 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-an-underestimated-factor-in-sepsis--feb-2023">Vitamin D Deficiency: An Underestimated Factor in Sepsis? – Feb 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-strongly-associated-with-both-low-vitamin-d-and-poor-vitamin-d-receptors---jan2022">Sepsis strongly associated with both low vitamin D and poor Vitamin D Receptors - Jan 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#micronutrients-in-sepsis-and-covid-19-mostly-vitamin-d--april2021">Micronutrients in Sepsis and COVID-19 (mostly Vitamin D)- April 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-death-19-x-higher-risk-if-10-ng-of-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-march2020">Sepsis death 1.9 X higher risk if &amp;lt;10 ng of Vitamin D - meta-analysis March 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#200000-and-400000-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-septic-shock-length-of-stay---rct-june2015">200,000 and 400,000 IU of vitamin D reduced septic shock, length of stay - RCT June 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#12-x-more-likely-to-recover-from-septic-shock-in-24-hours-if-you-have-a-higher-level-of-vitamin-d--10-ng--2017">12 X more likely to recover from Septic Shock in 24 hours if you have a higher level of vitamin D (&amp;gt; 10 ng?) - 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-injection-of-300000-iu-of-vitamin-d-helped-in-a-small-rct---feb2017">Sepsis injection of 300,000 IU of vitamin D helped in a small RCT - Feb 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#two-meta-analyses-of-icu-and-vitamin-d---april-and-may2017">Two Meta-analyses of ICU and Vitamin D - April and May 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#high-dose--maint-dose-vitamin-d-reduce-mortality--large-rct2014">High dose + maint. dose Vitamin D reduce mortality – large RCT 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-only-people-who-died-of-sepsis-in-the-hospital-were-vitamin-d-deficient--april2017">The only people who died of sepsis in the hospital were vitamin D deficient – April 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-death-in-women-18x-more-likely-if-very-low-vitamin-d-nov2018">Sepsis death in women 1.8X more likely if very low vitamin D Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#review-of-vitamin-monotherapy-for-sepsis-vitamin-c-or-vitamin-d---july2021">Review of vitamin monotherapy for Sepsis: Vitamin C or Vitamin D - July 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#meta-analysis-concludes-sepsis-18-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---june2015">Meta-analysis concludes: Sepsis 1.8 X more likely if low vitamin D - June 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d---a-new-hope-for-septic-shock---july2013">Vitamin D - a new hope for septic shock - July 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-and-vitamin-d-inchildren">Sepsis and Vitamin D in children&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki">VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#role-of-vitamin-d-and-parathyroid-hormone-levels-in-prediction-of-late-onset-sepsis-among-preterm-infants---june-2024">Role of Vitamin D and Parathyroid Hormone Levels In Prediction of Late Onset Sepsis among Preterm Infants - June 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#neonatal-sepsis-47-x-more-likely-if-mother-was-vitamin-d-insufficient---feb2020">Neonatal Sepsis 4.7 X more likely if mother was Vitamin D insufficient - Feb 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#most-sepsis-children-also-have-a-chronic-disease-both-low-vitamin-d--aug2018">Most Sepsis children also have a chronic disease (both low vitamin D) – Aug 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-in-infants-8x-higher-if-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-india--june2021">Sepsis in infants 8X higher if less than 30 ng of vitamin D (India) – June 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-small-amount-of-vitamin-d-helped-children-with-sepsis---may-2020rct">A small amount of vitamin D helped children with Sepsis - May 2020 RCT&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-72-or-more-hours-after-birth-17-x-higher-risk-if-low-vitamin-d---nov2018">Sepsis 72 or more hours after birth: 1.7 X higher risk if low Vitamin D - Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#infants-with-sepsis-have-very-low-vitamin-d-levels--aug2014">Infants with sepsis have very low Vitamin D levels – Aug 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#neonatal-sepsis-48-x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor--june2018">Neonatal Sepsis 4.8 X more likely if poor Vitamin D receptor – June 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#neonates-are-17-x-more-likely-to-get-sepsis-if-they-low-vitamin-d-mothers-had-low-levels-as-well---july2018">Neonates are 1.7 X more likely to get Sepsis if they low vitamin D, mothers had low levels as well - July 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-in-general">Sepsis in general&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#is-sepsis-responsible-for-20-of-deaths-worldwide-asked-chat-gpt-jan-2-2024">Is Sepsis Responsible for 20% of Deaths Worldwide?: Asked Chat-GPT Jan 2, 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-overlaps-with-systemic-inflammatory-responsesyndrome">Sepsis overlaps with Systemic Inflammatory Response Syndrome&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-incidence-and-mortality-are-higher-than-many-other-healthproblems">Sepsis incidence and mortality are higher than many other health problems&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#severe-sepsis-increased-35x-in-adecade">Severe sepsis increased 3.5X in a decade.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#subtile-signs-of-sepsis---pintrest-2018httpswwwpinterestcompin544794886167487408">&lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/544794886167487408/">Subtile Signs of Sepsis - Pintrest -2018&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-myths-andfactshttpswwwpinnaclehealthorgwellness-libraryblog-and-staywellblog-homepostsepsis-the-silent-killer">&lt;a href="https://www.pinnaclehealth.org/wellness-library/blog-and-staywell/blog-home/post/sepsis-the-silent-killer">Sepsis Myths and Facts&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#i-nearly-died-from-sepsis--and-ignorance-of-this-condition-is-killing-millionshttpstheconversationcomi-nearly-died-from-sepsis-and-ignorance-of-this-condition-is-killing-millions-99051__-july2018">&lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/i-nearly-died-from-sepsis-and-ignorance-of-this-condition-is-killing-millions-99051#_=_">I nearly died from sepsis – and ignorance of this condition is killing millions&lt;/a>. July 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-treatment-other-than-vitamin-d">Sepsis treatment other than Vitamin D&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#flccc-sepsis-at-home-melatonin-vit-c-zinc-quercetin-curcumin-pre--probiotics---sept-2023">FLCCC: Sepsis at home: Melatonin, Vit. C, Zinc, Quercetin, Curcumin, Pre &amp;amp; Probiotics: - Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-c-perhaps-reducessepsis">Vitamin C perhaps reduces Sepsis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#update-on-vitamin-cocktail-without-vitamin-d---may2018">Update on Vitamin cocktail (without Vitamin D) - May 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-best-treated-by-thiamine-b1---vitamin-d-selenium-etc-also-considered---literature-review-july2018">Sepsis best treated by Thiamine (B1) - Vitamin D, Selenium, etc. also considered - literature review July 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="summary-of-sepsis-and-vitamin-d">Summary of Sepsis and Vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sepsis is more likely in those with poor immune systems&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Infants, the elderly, the sick, and those with low vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stem Cell Transplants consume vitamin D</title><link>/posts/stem-cell-transplants-consume-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stem-cell-transplants-consume-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="2-items-on-this-page">2 items on this page&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="high-incidence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-undergoing-allogeneic-stem-cell-transplantation--letter">High incidence of vitamin D deficiency in patients undergoing allogeneic stem cell transplantation – Letter&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Richard W. Joseph1,*,†; Amin Alousi1; Bhavana Konda2; Krishna Komanduri3; Joyce Neumann1; Cindy Trevino1; Karen Stolar1; Muzaffar Qazibash1; Chitra Hosing1; Partow Kebriaei1; Daniel R. Couriel1; Richard E. Champlin1; Rima Saliba1; Uday Popat1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Stem Cell Transplant and Cellular Therapy, MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, TX&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Internal Medicine, University of Miami Miller School of Medicine, Regional Campus, Atlantis, FL&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart transplant 19 ng vitamin D vs liver transplant 13 ng</title><link>/posts/heart-transplant-19-ng-vitamin-d-vs-liver-transplant-13-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-transplant-19-ng-vitamin-d-vs-liver-transplant-13-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="severe-vitamin-d-deficiency-among-heart-and-liver-transplant-recipients">Severe vitamin D deficiency among heart and liver transplant recipients&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Emily M. Stein, Adi Cohen, Matthew Freeby, Halley Rogers, Shannon Kokolus, Vanessa Scott, Donna Mancini, Susan Restaino, Robert Brown, Donald J. McMahon, and Elizabeth Shane ; &lt;a href="mailto:es54@columbia.edu">es54@columbia.edu&lt;/a>, Department of Medicine, College of Physicians and Surgeons, Columbia University, New York, NY, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clin Transplant. 2009 Nov-Dec; 23(6): 861–865.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2009 April 23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-0012.2009.00989.x">doi: 10.1111/j.1399-0012.2009.00989.x&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Although patients with end-stage organ failure are at high risk for vitamin D deficiency because of limited sunlight exposure and hepatic dysfunction, few studies have measured 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25OHD) at the time of transplantation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MRSA inpatient cost 2X higher if less than 20 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mrsa-inpatient-cost-2x-higher-if-less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mrsa-inpatient-cost-2x-higher-if-less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="healthcare-costs-of-methicillin-resistant-staphylococcus-aureus-and-pseudomonas-aeruginosa-infections-in-veterans-role-of-vitamin-d-deficiency">Healthcare costs of methicillin resistant Staphylococcus aureus and Pseudomonas aeruginosa infections in veterans: role of vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2011 Jun 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Youssef D, Bailey B, El-Abbassi A, Vannoy M, Manning T, Moorman JP, Peiris AN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Infectious Diseases, East Tennessee State University, Johnson City, TN, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:estecina@hotmail.com">estecina@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methicillin resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) and Pseudomonas aeruginosa (P. aeruginosa) infections are frequently associated with hospitalization and increased healthcare costs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Knee surgery reduced vitamin D by 40 percent in 2 days</title><link>/posts/knee-surgery-reduced-vitamin-d-by-40-percent-in-2-days.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/knee-surgery-reduced-vitamin-d-by-40-percent-in-2-days.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-relation-between-acute-changes-in-the-systemic-inflammatory-response-and-plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-after-elective-knee-arthroplasty">The relation between acute changes in the systemic inflammatory response and plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations after elective knee arthroplasty.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 May;93(5):1006-11. Epub 2011 Mar 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reid D, Toole BJ, Knox S, Talwar D, Harten J, O&amp;rsquo;Reilly DS, Blackwell S, Kinsella J, McMillan DC, Wallace AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Anaesthesia, Faculty of Medicine, University of Glasgow, Royal Infirmary, Glasgow, United Kingdom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Studies indicate that low plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> is associated with a range of disease processes, many of which are inflammatory. However, other lipid-soluble vitamins decrease during the systemic inflammatory response, and this response may confound the interpretation of plasma 25(OH)D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Should stock-up on vitamin D if having surgery due to fragile bones</title><link>/posts/should-stock-up-on-vitamin-d-if-having-surgery-due-to-fragile-bones.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/should-stock-up-on-vitamin-d-if-having-surgery-due-to-fragile-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="short-term-and-long-term-orthopaedic-issues-in-patients-with-fragility-fractures">Short-term and Long-term Orthopaedic Issues in Patients With Fragility Fractures.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2011 Jan 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bukata SV, Kates SL, O&amp;rsquo;Keefe RJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Orthopaedics, University of Rochester, 601 Elmwood Ave, Box 665, Rochester, NY, 14534, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:susan_bukata@urmc.rochester.edu">susan_bukata@urmc.rochester.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Patients with impaired bone quality who suffer a fragility fracture face substantial challenges in both their short- and long-term care. In addition to poor bone quality, many of these patients have multiple medical comorbidities that alter their surgical risk and affect their ultimate functional recovery. Some medical issues can contribute to the altered bone quality and must be addressed to prevent future fractures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>540000 IU before ICU raised vitamin D by 25 ng in 2 days</title><link>/posts/540000-iu-before-icu-raised-vitamin-d-by-25-ng-in-2-days.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/540000-iu-before-icu-raised-vitamin-d-by-25-ng-in-2-days.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-7th-space-interactivehttp7thspacecomheadlines377128short_term_effects_of_high_dose_oral_vitamin_d3_in_critically_ill_vitamin_d_deficient_patients_a_randomized_double_blind_placebo_controlled_pilot_studyhtml--reporting-on-critical-care-2011-15r104">From &lt;a href="http://7thspace.com/headlines/377128/short_term_effects_of_high_dose_oral_vitamin_d3_in_critically_ill_vitamin_d_deficient_patients_a_randomized_double_blind_placebo_controlled_pilot_study.html">7th Space interactive&lt;/a> reporting on Critical Care 2011, 15:R104]&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="short-term-effects-of-high-dose-oral-vitamin-d3-in-critically-ill-vitamin-d-deficient-patients-a-randomized-double-blind-placebo-controlled-pilot-study">Short-term effects of high-dose oral vitamin D3 in critically ill vitamin D deficient patients: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled pilot study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>IntroductionVitamin D deficiency is encountered frequently in critically ill patients and might be harmful. Current nutrition guidelines recommend very low vitamin D doses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this trial was to evaluate the safety and efficacy of a single oral high-dose vitamin D3 supplementation in an intensive care setting over a one-week observation period.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hardly any children had enough vitamin D before bone surgery</title><link>/posts/hardly-any-children-had-enough-vitamin-d-before-bone-surgery.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hardly-any-children-had-enough-vitamin-d-before-bone-surgery.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Inflammation or surgery or heart attack decreases measured vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/inflammation-or-surgery-or-heart-attack-decreases-measured-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inflammation-or-surgery-or-heart-attack-decreases-measured-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="second-article-noticed-vitamin-d-level-low-after-resuscitation-following-heart-failure">Second article: Noticed vitamin D level low after resuscitation following heart failure&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Concluded that the 35% decrease in vitamin D was due to increase in amount of blood, not because the body was using vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acute-fluid-shifts-influence-the-assessment-of-serum-vitamin-d-status-in-critically-ill-patients">Acute fluid shifts influence the assessment of serum vitamin D status in critically ill patients.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Crit Care. 2010;14(6):R216. Epub 2010 Nov 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Krishnan A, Ochola J, Mundy J, Jones M, Kruger P, Duncan E, Venkatesh B.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtually all Bariatric Surgery patients vitamin D deficient – should we routinely supplement</title><link>/posts/virtually-all-bariatric-surgery-patients-vitamin-d-deficient-should-we-routinely-supplement.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/virtually-all-bariatric-surgery-patients-vitamin-d-deficient-should-we-routinely-supplement.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-before-bariatric-surgery-should-supplement-intake-be-routinely-prescribed">Vitamin D Deficiency Before Bariatric Surgery: Should Supplement Intake Be Routinely Prescribed?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Obes Surg. 2011 Jan 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ducloux R, Nobécourt E, Chevallier JM, Ducloux H, Elian N, Altman JJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Service de Diabétologie-Endocrinologie-Nutrition, Hôpital Européen Georges Pompidou, Paris, France, &lt;a href="mailto:roxane.ducloux@egp.aphp.fr">roxane.ducloux@egp.aphp.fr&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Before bariatric surgery, we demonstrate a 96% rate of vitamin D deficiency in morbidly obese French patients: should supplement intake be routinely prescribed? We conducted a prospective observational study to demonstrate the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in morbidly obese patients awaiting bariatric surgery.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium and vitamin D supplements after hip fracture reduced death rate by 25%</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-supplements-after-hip-fracture-reduced-death-rate-by-25-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-supplements-after-hip-fracture-reduced-death-rate-by-25-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="post-hip-fracture-use-of-prescribed-calcium-plus-vitamin-d-or-vitamin-d-supplements-and-anti-osteoporotic-drugs-are-associated-with-lower-mortality">Post-hip fracture use of prescribed calcium plus vitamin D or vitamin D supplements and anti-osteoporotic drugs are associated with lower mortality.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="a-nationwide-study-in-finland">A nationwide study in Finland.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2011 Feb 23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jbmr.375.">doi: 10.1002/jbmr.375.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nurmi-Lüthje I, Sund R, Juntunen M, Lüthje P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Injury and Violence Prevention, Health Center of Kouvola, FI-45100 Kouvola, Finland; Hjelt Institute, Department of Public Health, FI-00014 Helsinki University, Finland. &lt;a href="mailto:ilona.nurmi@pp.inet.fi">ilona.nurmi@pp.inet.fi&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We previously found a positive association between calcium plus vitamin D and anti-osteoporotic drugs and survival among hip fracture patients. Our aim was to verify this observation using a nationwide database. A retrospective cohort of home-discharged hip fracture patients aged ?50 years (n?=?23 615) was enrolled from the national database. Primary exposure was medical treatment for osteoporosis and the outcome was all-cause mortality. Cumulative mortalities were calculated by using the Kaplan-Meier estimator. The relationship between mortality and medication purchases was modeled using Cox&amp;rsquo;s proportional hazards regression with time-dependent covariates for medication use. One in four women and one in ten men with a hip fracture were treated for osteoporosis in Finland. Unadjusted &lt;strong>one-year mortality was lower among patients who purchased calcium plus vitamin D or vitamin D supplements and anti-osteoporotic drugs&lt;/strong> than among those who did not purchase these medications (HR 0.74; 95% CI 0.67-0.81).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ICU time is 2X more likely to be longer than 2 days if vitamin D less than 20 ng</title><link>/posts/icu-time-is-2x-more-likely-to-be-longer-than-2-days-if-vitamin-d-less-than-20-ng.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/icu-time-is-2x-more-likely-to-be-longer-than-2-days-if-vitamin-d-less-than-20-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="relationship-between-vitamin-d-status-and-icu-outcomes-in-veterans">Relationship between vitamin d status and ICU outcomes in veterans.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2011 Mar;12(3):208-11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>McKinney JD, Bailey BA, Garrett LH, Peiris P, Manning T, Peiris AN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mountain Home VAMC, Mountain Home, TN; ETSU Department of Internal Medicine, Johnson City, TN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Vitamin D deficiency remains a poorly recognized pandemic and is closely linked to increased health care costs in veterans. Projected health care needs in veterans are expected to increase over the next decade. Intensive care unit (ICU) costs contribute significantly to hospital costs and stem from intervention services and management of sepsis including nosocomial infections. Vitamin D has immunomodulating and antimicrobial properties through antimicrobial peptides such as cathelicidin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtually all veterans in ICU had vitamin D less than 32 ng</title><link>/posts/virtually-all-veterans-in-icu-had-vitamin-d-less-than-32-ng.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/virtually-all-veterans-in-icu-had-vitamin-d-less-than-32-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-high-in-the-surgical-icu2">Vitamin D Deficiency High in the Surgical ICU(2)&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="elsevier-global-medical-newshttpwwwaceporgcontentaspxid75486">&lt;a href="http://www.acep.org/Content.aspx?id=75486">Elsevier Global Medical News&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>SAN DIEGO (EGMN) - Nearly all veterans admitted to a surgical intensive care unit were vitamin D deficient, yet they were only mildly hypocalcemic, results from a single-center study showed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Research is still needed to determine if vitamin D deficiency contributes to complications in the ICU setting and if acute supplementation improves morbidity,&amp;rdquo; researchers led by Mark Wong, Pharm.D., of the South Texas Veterans Health System, San Antonio, wrote in an abstract presented during a poster session at the annual congress of the Society of Critical Care Medicine. &amp;ldquo;Preemptive screening may become the standard of practice as more research becomes available.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Critically ill 70 percent more likely to die if vitamin D less than 15ng</title><link>/posts/critically-ill-70-percent-more-likely-to-die-if-vitamin-d-less-than-15ng.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/critically-ill-70-percent-more-likely-to-die-if-vitamin-d-less-than-15ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D helps organ transplant - many studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-organ-transplant-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-organ-transplant-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary-of-many-studies-of-vitamin-d-and-organ-transplantation">Summary of many studies of Vitamin D and organ transplantation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-in-organ-transplantation---2011">Vitamin D in organ transplantation - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#survive-heart-transplant-better-if-have-more-vitamin-d">Survive heart transplant better if have more vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#immune-system-is-often-supressed-so-that-a-new-organ-can-be-accepted-by-the-body">Immune system is often supressed so that a new organ can be accepted by the body&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="summary-of-many-studies-of-vitamin-d-and-organ-transplantation">Summary of many studies of Vitamin D and organ transplantation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>More vitamin D needed especially needed if organ = liver or kidney (low vitamin d ==&amp;gt; poor bones)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Every Thyroidectomy patient should get vitamin D and Calcium</title><link>/posts/every-thyroidectomy-patient-should-get-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/every-thyroidectomy-patient-should-get-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="two-articles-on-this-page">two articles on this page&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="to-supplement-or-not-to-supplement-a-cost-utility-analysis-of-calcium-and-vitamin-d-repletion-in-patients-after-thyroidectomy">To Supplement or Not to Supplement: A Cost-Utility Analysis of Calcium and Vitamin D Repletion in Patients After Thyroidectomy.&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="it-adds-about-1-quality-year-of-life">It adds about 1 quality year of life&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ann Surg Oncol. 2010 Nov 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wang TS, Cheung K, Roman SA, Sosa JA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Surgery, Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, WI, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:tswang@mcw.edu">tswang@mcw.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Postoperative hypocalcemia is the most common complication after thyroidectomy; prevention and treatment remain areas of ongoing debate. The purpose of this study was to determine the incremental cost utility of routine versus selective calcium and vitamin D supplementation after total or completion thyroidectomy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Patients low on vitamin D stay in hospital longer after thyroid removal</title><link>/posts/patients-low-on-vitamin-d-stay-in-hospital-longer-after-thyroid-removal.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/patients-low-on-vitamin-d-stay-in-hospital-longer-after-thyroid-removal.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="preoperative-vitamin-d-deficiency-predicts-postoperative-hypocalcemia-after-total-thyroidectomy">Preoperative Vitamin D Deficiency Predicts Postoperative Hypocalcemia After Total Thyroidectomy.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>World J Surg. 2010 Dec 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kirkby-Bott J, Markogiannakis H, Skandarajah A, Cowan M, Fleming B, Palazzo F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrine Surgery, Hammersmith Hospital, Imperial College NHS Trust, Du Cane Road, London, W12 0HS, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Transient postthyroidectomy hypocalcemia occurs in up to 30% of patients. We evaluated the effect of vitamin D deficiency on postthyroidectomy hypocalcemia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: Data were collected prospectively between January 2006 and March 2009. A total of 166 consecutive total thyroidectomies were analyzed regarding the relation between preoperative vitamin D(3) levels and postoperative corrected calcium levels. Patients were divided into three groups dependent upon the preoperative vitamin D(3) level: group 1, &amp;lt;25 nmol/l; group 2, 25-50 nmol/l; group 3, &amp;gt;50 nmol/l (conversion factor of 2.5× between nanomoles per liter and nanograms per milliliter). Hypocalcemia was defined as a postoperative calcium level &amp;lt;2.00 mmol/l (8 mg/dl). Hospital length of stay was recorded.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Vitamin D decreased kidney deaths by 4x</title><link>/posts/adding-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-deaths-by-4x.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adding-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-deaths-by-4x.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Noticed bones heal faster when more than 60 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/noticed-bones-heal-faster-when-more-than-60-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/noticed-bones-heal-faster-when-more-than-60-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bypass surgery and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/bypass-surgery-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bypass-surgery-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="acute-fluid-shifts-influence-the-assessment-of-serum-vitamin-d-status-in-critically-ill-patients">Acute fluid shifts influence the assessment of serum vitamin D status in critically ill patients&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Anand Krishnan email, Judith Ochola email, Julie Mundy email, Mark Jones email, Peter Kruger email, Emma Duncan email and Bala Venkatesh email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Critical Care 2010, 14:R216doi:10.1186/cc9341, 26 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent reports have highlighted the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency and suggested an association with excess mortality in critically ill patients. Serum vitamin D concentrations in these studies were measured following resuscitation. It is unclear whether aggressive fluid resuscitation independently influences serum vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Earthquake and Vitamin D - several studies</title><link>/posts/earthquake-and-vitamin-d-several-studies.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/earthquake-and-vitamin-d-several-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-nutritional-status-of-reproductive-women-at-one-year-after-the-disaster-of-earthquake-in-wenchuan">(The nutritional status of reproductive women at one year after the disaster of Earthquake in Wenchuan)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-articles-on-vitamin-d-and-stress-at-vitamindwiki">Some articles on Vitamin D and stress at VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#study-by-same-chinese-authors-found-92-of-children-under-5-in-earthquake-area-were-vitamin-d-insufficient">Study by same Chinese authors found 92% of children under 5 in earthquake area were vitamin D insufficient&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#200000-iu-of-vitamin-d-monthly-did-not-help-after-earthquake---rct-dec-2014">200,000 IU of Vitamin D monthly did not help after earthquake - RCT Dec 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-nutritional-status-of-reproductive-women-at-one-year-after-the-disaster-of-earthquake-in-wenchuan">(The nutritional status of reproductive women at one year after the disaster of Earthquake in Wenchuan)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Zhonghua Yu Fang Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2010 Aug;44(8):686-90.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stop - Read This Before You Have Orthopedic Surgery</title><link>/posts/stop-read-this-before-you-have-orthopedic-surgery.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stop-read-this-before-you-have-orthopedic-surgery.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="clipped-from-httpwwwstopagingnowcomliveinthenowarticlestop-read-this-before-you-have-orthopedic-surgery">clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.stopagingnow.com/liveinthenow/article/stop-read-this-before-you-have-orthopedic-surgery">http://www.stopagingnow.com/liveinthenow/article/stop-read-this-before-you-have-orthopedic-surgery&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Author = Gale Maleskey, MS, RD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>50% of his patients for orthopedic surgery had less than 20ng/ml&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He recommends taking 50,000 IU vitamin D weekly until up to 50ng/ml&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>his reference - - - -&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-patients-scheduled-to-undergo-orthopaedic-surgery-a-single-center-analysis">Hypovitaminosis D in Patients Scheduled to Undergo Orthopaedic Surgery, A Single-Center Analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Bone and Joint Surgery (American). 2010;92:2300-2304. doi:10.2106/JBJS.I.01231&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ljiljana Bogunovic, MD1, Abraham D. Kim, MD1, Brandon S. Beamer, MD1, Joseph Nguyen, MPH1 and Joseph M. Lane, MD1&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>