<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Colon Cancer on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/colon-cancer.html</link><description>Recent content in Colon Cancer on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/colon-cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Colorectal cancer 60 percent less likely: high vs low Vitamin D level – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colorectal-cancer-60-percent-less-likely-high-vs-low-vitamin-d-level-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-cancer-60-percent-less-likely-high-vs-low-vitamin-d-level-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Colorectal Cancer recurrence not prevented by 1,000 IU of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colorectal-cancer-recurrence-not-prevented-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-cancer-recurrence-not-prevented-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Risk of Cancer increased if poor Vitamin D Receptor – meta-analysis of 73 studies</title><link>/posts/risk-of-cancer-increased-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis-of-73-studies.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/risk-of-cancer-increased-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis-of-73-studies.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D review of Colorectal, Breast, and Prostate Cancers</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-review-of-colorectal-breast-and-prostate-cancers.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-review-of-colorectal-breast-and-prostate-cancers.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and cancer – epidemiological association with colon and breast</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-epidemiological-association-with-colon-and-breast.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-epidemiological-association-with-colon-and-breast.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-an-overview-on-epidemiological-studies">Vitamin D and Cancer: An overview on Epidemiological studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology 810:17-32 · September 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>José Manuel Ordóñez Mena1,2 and Hermann Brenner1,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Clinical Epidemiology and Aging Research, German Cancer Research Centre, Im Neuenheimer Feld 581, 69120 Heidelberg, Germany.E-Mail: 2 &lt;a href="mailto:jose.ordonezmena@dkfz.de">jose.ordonezmena@dkfz.de&lt;/a> ; 3 &lt;a href="mailto:hermann.brenner@dkfz.de">hermann.brenner@dkfz.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In recent years, a rapidly increasing number of studies have investigated the relationship of vitamin D with total cancer and site-specific cancer obtaining diverse findings. In this chapter we provide an overview of epidemiological studies of vitamin D intake, 25-hydroxyvitamin D and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D serum levels and vitamin D associated polymorphisms in relation to total and site-specific cancer risk. Overall, epidemiological evidence for total cancer is inconclusive.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bile acids in fecal matter (related to colon cancer) 40 percent less if good Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/bile-acids-in-fecal-matter-related-to-colon-cancer-40-percent-less-if-good-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bile-acids-in-fecal-matter-related-to-colon-cancer-40-percent-less-if-good-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-between-circulating-vitamin-d-metabolites-and-fecal-bile-acid-concentrations">Association between circulating vitamin D metabolites and fecal bile acid concentrations&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Prevention Research, OnlineFirst May 2, 2016; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1158/1940-6207.CAPR-16-0033">doi: 10.1158/1940-6207.CAPR-16-0033&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elizabeth T. Jacobs 1, &lt;a href="mailto:jacobse@email.arizona.edu">jacobse@email.arizona.edu&lt;/a>, Mark R Haussler 2, David S. Alberts 3, Lindsay N. Kohler 1, Peter Lance 4, Maria E Martinez 5, Denise J. Roe 1, and Peter W. Jurutka 6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Arizona&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Basic Medical Sciences, University of Arizona&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 University of Arizona Cancer Center, University of Arizona&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon cancer 30 percent more likely if problems with Vitamin D genes CYP24A1 or CYP27B1</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-30-percent-more-likely-if-problems-with-vitamin-d-genes-cyp24a1-or-cyp27b1.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-30-percent-more-likely-if-problems-with-vitamin-d-genes-cyp24a1-or-cyp27b1.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Colon Cancer proven again to not be treated by just 1000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-proven-again-to-not-be-treated-by-just-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-proven-again-to-not-be-treated-by-just-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-trial-of-calcium-and-vitamin-d-for-the-prevention-of-colorectal-adenomas">A Trial of Calcium and Vitamin D for the Prevention of Colorectal Adenomas&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med 2015; 373:1519-1530October 15, 2015DOI: 10.1056/NEJMoa1500409&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-cancer-colon-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Cancer-Colon and vitamin D">Overview Cancer-Colon and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/after-30-years-it-still-appears-that-vitamin-d-deals-with-colorectal-cancer">After 30 years it still appears that vitamin D deals with colorectal cancer – Oct 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/colon-cancer-30-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-12th-meta-analysis">Colon cancer 30 percent more likely if low vitamin D – 12th meta-analysis Aug 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon Cancer 20 percent more likely if low Magnesium</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-20-percent-more-likely-if-low-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-20-percent-more-likely-if-low-magnesium.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-between-magnesium-intake-and-risk-of-colorectal-cancer-among-postmenopausal-women">Association between magnesium intake and risk of colorectal cancer among postmenopausal women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2015 Sep 21. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gorczyca AM1 &lt;a href="mailto:amgabbar@umail.iu.edu">amgabbar@umail.iu.edu&lt;/a>, He K2, Xun P2, Margolis KL3, Wallace JP4, Lane D5, Thomson C6, Ho GY7, Shikany JM8, Luo J2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: Data relating to magnesium intake and colorectal cancer (CRC) risk in postmenopausal women are incomplete. We investigated the association between total magnesium intake and the risk of CRC in an ethnically diverse cohort of postmenopausal women enrolled in the Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Initiative.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon cancer 30 percent more likely if low vitamin D – 12th meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-30-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-12th-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-30-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-12th-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Colon cancer patients with high vitamin D live 1 year longer</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-patients-with-high-vitamin-d-live-1-year-longer.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-patients-with-high-vitamin-d-live-1-year-longer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="high-vitamin-d-levels-increase-survival-rates-in-patients-with-metastatic-colorectal-cancer">High vitamin D levels increase survival rates in patients with metastatic colorectal cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer, Volume 121, Issue 13, page 2105, July 1, 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Study participants with high levels of vitamin D in their bloodstream prior to being treated with chemotherapy and targeted drugs survived longer, on average, than patients with lower levels of the vitamin, according to a study by researchers at the Dana-Farber Cancer Institute in Boston, Massachusetts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The study was presented at the 2015 ASCO Gastrointestinal Cancers Symposium, held in San Francisco, California, from January 15 to 17, 2015. Researchers analyzed data from more than 1000 patients with metastatic colorectal cancer who enrolled in a phase 3 clinical trial of chemotherapy plus biologic therapies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon cancer – vitamin D, probiotics, and leptin might help</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-vitamin-d-probiotics-and-leptin-might-help.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-vitamin-d-probiotics-and-leptin-might-help.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="associations-of-probiotics-with-vitamin-d-and-leptin-receptors-and-their-effects-on-colon-cancer">Associations of Probiotics with Vitamin D and Leptin Receptors and their Effects on Colon Cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2015;16(9):3621-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ranji P1, Akbarzadeh A, Rahmati-Yamchi M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Medical Biotechnology, Faculty of Advanced Medical Sciences, International Branch of Tabriz University of Medical sciences (Aras), Tabriz, Iran E-mail : &lt;a href="mailto:rahmati_bio@yahoo.com">rahmati_bio@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Colorectal cancer (CRC) is one of most common causes of cancer-related death worldwide. Recent studies have suggested that microbial and environmental factors including diet and lifestyle can impact on colon cancer development. Vitamin D deficiency and dysfunction of vitamin D receptor (VDR) also correlate with colon cancer. Moreover, leptin, a 16-kDa polypeptide, participates in the regulation of food intake and is associated with other environmental factors affecting colon cancer through the leptin receptor. Altered levels of serum leptin and patterns of expression of its receptor (LPR) may be observed in human colon tumours. Furthermore, the collected data from in vitro and in vivo studies have indicated that consuming probiotic non-pathogenic lactic acid bacteria have beneficial effects on colon cancer. Probiotics, inflammation and vitamin D/VDR have been correlated with leptin and its receptor and are also with colon cancer. Thus, in this paper, we review recent progress on the roles of probiotic, vitamin D/VDR and leptin/LPR in inflammation and colon cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Role of vitamins in gastrointestinal diseases – review</title><link>/posts/role-of-vitamins-in-gastrointestinal-diseases-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/role-of-vitamins-in-gastrointestinal-diseases-review.html</guid><description>&lt;p>World J Gastroenterol. 2015 May 7; 21(17): 5191–5209., &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3748/wjg.v21.i17.5191">doi: 10.3748/wjg.v21.i17.5191&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omar A Masri, Jean M Chalhoub, and Ala I Sharara&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A tremendous amount of data from research was published over the past decades concerning the roles of different vitamins in various gastrointestinal diseases. For instance, most vitamins showed an inverse relationship with the risk of colorectal carcinoma as well as other malignancies like gastric and esophageal cancer in observational trials, however interventional trials failed to prove a clear beneficial preventive role. On the other hand, more solid evidence was obtained from high quality studies for a role of certain vitamins in specific entities. Examples for this include the&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer deaths strongly related to low vitamin D if sampled near time of diagnosis</title><link>/posts/cancer-deaths-strongly-related-to-low-vitamin-d-if-sampled-near-time-of-diagnosis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-deaths-strongly-related-to-low-vitamin-d-if-sampled-near-time-of-diagnosis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-survival-in-norwegian-patients-with-cancer-of-breast-colon-lung-and-lymphoma-a-population-based-study">Serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D and survival in Norwegian patients with cancer of breast, colon, lung, and lymphoma: a population-based study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2012 Feb;23(2):363-70. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10552-011-9885-6.">doi: 10.1007/s10552-011-9885-6.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tretli S1, Schwartz GG, Torjesen PA, Robsahm TE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1The Cancer Registry of Norway, Institute of Population-based Cancer Research, Majorstuen, 0304 Oslo, Norway. &lt;a href="mailto:steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no">steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We investigated the association between serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) and risk of death in Norwegian cancer patients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active vitamin D associated with Metabolic Syndrome and LDL in colon cancer patients</title><link>/posts/active-vitamin-d-associated-with-metabolic-syndrome-and-ldl-in-colon-cancer-patients.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-vitamin-d-associated-with-metabolic-syndrome-and-ldl-in-colon-cancer-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="concentrations-of-the-vitamin-d-metabolite-125oh2d-and-odds-of-metabolic-syndrome-and-its-components">Concentrations of the Vitamin D Metabolite 1,25(OH)2D and Odds of Metabolic Syndrome and its Components&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Metabolism, Volume 64, Issue 3, March 2015, Pages 447–459, doi:10.1016/j.metabol.2014.11.010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jennifer W. Beaa, Peter W. Jurutkab, Elizabeth A. Hiblerc, e, Peter Lancea, Maria E. Martínezd, Denise J. Roea, e, Christine L. Sardo Molmentif, Patricia A. Thompsona, Elizabeth T. Jacobsa, e, Corresponding author at: Mel and Enid Zuckerman College of Public Health, University of Arizona Cancer Center, 1515 N Campbell Ave., Tucson, AZ, 85724-5024, USA. Tel.: + 1 520 626 0341.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon cancer risk reduced by many vitamins – 13 percent reduction by Vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-risk-reduced-by-many-vitamins-13-percent-reduction-by-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-risk-reduced-by-many-vitamins-13-percent-reduction-by-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-and-multiple-vitamin-supplement-intake-and-incidence-of-colorectal-cancer-a-meta-analysis-of-cohort-studies">Vitamin and multiple-vitamin supplement intake and incidence of colorectal cancer: a meta-analysis of cohort studies.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Med Oncol. 2015 Jan;32(1):434. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s12032-014-0434-5.">doi: 10.1007/s12032-014-0434-5.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Dec 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liu Y1, Yu Q, Zhu Z, Zhang J, Chen M, Tang P, Li K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Public Health, Shantou University Medical College, No. 22 Xinling Road, Shantou, 515041, Guangdong, China, &lt;a href="mailto:huajianrui6666@126.com">huajianrui6666@126.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This paper systematically evaluated the association of intake of different vitamins and multiple-vitamin supplements and the incidence of colorectal cancer. Relevant studies were identified in MEDLINE via PubMed (published up to April 2014). We extracted data from articles on vitamins A, C, D, E, B9 (folate), B2, B3, B6, and B12 and multiple-vitamin supplements. We used multivariable-adjusted relative risks (RRs) and a random-effects model for analysis and random effects. With heterogeneity, we looked for the source of heterogeneity or performed sensitivity and stratified analyses. We found 47 articles meeting the inclusion criteria.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon cancer – how vitamin D prevents and treats it</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-how-vitamin-d-prevents-and-treats-it.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-how-vitamin-d-prevents-and-treats-it.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cancer (colon, breast, lymph) survival about 2X better with high level vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cancer-colon-breast-lymph-survival-about-2x-better-with-high-level-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-colon-breast-lymph-survival-about-2x-better-with-high-level-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="review-the-impacts-of-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-on-cancer-patient-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Review: the impacts of circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels on cancer patient outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014 Jul;99(7):2327-36. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2013-4320.">doi: 10.1210/jc.2013-4320.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Apr 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Li M1, Chen P, Li J, Chu R, Xie D, Wang H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CONTEXT:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Circulating levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> may affect the prognosis of cancer patients; however, the epidemiological results are not consistent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To perform a meta-analysis of all published studies to assess the associations of circulating 25(OH)D levels measured at or near the time of diagnosis and outcomes for cancer patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon cancer more likely in blacks due to differences in Vitamin D genes (wonder if more Vitamin D would help)</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-more-likely-in-blacks-due-to-differences-in-vitamin-d-genes-wonder--in-d-would-help.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-more-likely-in-blacks-due-to-differences-in-vitamin-d-genes-wonder--in-d-would-help.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#genetic-variation-in-vitamin-d-related-genes-and-risk-of-colorectal-cancer-in-african-americans">Genetic variation in vitamin D-related genes and risk of colorectal cancer in African Americans.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="genetic-variation-in-vitamin-d-related-genes-and-risk-of-colorectal-cancer-in-african-americans">Genetic variation in vitamin D-related genes and risk of colorectal cancer in African Americans.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2014 May;25(5):561-70. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10552-014-0361-y.">doi: 10.1007/s10552-014-0361-y.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Feb 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pibiri F1, Kittles RA, Sandler RS, Keku TO, Kupfer SS, Xicola RM, Llor X, Ellis NA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Disparities in both colorectal cancer (CRC) incidence and survival impact African Americans (AAs) more than other US ethnic groups. Because vitamin D is thought to protect against CRC and AAs have lower serum vitamin D levels, genetic variants that modulate the levels of active hormone in the tissues could explain some of the cancer health disparity. Consequently, we hypothesized that genetic variants in vitamin D-related genes are associated with CRC risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colorectal cancer – need more vitamin D if you have certain genes</title><link>/posts/colorectal-cancer-need-more-vitamin-d-if-you-have-certain-genes.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-cancer-need-more-vitamin-d-if-you-have-certain-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-vitamin-d-metabolites-in-colorectal-cancer-patients-receiving-cholecalciferol-supplementation-correlation-with-polymorphisms-in-the-vitamin-d-genes">Serum vitamin D metabolites in colorectal cancer patients receiving cholecalciferol supplementation: correlation with polymorphisms in the vitamin D genes.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Horm Cancer. 2013 Aug;4(4):242-50. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s12672-013-0139-9.">doi: 10.1007/s12672-013-0139-9.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Feb 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Muindi JR, Adjei AA, Wu ZR, Olson I, Huang H, Groman A, Tian L, Singh PK, Sucheston LE, Johnson CS, Trump DL, Fakih MG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Roswell Park Cancer Institute, Elm and Carlton Streets, Buffalo, NY 14263, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:Josephia.muindi@roswellpark.org">Josephia.muindi@roswellpark.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cholecalciferol (D(3)) supplementation results in variable increases in serum 25(OH)D(3) levels, however, the influence of genetic polymorphisms on these variable responses is unclear. We measured serum 25(OH)D(3), 24,25(OH)(2)D(3), 1,25(OH)2D(3) and VDBP levels in 50 colorectal cancer (CRC) patients before and during &lt;strong>2,000 IU&lt;/strong> daily oral D(3) supplementation for six months and in 263 archived CRC serum samples. Serum PTH levels and PBMC 24-OHase activity were also measured during D(3) supplementation. TagSNPs in CYP2R1, CYP27A1, CYP27B1, CYP24A1, VDR, and GC genes were genotyped in all patients, and the association between these SNPs and serum vitamin D(3) metabolites levels before and after D(3) supplementation was analyzed. The mean baseline serum 25(OH)D(3) level was less than 32 ng/mL in 65 % of the 313 CRC patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer survival 4 percent more likely with just a little more vitamin D (4 ng) - meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cancer-survival-4-percent-more-likely-with-just-a-little-more-vitamin-d-4-ng-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-survival-4-percent-more-likely-with-just-a-little-more-vitamin-d-4-ng-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-impacts-of-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-on-cancer-patient-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">The Impacts of Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels on Cancer Patient Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-impacts-of-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-on-cancer-patient-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">The Impacts of Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels on Cancer Patient Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014 Apr 29:jc20134320.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Li M1, Chen P, Li J, Chu R, Xie D, Wang H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Key Laboratory of Food Safety Research (M.L., P.C., J.L., R.C., D.X., H.W.), Institute for Nutritional Sciences, Shanghai Institutes for Biological Sciences, Chinese Academy of Sciences, University of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai 200031, China; Key Laboratory of Food Safety Risk Assessment (D.X., H.W.), Ministry of Health, Beijing 100021, China; and School of Life Science and Technology (D.X., H.W.), Shanghai Tech University, Shanghai, 200031, China.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colorectal and Breast Cancer – Vitamin D is associated with fewer deaths – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colorectal-and-breast-cancer-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-fewer-deaths-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-and-breast-cancer-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-fewer-deaths-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-survival-in-colorectal-and-breast-cancer-patients-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-prospective-cohort-studies">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels and survival in colorectal and breast cancer patients: Systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Cancer. 2014 Feb 27. pii: S0959-8049(14)00124-5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejca.2014.02.006.">doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2014.02.006.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maalmi H1, Ordóñez-Mena JM1, Schöttker B1, Brenner H2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ), Division of Clinical Epidemiology and Aging Research, Im Neuenheimer Feld 581, 69120 Heidelberg, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ), Division of Clinical Epidemiology and Aging Research, Im Neuenheimer Feld 581, 69120 Heidelberg, Germany; German Cancer Consortium (DKTK), Heidelberg, Germany. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:h.brenner@dkfz.de">h.brenner@dkfz.de&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon cancer 23 percent less likely if vitamin D levels higher than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-23-percent-less-likely-if-vitamin-d-levels-higher-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-23-percent-less-likely-if-vitamin-d-levels-higher-than-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="association-between-circulating-concentrations-of-25ohd-and-colorectal-adenoma-a-pooled-analysis">Association between circulating concentrations of 25(OH)D and colorectal adenoma: a pooled analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Int J Cancer. 2013 Dec 15;133(12):2980-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ijc.28316.">doi: 10.1002/ijc.28316.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Jul 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elizabeth T. Jacobs 1,2,*, Elizabeth A. Hibler 1,2, Peter Lance 1, Christine L. Sardo 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter W. Jurutka 3,4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 University of Arizona Cancer Center, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Division of Epidemiology, Mel and Enid Zuckerman College of Public Health, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Molecular Link between Vitamin D and Cancer Prevention</title><link>/posts/molecular-link-between-vitamin-d-and-cancer-prevention.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/molecular-link-between-vitamin-d-and-cancer-prevention.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(10), 3993-4021; doi:10.3390/nu5103993&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meis Moukayed 1email and William B. Grant 2,* email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Arts and Sciences, American University in Dubai, P. O. Box 28282, Dubai, UAE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, San Francisco, CA 94164-1603, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Author to whom correspondence should be addressed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Received: 7 August 2013; in revised form: 11 September 2013 / Accepted: 18 September 2013 / Published: 30 September 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(This article belongs to the Special Issue Vitamin D and Human Health)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: low vitamin D increases probability of colon cancer</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-low-vitamin-d-increases-probability-of-colon-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-low-vitamin-d-increases-probability-of-colon-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="selection-approach-suggests-causal-association-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-colorectal-cancer">Selection Approach Suggests Causal Association between 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Colorectal Cancer.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Model PLoS ONE 8(5): e63475. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0063475&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zgaga L, Agakov F, Theodoratou E, Farrington SM, Tenesa A, et al.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with increased risk of colorectal cancer (CRC), but causal relationship has not yet been confirmed. We investigate the direction of causation between vitamin D and CRC by extending the conventional approaches to allow pleiotropic relationships and by explicitly modelling unmeasured confounders.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>45 percent fewer deaths from digestive cancers for 10 ng increase in vitamin D – 2006</title><link>/posts/45-percent-fewer-deaths-from-digestive-cancers-for-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-2006.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/45-percent-fewer-deaths-from-digestive-cancers-for-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-2006.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="prospective-study-of-predictors-of-vitamin-d-status-and-cancer-incidence-and-mortality-in-men">Prospective study of predictors of vitamin D status and cancer incidence and mortality in men.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Natl Cancer Inst. 2006 Apr 5;98(7):451-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giovannucci E, Liu Y, Rimm EB, Hollis BW, Fuchs CS, Stampfer MJ, Willett WC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Harvard Medical School, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Boston, MA, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:edward.giovannucci@channing.harvard.edu">edward.giovannucci@channing.harvard.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D has potent anticancer properties, especially against digestive-system cancers. Many human studies have used geographic residence as a marker of solar ultraviolet B and hence vitamin D exposure. Here, we considered multiple determinants of vitamin D exposure (dietary and supplementary vitamin D, skin pigmentation, adiposity, geographic residence, and leisure-time physical activity-to estimate sunlight exposure) in relation to cancer risk in the Health Professionals Follow-Up Study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D monotherapy reduces colorectal cancer but has calcemic side effects</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-monotherapy-reduces-colorectal-cancer-but-has-calcemic-side-effects.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-monotherapy-reduces-colorectal-cancer-but-has-calcemic-side-effects.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="antineoplastic-effects-of-125oh2d3-and-its-analogs-in-breast-prostate-and-colorectal-cancer">Antineoplastic effects of 1,25(OH)2D3 and its analogs in breast, prostate and colorectal cancer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Endocr Relat Cancer April 1, 2013 20 R31-R47&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carlien Leyssens,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lieve Verlinden and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annemieke Verstuyf, &lt;a href="mailto:mieke.verstuyf@med.kuleuven.be">mieke.verstuyf@med.kuleuven.be&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical and Experimental Endocrinology, KU Leuven, Herestraat 49, bus 902, 3000 Leuven, Belgium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The active form of vitamin D3, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3), is mostly known for its importance in the maintenance of calcium and phosphate homeostasis. However, next to its classical effects on bone, kidney and intestine, 1,25(OH)2D3 also exerts antineoplastic effects on various types of cancer. The use of 1,25(OH)2D3 itself as treatment against neoplasia is hampered by its calcemic side effects. Therefore, 1,25(OH)2D3-derived analogs were developed that are characterized by lower calcemic side effects and stronger antineoplastic effects. This review mainly focuses on the role of 1,25(OH)2D3 in breast, prostate and colorectal cancer (CRC) and the underlying signaling pathways. 1,25(OH)2D3 and its analogs inhibit proliferation, angiogenesis, migration/invasion and induce differentiation and apoptosis in malignant cell lines. Moreover, prostaglandin synthesis and Wnt/b-catenin signaling are also influenced by 1,25(OH)2D3 and its analogs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colorectal Cancer and Vitamin D infographic</title><link>/posts/colorectal-cancer-and-vitamin-d-infographic.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-cancer-and-vitamin-d-infographic.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Colon Cancer vs vitamin D, 30 ng is good - Chart</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-vs-vitamin-d-30-ng-is-good-chart.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-vs-vitamin-d-30-ng-is-good-chart.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-the-relationship-between-uv-b-and-global-incidence-rates-of-colorectal-cancer">What is the relationship between UV B and global incidence rates of colorectal cancer?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dermato-Endocinology Volume 5, Issue 1 February/March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Raphael E. Cuomo, Sharif B. Mohr, Edward D. Gorham and Cedric F. Garland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this study is to examine the relationship between UV B and global incidence of colorectal cancer, while controlling for relevant covariates. Linear regression was used to assess the relationship between latitude and incidence rates of colon cancer in 173 countries. Multiple linear regression was employed to investigate the relationship between UVB dose and colorectal cancer rates while controlling for per capita intake of energy from animal sources, per capita health expenditure, pigmentation, and life expectancy. Data on all variables were available for &lt;strong>139 countries&lt;/strong> . Incidence of colon cancer was highest in countries distant from the equator (R2 = 0.50, p &amp;lt; 0.0001). UV B dose (p &amp;lt; 0.0001) was independently, inversely associated with incidence rates of colorectal cancer after controlling for intake of energy from animal sources, per capita health expenditure, pigmentation, and life expectancy (R2 for overall model = 0.76, p &amp;lt; 0.0001). Consistent with previous research, UVB was inversely associated with incidence of colon cancer. Further research on vitamin D and prevention of colon cancer in individuals should be conducted, including studies of higher serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations than have been studied to date.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pathways that vitamin D prevents and treats colon cancer discovered, 2000 IU needed</title><link>/posts/pathways-that-vitamin-d-prevents-and-treats-colon-cancer-discovered-2000-iu-needed.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pathways-that-vitamin-d-prevents-and-treats-colon-cancer-discovered-2000-iu-needed.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="using-components-of-the-vitamin-d-pathway-to-prevent-and-treat-colon-cancer">Using components of the vitamin D pathway to prevent and treat colon cancer.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutr Rev. 2012 Dec;70(12):721-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1753-4887.2012.00522.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1753-4887.2012.00522.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Oct 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stubbins RE, Hakeem A, Núñez NP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas 78712, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this review was to analyze the components of vitamin D and their potential usefulness in preventing and treating colorectal cancer. The active form of vitamin D, 1α,25(OH(2) )D(3) , targets the &lt;strong>wnt/β-catenin pathway&lt;/strong> by upregulating key tumor suppressor genes such as E-cadherin, which promotes an epithelial phenotype, but this is only possible when the vitamin D receptor (VDR) is present. Colorectal cell lines have shown that VDR expression levels decrease in the later stages of colon cancer. In colorectal cancers with low VDR expression, treatments to increase VDR expression could target alterations at the genomic and epigenomic levels by modulating transcription factors such as SNAIL1 and by utilizing histone deacetyltransferase inhibitors, respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The sun appears better at reducing incidence of some cancers than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-prevention-of-cancer-by-sun-exposure-more-than-just-the-effect-of-vitamin-d--a-systematic-review-of-epidemiological-studies">Is prevention of cancer by sun exposure more than just the effect of vitamin D? -A systematic review of epidemiological studies.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Cancer. 2012 Dec 10. pii: S0959-8049(12)00885-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.">doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van der Rhee H, Coebergh JW, de Vries E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Hagaziekenhuis, P.O. Box 40551, Leyweg 275, 2504 LN Den Haag, Zuid-Holland, The Netherlands. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:hvdrhee@casema.nl">hvdrhee@casema.nl&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The number of studies reporting on the association between sunlight exposure, vitamin D and cancer risk is steadily increasing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epidemiology of Vitamin D and Colorectal Cancer</title><link>/posts/epidemiology-of-vitamin-d-and-colorectal-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/epidemiology-of-vitamin-d-and-colorectal-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1, pp.11-19 (9)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Edward Giovannucci&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Garland and Garland first hypothesized that better vitamin D status lowered risk of colorectal cancer in 1980. Subsequently, the relation between vitamin D status and colorectal cancer risk has been investigated in epidemiologic studies. Various approaches have been used to estimate vitamin D status, including direct measures of circulating 25(OH)vitamin D levels, surrogates or determinants of vitamin D (including region of residence, intake, and sun exposure estimates, or a combination of these). These measures of vitamin D status have been studied in relation to colorectal adenoma, precursors of cancer, and colorectal cancer incidence and mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer - Colon</title><link>/posts/cancer-colon.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-colon.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>!!!!Now USPSTF also suggests start CRC screening at age 45 - Oct 2020
USPSTF = US &lt;strong>Preventive&lt;/strong> Services Task Force
Instead of &lt;strong>preventing&lt;/strong> CRC with Vitamin D - which has been proven in ((Colorectal cancer treated by Vitamin D – 19th meta-analysis – Sept 2020|19 meta-analyses)),
&lt;del>hs&lt;/del> &lt;del>hs&lt;/del> they propose increasing CRC jobs by doing testing even earlier in life
[https://www.mdedge.com/internalmedicine/article/230762/oncology/now-uspstf-also-suggests-start-crc-screening-age-45?ecd=wnl_evn_201027_mdedge_8pm&amp;amp;uac=138704MX&amp;amp;utm_source=News%5FMDedge%5FeNL%5F102720%5FF&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=USPSTF%3A%20Start%20CRC%20screening%20at%20age%2045|MD Edge]
&lt;del>/tc&lt;/del> &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>After 30 years it still appears that vitamin D deals with colorectal cancer</title><link>/posts/after-30-years-it-still-appears-that-vitamin-d-deals-with-colorectal-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/after-30-years-it-still-appears-that-vitamin-d-deals-with-colorectal-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="epidemiology-of-vitamin-d-and-colorectal-cancer">Epidemiology of Vitamin D And Colorectal Cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Anticancer Agents Med Chem. 2012 Oct 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giovannucci E., Departments of Nutrition and Epidemiology, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, U.S.A. &lt;a href="mailto:egiovann@hsph.harvard.edu">egiovann@hsph.harvard.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Garland and Garland first hypothesized that better vitamin D status lowered risk of colorectal cancer in &lt;strong>1980&lt;/strong> . Subsequently, the relation between vitamin D status and colorectal cancer risk has been investigated in epidemiologic studies. Various approaches have been used to estimate vitamin D status, including direct measures of circulating 25(OH)vitamin D levels, surrogates or determinants of vitamin D (including region of residence, intake, and sun exposure estimates, or a combination of these).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is one of several ways to prevent, but not treat colon cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-one-of-several-ways-to-prevent-but-not-treat-colon-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-one-of-several-ways-to-prevent-but-not-treat-colon-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dietary-lifestyle-and-colorectal-cancer-onset-recurrence-and-survival-myth-or-reality">Dietary Lifestyle and Colorectal Cancer Onset, Recurrence, and Survival: Myth or Reality?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>JOURNAL OF GASTROINTESTINAL CANCER, 2012, DOI: 10.1007/s12029-012-9425-y&lt;/p>
&lt;p>REVIEW ARTICLE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katia Lofano, Mariabeatrice Principi, Maria Principia Scavo, Maria Pricci, Enzo Ierardi and Alfredo Di Leo&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and Purpose&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interest in the possibility that diet might help to reduce the risk of colorectal cancer dates back to 1970 based on both the large variation in rates of specific cancers in different countries and the impressive changes observed in the incidence of cancer in &lt;strong>migrants&lt;/strong> from low- to high-risk areas. Here, we report the state of art of literature data about this topic.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>