<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vit D Binding Protein on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/vit-d-binding-protein.html</link><description>Recent content in Vit D Binding Protein on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vit-d-binding-protein/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>If parents exposed to pesticides, genes changed. will need more vitamin D to avoid Prostate Cancer</title><link>/posts/if-parents-exposed-to-pesticides-genes-changed-will-need-more-vitamin-d-to-avoid-prostate-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-parents-exposed-to-pesticides-genes-changed-will-need-more-vitamin-d-to-avoid-prostate-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pesticide-exposure-and-inherited-variants-in-vitamin-d-pathway-genes-in-relation-to-prostate-cancer">Pesticide exposure and inherited variants in vitamin D pathway genes in relation to prostate cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Sara Karami1, &lt;a href="mailto:karamis@mail.nih.gov">karamis@mail.nih.gov&lt;/a>; Gabriella Andreotti 2; Stella Koutros 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kathryn Hughes Barry 3; Lee E. Moore 4; Summer S Han 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jane A Hoppin 5; Dale P. Sandler 6; Jay H Lubin 3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laurie Burdette 3; Jeffrey Yuenger 7; Meredith Yeager 8,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laura Beane Freeman 2; Aaron Blair 3, and Michael C.R. Alavanja3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1DCEG, National Cancer Institute&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4,000 IU vitamin D did not change 25OHD to Vitamin D Binding Protein ratio for obese – RCT</title><link>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-change-25ohd-to-vitamin-d-binding-protein-ratio-for-obese-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-change-25ohd-to-vitamin-d-binding-protein-ratio-for-obese-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="high-dose-4000-iu-vitamin-d-supplementation-does-not-increase-circulating-concentrations-of-free-25-hydroxyvitamin-d">High-dose (4000 IU) Vitamin D Supplementation Does Not Increase Circulating Concentrations of Free 25-hydroxyvitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>(The FASEB Journal. 2013;27:859.4) Meeting Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anthony M Belenchia1, Aneesh Tosh2, Laura Hillman2 and Catherine A Peterson2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Nutrition and Exercise Physiology, University of Missouri, Columbia, MO&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 University of Missouri, Columbia, MO&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Free/bioavailable circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) makes up a small fraction of total 25OHD concentration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We demonstrated the efficacy of a daily 4000 IU vit D dosage in raising total 25OHD concentrations of obese adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Common Vitamin D gene variants and resulting diseases</title><link>/posts/common-vitamin-d-gene-variants-and-resulting-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/common-vitamin-d-gene-variants-and-resulting-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The vitamin D binding protein (DBP) is the major plasma carrier for vitamin D and its metabolites, but it is also an actin scavenger, and is the precursor to the immunomodulatory protein, Gc-MAF. Two missense variants of the DBP gene - rs7041 encoding Asp432Glu and rs4588 encoding Thr436Lys - change the amino acid sequence and alter the protein function.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They are common enough to generate population-wide constitutive differences in vitamin D status, based on assay of the serum metabolite, 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D level can be high, but little benefit: due to kidney, genes, low Magnesium etc.</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Late-stage MS associated with protein in spinal cord which blocks vitamin D</title><link>/posts/late-stage-ms-associated-with-protein-in-spinal-cord-which-blocks-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/late-stage-ms-associated-with-protein-in-spinal-cord-which-blocks-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-binding-protein-in-cerebrospinal-fluid-is-associated-with-multiple-sclerosis-progression">Vitamin D-binding Protein in Cerebrospinal Fluid is Associated with Multiple Sclerosis Progression.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mol Neurobiol. 2013 Jan 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yang M, Qin Z, Zhu Y, Li Y, Qin Y, Jing Y, Liu S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, School of Medicine, Shandong University, 44 Wenhuaxi Road, Jinan, Shandong, 250012, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiple sclerosis is a neurological disorder that presents with symptoms including inflammation, neurodegeneration, and demyelination of the central nervous system (CNS).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7 genes associated with low vitamin D levels in China – 2012, 2013</title><link>/posts/gc-cyp2r1-and-dhcr7-genes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels-in-china-2012-2013.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gc-cyp2r1-and-dhcr7-genes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels-in-china-2012-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolorf00two-articles-from-china-on-this-page-have-the-same-conclusionspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Two articles from China on this page have the same conclusion&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="the-gc-cyp2r1-and-dhcr7-genes-are-associated-with-vitamin-d-levels-in-northeastern-han-chinese-children">The GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7 genes are associated with vitamin D levels in northeastern Han Chinese children.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Swiss Med Wkly. &lt;strong>2012 July&lt;/strong> 16;142:w13636. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4414/smw.2012.13636.">doi: 10.4414/smw.2012.13636.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhang Y, Wang X, Liu Y, Qu H, Qu S, Wang W, Ren L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, Heilongjiang Province, PR China. &lt;a href="mailto:zhangyuling0000@yahoo.com.cn">zhangyuling0000@yahoo.com.cn&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is associated with risk in several diseases. Vitamin D status has high heritability, yet the genetic epidemiology of vitamin D or its metabolites has not been well studied. Our objective was to identify the relationship among three vitamin D-related genes (GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7/NADSYN1) and the levels of 25(OH)D in northeastern Han Chinese children. A total of 506 northeastern Han Chinese children were enrolled in this study. Linear regression was used to examine the impact of 12 SNPs on 25(OH)D concentrations after adjustment for age, gender, BMI and regular usage of vitamin D, and Bonferroni&amp;rsquo;s method was adopted for multiple corrections. The two SNPs in GC (rs222020, rs2298849), four SNPs in CYP2R1 (rs10741657, rs10766197, rs12794714 and rs1562902) and two SNPs in DHCR7/NADSYN1 (rs3829251, rs12785878) were significantly associated with plasma 25(OH)D concentrations under both additive and recessive models (P &amp;lt;0.05). The genotypes of the CYP2R1 rs2060793 polymorphism showed positive association with serum 25(OH)D status under all of the three genetic models even after correction for multiple comparison. This population-based study was the first to confirm the strong effects of the GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7/NADSYN1 loci on circulating 25(OH)D concentrations in northeastern Han Chinese children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart problems such as Afib related to little Magnesium, Omega-3, Vitamin D getting to tissues</title><link>/posts/heart-problems-such-as-afib-related-to-little-magnesium-omega-3-vitamin-d-getting-to-tissues.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-problems-such-as-afib-related-to-little-magnesium-omega-3-vitamin-d-getting-to-tissues.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="for-40-years-cardiovascular-problems-associated-with-low-magnesium">For 40+ years Cardiovascular problems associated with low Magnesium&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJM196904102801504%20">Sudden Death and Ischemic Heart Disease: Correlation With Hardness of the Local Water Supply.&lt;/a> 1969, New England Journal of Medicine&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>People who died suddenly had far lower levels of Magnesium than those who died in accidents&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed?term=magnesium%20(heart%20OR%20cardiac)">PubMed search for magnesium (heart OR cardiac)&lt;/a> 7879 items as of Dec 2018&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17560883%20">Meta-analysis of magnesium therapy for the acute management of rapid atrial fibrillation.&lt;/a> 2007&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels are strongly associated with genes: overview of twin studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-are-strongly-associated-with-genes-overview-of-twin-studies.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-are-strongly-associated-with-genes-overview-of-twin-studies.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D Binding Protein, And Airflow In COPD</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-binding-protein-and-airflow-in-copd.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-binding-protein-and-airflow-in-copd.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>GC genotypes associated with lower vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/gc-genotypes-associated-with-lower-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gc-genotypes-associated-with-lower-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="allelic-determinants-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-bone-mineral-density-and-bone-fractures">Allelic Determinants of Vitamin D Insufficiency, Bone Mineral Density, and Bone Fractures&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Olivia Trummer, Verena Schwetz, Daniela Walter-Finell, Elisabeth Lerchbaum, Wilfried Renner, Markus Gugatschka, Harald Dobnig, Thomas R. Pieber and Barbara Obermayer-Pietsch&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Internal Medicine (O.T., V.S., D.W.-F., E.L., H.D., T.R.P., B.O.-P.);&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical Institute of Medical and Chemical Laboratory Diagnostics (W.R.); and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ear, Nose, and Throat University Hospital, Department of Phoniatrics (M.G.), Medical University of Graz, 8036 Graz, Austria&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pancreatic Cancer with high levels of Vitamin D and Vitamin D Binding Protein</title><link>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-with-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-d-binding-protein.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-with-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-d-binding-protein.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="impact-of-circulating-vitamin-d-binding-protein-levels-on-the-association-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-pancreatic-cancer-risk-a-nested-casecontrol-study">Impact of Circulating Vitamin D Binding Protein Levels on the Association between 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Pancreatic Cancer Risk: A Nested Case–Control Study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancer Res March 1, 2012 72; 1190-8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephanie J. Weinstein1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachael Z. Stolzenberg-Solomon1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William Kopp2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Helen Rager2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jarmo Virtamo3, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Demetrius Albanes1 &lt;a href="mailto:daa@nih.gov">daa@nih.gov&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Nutritional Epidemiology Branch, Division of Cancer Epidemiology and Genetics, National Cancer Institute, Bethesda;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Clinical Support Laboratory, SAIC-Frederick, Inc., NCI-Frederick, Frederick, Maryland; and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Chronic Disease Prevention, National Institute for Health and Welfare, Helsinki, Finland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-vitamin-d-axis-in-chronic-kidney-disease--state-of-the-art-and-future-perspectives">The Vitamin D Axis in Chronic Kidney Disease – State of the Art and Future Perspectives&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Marco Ruggiero, Stefania Pacini&lt;/p>
&lt;p>European Nephrology, 2011;5(1):15-19&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the components of the vitamin D axis participate in the pathogenesis of chronic kidney disease (CKD) and this knowledge can be exploited to devise targeted therapeutic strategies. The vitamin D axis includes vitamin D, vitamin D receptor and vitamin D-binding protein (VDBP), which is the precursor of a potent macrophage activating factor, group-specific component (Gc)-protein-derived macrophage activating factor (GcMAF), a protein that is being extensively studied after it was demonstrated that it eradicates advanced cancer and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. Thanks to its effects on the immune system and angiogenesis, it also appears to be a promising candidate for targeted therapy of CKD. In this article we shall summarise the state of the art on vitamin D and CKD, and then we shall focus on the perspectives opened by increasing knowledge of other components of the axis, in particular VDBP and GcMAF.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Genes varied seasonally with European but not Asian ancestors – VDBP</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-genes-varied-seasonally-with-european-but-not-asian-ancestors-vdbp.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-genes-varied-seasonally-with-european-but-not-asian-ancestors-vdbp.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-of-vitamin-d-binding-protein-vdbp-polymorphisms-and-serum-25ohd-concentrations-in-a-sample-of-young-canadian-adults-of-different-ancestry">Association of vitamin D binding protein (VDBP) polymorphisms and serum 25(OH)D concentrations in a sample of young Canadian adults of different ancestry&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Agnes Gozdzika, &lt;a href="mailto:agnes.gozdzik@utoronto.ca">agnes.gozdzik@utoronto.ca&lt;/a> , Justin Zhub, Betty Y.-L. Wongb, Lei Fub, David E.C. Coleb, and Esteban J. Parraa,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Anthropology, University of Toronto at Mississauga, 3359 Mississauga Road North, Mississauga, Ontario L5L 1C6, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathobiology, University of Toronto, Banting Institute, 100 College Street, Toronto, Ontario M5G 1L5, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 1 diabetes patients may be pissing away vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-patients-may-be-pissing-away-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-patients-may-be-pissing-away-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="enhanced-excretion-of-vitamin-d-binding-protein-in-type-1-diabetes-a-role-in-vitamin-d-deficiency">Enhanced Excretion of Vitamin D Binding Protein in Type 1 Diabetes: A Role in Vitamin D Deficiency?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism Vol. 96, No. 1 142-149&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kathryn M. Thrailkill, Chan-Hee Jo, Gael E. Cockrell, Cynthia S. Moreau and John L. Fowlkes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences and Arkansas Children’s Hospital Research Institute, Little Rock Arkansas 72205&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address all correspondence and requests for reprints to: Kathryn M. Thrailkill, M.D., Arkansas Children’s Hospital, 1 Children’s Way, Slot 512-6, Little Rock, Arkansas 72202 E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:thrailkillkathrynm@uams.edu">thrailkillkathrynm@uams.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>