<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vit D Binding Protein on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/vit-d-binding-protein.html</link><description>Recent content in Vit D Binding Protein on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vit-d-binding-protein/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D and Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-vitamin-d-axis-in-chronic-kidney-disease--state-of-the-art-and-future-perspectives">The Vitamin D Axis in Chronic Kidney Disease – State of the Art and Future Perspectives&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Marco Ruggiero, Stefania Pacini&lt;/p>
&lt;p>European Nephrology, 2011;5(1):15-19&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the components of the vitamin D axis participate in the pathogenesis of chronic kidney disease (CKD) and this knowledge can be exploited to devise targeted therapeutic strategies. The vitamin D axis includes vitamin D, vitamin D receptor and vitamin D-binding protein (VDBP), which is the precursor of a potent macrophage activating factor, group-specific component (Gc)-protein-derived macrophage activating factor (GcMAF), a protein that is being extensively studied after it was demonstrated that it eradicates advanced cancer and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. Thanks to its effects on the immune system and angiogenesis, it also appears to be a promising candidate for targeted therapy of CKD. In this article we shall summarise the state of the art on vitamin D and CKD, and then we shall focus on the perspectives opened by increasing knowledge of other components of the axis, in particular VDBP and GcMAF.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Genes varied seasonally with European but not Asian ancestors – VDBP</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-genes-varied-seasonally-with-european-but-not-asian-ancestors-vdbp.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-genes-varied-seasonally-with-european-but-not-asian-ancestors-vdbp.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-of-vitamin-d-binding-protein-vdbp-polymorphisms-and-serum-25ohd-concentrations-in-a-sample-of-young-canadian-adults-of-different-ancestry">Association of vitamin D binding protein (VDBP) polymorphisms and serum 25(OH)D concentrations in a sample of young Canadian adults of different ancestry&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Agnes Gozdzika, &lt;a href="mailto:agnes.gozdzik@utoronto.ca">agnes.gozdzik@utoronto.ca&lt;/a> , Justin Zhub, Betty Y.-L. Wongb, Lei Fub, David E.C. Coleb, and Esteban J. Parraa,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Anthropology, University of Toronto at Mississauga, 3359 Mississauga Road North, Mississauga, Ontario L5L 1C6, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathobiology, University of Toronto, Banting Institute, 100 College Street, Toronto, Ontario M5G 1L5, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 1 diabetes patients may be pissing away vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-patients-may-be-pissing-away-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-patients-may-be-pissing-away-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="enhanced-excretion-of-vitamin-d-binding-protein-in-type-1-diabetes-a-role-in-vitamin-d-deficiency">Enhanced Excretion of Vitamin D Binding Protein in Type 1 Diabetes: A Role in Vitamin D Deficiency?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism Vol. 96, No. 1 142-149&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kathryn M. Thrailkill, Chan-Hee Jo, Gael E. Cockrell, Cynthia S. Moreau and John L. Fowlkes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences and Arkansas Children’s Hospital Research Institute, Little Rock Arkansas 72205&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address all correspondence and requests for reprints to: Kathryn M. Thrailkill, M.D., Arkansas Children’s Hospital, 1 Children’s Way, Slot 512-6, Little Rock, Arkansas 72202 E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:thrailkillkathrynm@uams.edu">thrailkillkathrynm@uams.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>