<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Calcium on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/calcium.html</link><description>Recent content in Calcium on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/calcium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hypercalcemia and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/hypercalcemia-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypercalcemia-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hypercalcemia-can-be-avoided-in-at-least-6-ways">Hypercalcemia can be avoided in at least 6 ways&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="hypercalcemia-can-be-avoided-in-at-least-6-ways">Hypercalcemia can be avoided in at least 6 ways&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>1 )Take less than 750 mg of Calcium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>  &lt;a href="/posts/1200-mg-is-too-much-calcium-for-seniors-if-take-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-oct-rct-2018">1200 mg is too much Calcium for seniors if take 4,000 IU of vitamin D – Oct RCT 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Take organic instead of rock Calcium (Calcium Carbonate)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>  &lt;a href="/posts/should-not-add-rock-calcium-to-vitamin-d-after-20-year-followup-6-percent-increa-no-surprise-rct">Should not add rock Calcium to Vitamin D (after 20 year followup: 6% increase in heart problems – no surprise) – RCT May 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Which supplements are often taken for healing hairline bone fractures</title><link>/posts/which-supplements-are-often-taken-for-healing-hairline-bone-fractures.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/which-supplements-are-often-taken-for-healing-hairline-bone-fractures.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#calcium">Calcium&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d">Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-c">Vitamin C&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-k">Vitamin K&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#magnesium">Magnesium&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#protein">Protein&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#omega-3-fatty-acids">Omega-3 Fatty Acids&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#zinc">Zinc&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#lysine-and-proline">Lysine and Proline&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#multi-nutrient-supplements">Multi-Nutrient Supplements&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-silicon-vitamin-d-and-bone-health---multiple-studiespostssilicon-vitamin-d-and-bone-health-multiple-studies">See also: &lt;a href="/posts/silicon-vitamin-d-and-bone-health-multiple-studies">Silicon, Vitamin D and Bone Health - multiple studies&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Supplements commonly taken to aid in the healing of hairline bone fractures include:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="calcium">Calcium&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Essential for bone strength and repair.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Recommended daily intake varies by age and gender, typically around 1,000-1,200 mg per day for adults.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d">Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Facilitates calcium absorption and bone mineralization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Should not add rock Calcium to Vitamin D (after 20 year followup: 6% increase in heart problems – no surprise) – RCT</title><link>/posts/should-not-add-rock-calcium-to-vitamin-d-after-20-year-followup-6-percent-increa-no-surprise-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/should-not-add-rock-calcium-to-vitamin-d-after-20-year-followup-6-percent-increa-no-surprise-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#insights-from-decades-of-supplementing-calcium-and-vitamin-d">Insights from Decades of Supplementing Calcium and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="insights-from-decades-of-supplementing-calcium-and-vitamin-d">Insights from Decades of Supplementing Calcium and Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocrinol Metab &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3803/EnM.2024.2016">https://doi.org/10.3803/EnM.2024.2016&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Editorial: Sung Hye Kong1,2orcid&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>7 year trial of 1,000 mg of calcium carbonate with 400 IU of vitamin D3 daily, with 20 year followup&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/calcium-and-vitamin-d-decades.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki &lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium often reduces the risk of health problems such as Colorectal Cancer</title><link>/posts/calcium-often-reduces-the-risk-of-health-problems-such-as-colorectal-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-often-reduces-the-risk-of-health-problems-such-as-colorectal-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#implication-of-calcium-supplementations-in-health-and-diseases-with-special-focus-on-colorectal-cancer">Implication of calcium supplementations in health and diseases with special focus on colorectal cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;p>–-&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="implication-of-calcium-supplementations-in-health-and-diseases-with-special-focus-on-colorectal-cancer">Implication of calcium supplementations in health and diseases with special focus on colorectal cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Crit Rev Clin Lab Sci. 2024 Mar 8:1-14. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10408363.2024.2322565">doi: 10.1080/10408363.2024.2322565&lt;/a> PDF behind a paywall&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shahanavaj Khan 1 2, S Needa Mosvi 3, Saeed Vohra 4, Nitesh Kumar Poddar 5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calcium is a fundamental and integrative element and helps to ensure optimal health by regulating various physiological and pathological processes. While there is substantiated evidence confirming the beneficial effects of calcium in the treatment, management, and prevention of various health conditions, including cancer, conflicting studies are imperative to acknowledge the potential negative role of calcium supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Potassium helps bones by increasing the absorption of both Calcium and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/potassium-helps-bones-by-increasing-the-absorption-of-both-calcium-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/potassium-helps-bones-by-increasing-the-absorption-of-both-calcium-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#potassium-a-frontier-in-osteoporosis">Potassium: A Frontier in Osteoporosis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dietary-guidelines">Dietary Guidelines&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#chart-of-recent-decrease-in-potassium-from-crops---published-2020">Chart of recent decrease in Potassium from crops - published 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="potassium-a-frontier-in-osteoporosis">Potassium: A Frontier in Osteoporosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Horm Metab Res DOI: 10.1055/a-2254-8533&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Widhilika Singh , Poonam Kushwaha&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis is a significant public health concern, particularly in aging populations, leading to fractures, decreased mobility, and reduced quality of life. While calcium and vitamin D have long been recognized as essential for bone health, emerging research suggests that potassium may play a crucial role in maintaining bone density and preventing osteoporosis. This manuscript explores the relationship between potassium and osteoporosis, delving into the mechanisms, epidemiological evidence, and potential therapeutic implications of potassium in bone health. Furthermore, the manuscript discusses the sources of dietary potassium, its impact on bone metabolism, and the future directions in research and clinical practice regarding potassium’s role in osteoporosis management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium - Kale has 5X Calcium than skim milk, and is more bioavailable</title><link>/posts/calcium-kale-has-5x-calcium-than-skim-milk-and-is-more-bioavailable.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-kale-has-5x-calcium-than-skim-milk-and-is-more-bioavailable.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-comparison-of-the-bioaccessible-calcium-supplies-of-various-plant-based-products-relative-to-bovine-milk">A comparison of the bioaccessible calcium supplies of various plant-based products relative to bovine milk&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="a-comparison-of-the-bioaccessible-calcium-supplies-of-various-plant-based-products-relative-to-bovine-milk">A comparison of the bioaccessible calcium supplies of various plant-based products relative to bovine milk&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Food Res Int 2024 Jan:175:113795. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodres.2023.113795">doi: 10.1016/j.foodres.2023.113795&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Molly Muleya 1, Esther F Bailey 2, Elizabeth H Bailey 3&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/png/kale-calcium.png" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>Calcium deficiency is widespread globally, especially in diets with minimal consumption of dairy. It is therefore important to identify plant-based sources of calcium that can make a meaningful contribution to calcium intakes for populations following diets with a minimum supply of dairy products. The best sources of calcium have a high calcium content and bioavailability. Therefore, we evaluated the gross and bioaccessible calcium supplies of 25 plant-based products from 5 food groups considered to be good and important sources of calcium. Bioaccessible calcium was examined using the INFOGEST static digestion model in which isotopically labelled 43Ca was used as a tracer of reagent calcium to improve accuracy of bioaccessibility measurements. The gross calcium content varied widely amongst all the food products, ranging between 7.48 and 959 mg/100 g fresh weight (fw), with approximately 50 % of the products being equivalent to or surpassing the calcium content of skimmed milk. Bioaccessibility of calcium was equally variable, ranging from about 0.1 - 50 %. The lowest bioaccessibility (&amp;lt;10 %) was found in spinach, plant-based beverages, tofu, dried figs and tahini and was attributed to: 1. the high content of oxalate and phytate in some of the products, and 2. the low solubility of tricalcium phosphate which was used for fortification in the plant-based beverages. The remaining products generally had a high bioaccessibility that was similar to, or higher than that of skimmed milk (∼30 %). When both bioaccessibility and recommended serving portions were considered, only 3 products were identified as good sources of calcium, requiring 0.2 - 1.4 servings to equal the bioaccessible supply from skimmed milk. The top three sources of plant-based calcium identified were kale, finger millet and fortified white bread in that order, with kale providing 5 times more bioaccessible calcium than 1 serving of skimmed milk. Moderate sources of calcium where 1.5 - 3 servings was equivalent to 1 serving of skimmed milk included wholemeal bread, some bean varieties (black chickpeas, chickpeas, kidney beans, peas), broccoli, cabbage and almond drink. The rest of the products were either of low calcium content, poor bioaccessibility, and/or not consumed in sufficient quantities to make a significant contribution to daily requirements. White bread was a good source of calcium as it was fortified with calcium carbonate and this suggests that mandatory widescale fortification of staple cereals with this form of calcium should be considered a viable approach to augment dietary calcium intakes in vulnerable populations. Low bioaccessibility of fortified calcium in plant-based beverages, often marketed as good sources of calcium, suggests the need for regulation and for further in vivo studies to validate bioavailability of calcium in these products.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less Calcification if less Calcium or more Vitamin K, Magnesium, etc. - many studies</title><link>/posts/less-calcification-if-less-calcium-or-more-vitamin-k-magnesium-etc-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-calcification-if-less-calcium-or-more-vitamin-k-magnesium-etc-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">&lt;/nav></description></item><item><title>Calcium supplements are HARMFUL – a reversal of recommendations from 2000</title><link>/posts/calcium-supplements-are-harmful-a-reversal-of-recommendations-from-2000.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-supplements-are-harmful-a-reversal-of-recommendations-from-2000.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#are-calcium-supplements-safe">Are Calcium Supplements Safe?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#6-ways-which-might-decrease-calcium-hazards">6 ways which might decrease Calcium Hazards&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="are-calcium-supplements-safe">Are Calcium Supplements Safe?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://nutritionfacts.org/video/are-calcium-supplements-safe/">Dr. Greger – 5 minute video&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> includes &amp;gt;20 references&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“In 12 short years, government panels have gone from suggesting widespread calcium supplementation may be necessary to protect our bones to “Do Not Supplement”.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“Perhaps because when you take calcium pills, you get a &lt;strong>spike of calcium in your bloodstream&lt;/strong> that you don’t get just eating calcium rich foods. Within hours of taking supplemental calcium, the calcium levels in the blood shoot up and can stay up as long as eight hours. This evidently produces what’s called a hypercoagulable state, your blood clots more easily, which could increase the risk of clots in the heart or brain. And, indeed, higher calcium blood levels are tied to higher heart attack and stroke rates. So, the mechanism may be calcium supplements lead to unnaturally large, rapid, and sustained calcium levels in the blood, which can have a variety of potentially problematic effects.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium and Vitamin K2 - many studies</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-k2-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-k2-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2-options-to-reduce-excess-calcium-in-the-arteries-if-take-high-dose-vitamin-d">2 options to reduce excess Calcium in the arteries if take high-dose Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="2-options-to-reduce-excess-calcium-in-the-arteries-if-take-high-dose-vitamin-d">2 options to reduce excess Calcium in the arteries if take high-dose Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Reduce Calcium intake (so that the same amout of Calcium gets into the body)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Note: Might only need to reduce the &lt;a href="/tags/rock-calcium-not-natural-calcium-plants-dairy.html">rock-calcium, not natural Calcium (plants, dairy)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Take Vitamin K2 - at least once every 3 days while taking high-dose vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>You are probably unaware that health needs a Ca-Mg ratio of 2</title><link>/posts/you-are-probably-unaware-that-health-needs-a-ca-mg-ratio-of-2.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/you-are-probably-unaware-that-health-needs-a-ca-mg-ratio-of-2.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#camg-d-the-shield-that-interdicts-the-crown-viruses-and-vaccines">Ca:Mg D, the Shield that Interdicts the Crown Viruses and Vaccines&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="camg-d-the-shield-that-interdicts-the-crown-viruses-and-vaccines">Ca:Mg D, the Shield that Interdicts the Crown Viruses and Vaccines&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Preprint DOI: 10.4236/oalib.1109249, PP. 1-24&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patrick Chambers&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The calcium to magnesium ratio plus adequate vitamin D greatly determine success or not in the immune battle against pathogens and cancer, not to mention cardiovascular disease. Ionized calcium and magnesium in normal, healthy individuals can be calculated and a ratio determined from serum levels. Using widely accepted laboratory reference range values and NHANES data, the recommended daily allowances from the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences for calcium, magnesium, and D3 (cholecalciferol) are objectively refuted mathematically and physiologically. Midrange values for both cations, despite RDA sufficiency, are shown to be unattainable without secondary hyperparathyroidism (high parathormone (PTH), low D) or hypoparathyroidism (low PTH, high iCa:iMg) at the officially designated level of 25(OH)D sufficiency (30 ng/mL). Calcium and magnesium utilize the same calcium sensing receptor (CaSR) not only on cell membranes but also on organelle membranes. Intramitochondrial hydroxylation of chole-calciferol can become compromised. An imbalanced intake of calcium and magnesium can impact the efficacy of vitamin D supplementation. Several pertinent articles underscoring these conclusions are analyzed in detail. The impact of an imbalanced Ca:Mg ratio on Covid-19, Long Covid and vaccination is also discussed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium to Magnesium Ratio - many studies</title><link>/posts/calcium-to-magnesium-ratio-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-to-magnesium-ratio-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#google-scholar-calcium-magnesium-ratio-not-soil-water-630000-hits-nov-2024">Google Scholar: Calcium Magnesium ratio (NOT soil, water): 630,000 hits Nov 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="google-scholar-calcium-magnesium-ratio-not-soil-water-630000-hits-nov-2024">Google Scholar: Calcium Magnesium ratio (NOT soil, water): 630,000 hits Nov 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0%2C48&amp;amp;q=calcium+magnesium+ratio+-soil+-water&amp;amp;btnG=">Google Scholar&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Evaluation of calcium/magnesium ratio in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus - May, 2023  &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1515/tjb-2023-0022">FREE PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Magnesium and Cognitive Health in Adults: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis - Aug 2024, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.advnut.2024.100272">FREE PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Dietary calcium and magnesium intake and risk for incident dementia: The Shanghai Aging Study - Dec 2022 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/trc2.12362">FREE PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D may need Calcium to fight obesity</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-may-need-calcium-to-fight-obesity.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-may-need-calcium-to-fight-obesity.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#interrelationship-between-vitamin-d-and-calcium-in-obesity-and-its-comorbid-conditions">Interrelationship between Vitamin D and Calcium in Obesity and Its Comorbid Conditions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="interrelationship-between-vitamin-d-and-calcium-in-obesity-and-its-comorbid-conditions">Interrelationship between Vitamin D and Calcium in Obesity and Its Comorbid Conditions&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2022, 14(15), 3187; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/nu14153187">https://doi.org/10.3390/nu14153187&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>by Iskandar Azmy Harahap&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 &lt;span>[ORCID]&lt;/span> , Jean-François Landrier&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 &lt;span>[ORCID]&lt;/span> and Joanna Suliburska&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Human Nutrition and Dietetics, Poznan University of Life Sciences, Wojska Polskiego St. 31, 60-624 Poznan, Poland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Aix Marseille University, C2VN, INRAE, INSERM, 13385 Marseille, France&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Urate (kidney stones, gout) reduced by Calcium – RCT</title><link>/posts/urate-kidney-stones-gout-reduced-by-calcium-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/urate-kidney-stones-gout-reduced-by-calcium-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#urate-lowering-effect-of-calcium-supplementation-analyses-of-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Urate-lowering effect of calcium supplementation: Analyses of a randomized controlled trial&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#google-scholar---41000-studies-of-urate-and-calcium---may-2022httpsscholargooglecomscholarhlenas_sdt02c48quratecalciumbtng">Google Scholar - &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0%2C48&amp;amp;q=urate+calcium&amp;amp;btnG=">41,000 studies of Urate AND Calcium - May 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#google-scholar---18000-studies-of-urate-and-kidney-stones---may-2022httpsscholargooglecomscholarhlenas_sdt02c48qurate22kidneystones22btng">Google Scholar - &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0%2C48&amp;amp;q=urate+%22kidney+stones%22&amp;amp;btnG=">18,000 studies of Urate and &amp;ldquo;Kidney Stones&amp;rdquo; - May 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="urate-lowering-effect-of-calcium-supplementation-analyses-of-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Urate-lowering effect of calcium supplementation: Analyses of a randomized controlled trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2022 Jun;49:86-91. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnesp.2022.02.121">doi: 10.1016/j.clnesp.2022.02.121&lt;/a> behind $$ paywall&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Flávia Galvão Cândido 1, Raquel Duarte Moreira Alves 2, Dayse Mara de Oliveira Freitas 2, Jersica Martins Bittencourt 2, Daniela Mayumi Usuda Prado Rocha 2, Rita de Cássia Gonçalves Alfenas 2&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COVID treatment patent applied for - using Rutin, Vitamin D, Vitamin C, Magnesium, etc.</title><link>/posts/covid-treatment-patent-applied-for-using-rutin-vitamin-d-vitamin-c-magnesium-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/covid-treatment-patent-applied-for-using-rutin-vitamin-d-vitamin-c-magnesium-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#promising-therapeutic-approach-for-sars-cov-2-infection-by-using-a-rutin-based-combination-therapy">Promising therapeutic approach for SARS-CoV-2 infection by using a rutin-based combination therapy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#note-rutin-is-very-similar-chemically-to-quercetin-which-increases-vitamin-d-getting-to-cells">Note: RUTIN is very similar chemically to Quercetin which increases Vitamin D getting to cells&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="promising-therapeutic-approach-for-sars-cov-2-infection-by-using-a-rutin-based-combination-therapy">Promising therapeutic approach for SARS-CoV-2 infection by using a rutin-based combination therapy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>ChemMedChem. 2022 Apr 30. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/cmdc.202200157">doi: 10.1002/cmdc.202200157&lt;/a> behind paywall&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Monika Mazik 1&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/rutin-ref-6.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/rutin-reference-6.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;p>The development of new therapeutic approaches for SARS-CoV-2 infection is of particular current importance. The combination therapy proposed here is based on already proven, safe compounds. The natural compound rutin, one of the six therapy components, has the potential to inhibit both viral and host cell targets. In addition, this therapy involves the use of acetylsalicylic acid, vitamin C and vitamin D 3 , which should be administered together with calcium and magnesium. The importance of each component is briefly described in this article. Due to multiple anti-infective properties of rutin, it provides a basis for combating SARS-CoV-2 infection as well as various viral and bacterial co-infections observed in patients. There are strong indications for a good effect of this simple combination therapy, especially in the early stages of infection. It has the potential to be of interest both prophylactically and therapeutically, and offers the possibility of protection against severe disease progression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Excellent reviews of supplements at ConsumerLab</title><link>/posts/excellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlab.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/excellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlab.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#200-supplement-reviews-at-consumerlabhttpswwwconsumerlabcom-include">200+ supplement reviews at &lt;a href="https://www.consumerlab.com/">ConsumerLab&lt;/a> include:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="200-supplement-reviews-at-consumerlabhttpswwwconsumerlabcom-include">200+ supplement reviews at &lt;a href="https://www.consumerlab.com/">ConsumerLab&lt;/a> include:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D, Omega-3, Magnesium, Vitamin K, B Vitamins, Probiotics, Turmeric/Curcumin, Ashwagandha, Iron, Quercetin, Resveratrol, Selenium, Tuna, Zinc&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I have been subscribing to their reviews for over a decade ($54/year)&lt;br>
Each review includes&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>10-100 pages of science (with about 95% correct interpretation)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A tabular review of about 10% of the products on the market (those that paid to be reviewed)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The prices per dose often range by 10 to 1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Several rheumatic diseases treated by high-dose vitamin D, but made worse if Calcium was added</title><link>/posts/several-rheumatic-diseases-treated-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-but-made-worse-if-calcium-was-added.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/several-rheumatic-diseases-treated-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-but-made-worse-if-calcium-was-added.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effects-of-vitamin-d-with-or-without-calcium-on-pathological-ossification-a-retrospective-clinical-study">Effects of vitamin D with or without calcium on pathological ossification: A retrospective clinical study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki----plant-based-calcium-probably-better-than-rock-basedpostsplant-based-calcium-probably-better-than-rock-based">VitaminDWiki - &lt;a href="/posts/plant-based-calcium-probably-better-than-rock-based">Plant-based Calcium probably better than rock-based&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-with-or-without-calcium-on-pathological-ossification-a-retrospective-clinical-study">Effects of vitamin D with or without calcium on pathological ossification: A retrospective clinical study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Exp Ther Med. 2022 Apr;23(4):285. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3892/etm.2022.11214.">doi: 10.3892/etm.2022.11214.&lt;/a> Epub 2022 Feb 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Libin Liang 1, Tong Tong 2, Luyang Qin 3, Jing Xie 4, Yanping Xu 1, Yuguo Qin 1, Lansen Zhang 1, Dehui Liu 1, Xiaoyun Niu 1, Xinglong Tong 1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D fights Tuberculosis by reducing Calcium</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-fights-tuberculosis-by-reducing-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-fights-tuberculosis-by-reducing-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d3-promotes-autophagy-in-thp-1-cells-infected-with-mycobacterium-tuberculosis">Vitamin D3 promotes autophagy in THP-1 cells infected with Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-promotes-autophagy-in-thp-1-cells-infected-with-mycobacterium-tuberculosis">Vitamin D3 promotes autophagy in THP-1 cells infected with Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Exp Ther Med. 2022 Mar;23(3):240. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3892/etm.2022.11165.">doi: 10.3892/etm.2022.11165.&lt;/a> Epub 2022 Jan 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yiming Wu 1 2, Xue Lin 1 2, Fuyang Song 1 2, Di Xue 1 2, Yujiong Wang 1 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(img type=&amp;ldquo;attId&amp;rdquo; attId=&amp;ldquo;17131&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(img type=&amp;ldquo;attId&amp;rdquo; attId=&amp;ldquo;17132&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tuberculosis (TB) is a major disease that causes mortality worldwide. The lethality of this disease is a result of the contagious bacteria Mycobacterium tuberculosis (M.tb). Infection can inhibit phagosomal maturation, with M.tb mainly attacking macrophages and inhibiting autophagy and apoptosis. Vitamin D has been used to treat tuberculosis, whereby the active metabolite, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D, may enhance the immune response to M.tb. Moreover, macrophages infected with M.tb have a high demand for Ca2+. However, the mechanisms by which vitamin D3 protects against and treats TB remain unclear. In the present study, MTT assay showed that vitamin D3 decreased the viability of THP-1 cells in a dose- and time-dependent manner. Autophagy-related factors in THP-1 cells infected with M.tb were analyzed by western blotting and RT-qPCR and the results demonstrated that vitamin D3 significantly increased the expression level of p62, LC3Ⅱ/LC3Ⅰ, Beclin-1, ATG-5 and AMPK in THP-1 cells following M.tb infection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Plant-based Calcium probably better than rock-based</title><link>/posts/plant-based-calcium-probably-better-than-rock-based.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/plant-based-calcium-probably-better-than-rock-based.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#amazon-us-has-400-plant-based-calcium-supplements">Amazon (US) has &amp;gt;400 plant-based Calcium supplements&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#nice-7-year-trial-of-algae-calcium---2016">Nice 7 year trial of Algae Calcium - 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#plant-calcium-has-smaller-crystals-and-is-15x-more-bio-available-than-synthetic-ca---sept-2021">Plant Calcium has smaller crystals and is 1.5X more bio-available than synthetic Ca - Sept 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="amazon-us-has-400-plant-based-calcium-supplements">Amazon (US) has &amp;gt;400 plant-based Calcium supplements&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Plant-Based-Calcium/s?k=Plant+Based+Calcium">Amazon&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Personally, I use the Algae Calcium powder from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07CZ1RBVB/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1?tag=vdw-20">Amazon&lt;/a> I put the powder in a modified salt shaker, and shake in on my morning cereal&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="nice-7-year-trial-of-algae-calcium---2016">Nice 7 year trial of Algae Calcium - 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A 7-Year Longitudinal Trial of the Safety and Efficacy of a Vitamin/Mineral Enhanced Plant-Sourced Calcium Supplement&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nightmares associated with low Vitamin D and low Calcium</title><link>/posts/nightmares-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-low-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nightmares-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-low-calcium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Some people taking 1 million IU of Vitamin D were hypercalcemic for a while</title><link>/posts/some-people-taking-1-million-iu-of-vitamin-d-were-hypercalcemic-for-a-while.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-people-taking-1-million-iu-of-vitamin-d-were-hypercalcemic-for-a-while.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pain reduced by Vitamin D (60K weekly, then monthly) plus daily Calcium in 3 months</title><link>/posts/pain-reduced-by-vitamin-d-60k-weekly-then-monthly-plus-daily-calcium-in-3-months.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pain-reduced-by-vitamin-d-60k-weekly-then-monthly-plus-daily-calcium-in-3-months.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="chronic-non-specific-pain-helped-with-vitamin-d--grassroots-health-on-this-studyhttpswwwgrassrootshealthnetblogchronic-non-specific-pain-helped-vitamin-d20">&lt;a href="https://www.grassrootshealth.net/blog/chronic-non-specific-pain-helped-vitamin-d/%20">Chronic, Non-Specific Pain Helped with Vitamin D- Grassroots Health on this study&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/pain-grh.jpg" alt="image" width="700"></description></item><item><title>Very rarely will Vitamin D cause Hypercalcemia – a simple diagnostic</title><link>/posts/very-rarely-will-vitamin-d-cause-hypercalcemia-a-simple-diagnostic.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/very-rarely-will-vitamin-d-cause-hypercalcemia-a-simple-diagnostic.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#differential-diagnosis-of-vitamin-d-related-hypercalcemia-using-serum-vitamin-d-metabolite-profiling">Differential diagnosis of vitamin D-related hypercalcemia using serum vitamin D metabolite profiling&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="differential-diagnosis-of-vitamin-d-related-hypercalcemia-using-serum-vitamin-d-metabolite-profiling">Differential diagnosis of vitamin D-related hypercalcemia using serum vitamin D metabolite profiling&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2021 Apr 15. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jbmr.4306">doi: 10.1002/jbmr.4306&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martin Kaufmann 1 2, Karl-Peter Schlingmann 3, Linor Berezin 1, Arnaud Molin 4, Jesse Sheftel 1, Melanie Vig 1, John C Gallagher 5, Akiko Nagata 6, Shadi Sedghi Masoud 6, Ryota Sakamoto 6, Kazuo Nagasawa 6, Motonari Uesugi 7, Marie Laure Kottler 4, Martin Konrad 3, &lt;strong>Glenville Jones&lt;/strong> 1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Calcium associated with severe COVID-19 – several studies</title><link>/posts/low-calcium-associated-with-severe-covid-19-several-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-calcium-associated-with-severe-covid-19-several-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-calcium-increases-risk-of-covid-19-death-by-7x---aug-2021">Low Calcium increases Risk of COVID-19 death by 7X - Aug 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hypocalcemia-in-covid-19-prevalence-clinical-significance-and-therapeutic-implications---april-2021">Hypocalcemia in COVID-19: Prevalence, clinical significance and therapeutic implications - April 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="low-calcium-increases-risk-of-covid-19-death-by-7x---aug-2021">Low Calcium increases Risk of COVID-19 death by 7X - Aug 2021&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The effect of low serum calcium level on the severity and mortality of Covid patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Immunity, Inflammation and Disease 2021;1-10. DOI: 10.1002/iid3.528&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/ca-covid-mortality.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;p>Effat Alemzadeh1 © | Esmat Alemzadeh2,3 © | Masood Ziaee1 © | Ali Abedi4 ©	| Hamid Salehiniya5 ©&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No correlation found between hypercalcemia and high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/no-correlation-found-between-hypercalcemia-and-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-correlation-found-between-hypercalcemia-and-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="risk-of-hypercalcemia-in-patients-with-very-high-serum-25-oh-vitamin-d-levels">Risk of Hypercalcemia in Patients with Very High Serum 25-OH Vitamin D Levels&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Clin Pract. 2021 Mar 24;e14181. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/ijcp.14181">doi: 10.1111/ijcp.14181&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adnan Batman 1, Emre Sedar Saygili 1, Duygu Yildiz 1, Esra Cil Sen 1, Rumeysa Selvinaz Erol 1, Muhammed Masum Canat 1, Feyza Yener Ozturk 1, Yuksel Altuntas 1&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
#### Interesting that their title indicted a risk but their analysis found no correlation
&lt;p>The patients probably avoided hypercalcemia by doing one or more of the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased Vitamin D increases Phosphate as well as Calcium</title><link>/posts/increased-vitamin-d-increases-phosphate-as-well-as-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-vitamin-d-increases-phosphate-as-well-as-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="increased-intestinal-phosphate-absorption-an-often-overlooked-effect-of-vitamin-d">Increased intestinal phosphate absorption, an often-overlooked effect of vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>R. Todd Alexander1,2,3 &lt;a href="mailto:todd2@ualberta.ca">todd2@ualberta.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Physiology University of Alberta, Edmonton, T6G 1C9, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Pediatrics, University of Alberta, Edmonton, T6G 1C9, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Membrane Protein Disease Research Group, University of Alberta, Edmonton, T6G 1C9 Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>_This study does not indicate by how much Phospate is increased by Vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-increased-absorption-of-phosphorus-and-calcium-in-steers">Vitamin D increased absorption of Phosphorus and Calcium in steers – April 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Consensus: Upper Limit of daily Vitamin D intake is still 4,000 IU (if you do not reduce Calcium)</title><link>/posts/consensus-upper-limit-of-daily-vitamin-d-intake-is-still-4000-iu-if-you-do-not-reduce-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/consensus-upper-limit-of-daily-vitamin-d-intake-is-still-4000-iu-if-you-do-not-reduce-calcium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Increased Calcium decreases Vitamin D in males</title><link>/posts/increased-calcium-decreases-vitamin-d-in-males.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-calcium-decreases-vitamin-d-in-males.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Increased dental decay if take Calcium without Magnesium</title><link>/posts/increased-dental-decay-if-take-calcium-without-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-dental-decay-if-take-calcium-without-magnesium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chronic Hypoparathyroidism typically uses daily Calcium, alternate day is 7X better</title><link>/posts/chronic-hypoparathyroidism-typically-uses-daily-calcium-alternate-day-is-7x-better.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-hypoparathyroidism-typically-uses-daily-calcium-alternate-day-is-7x-better.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="alternate-day-calcium-dosing-may-be-an-effective-treatment-option-for-chronic-hypoparathyroidism">Alternate-day Calcium Dosing May Be an Effective Treatment Option for Chronic Hypoparathyroidism&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Endocrinol Invest, 2020 Jan 3, PMID: 31900832 DOI: 10.1007/s40618-019-01173-9&lt;/p>
&lt;p>T Akkan 1, M Dagdeviren 2, A O Koca 2, D T Ertugrul 2, M Altay 2&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/hypothyroidism-risk-reduced-32-percent-in-those-getting-vitamin-d-levels-above-50-ng">Hypothyroidism risk reduced 32 percent in those getting vitamin D levels above 50 ng – Oct 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-receptor-controls-pth-without-needing-vitamin-d">Hypothesis Vitamin D receptor controls PTH without needing Vitamin D – Aug 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/calcium-supplementation-is-ok-provided-you-also-take-vitamin-k">Calcium Supplementation is OK provided you also take Vitamin K – Feb 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lowering Calcium Risk when having High Dose Vitamin D3 – Cawley</title><link>/posts/lowering-calcium-risk-when-having-high-dose-vitamin-d3-cawley.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lowering-calcium-risk-when-having-high-dose-vitamin-d3-cawley.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="michael-cawley--facebookhttpswwwfacebookcomgroups629001147449412multi_permalinks1041103066239216notif_id1576628095659287notif_tgroup_highlightsrefnotif">&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/629001147449412/?multi_permalinks=1041103066239216&amp;amp;notif_id=1576628095659287&amp;amp;notif_t=group_highlights&amp;amp;ref=notif">Michael Cawley – Facebook&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A major concern for people taking doses of vitamin D3 above 10,000 iu per day (250 mcg) is the risk of severe kidney damage from excessive amounts of calcium circulating in the blood. Vitamin D3 regulates the absorption of calcium from food and water. The higher the dose of vitamin D3, the greater the amount of calcium that will be absorbed. Too much calcium is toxic to the kidneys and can cause kidney damage and even kidney failure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium by itself does not reduce risk of fractures (shown yet again)</title><link>/posts/calcium-by-itself-does-not-reduce-risk-of-fractures-shown-yet-again.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-by-itself-does-not-reduce-risk-of-fractures-shown-yet-again.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypercalcemia in critically ill patients taking 10,000 IU of vitamin D (many solutions)</title><link>/posts/hypercalcemia-in-critically-ill-patients-taking-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-many-solutions.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypercalcemia-in-critically-ill-patients-taking-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-many-solutions.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="hypercalcemia-without-hypervitaminosis-d-during-cholecalciferol-supplementation-in-critically-ill-patients">Hypercalcemia Without Hypervitaminosis D During Cholecalciferol Supplementation in Critically Ill Patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr Clin Pract. 2019 Oct 11. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ncp.10407.">doi: 10.1002/ncp.10407.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/comparing-high-dose-vitamin-d-therapies">Most groups taking high-dose vitamin D&lt;/a> do one or more of the following:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Increase Magnesium&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Increase Vitamin K&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Reduce Calcium intake - &lt;a href="/posts/10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-too-much-if-you-also-take-calcium-supplements-rct">especially pills&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Increase Water&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The &lt;a href="/posts/bulk-supplementation-of-vitamin-d-magnesium-zinc-b-12-k2-boron-etc-lower-cost-and-easier-than-pills">founder of VitaminDWiki&lt;/a> takes 20,000 IU Vitamin D average along with Magnesium and Vitamin K&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/hypercalcemia-and-vitamin-d-many-studies">Hypercalcemia and Vitamin D - many studies&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/increased-calcium-decreases-vitamin-d-in-males">Increased Calcium decreases Vitamin D in males – Nov 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10,000 IU of Vitamin D for 7 years with no excessive Calcium in 4,800 patients</title><link>/posts/10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-7-years-with-no-excessive-calcium-in-4800-patients.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-7-years-with-no-excessive-calcium-in-4800-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Daily oral dosing of vitamin D3 using 5000 TO 50,000 international units a day in long-term hospitalized patients: Insights from a seven year experience&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Steroid Biochemistry &amp;amp; Molecular Biology https://doi.Org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2018.12.010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patrick J McCullough MD1,2, Douglas S Lehrer MD1,2, Jeffrey Amend RN2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Psychiatry, Wright State University School of Medicine, Dayton, Ohio, 45435&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Summit Behavioral Healthcare, Cincinnati, Ohio, 45237.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-toxicity-of-vitamin-d">Overview Toxicity of vitamin D&lt;/a> has the following chart&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Transcutaneous enhancers (DMSO, etc) for Vitamin D, Vitamin C, Resveratrol, Magnesium, etc.</title><link>/posts/off-topic-transcutaneous-enhancers-dmso-etc-for-vitamin-d-vitamin-c-resveratrol-magnesium-etc.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-transcutaneous-enhancers-dmso-etc-for-vitamin-d-vitamin-c-resveratrol-magnesium-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>DMSO is able to enhance “small sized” molecules (&amp;lt; 500 daltons) getting through the skin&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have not yet found out the DMSO &amp;ldquo;speedup factor&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DMSO was made in 1860 and its transdermal properties were discovered about 40 years later&lt;/p>
&lt;p>High concentration DMSO has used on the skin for various purposed 4 times a day for a month&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DMSO by itself has various health benefits&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://realizebeauty.wordpress.com/2017/03/27/cosmetic-science/%20">The 500 Dalton Rule of Dermal Penetration and Cosmetic Science&lt;/a> March 2017&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium Supplementation is OK provided you also take Vitamin K</title><link>/posts/calcium-supplementation-is-ok-provided-you-also-take-vitamin-k.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-supplementation-is-ok-provided-you-also-take-vitamin-k.html</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.nattopharma.com/vitamin-k2-calcium-paper-supported-nattopharma-published-frontiers-cardiovascular-medicine/">VITAMIN K2 &amp;amp; CALCIUM PAPER, SUPPORTED BY NATTOPHARMA, PUBLISHED IN FRONTIERS IN CARDIOVASCULAR MEDICINE&lt;/a> Press Release&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The review paper is the result of a grant from the Norwegian Research Council awarded to NattoPharma to fund a 4-year PhD project to documentthe effect of calcium metabolism in the body based on the presence or absence of vitamin K2, MK-7&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/the-bone-vasculature-axis.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/axis-table-1-ca-types.jpg" alt="image" width="900">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Interactions with P and Vit K&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Osteoporosis treatment – Vitamin D is the most cost-effective</title><link>/posts/osteoporosis-treatment-vitamin-d-is-the-most-cost-effective.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/osteoporosis-treatment-vitamin-d-is-the-most-cost-effective.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cost-effectiveness-of-antiosteoporosis-strategies-for-postmenopausal-women-with-osteoporosis-in-china">Cost-effectiveness of antiosteoporosis strategies for postmenopausal women with osteoporosis in China.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Menopause. 2019 Apr 15. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/GME.0000000000001339">doi: 10.1097/GME.0000000000001339&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Li N1,2, Zheng B1,2, Liu M1,2, Zhou H1, Zhao L2, Cai H1,2, Huang J3.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
#### Cost of 40 years of treatment (for similar benefits)
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Calcium/vitamin D&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>$3,800&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Zoledronate&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>$8,400&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Alendronate&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>$9,800&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Teriparatide&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>$34,800&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Raloxifene&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>$13,400&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;hr>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-helps-treat-osteoporosis">Vitamin D helps treat Osteoporosis – Sept 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/osteoporosis-4x-more-likely-if-poor-gut-probably-poor-vitamin-d-absorption">Osteoporosis 4X more likely if poor gut (probably poor vitamin D absorption) – Aug 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium from food or supplements associated with more deaths (US Cohort of 31,000 people)</title><link>/posts/calcium-from-food-or-supplements-associated-with-more-deaths-us-cohort-of-31000-people.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-from-food-or-supplements-associated-with-more-deaths-us-cohort-of-31000-people.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D prevents diabetes but Dairy does not appear to help</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-prevents-diabetes-but-dairy-does-not-appear-to-help.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-prevents-diabetes-but-dairy-does-not-appear-to-help.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Calcium supplements go to muscle, not bone, unless have enough Vitamin K</title><link>/posts/calcium-supplements-go-to-muscle-not-bone-unless-have-enough-vitamin-k.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-supplements-go-to-muscle-not-bone-unless-have-enough-vitamin-k.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D accumulation in 1 in 300 people due to gene (CYP24A1) can cause Calcium problems</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-accumulation-in-1-in-300-people-due-to-gene-cyp24a1-can-cause-calcium-problems.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-accumulation-in-1-in-300-people-due-to-gene-cyp24a1-can-cause-calcium-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cyp24a1-mutations-and-human-disease-1-are-carriers---2016">CYP24A1 mutations and human disease (1% are carriers) - 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-hypercalcaemia-of-cyp24a1-inactivation-1---aug-2015">The hypercalcaemia of CYP24A1 inactivation (1%?) - Aug 2015&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamin-d-non-responders-may-have-one-or-more-poor-genes-gc-lipc-cyp24a1-and-pde3b--oct-2022postsvitamin-d-non-responders-may-have-one-or-more-poor-genes-gc-lipc-cyp24a1-and-pde3b">See also &lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-non-responders-may-have-one-or-more-poor-genes-gc-lipc-cyp24a1-and-pde3b">Vitamin D non-responders may have one or more poor genes: GC, LIPC, CYP24A1, and PDE3B – Oct 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="cyp24a1-mutations-and-human-disease-1-are-carriers---2016">CYP24A1 mutations and human disease (1% are carriers) - 2016&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocrine Abstracts (2016) 41 S14.3 | DOI: 10.1530/endoabs.41.S14.3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glenville Jones&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Idiopathic infantile hypercalcemia (IIH) constitutes a broad group of diseases with a common outcome namely, hypercalcemia. It is now recognized that mutations of the vitamin D catabolic cytochrome P450, CYP24A1 represent one of the major causes of IIH. Patients often present in neonatal life with transient hypercalcemia, but adults with hypercalciuria, renal stones &amp;amp; nephrocalcinosis also appear with CYP24A1 defects. Recently, there have been reports that pregnant females with IIH can suffer hypercalcemic episodes during pregnancy, presumably due to increased synthesis of 1,25-(OH)2D3 by the placenta, that abate after pregnancy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1200 mg is too much Calcium for seniors if take 4,000 IU of vitamin D – Oct RCT 2018</title><link>/posts/1200-mg-is-too-much-calcium-for-seniors-if-take-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-oct-rct-2018.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1200-mg-is-too-much-calcium-for-seniors-if-take-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-oct-rct-2018.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>More than 1.4 grams of Calcium increased male death rate by 1.4 X</title><link>/posts/more-than-14-grams-of-calcium-increased-male-death-rate-by-14-x.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-14-grams-of-calcium-increased-male-death-rate-by-14-x.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="high-calcium-intake-in-men-not-women-is-associated-with-all-cause-mortality-risk-melbourne-collaborative-cohort-study">High calcium intake in men not women is associated with all-cause mortality risk: Melbourne Collaborative Cohort Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arch Osteoporos. 2018 Sep 21;13(1):101. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11657-018-0518-5.">doi: 10.1007/s11657-018-0518-5.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/aggressive-prostate-cancer-in-blacks-with-low-vitamin-d-7x-more-likely-if-added-calcium">Aggressive Prostate Cancer in blacks with low vitamin D – 7X more likely if added Calcium – Jan 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/drinking-3-glasses-of-milk-daily-associated-with-doubling-the-death-rate">Drinking 3 glasses of milk daily associated with doubling the death rate – Oct 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/calcium-supplements-proven-to-not-reduce-fractures-but-are-proven-to-increase-heart-problems">Calcium supplements proven to NOT reduce fractures, but are proven to INCREASE heart problems – July 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10,000 IU of Vitamin D is too much if you also take Calcium supplements – RCT</title><link>/posts/10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-too-much-if-you-also-take-calcium-supplements-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-too-much-if-you-also-take-calcium-supplements-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="safety-of-calcium-and-vitamin-d-supplements-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Safety of Calcium and Vitamin D Supplements, a Randomized Controlled Trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2018 Sep 4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/cen.13848.">doi: 10.1111/cen.13848.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aloia JF1, Katumuluwa S1, Stolberg A1, Usera G1, Mikhail M1, Hoofnagle AN2, Islam S1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Winthrop University Hospital Bone Mineral Research Center, Mineola, NY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 University of Washington, Seattle, WA.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/iom-again-fails-to-look-at-interactions">IoM again fails to look at interactions - Nov 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Excess Calcium was known to be a problem by supplement suppliers back in 2010,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colorectal Cancer risk increases 1.6 X if high Calcium, low Magnesium and a poor gene</title><link>/posts/colorectal-cancer-risk-increases-16-x-if-high-calcium-low-magnesium-and-a-poor-gene.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-cancer-risk-increases-16-x-if-high-calcium-low-magnesium-and-a-poor-gene.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-relation-of-magnesium-and-calcium-intakes-and-a-genetic-polymorphism-in-the-magnesium-transporter-to-colorectal-neoplasia-risk123">The relation of magnesium and calcium intakes and a genetic polymorphism in the magnesium transporter to colorectal neoplasia risk1,2,3&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2007 Sep; 86(3): 743–751. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/86.3.743">doi: 10.1093/ajcn/86.3.743&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Qi Dai, Martha J Shrubsole, Reid M Ness, David Schlundt, Qiuyin Cai, Walter E Smalley, Ming Li, Yu Shyr, and Wei Zheng&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mean magnesium intake in the US population does not differ from that in East Asian populations with traditionally low risks of colorectal cancer and other chronic diseases, but the ratio of calcium to magnesium (Ca:Mg) intake is much higher in the US population. Transient receptor potential melastatin 7 (TRPM7) is a newly found gene essential to magnesium absorption and homeostasis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Girls had slightly worse bones if mothers had 1500 mg of Calcium daily while pregnant</title><link>/posts/girls-had-slightly-worse-bones-if-mothers-had-1500-mg-of-calcium-daily-while-pregnant.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/girls-had-slightly-worse-bones-if-mothers-had-1500-mg-of-calcium-daily-while-pregnant.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="long-term-effects-of-maternal-calcium-supplementation-on-childhood-growth-differ-between-males-and-females-in-a-population-accustomed-to-a-low-calcium-intake">Long-term effects of maternal calcium supplementation on childhood growth differ between males and females in a population accustomed to a low calcium intake.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bone. 2017 Oct;103:31-38. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bone.2017.06.001.">doi: 10.1016/j.bone.2017.06.001.&lt;/a> Epub 2017 Jun 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ward KA1, Jarjou L2, Prentice A3.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/is-a-health-problem-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-low-magnesium-or-too-much-calcium">Is a health problem associated with Low vitamin D, Low Magnesium, or too much Calcium – Jan 2016 &lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/calcium-supplementation-on-childhood-growth.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The importance of adequate calcium intakes for healthy growth and bone development has long been recognised.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mineral adsorption and Vitamin D (Magnesium, Calcium, etc) - 2011</title><link>/posts/mineral-adsorption-and-vitamin-d-magnesium-calcium-etc-2011.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mineral-adsorption-and-vitamin-d-magnesium-calcium-etc-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="review-of-mineral-absorption-with-special-consideration-of-chelation-as-a-method-to-improve-bioavailability-of-mineralsupplements">Review of Mineral Absorption with Special Consideration of Chelation as a Method to Improve Bioavailability of Mineral Supplements&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;lsquo;by James Gerber, MD&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.integrativepractitioner.com/topics/nutrition/a-review-of-mineral-absorption-with-special-consideration-of-chelation-as-a-method-to-improve-bioavailability-of-mineral-supplements/">Online&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mineral absorption from supplements has been a hotly contested issue in the supplement industry. Companies naturally desire to provide the best products and gain market share by promoting them as the best. This has led many companies to claim superior absorption from particular formulations of mineral supplements. Understanding and validating some of these claims has often been difficult, due to insufficient or conflicting research. This white paper will attempt to shed some light on the controversy and establish the state of scientific knowledge about mineral absorption from supplements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High vitamin D is associated with high Calcium and no Boron (in hair)</title><link>/posts/high-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-high-calcium-and-no-boron-in-hair.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-vitamin-d-is-associated-with-high-calcium-and-no-boron-in-hair.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="what-vitamin-d-supplements-do-to-your-mineral-levels-hint-its-not-goodhttpsbutternutritioncomvitamin-d-supplement-warning">&lt;a href="https://butternutrition.com/vitamin-d-supplement-warning/">WHAT VITAMIN D SUPPLEMENTS DO TO YOUR MINERAL LEVELS (HINT: IT’S NOT GOOD)&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“This hair analysis graph is of someone who has a history of taking vitamin D3 supplements. For me, it’s pretty obvious without even knowing this due to the high calcium, low potassium, and low boron on their hair analysis report. And this pattern isn’t an isolated incident; it’s a pattern that I see in 75-80% of my hair analysis clients!”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium added for osteoporosis may not help and might be harmful</title><link>/posts/calcium-added-for-osteoporosis-may-not-help-and-might-be-harmful.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-added-for-osteoporosis-may-not-help-and-might-be-harmful.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Prostate cancer risk increase with Vitamin D (other studies disagree) – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/prostate-cancer-risk-increase-with-vitamin-d-other-studies-disagree-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prostate-cancer-risk-increase-with-vitamin-d-other-studies-disagree-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mild acidic diet with vitamin D eliminated hypocalcemia before birth (cows)</title><link>/posts/mild-acidic-diet-with-vitamin-d-eliminated-hypocalcemia-before-birth-cows.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mild-acidic-diet-with-vitamin-d-eliminated-hypocalcemia-before-birth-cows.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-prepartum-dietary-cation-anion-difference-and-source-of-vitamin-d-in-dairy-cows-health-and-reproductive-responses">Effects of prepartum dietary cation-anion difference and source of vitamin D in dairy cows: Health and reproductive responses.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Dairy Sci. 2017 Dec 20. pii: S0022-0302(17)31191-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3168/jds.2017-13740.">doi: 10.3168/jds.2017-13740.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martinez N1, Rodney RM2, Block E3, Hernandez LL4, Nelson CD1, Lean IJ2, Santos JEP5.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>Mild acidosis with Vitamin D: hypocalcemia 23 % ==&amp;gt; 0%&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using Calcidiol instead of Vitamin D also reduces&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Placenta retention 30% ==&amp;gt; 3%&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pelvic inflammatory disease 46% ==&amp;gt; 26%&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium increased risk of side effects in trials (no problems with just Vitamin D) – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/calcium-increased-risk-of-side-effects-in-trials-no-problems-with-just-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-increased-risk-of-side-effects-in-trials-no-problems-with-just-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Calcium Essential to Limit Osteoporosis but Avoid Excess, Say Europeans</title><link>/posts/calcium-essential-to-limit-osteoporosis-but-avoid-excess-say-europeans.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-essential-to-limit-osteoporosis-but-avoid-excess-say-europeans.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calcium-in-the-prevention-of-postmenopausal-osteoporosis-emas-clinical-guide">Calcium in the prevention of postmenopausal osteoporosis: EMAS clinical guide&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Summary from PDF&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>An adequate intake of calcium as a mainstay in the prevention of postmenopausal osteoporosis remains a universal recommendation in guidelines.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It is important to get an assessment, even approximate, of the individual’s intake of calcium.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Supplementation may be recommended, where levels are or seem to be insufficient.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Women should be warned that calcium intakes above the recommended levels may be useless,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>or may even entail some harm&lt;/strong> , though this remains uncertain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium problems associated with CYP24A1 (a Vitamin D gene)</title><link>/posts/calcium-problems-associated-with-cyp24a1-a-vitamin-d-gene.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-problems-associated-with-cyp24a1-a-vitamin-d-gene.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Drinking 3 glasses of milk daily associated with doubling the death rate</title><link>/posts/drinking-3-glasses-of-milk-daily-associated-with-doubling-the-death-rate.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/drinking-3-glasses-of-milk-daily-associated-with-doubling-the-death-rate.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="milk-intake-and-risk-of-mortality-and-fractures-in-women-and-men-cohort-studies">Milk intake and risk of mortality and fractures in women and men: cohort studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMJ 2014; 349 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/https">doi: https&lt;/a>://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.g6015 (Published 28 October 2014)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karl Michaëlsson, professor1, Alicja Wolk, professor2, Sophie Langenskiöld, senior lecturer3, Samar Basu, professor3, Eva Warensjö Lemming, researcher14, Håkan Melhus, professor5, Liisa Byberg, associate professor1&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note: Many people now tend to drink low-fat milk, which provides &lt;a href="/posts/skim-fat-milk-provides-3-percent-less-vitamin-d">2.5X less Vitamin D to the body&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note: Various groups around the world are trying to increase milk consumption by elderly&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preeclampsia reduced 2X by Vitamin D, by 5X if also add Calcium – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/preeclampsia-reduced-2x-by-vitamin-d-by-5x-if-also-add-calcium-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/preeclampsia-reduced-2x-by-vitamin-d-by-5x-if-also-add-calcium-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Drugs which create deficiencies in Vitamin D, Vitamin K, Magnesium, Zinc, Iron, etc.</title><link>/posts/drugs-which-create-deficiencies-in-vitamin-d-vitamin-k-magnesium-zinc-iron-etc.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/drugs-which-create-deficiencies-in-vitamin-d-vitamin-k-magnesium-zinc-iron-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-chemical-disruption-of-human-metabolism">The chemical disruption of human metabolism.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Toxicol Mech Methods. 2017 Sep;27(7):477-500. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/15376516.2017.1323986.">doi: 10.1080/15376516.2017.1323986.&lt;/a> Epub 2017 Jun 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Genuis SJ1, Kyrillos E2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Faculty of Medicine, University of Alberta , Edmonton , Alberta , Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Family Medicine , Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa , Ottawa , Ontario , Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent evidence highlights the reality of unprecedented human exposure to toxic chemical agents found throughout our environment - in our food and water supply, in the air we breathe, in the products we apply to our skin, in the medical and dental materials placed into our bodies, and even within the confines of the womb. With biomonitoring confirming the widespread bioaccumulation of myriad toxicants among population groups, expanding research continues to explore the pathobiological impact of these agents on human metabolism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thyroid Cancer rate has increased 3X in 3 decades, Vitamin D Receptor decreases, Calcium increases</title><link>/posts/thyroid-cancer-rate-has-increased-3x-in-3-decades-vitamin-d-receptor-decreases-calcium-increases.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/thyroid-cancer-rate-has-increased-3x-in-3-decades-vitamin-d-receptor-decreases-calcium-increases.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="thyroid-cancer-is-the-fastest-growing-cancer-in-americahttpwwwaarporghealthconditions-treatmentsinfo-2017thyroid-cancer-rates-increasing-fdhtmlcmpemc-dso-nlc-wbltr---nmctrl-082517-f1-2368675et_cid2368675et_rid7879513encparamxb0a8m9yqixowhba5hkb5qvkttrosbfzjr0tnlhia0e-aarp-july-2017">&lt;a href="http://www.aarp.org/health/conditions-treatments/info-2017/thyroid-cancer-rates-increasing-fd.html?cmp=EMC-DSO-NLC-WBLTR---NMCTRL-082517-F1-2368675&amp;amp;ET_CID=2368675&amp;amp;ET_RID=7879513&amp;amp;encparam=xB0a8m9yQIXOWhBA5HKb5QvkttROsbfZJr0tnlHiA0E=">Thyroid Cancer is the Fastest-Growing Cancer in America&lt;/a> AARP July 2017&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>“According to the American Cancer Society, the chance of being diagnosed with thyroid cancer has &lt;strong>tripled over the last three decades&lt;/strong> , making it the fastest-growing cancer.”&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="thyroid-cancer-rate-has-increased-age-adjusted-from-the-web">Thyroid Cancer rate has increased (age adjusted, from the web)&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/thyroid-cancer---age-adjusted.jpg" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;h4 id="micronutrient-status-calcium-zinc-vitamins-d-and-e-in-patients-with-medullary-thyroid-carcinoma-a-cross-sectional-study-sept-2017">Micronutrient status (calcium, zinc, vitamins D and E) in patients with medullary thyroid carcinoma: A cross-sectional study] Sept 2017&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“We found that &lt;strong>serum calcium&lt;/strong> remarkably associated with enhanced risk for thyroid cancer (odds ratio &lt;span>[OR]&lt;/span>, &lt;strong>6.5&lt;/strong> ; P = 0.001)”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypercalcemia can result from excess Vitamin D (if not reduce Ca or increase water)</title><link>/posts/hypercalcemia-can-result-from-excess-vitamin-d-if-not-reduce-ca-or-increase-water.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypercalcemia-can-result-from-excess-vitamin-d-if-not-reduce-ca-or-increase-water.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-mediated-hypercalcemia-mechanisms-diagnosis-and-treatment">Vitamin D-Mediated Hypercalcemia: Mechanisms, Diagnosis, and Treatment.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Rev. 2016 Oct;37(5):521-547. Epub 2016 Sep 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tebben PJ1, Singh RJ1, Kumar R1.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-comparing-symptoms-of-hypercalcemia-with-low-magnesium">Vitamin D - Comparing Symptoms of Hypercalcemia with Low Magnesium - Sept 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://VitaminDWiki.com/Search+Results?hl=en&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search&amp;amp;googles.x=0&amp;amp;googles.y=0&amp;amp;q=Hypercalcemia&amp;amp;domains=VitaminDWiki.com&amp;amp;sitesearch=VitaminDWiki.com">Search VitaminDWiki for HYPERCALCEMIA&lt;/a> 1480 results as of Oct 2019&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/no-risk-of-hypercalcemia-with-prolonged-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d3">No risk of hypercalcemia with prolonged 10000 IU of vitamin D3 – July 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/hypercalcemia-in-critically-ill-patients-taking-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-many-solutions">Hypercalcemia in critically ill patients taking 10,000 IU of vitamin D (many solutions) – Oct 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Risk of Ischemic Stroke doubles if take more than 1 gram of Calcium daily for years</title><link>/posts/risk-of-ischemic-stroke-doubles-if-take-more-than-1-gram-of-calcium-daily-for-years.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/risk-of-ischemic-stroke-doubles-if-take-more-than-1-gram-of-calcium-daily-for-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="risk-of-ischemic-stroke-associated-with-calcium-supplements-with-or-without-vitamin-d-a-nested-case-control-study">Risk of Ischemic Stroke Associated With Calcium Supplements With or Without Vitamin D: A Nested Case-Control Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Am Heart Assoc. 2017 May 18;6(5). pii: e005795. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.117.005795.">doi: 10.1161/JAHA.117.005795.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>de Abajo FJ1,2, Rodríguez-Martín S3, Rodríguez-Miguel A3, Gil MJ4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Clinical Pharmacology Unit, University Hospital Príncipe de Asturias, Alcalá de Henares Madrid, Spain &lt;a href="mailto:francisco.abajo@uah.es">francisco.abajo@uah.es&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Departament of Biomedical Sciences (Pharmacology Sector), University of Alcalá, Alcalá de Henares Madrid, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Clinical Pharmacology Unit, University Hospital Príncipe de Asturias, Alcalá de Henares Madrid, Spain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pregnancies in the winter lacking vitamin D need more Calcium</title><link>/posts/pregnancies-in-the-winter-lacking-vitamin-d-need-more-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnancies-in-the-winter-lacking-vitamin-d-need-more-calcium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Natural variation in mineral content of a food is typically 3 to 1</title><link>/posts/natural-variation-in-mineral-content-of-a-food-is-typically-3-to-1.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/natural-variation-in-mineral-content-of-a-food-is-typically-3-to-1.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mineral-nutrient-composition--of-vegetables-fruits-and-grains-the-context-of-reports-of-apparent-historical-declines">Mineral nutrient composition of vegetables, fruits and grains: The context of reports of apparent historical declines&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Food Composition and Analysis &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jfca.2016.11.012">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jfca.2016.11.012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robin J. Marles &lt;a href="mailto:robin.marles@hc-sc.gc.ca">robin.marles@hc-sc.gc.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Senior Scientific Advisor, Nutrition Premarket Assessment Division, Bureau of Nutritional Sciences, Food Directorate, Health Canada, 251 Sir Frederick Banting Driveway (Mail Stop 2203E), Ottawa, Ontario K1A 0K9, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Nicely describes why most of the alarmest reports of declines should not be believed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Documents the huge variation in mineral content due to differences in climate, species, cultivars, etc. - see table below&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aggressive Prostate Cancer in blacks with low vitamin D – 7X more likely if added Calcium</title><link>/posts/aggressive-prostate-cancer-in-blacks-with-low-vitamin-d-7x-more-likely-if-added-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/aggressive-prostate-cancer-in-blacks-with-low-vitamin-d-7x-more-likely-if-added-calcium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Less than 900 IU of Vitamin D and Calcium do not cause cardiovascular problems</title><link>/posts/less-than-900-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-do-not-cause-cardiovascular-problems.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-than-900-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-do-not-cause-cardiovascular-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="lack-of-evidence-linking-calcium-with-or-without-vitamin-d-supplementation-to-cardiovascular-disease-in-generally-healthy-adults-a-clinical-guideline-from-the-national-osteoporosis-annals-of-internal-medicine">Lack of Evidence Linking Calcium With or Without Vitamin D Supplementation to Cardiovascular Disease in Generally Healthy Adults: A Clinical Guideline From the National Osteoporosis Annals of Internal Medicine,&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>CLINICAL GUIDELINES 20 DECEMBER 2016, Foundation and the American Society for Preventive Cardiology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ann Intern Med. 2016;165(12):867-868. DOI: 10.7326/M16-1743&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:750px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It is amazing that they make the statement that (any amount) of Vitamin D and Calcium do not cause problems when most of the studies they considered used 400 IU and only one used 800 IU.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium from plants might be OK</title><link>/posts/calcium-from-plants-might-be-ok.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-from-plants-might-be-ok.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>800 IU of vitamin D is not enough to help Cardiovascular Disease (found again)</title><link>/posts/800-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-not-enough-to-help-cardiovascular-disease-found-again.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-not-enough-to-help-cardiovascular-disease-found-again.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cancer risk in older women reduced 32 percent by 2,000 IU of Vitamin D plus Calcium – 4 year RCT</title><link>/posts/cancer-risk-in-older-women-reduced-32-percent-by-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-plus-calcium-4-year-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-risk-in-older-women-reduced-32-percent-by-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-plus-calcium-4-year-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-and-calcium-supplementation-significantly-decreases-cancer-risk-in-older-women">Vitamin D3 and calcium supplementation significantly decreases cancer risk in older women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Public Health Association 2016 meeting Oct 31, 2016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joan Lappe, Creighton University; Dianne Travers-Gustafson, Creighton University; Cedric Garland, University of California at San Diego; Robert Heaney, Creighton University; Robert Recker, Creighton University; Patrice Watson, Creighton University&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:750px">
&lt;p>This RCT did not have an arm for Vitamin D without Calcium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a lot of controversy about Calcium - does it help or harm health?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skim fat milk provides 3% less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/skim-fat-milk-provides-3-percent-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skim-fat-milk-provides-3-percent-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#higher-milk-fat-content-is-associated-with-higher-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-in-early-childhood">Higher milk fat content is associated with higher 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration in early childhood.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#history-of-us-milk-consumption">History of US Milk Consumption&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reminder-64-of-all-humans-are-lactose-intollerant">Reminder: 64% of all humans are lactose intollerant&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hypothesis-decreased-bioavailable-calcium-if-decreased-vitamin-d-low-fat-milk">Hypothesis: decreased bioavailable Calcium if decreased Vitamin D (low-fat milk)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="higher-milk-fat-content-is-associated-with-higher-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-in-early-childhood">Higher milk fat content is associated with higher 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration in early childhood.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016 May;41(5):516-521 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1139/apnm-2015-0671">https://doi.org/10.1139/apnm-2015-0671&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vanderhout SM1,2,3, Birken CS4,5,6,7, Parkin PC4,5,6,7, Lebovic G3,7, Chen Y3, O&amp;rsquo;Connor DL1, Maguire JL1,2,3,4; &lt;a href="mailto:jonathon.maguire@utoronto.ca">jonathon.maguire@utoronto.ca&lt;/a> TARGetKids! Collaboration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Calcium report for IoM - not much change - updated 2014</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcium-report-for-iom-not-much-change-updated-2014.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcium-report-for-iom-not-much-change-updated-2014.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="i-classfas-fa-file-pdf-stylemargin-right-03emia-hrefhttpsd378j1rmrlek7xcloudfrontnetattachmentspdfvitamin-d-calcium-report-pdfdownload-the-entire-pdf-from-vitamindwikia">&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/vitamin-d-calcium-report-.pdf">Download the entire PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency">Vitamin D Deficiency&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/is-the-institute-of-medicine-report-on-calcium-and-vitamin-d-good-science">Is the Institute of Medicine Report on Calcium and Vitamin D Good Science - Jan 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/wonder-about-conflict-of-interest-of-iom-panel-members">Wonder about conflict of interest of IoM panel members&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h4 id="this-is-an-update-of-the-report-used-by-the-institute-of-medicine-in-2010">This is an update of the report used by the Institute of Medicine in 2010&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Just introduction and Executive summary on this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN"

"http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/loose.dtd">
&lt;html>
&lt;head>&lt;meta http-equiv="content-type" content="text/html; charset=UTF-8"/>&lt;meta name="generator" content="‎ABBYY PDF Transformer+‎"/>&lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="vitamin-d-calcium-report-_files/vitamin-d-calcium-report-.css" type="text/css"/>
&lt;/head>
&lt;body>
&lt;p>&lt;span class="font11" style="font-weight:bold;font-style:italic;text-decoration:underline;">Evidence Report/Technology Assessment&lt;/span>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interactions between Magnesium, Vitamin D, and Calcium</title><link>/posts/interactions-between-magnesium-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/interactions-between-magnesium-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Is a health problem associated with Low vitamin D, Low Magnesium, or too much Calcium</title><link>/posts/is-a-health-problem-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-low-magnesium-or-too-much-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-a-health-problem-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-low-magnesium-or-too-much-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="essential-nutrient-interactions-does-low-or-suboptimal-magnesium-status-interact-with-vitamin-d-andor-calcium-status">Essential Nutrient Interactions: Does Low or Suboptimal Magnesium Status Interact with Vitamin D and/or Calcium Status?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Adv Nutr. 2016 Jan 15;7(1):25-43. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3945/an.115.008631.">doi: 10.3945/an.115.008631.&lt;/a> Print 2016 Jan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rosanoff A1, Dai Q2, Shapses SA3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 &lt;a href="http://www.magnesiumeducation.com/">Center for Magnesium Education and Research&lt;/a>, Pahoa, HI; &lt;a href="mailto:arosanoff@gmail.com">arosanoff@gmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Vanderbilt Epidemiology Center, Department of Medicine, School of Medicine, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:750px">
&lt;p>Optimum Calcium somewhere 1.7 - 2.5 X Magnesium &lt;a href="/posts/calcium-2x-of-magnesium-seems-good-china">China says 2.0 X&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D response reduced if taken with Calcium – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-response-reduced-if-taken-with-calcium-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-response-reduced-if-taken-with-calcium-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-or-activated-vitamin-d-on-circulating-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-a-systematic-review-and-metaanalysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials">Effect of Vitamin D or Activated Vitamin D on Circulating 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D Concentrations: A Systematic Review and Metaanalysis of Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Armin Zittermann1,*, Jana B. Ernst1, Ingvild Birschmann2 and Marcus Dittrich3,4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Clinic for Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Institute for Laboratory and Transfusion Medicine, Heart and Diabetes Center North Rhine-Westphalia, Ruhr University Bochum, Bad Oeynhausen, Germany;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Bioinformatics, Biocenter, University of Wuerzburg, Wuerzburg, Germany;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Institute of Human Genetics, University of Wuerzburg, Wuerzburg, Germany.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidneys, Vitamin D and Calcium</title><link>/posts/kidneys-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidneys-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-the-kidneys-a-fascinating-relationship--editorial">Vitamin D and the kidneys: a fascinating relationship – EDITORIAL&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J. Bras. Patol. Med. Lab. vol.51 no.5 Rio de Janeiro Sept./Oct. 2015, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.5935/1676-2444.20150045">http://dx.doi.org/10.5935/1676-2444.20150045&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>José Gilberto Henriques Vieira 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Escola Paulista de Medicina da Universidade Federal de São Paulo (EPM/Unifesp)&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/kidney-vitamin-d-ca.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;p>The complexity of the physiological system that controls serum calcium levels is remarkable. In the Figure we present a very simplified view of this system, stressing the crucial role of vitamin D and the kidneys in the overall complex. No wonder, the system without normal renal function turns out to be highly deranged. Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is, unfortunately, very frequent, and metabolic bone disease, the result of specific alterations in calcium and phosphorus metabolism, one of its main complications(1). The availability of kidney transplantation provided a real step forward in CKD patients&amp;rsquo; survival and quality of life. For the majority of transplant patients, a return to nearly normal renal function is the more likely result(2).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low fertility associated with low Calcium intake and low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/low-fertility-associated-with-low-calcium-intake-and-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-fertility-associated-with-low-calcium-intake-and-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-among-subfertile-women-case-control-study">Vitamin D deficiency among subfertile women: case control study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Gynecol Endocrinol. 2015 Nov 16:1-18. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:400px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>| | | |
| &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; |
| | subfertile | fertile |
| Vitamin D deficiency | 59% | 40% |
| Calcium intake | 10% | 65% |&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-and-fertility-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D and fertility: a systematic review – May 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-and-fertility-lerchbaum-2012-2014">Vitamin D and fertility – Lerchbaum 2012, 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D - Comparing Symptoms of Hypercalcemia with Low Magnesium</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-comparing-symptoms-of-hypercalcemia-with-low-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-comparing-symptoms-of-hypercalcemia-with-low-magnesium.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="from-httpwwwvitamindcouncilorgq-a-forumtopicis-there-a-form-of-vitamin-d-that-wont-give-me-nausea-i-was-taking-the-3k-worth-of-d-that-my-md-recommended-and-i-started-to-experience-extreme-nausea-what-good-is-the-d-if-i-throw-it-up">From [http://www.vitamindcouncil.org/q-a-forum/topic/is-there-a-form-of-vitamin-d-that-wont-give-me-nausea-i-was-taking-the-3k-worth-of-d-that-my-md-recommended-and-i-started-to-experience-extreme-nausea-what-good-is-the-d-if-i-throw-it-up/|&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Is there a form of vitamin D that won&amp;rsquo;t give me nausea? I was taking the 3K worth of D that my MD recommended and I started to experience extreme nausea] Vitamin D Council&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{SPLIT(fixedsize=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; colsize=&amp;ldquo;200px|200px|&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hypercalcemia Symptoms&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(too much vitamin D)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•	feeling sick or being sick&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•	poor appetite or loss of appetite&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• feeling very thirsty&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•	passing urine often&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• constipation or diarrhea&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• abdominal pain&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Cofactors in a nutshell</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-cofactors-in-a-nutshell.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-cofactors-in-a-nutshell.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#perspective-of-the-importance-of-vit-d-and-co-factors-to-healthpostsways-to-improve-health">&lt;a href="/posts/ways-to-improve-health">Perspective of the importance of Vit D and co-factors to health&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also---excellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlabpostsexcellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlab">See also - &lt;a href="/posts/excellent-reviews-of-supplements-at-consumerlab">Excellent reviews of supplements at ConsumerLab&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h5 id="glutathionetagsglutathionehtml---the-master-antioxidant-synergistic-with-vitamin-d">&lt;a href="/tags/glutathione.html">Glutathione&lt;/a> - the master antioxidant, synergistic with Vitamin D&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Increased Glutathione (the master antioxidant) - increases both cellular and blood levels of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D also increases Glutathione&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glutathione can be increased in many ways, perhaps the best is liposomal Glutathione&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h5 id="supplements-taken-by-the-founder-of-vitamindwikipostssupplements-taken-by-the-founder-of-vitamindwiki">&lt;a href="/posts/supplements-taken-by-the-founder-of-vitamindwiki">Supplements taken by the founder of VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>As of Dec 2024, my only daily supplement is Calcium. The rest are every 2 to 7 days&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D increases mineral availability which protect against toxic elements</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-increases-mineral-availability-which-protect-against-toxic-elements.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-increases-mineral-availability-which-protect-against-toxic-elements.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="higher-concentration-of-some-metals-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-near-a-mine-in-mexico---aug-2015">Higher concentration of some metals associated with higher vitamin D near a mine in Mexico - Aug 2015&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Association of arsenic and metals with concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D among adolescents in Torreón, Mexico.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Environ Health Perspect. 2014 Nov;122(11):1233-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1289/ehp.1307861.">doi: 10.1289/ehp.1307861.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Aug 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zamoiski RD1, Guallar E, García-Vargas GG, Rothenberg SJ, Resnick C, Andrade MR, Steuerwald AJ, Parsons PJ, Weaver VM, Navas-Acien A, Silbergeld EK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Environmental Health Sciences, Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium supplements proven to NOT reduce fractures, but are proven to INCREASE heart problems</title><link>/posts/calcium-supplements-proven-to-not-reduce-fractures-but-are-proven-to-increase-heart-problems.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-supplements-proven-to-not-reduce-fractures-but-are-proven-to-increase-heart-problems.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Calcium supplementation associated with 3.9X increase risk of atrial fibrillation</title><link>/posts/calcium-supplementation-associated-with-39x-increase-risk-of-atrial-fibrillation.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-supplementation-associated-with-39x-increase-risk-of-atrial-fibrillation.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Note: The increased Afib is probably due to the high ratio of Ca to Mg&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Supplementation of calcium (Ca) and vitamin D for the prevention of osteoporosis is frequently found in Western countries. Recent re-analyses of clinical trials observed a higher risk of myocardial infarction and stroke in subjects taking Ca (+vitamin D) supplements, although the underlying mechanisms are not clear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus, we analyzed the associations between Ca and vitamin D supplementation as well as serum concentrations of Ca and 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and subclinical cardiovascular disease (CVD) phenotypes, namely intima-media thickness, ankle-brachial-index (ABI), intermittent claudication, and atrial fibrillation (AF).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Most Calcium Supplement Recommendations are DEAD WRONG</title><link>/posts/why-most-calcium-supplement-recommendations-are-dead-wrong.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-most-calcium-supplement-recommendations-are-dead-wrong.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="greenmedinfohttpwwwgreenmedinfocomblogwhy-most-calcium-supplement-recommendations-are-dead-wrong1">&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/why-most-calcium-supplement-recommendations-are-dead-wrong1">GreenMedInfo&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Starts with&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An alarming new meta-analysis published in the journal Nutrients titled, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3738985/">Cardiovascular Effects of Calcium Supplements&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; brings to the forefront the serious though mainly downplayed health risks associated with calcium supplementation, concluding they increase the risk of heart attack by 27%-31% and the risk of stroke by 12%-20%.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off Topic: More than 800 mg of Calcium increases risk of Macular Degeneration in seniors by 2.6X – JAMA</title><link>/posts/off-topic-more-than-800-mg-of-calcium-increases-risk-of-macular-degeneration-in-seniors-by-26x-jama.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-more-than-800-mg-of-calcium-increases-risk-of-macular-degeneration-in-seniors-by-26x-jama.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="self-reported-calcium-supplementation-and-age-related-macular-degeneration-online-first">Self-reported Calcium Supplementation and Age-Related Macular Degeneration ONLINE FIRST&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>JAMA Ophthalmol. Published online April 09, 2015. doi:10.1001/jamaophthalmol.2015.0514 Caitlin L. M. Kakigi, BA1; Kuldev Singh, MD, MPH2; Sophia Y. Wang, MD3; Wayne T. Enanoria, PhD, MPH4; Shan C. Lin, MD1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Importance Despite widespread use of calcium supplementation among elderly people, little is known about the association between such consumption and the prevalence of age-related macular degeneration (AMD) in the United States.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stronger bones after 3 generations of tap water (more Ca and Mg) vs bottled water</title><link>/posts/stronger-bones-after-3-generations-of-tap-water-more-ca-and-mg-vs-bottled-water.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stronger-bones-after-3-generations-of-tap-water-more-ca-and-mg-vs-bottled-water.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="multi-generational-drinking-of-bottled-low-mineral-water-impairs-bone-quality-in-female-rats">Multi-generational drinking of bottled low mineral water impairs bone quality in female rats.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2015 Mar 24;10(3):e0121995. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0121995.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0121995.&lt;/a> eCollection 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Qiu Z1, Tan Y1, Zeng H1, Wang L1, Wang D1, Luo J1, Zhang L1, Huang Y1, Chen JA2, Shu W1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of reproductions and hormone changes, females are more sensitive to bone mineral loss during their lifetime. Bottled water has become more popular in recent years, and a large number of products are low mineral water. However, research on the effects of drinking bottled low mineral water on bone health is sparse.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>T1 diabetes in children helped with two doses of 150,000 IU of vitamin D and Calcium</title><link>/posts/t1-diabetes-in-children-helped-with-two-doses-of-150000-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/t1-diabetes-in-children-helped-with-two-doses-of-150000-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-vitamin-d3-supplement-in-glycemic-control-of-pediatrics-with-type-1-diabetes-mellitus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency">Effect of Vitamin D3 Supplement in Glycemic Control of Pediatrics with Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus and Vitamin D Deficiency&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical and Diagnsotic Research 2015 March V-9 #3 SC05 - SC07&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sakineh Mohammadian, Nasrin Fatahi, Hossein Zaeri, Mohammad Ali Vakili&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence : Dr. Nasrin Fatahi,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pediatric Resident, Golestan University of Medical Science, Neonatal and Children Health Research Center, Gorgan, Iran. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:nfty3063@yahoo.com">nfty3063@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Glycemic control prevents microvascular complications in patients with type I diabetes mellitus such as retinopathy, nephropathy and neuropathy that influences quality of life. Some studies show the immunomodulatory effect of vitamin D in synthesis and secretion of insulin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetic hypertension reduced with Vitamin D and Calcium – RCT</title><link>/posts/diabetic-hypertension-reduced-with-vitamin-d-and-calcium-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetic-hypertension-reduced-with-vitamin-d-and-calcium-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-calcium-plus-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-anthropometric-measurements-and-blood-pressure-in-vitamin-d-insufficient-people-with-type-2-diabetes-a-randomized-controlled-clinical-trial">Effects of Calcium Plus Vitamin D Supplementation on Anthropometric Measurements and Blood Pressure in Vitamin D Insufficient People with Type 2 Diabetes: A Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Am Coll Nutr. 2015 Mar 4:1-9. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tabesh M1, Azadbakht L, Faghihimani E, Tabesh M, Esmaillzadeh A.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>50,000 IU vitamin D weekly + 1000 mg/d Calcium vs placebos&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Systolic blood pressure reduced by 8 mmHg in 8 weeks&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Calcium does NOT cause cardiovascular problems (reverses their meta-analysis)</title><link>/posts/adding-calcium-does-not-cause-cardiovascular-problems-reverses-their-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adding-calcium-does-not-cause-cardiovascular-problems-reverses-their-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="cardiovascular-complications-of-calcium-supplements">Cardiovascular Complications of Calcium Supplements.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Cell Biochem. 2014 Dec 10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jcb.25028.">doi: 10.1002/jcb.25028.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reid IR1, Bristow SM, Bolland MJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand; Department of Endocrinology, Auckland District Health Board, New Zealand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is longstanding concern that calcium supplements might increase cardiovascular risk in patients with renal impairment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Auckland Calcium Study suggested that the same problem occurs in older people taking these supplements for prevention of osteoporosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium intestinal absorption increased with active, but not tested level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/calcium-intestinal-absorption-increased-with-active-but-not-tested-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-intestinal-absorption-increased-with-active-but-not-tested-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-does-not-reflect-intestinal-calcium-absorption-an-assay-using-strontium-as-a-surrogate-marker">25-Hydroxyvitamin D level does not reflect intestinal calcium absorption: an assay using strontium as a surrogate marker.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Metab. 2014 May 24. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Camargo MB1, Vilaça T, Hayashi LF, Rocha OG, Lazaretti-Castro M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Endocrinology, School of Medicine, Federal University of São Paulo/UNIFESP, Avenida Nove de Julho, 5581, Apto. 30, Jardim Paulista, São Paulo, SP, CEP 01407-200, Brazil, &lt;a href="mailto:lilacamargo@uol.com.br">lilacamargo@uol.com.br&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is conflicting evidence as to the optimal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentration for intestinal calcium absorption (Abs-Ca). Our purpose was to assess the relationship between vitamin D status and Abs-Ca in postmenopausal women. Fifty volunteers with low bone mass were grouped according to their serum 25(OH)D concentration as follows: mild deficient, &amp;lt;50 nmol/L (DEF) and sufficient, ≥75 nmol/L (SUF). The subjects were submitted to an oral strontium overload test to assess their Abs-Ca. Fasting blood samples were obtained to perform the relevant hormonal and biochemical tests. After the subjects received the test solution, blood samples were drawn at 30, 60, 120, and 240 min to determine the strontium concentrations. Abs-Ca was indirectly expressed as the area under the serum strontium concentration curve (AUC). A repeated measures ANOVA was performed to determine the differences among the groups. Pearson&amp;rsquo;s correlation and multiple linear regression analysis were used to study the associations between the variables. The mean 25(OH)D and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[1,25(OH)2D]&lt;/span> concentrations differed between the groups (SUF vs. DEF) as follows: 98.7 ± 18.2 vs. 38.4 ± 8.5 nmol/L (p &amp;lt; 0.001) and 36.2 ± 10.2 vs. 24.9 ± 4.6 pg/mL (p &amp;lt; 0.001), respectively. There was no statistically significant difference between the groups for parathyroid hormone and AUC.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hydrochlorothiazide might be a problem when getting lots of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hydrochlorothiazide-might-be-a-problem-when-getting-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hydrochlorothiazide-might-be-a-problem-when-getting-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#risk-of-hypercalcemia-in-blacks-taking-hydrochlorothiazide-and-vitamin-d">Risk of Hypercalcemia in Blacks Taking Hydrochlorothiazide and Vitamin D&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#thiazide-induced-severe-hypercalcemia-a-case-report-and-review-of-literature">Thiazide-induced severe hypercalcemia: a case report and review of literature.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#case-report-by-henry-lahore-founder-of-vitamindwiki">Case report by Henry Lahore, founder of VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="risk-of-hypercalcemia-in-blacks-taking-hydrochlorothiazide-and-vitamin-d">Risk of Hypercalcemia in Blacks Taking Hydrochlorothiazide and Vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>American Journal of Medicine, DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2014.02.044">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2014.02.044&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received: February 4, 2014; Received in revised form: February 28, 2014; Accepted: February 28, 2014; Published Online: March 20, 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paulette D. Chandler, MD, MPH , Jamil B. Scott, PhD, MPH, Bettina F. Drake, PhD, MPH, Kimmie Ng, MD, MPH, John P. Forman, Andrew T. Chan, MD, Gary G. Bennett, PhD, Bruce W. Hollis, PhD, Edward L. Giovannucci, MD, ScD, Karen M. Emmons, PhD, Charles S. Fuchs, MD, MPH&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium intake of 500 mg is typically enough</title><link>/posts/calcium-intake-of-500-mg-is-typically-enough.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-intake-of-500-mg-is-typically-enough.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="calcium-supplements-do-they-help-or-harm">Calcium supplements: do they help or harm?.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Menopause. 21(1):106-108, January 2014, &lt;span>[Clinical Corner: NAMS Practice Pearl]&lt;/span>, AN: 00042192-201401000-00018.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manson, JoAnn E. MD, DrPH, NCMP; Bassuk, Shari S. ScD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Current recommendations for calcium intake call for 1,000 mg per day for women ages 19-50 and 1,200 mg per day for women over age 50 to ensure bone health. Given recent concerns that calcium supplements may raise risk for cardiovascular disease and kidney stones, women should aim to meet this recommendation primarily by eating a calcium-rich diet and taking calcium supplements only if needed to reach the RDA goal (often only ~500 mg per day in supplements is required).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The influence of Vitamin D and Calcium on fat and obesity</title><link>/posts/the-influence-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-on-fat-and-obesity.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-influence-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-on-fat-and-obesity.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-the-regulation-of-energy-balance-where-do-we-stand">Calcium and Vitamin D in the Regulation of Energy Balance: Where Do We Stand?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Int. J. Molecular. Sci. 2014, 15(3), 4938-4945; doi:10.3390/ijms15034938 (doi registration under processing)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mario J. Soares &lt;a href="mailto:m.soares@curtin.edu.au">m.soares@curtin.edu.au&lt;/a> , Kaveri Pathak †email and Emily K. Calton †email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Directorate of Nutrition, Dietetics &amp;amp; Food Science, School of Public Health, Faculty of Health Sciences, Curtin University, Perth 6845, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received: 19 February 2014; in revised form: 11 March 2014 / Accepted: 13 March 2014 / Published: 20 March 2014&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="web">Web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://drcarolyndean.com/2017/11/the-war-on-calcification/">The War on Calcification&lt;/a> C. Dean Nov 2017&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Heart disease – atheroma, atherosclerosis, aortic valve stenosis, calcium build up in carotids, coronary arteries, renal arteries – any arteries in the body.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Calcinosis – Deposition of calcium in the lung, kidneys, blood vessels, and stomach.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Calcific tendenitis in the rotator cuff&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Gall stones&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Hypoparathyroidism&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kidney stones&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>DCIS – breast tissue calcification misidentified as precancer&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fibromyalgia muscle spasms and calcification&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Bladder tissue and urethral calcification&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More Calcium absorbed with more vitamin D – 6.7% more with 4000 IU – RCT</title><link>/posts/more-calcium-absorbed-with-more-vitamin-d-67-percent-more-with-4000-iu-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-calcium-absorbed-with-more-vitamin-d-67-percent-more-with-4000-iu-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-increases-calcium-absorption-without-a-threshold-effect">Vitamin D supplementation increases calcium absorption without a threshold effect&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#81-citations-of-this-study-as-of-april-2023">81 citations of this study as of April 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-increases-calcium-absorption-without-a-threshold-effect">Vitamin D supplementation increases calcium absorption without a threshold effect&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr March 2014 vol. 99 no. 3 624-631&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John F Aloia, Ruban Dhaliwal, Albert Shieh, Mageda Mikhail, Melissa Fazzari, Louis Ragolia, and Steven A Abrams&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Winthrop University Hospital, Mineola, NY (JFA, RD, AS, MM, MF, and LR)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – low vitamin D level may indicate Calcium deficiency – Masterjohn II</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-low-vitamin-d-level-may-indicate-calcium-deficiency-masterjohn-ii.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-low-vitamin-d-level-may-indicate-calcium-deficiency-masterjohn-ii.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="an-ancestral-perspective-on-vitamin-d-status-part-2">An Ancestral Perspective on Vitamin D Status, Part 2:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Why Low 25(OH)D Could Indicate a Deficiency of Calcium Instead of Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.westonaprice.org/blogs/cmasterjohn/2013/12/19/an-ancestral-perspective-on-vitamin-d-status-part-2-why-low-25ohd-could-indicate-a-deficiency-of-calcium-instead-of-vitamin-d/%20">Winston Price Foundation&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chris Masterjohn – December 19, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first post in this series, I critiqued the “naked ape hypothesis of optimal serum 25(OH)D,” which I believe influences many researchers to interpret uncertainties in the scientific literature in a way that is biased towards recommendations for high intakes of vitamin D that could be harmful to some people, especially without appropriate attention to the nutrient density and balance of the diet, and to the overall context of a healthy diet and lifestyle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vascular calcification greatly reduced by 3 per week 1000 ug of Vitamin K2 MK-7</title><link>/posts/vascular-calcification-greatly-reduced-by-3-per-week-1000-ug-of-vitamin-k2-mk-7.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vascular-calcification-greatly-reduced-by-3-per-week-1000-ug-of-vitamin-k2-mk-7.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#press-release-12192013-menaq7-vitamin-k2-supplementation-may-benefit-dialysis-patients-by-inhibiting-vascular-calcification">Press Release 12/19/2013: MenaQ7® Vitamin K2 Supplementation May Benefit Dialysis Patients by Inhibiting Vascular Calcification&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-k2-supplementation-in-haemodialysis-patients-a-randomized-dose-finding-study">Vitamin K2 supplementation in haemodialysis patients: a randomized dose-finding study*&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="press-release-12192013-menaq7-vitamin-k2-supplementation-may-benefit-dialysis-patients-by-inhibiting-vascular-calcification">Press Release 12/19/2013: MenaQ7® Vitamin K2 Supplementation May Benefit Dialysis Patients by Inhibiting Vascular Calcification&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>NattoPharma has announced the publication of a new study performed in collaboration with OLV Hospital, Belgium, St. Jan Hospital, Belgium and VitaK, University of Maastricht, the Netherlands, published by Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ndt/gft464">doi: 10.1093/ndt/gft464&lt;/a> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death by Calcium, book by Thomas Levy</title><link>/posts/death-by-calcium-book-by-thomas-levy.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-by-calcium-book-by-thomas-levy.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="death-by-calcium-thomas-e-levyhttpwwwmedfoxpubcommedicalnewsproducts-dbcdeath-by-calciumdeath-by-calcium-md-jd">&lt;a href="http://www.medfoxpub.com/medicalnews/product/S-DBC/Death-by-Calcium/Death-by-Calcium/">Death by Calcium, Thomas E. Levy&lt;/a>, MD, JD&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Price:	$29.95 paper Pages:	432, $19.95 Ebook , &lt;strong>Chapter 1 at bottom of this page&lt;/strong> book was NOT on Amazon as of Dec 12, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent scientific studies now provide overwhelming proof that unequivocally confirms what many non-mainstream healthcare practitioners have long known and asserted: The regular intake of dairy and calcium supplementation promotes all known chronic degenerative diseases, and it significantly shortens life. All physicians and patients alike need to know the truth about calcium. Most people already have too much calcium in their tissues, and the incessant trumpeting of the purported health benefits of calcium supplementation and high-dairy diets must finally be exposed as marketing ploys only. The truth about calcium must finally be known.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children have better Calcium levels when vitamin D levels are higher than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/children-have-better-calcium-levels-when-vitamin-d-levels-are-higher-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-have-better-calcium-levels-when-vitamin-d-levels-are-higher-than-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="determination-of-reference-intervals-for-serum-total-calcium-in-the-vitamin-d-replete-pediatric-population">Determination of Reference Intervals for Serum Total Calcium in the Vitamin D-Replete Pediatric Population&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism November 11, 2013 jc.2013-3105&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jeffrey D. Roizen,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vipul Shah,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael A. Levine and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dean C. Carlow&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Diabetes (J.D.R., M.A.L.) and Division of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine (V.S., D.C.C.), The Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia, and University of Pennsylvania Perelman School of Medicine, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 19104&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address all correspondence and requests for reprints to: Dr Dean Carlow, Division of Pathology and Lab Medicine, The Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia, 34th and Civic Center Boulevard, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 19104. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:dc8236710@yahoo.com">dc8236710@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased Vitamin K2 reduces the problems of excess Calcium</title><link>/posts/increased-vitamin-k2-reduces-the-problems-of-excess-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-vitamin-k2-reduces-the-problems-of-excess-calcium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Calcium and 4,000 IU Vitamin D in Postmenopausal Women – RCT</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-4000-iu-vitamin-d-in-postmenopausal-women-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-4000-iu-vitamin-d-in-postmenopausal-women-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism November 1, 2013 vol. 98 no. 11 E1702-E1709&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John F. Aloia,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ruban Dhaliwal,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Albert Shieh,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mageda Mikhail,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shahidul Islam and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James K. Yeh&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Winthrop University Hospital, Bone Mineral Research Center, Mineola, New York 11501&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address all correspondence and requests for reprints to: John F. Aloia, MD, Winthrop University Hospital, 222 Station Plaza North, Suite 510, Mineola, New York 11501. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:jaloia@winthrop.org">jaloia@winthrop.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Context: Bone health is influenced by the intake of both calcium and vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium in blood (tightly regulated) did not increase when increase vitamin D to 40 ng – RCT</title><link>/posts/calcium-in-blood-tightly-regulated-did-not-increase-when-increase-vitamin-d-to-40-ng-rct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-in-blood-tightly-regulated-did-not-increase-when-increase-vitamin-d-to-40-ng-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-does-not-increase-calcium-absorption-in-young-women-a-randomized-clinical-trial">Vitamin D does not Increase Calcium Absorption in Young Women: A Randomized Clinical Trial&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Bone and Mineral Research, DOI: 10.1002/jbmr.2121&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christopher J Gallagher MD1, &lt;a href="mailto:jcg@creighton.edu">jcg@creighton.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS Jindal MBBS 1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M Smith Lynette MS 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Bone Metabolism Unit, Creighton University Medical Center, Omaha, Nebraska&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Biostatistics, University of Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha, Nebraska&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>1 year RCT with women&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ca with Vitamin D3 of 0, 400, 800, 1600, and 2400 IU&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ICU reduces Vitamin D levels, deregulates PTH</title><link>/posts/icu-reduces-vitamin-d-levels-deregulates-pth.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/icu-reduces-vitamin-d-levels-deregulates-pth.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="changes-in-the-calcium-parathyroid-hormone-vitamin-d-axis-and-prognosis-for-critically-ill-patients-a-prospective-observational-study">Changes in the Calcium-Parathyroid Hormone-Vitamin D Axis and Prognosis for Critically Ill Patients: A Prospective Observational Study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2013 Sep 20;8(9):e75441. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0075441.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0075441.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jieyu Hu equal contributor,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zuojie Luo equal contributor mail,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Xiaoqin Zhao,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Qiang Chen,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhaoyan Chen,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hua Qin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yingfen Qin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Xinghuan Liang,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yingjun Suo&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: Vitamin D deficiency is prevalent in critically ill patients and may contribute to suboptimal clinical outcomes, but little is known about alterations of the calcium-parathyroid hormone (PTH)-vitamin D axis and prognosis in these individuals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Micronutrients such as vitamin D for women and childhood</title><link>/posts/review-of-micronutrients-such-as-vitamin-d-for-women-and-childhood.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-micronutrients-such-as-vitamin-d-for-women-and-childhood.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="micronutrients-food-fortification-and-its-impact-on-woman-and-child-health-a-systematic-review">Micronutrients food fortification and its impact on woman and child health: a systematic review.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Syst Rev. 2013 Aug 23;2(1):67.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Das JK, Salam RA, Kumar R, Bhutta ZA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamins and minerals are essential for growth and metabolism. The World Health Organization estimates that more than 2 billion people are deficient in key vitamins and minerals. Groups most vulnerable to these micronutrient deficiencies are pregnant and lactating women and young children, given their increased demands. Food fortification is one of the strategies that has been used safely and effectively to prevent vitamin and mineral deficiencies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: An intestinal calcistat regulates Calcium level in body</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-an-intestinal-calcistat-regulates-calcium-level-in-body.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-an-intestinal-calcistat-regulates-calcium-level-in-body.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="calcium-homeostasis-and-clinical-or-subclinical-vitamin-d-deficiency">Calcium homeostasis, and clinical or subclinical vitamin D deficiency&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>– Can a hypothesis of “intestinal calcistat” explain it all?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical Hypotheses, Volume 81, Issue 2, August 2013, Pages 253–258&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M.K. Garg a, &lt;a href="mailto:mkgargs@gmail.com">mkgargs@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Namita Mahalle b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Endocrinology, Command Hospital (Southern Command), Pune 411040, Maharashtra, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Biochemistry Division, Department of Pathology, Deenanath Mangeshkar Hospital and Research Center, Erandawane, Pune, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main physiological function of vitamin D is maintenance of calcium homeostasis by its effect on calcium absorption, and bone health in association with parathyroid gland. Vitamin D deficiency (VDD) is defined as serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25OHD) levels &amp;lt;20 ng/ml. Vitamin D insufficiency is called when serum 25OHD levels are between 20–29 ng/ml, though existence of this entity has been questioned.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium reduced some rickets in Nigerian children</title><link>/posts/calcium-reduced-some-rickets-in-nigerian-children.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-reduced-some-rickets-in-nigerian-children.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevention-of-nutritional-rickets-in-nigerian-children-with-dietary-calcium-supplementation">Prevention of nutritional rickets in Nigerian children with dietary calcium supplementation.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bone. 2012 May;50(5):1074-80. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bone.2012.02.010.">doi: 10.1016/j.bone.2012.02.010.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Feb 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thacher TD, Fischer PR, Isichei CO, Zoakah AI, Pettifor JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Family Medicine (TDT), Mayo Clinic, 200 First Street, SW, Rochester, MN 55905, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:thacher.thomas@mayo.edu">thacher.thomas@mayo.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutritional rickets in Nigerian children usually results from dietary calcium insufficiency. Typical dietary calcium intakes in African children are about 200mg daily (approximately 20-28% of US RDAs for age). We sought to determine if rickets could be prevented with supplemental calcium or with an indigenous food rich in calcium. We enrolled Nigerian children aged 12 to 18 months from three urban communities. Two communities were assigned calcium, either as calcium carbonate (400mg) or ground fish (529±109mg) daily, while children in all three communities received vitamin A (2500IU) daily as placebo. Serum markers of mineral homeostasis and forearm bone density (pDEXA) were measured and radiographs were obtained at enrollment and after 18months of supplementation. The overall prevalence of radiographic rickets at baseline was 1.2% and of vitamin D deficiency &lt;a href="serum%2025(OH)D%3C12ng/ml">serum 25(OH)D&amp;lt;12ng/ml&lt;/a> 5.4%. Of 647 children enrolled, 390 completed the 18-month follow-up. Rickets developed in 1, 1, and 2 children assigned to the calcium tablet, ground fish, and control groups, respectively (approximate incidence 6.4/1000 children/year between 1 and 3years of age). Children who developed rickets in the calcium-supplemented groups had less than 50% adherence. Compared with the group that received no calcium supplementation, the groups that received calcium had a greater increase in areal bone density of the distal and proximal 1/3 radius and ulna over time (P&amp;lt;0.04). We conclude that calcium supplementation increased areal bone density at the radius and ulna, but a larger sample size would be required to determine its effect on the incidence of rickets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bones better after pregnancy with just 200 IU of vitamin D plus 600 Calcium – RCT</title><link>/posts/bones-better-after-pregnancy-with-just-200-iu-of-vitamin-d-plus-600-calcium-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bones-better-after-pregnancy-with-just-200-iu-of-vitamin-d-plus-600-calcium-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Magnesium may be more important to kids’ bone health than calcium</title><link>/posts/magnesium-may-be-more-important-to-kids-bone-health-than-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/magnesium-may-be-more-important-to-kids-bone-health-than-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#highlight-dietary-magnesium-intake-but-not-calcium-intake-was-significantly-associated-with-both-total-body-bone-mineral-content-and-density">Highlight: dietary magnesium intake, but not calcium intake, was significantly associated with both total body bone mineral content and density&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#27153-magnesium-but-not-calcium-intake">2715.3 Magnesium, but Not Calcium Intake&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#press-release">Press Release&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="highlight-dietary-magnesium-intake-but-not-calcium-intake-was-significantly-associated-with-both-total-body-bone-mineral-content-and-density">Highlight: dietary magnesium intake, but not calcium intake, was significantly associated with both total body bone mineral content and density&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="27153-magnesium-but-not-calcium-intake">2715.3 Magnesium, but Not Calcium Intake&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Is Significantly Association with Bone Mineral Status in 4 to 8 Year Old Children&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium 2X of Magnesium seems good – China</title><link>/posts/calcium-2x-of-magnesium-seems-good-china.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-2x-of-magnesium-seems-good-china.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="modifying-effect-of-calciummagnesium-intake-ratio-and-mortality-a-population-based-cohort-study">Modifying effect of calcium/magnesium intake ratio and mortality: a population-based cohort study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMJ Open. 2013 Feb 20;3(2). pii: e002111. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2012-002111.">doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2012-002111.&lt;/a> Print 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dai Q, Shu XO, Deng X, Xiang YB, Li H, Yang G, Shrubsole MJ, Ji B, Cai H, Chow WH, Gao YT, Zheng W.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Epidemiology, Department of Medicine, Vanderbilt Epidemiology Center, Vanderbilt-Ingram Cancer Center, Vanderbilt School of Medicine, Nashville, Tennessee, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:Magnesium (Mg) and calcium (Ca) antagonise each other in (re)absorption, inflammation and many other physiological activities. Based on mathematical estimation, the absorbed number of Ca or Mg depends on the dietary ratio of Ca to Mg intake. We hypothesise that the dietary Ca/Mg ratio modifies the effects of Ca and Mg on mortality due to gastrointestinal tract cancer and, perhaps, mortality due to diseases occurring in other organs or systems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Osteoporosis spot therapies: vitamin D with Calcium was the most popular</title><link>/posts/osteoporosis-spot-therapies-vitamin-d-with-calcium-was-the-most-popular.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/osteoporosis-spot-therapies-vitamin-d-with-calcium-was-the-most-popular.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="adherence-to-anti-osteoporotic-therapies-role-and-determinants-of-spot-therapy">Adherence to anti-osteoporotic therapies: role and determinants of &amp;ldquo;spot therapy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2013 Feb 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tafaro L, Nati G, Leoni E, Baldini R, Cattaruzza MS, Mei M, Falaschi P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Geriatric Unit, Sant&amp;rsquo;Andrea Hospital, Sapienza University of Rome, via di Grottarossa No. 1035, 00189, Rome, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A successful therapy needs high level of adherence consisting in right drug intake in terms of persistence and compliance. Our study suggests adherence is higher if spot (less than 30 days) therapies are excluded; the analysis of spot therapy causes underlines the importance of the interpersonal aspects of medical practice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More than 400 mg of Calcium supplements caused cardiovascular deaths in men</title><link>/posts/more-than-400-mg-of-calcium-supplements-caused-cardiovascular-deaths-in-men.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-400-mg-of-calcium-supplements-caused-cardiovascular-deaths-in-men.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="full-text-will-be-here-soon">full text will be here soon&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/calcium-cvd-1.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/caclium-cvd-2.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>for now&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong> !!full text will be here soon&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="note-calcium-is-far-less-of-a-problem-if-taken-with-vitamin-d-and--or-vitamin-d-2">Note: Calcium is far less of a problem if taken with Vitamin D and / or Vitamin D-2&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Calcium and vitamin D receptors are important to many health conditions</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-receptors-are-important-to-many-health-conditions.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-receptors-are-important-to-many-health-conditions.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calcium-nutrition-and-extracellular-calcium-sensing-relevance-for-the-pathogenesis-of-osteoporosis-cancer-and-cardiovascular-diseases">Calcium Nutrition and Extracellular Calcium Sensing: Relevance for the Pathogenesis of Osteoporosis, Cancer and Cardiovascular Diseases&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5, 302-327; doi:10.3390/nu5010302&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meinrad Peterlik &lt;a href="mailto:meinrad.peterlik@meduniwien.ac.at">meinrad.peterlik@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a>, Enikoe Kallay and Heide S. Cross&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pathophysiology, Medical University of Vienna, Waehringer Guertel 18-20, A-1090 Vienna, Austria; E-Mails: &lt;a href="mailto:enikoe.kallay@meduniwien.ac.at">enikoe.kallay@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a> (E.K.); &lt;a href="mailto:heide.cross@meduniwien.ac.at">heide.cross@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a> (H.S.C.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received: 30 October 2012; in revised form: 10 January 2013 / Accepted: 11 January 2013 / Published: 22 January 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF, including all figures and tables, is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1000 IU of vitamin D reduced child PTH, but did not increase Calcium – RCT</title><link>/posts/1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-child-pth-but-did-not-increase-calcium-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-child-pth-but-did-not-increase-calcium-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="supplementation-with-1000-iu-vitamin-dd-leads-to-parathyroid-hormone-suppression">Supplementation with 1000 IU vitamin D/d leads to parathyroid hormone suppression,&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="but-not-increased-fractional-calcium-absorption-in-48-y-old-children-a-double-blind-randomized-controlled-trial-1234">but not increased fractional calcium absorption, in 4–8-y-old children: a double-blind randomized controlled trial 1,2,3,4&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr January 2013 vol. 97 no. 1 217-223&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Steven A Abrams, Keli M Hawthorne, and Zhensheng Chen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 From the USDA/Agricultural Research Service, Children&amp;rsquo;s Nutrition Research Center, Department of Pediatrics, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author Notes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵2 The contents of this publication do not necessarily reflect the views or policies of the USDA, nor does mention of trade names, commercial products, or organizations imply endorsement by the US government.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Healthy bones need Ca, Silicon, Vitamins B, C, D, and K</title><link>/posts/healthy-bones-need-ca-silicon-vitamins-b-c-d-and-k.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/healthy-bones-need-ca-silicon-vitamins-b-c-d-and-k.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Update on nutrients involved in maintaining healthy bone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinol Nutr. 2012 Dec 27. pii: S1575-0922(12)00294-X. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.endonu.2012.09.006.">doi: 10.1016/j.endonu.2012.09.006.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Article in English, Spanish]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rondanelli M, Opizzi A, Perna S, Faliva MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Applied Health Sciences, Section of Human Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Medicine, University of Pavia, Endocrinology and Nutrition Unit, Azienda di Servizi alla Persona di Pavia, Pavia, Italy. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:mariangela.rondanelli@unipv.it">mariangela.rondanelli@unipv.it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis is a leading cause of morbidity and mortality in the elderly and influences quality of life, as well as life expectancy. Currently, there is a growing interest among the medical scientists in search of specific nutrients and/or bioactive compounds of natural origin for the prevention of disease and maintenance of bone health. Although calcium and vitamin D have been the primary focus of nutritional prevention of osteoporosis, a recent research has clarified the importance of several additional nutrients and food constituents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview of Vitamin K2 and Calcium Paradox author by Dr. Mercola</title><link>/posts/interview-of-vitamin-k2-and-calcium-paradox-author-by-dr-mercola.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/interview-of-vitamin-k2-and-calcium-paradox-author-by-dr-mercola.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="youtube-2012httpwwwyoutubecomwatchvfymexqnostq-1-hour---concerning-ca-k2-and-ostoeporosis">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fYMExQNosTQ">YouTube, 2012&lt;/a> 1 hour - concerning Ca, K2 and Ostoeporosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="interview-of-author-by-mercolahttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20121216vitamin-k2aspxe_cid20121216_snl_art_1-dec-2012">&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2012/12/16/vitamin-k2.aspx?e_cid=20121216_SNL_Art_1">Interview of author by Mercola&lt;/a> Dec 2012&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox--2012-bookpostsvitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book-review--and-table-of-contents-on-vitamindwiki">&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book">Vitamin K2 and the Calcium Paradox – 2012 book&lt;/a> Review and table of contents on VitaminDWiki&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/kate.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="overview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-dpostsoverview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-d">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-d">Overview Vitamin K and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights in BLUE added by VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolor00fbullet-points-by-vitamindwikispan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Bullet points by VitaminDWiki&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>100 micrograms of Vitamin K2 (MK-7) per 1,000 IU of vitamin D (example: 1,000 micrograms if taking 10,000 IU)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>600 mg of Calcium and a gene increases probability of Prostate Cancer by 50 pcnt</title><link>/posts/600-mg-of-calcium-and-a-gene-increases-probability-of-prostate-cancer-by-50-pcnt.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/600-mg-of-calcium-and-a-gene-increases-probability-of-prostate-cancer-by-50-pcnt.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="protective-effects-of-low-calcium-intake-and-low-calcium-absorption-vitamin-d-receptor-genotype-in-the-california-collaborative-prostate-cancer-study">Protective effects of low calcium intake and low calcium absorption vitamin D receptor genotype in the California Collaborative Prostate Cancer Study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Calcium Epidemiology Biomarkers and Prevention, November 5, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glovioell W Rowland 1, Gary G. Schwartz 2, Esther M. John 3, and Sue Ann Ingles 4,ingles@usc.edu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Preventive Medicine, University of Southern California&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Cancer Biology, Urology, and Epidemiology and Prevention, Wake Forest Baptist Medical Center&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Epidemiology, Cancer Prevention Institute of California&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Little change in Calcium absorption when taking 400 vs 4,000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/little-change-in-calcium-absorption-when-taking-400-vs-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/little-change-in-calcium-absorption-when-taking-400-vs-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D may prevent falls and fractures without Calcium – an overview of 9 meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-may-prevent-falls-and-fractures-without-calcium-an-overview-of-9-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-may-prevent-falls-and-fractures-without-calcium-an-overview-of-9-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="do-we-need-to-take-calcium-with-vitamin-d-supplements-to-prevent-falls-fractures-and-death">Do we need to take calcium with vitamin D supplements to prevent falls, fractures, and death?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2012 Oct 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scragg R, School of Population Health, University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE OF REVIEW:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 2011 report by the US Institute of Medicine (IOM) on dietary reference intakes for calcium and vitamin D is based on meta-analyses of randomized controlled trials (RCTs), which concluded that vitamin D supplements need to be taken with calcium supplements to prevent falls, fractures, and all-cause mortality. This study reviews recent meta-analyses of RCTs of vitamin D supplementation to determine whether their conclusions are consistent with the meta-analyses underpinning the IOM report.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium and bone disorders in pregnancy</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-bone-disorders-in-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-bone-disorders-in-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Indian J Endocrinol Metab. 2012 May-Jun; 16(3): 358–363, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4103/2230-8210.95665">doi: 10.4103/2230-8210.95665&lt;/a>, PMCID: PMC3354840&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shriraam Mahadevan, V. Kumaravel,1 and R. Bharath2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Endocrinology, Dr. E. V. Kalyani Medical Centre, Chennai, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Clinical Endocrinology, Alpha Hospital and Research Centre, Madurai, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Endocrinology, Chettinad Medical College and Research Institute, Chennai, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corresponding Author: Dr. Shriraam Mahadevan, Department of Clinical Endocrinology, Dr. E. V. Kalyani Medical Centre, 4, Radhakrishnan Salai, Mylapore, Chennai 600004, India. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:mshriraam@gmail.com">mshriraam@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium levels can be measured with ionized calcium tests</title><link>/posts/calcium-levels-can-be-measured-with-ionized-calcium-tests.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-levels-can-be-measured-with-ionized-calcium-tests.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Calcium absorption increased only 6 percent for high amounts of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/calcium-absorption-increased-only-6-percent-for-high-amounts-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-absorption-increased-only-6-percent-for-high-amounts-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Most people have major problems of milk as a source of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/most-people-have-major-problems-of-milk-as-a-source-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/most-people-have-major-problems-of-milk-as-a-source-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Stiff arteries in seniors associated with low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/stiff-arteries-in-seniors-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stiff-arteries-in-seniors-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="arterial-stiffness-and-vitamin-d-levels-the-baltimore-longitudinal-study-of-aging">Arterial Stiffness and Vitamin D Levels: the Baltimore Longitudinal Study of Aging&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism July 5, 2012 jc.2012-1584&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Francesco Giallauria &lt;a href="mailto:giallauriaf@mail.nih.gov">giallauriaf@mail.nih.gov&lt;/a>, Yuri Milaneschi, Toshiko Tanaka, Marcello Maggio, Marco Canepa, Palchamy Elango, Carlo Vigorito, Edward G. Lakatta, Luigi Ferrucci and James Strait&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Longitudinal Studies Section (F.G., Y.M., T.T., P.E., L.F.), Clinical Research Branch, National Institute on Aging, Baltimore, Maryland 21225; Department of Clinical Medicine (F.G., C.V.), Cardiovascular and Immunological Sciences, University of Naples “Federico II”, 80131 Naples, Italy; Department of Psychiatry (Y.M.), VU University Medical Center/GGZ inGeest, 1081 HZ Amsterdam, The Netherlands; Department of Internal Medicine and Biomedical Sciences (M.M.), Section of Geriatrics, University of Parma, 43100 Parma, Italy; Laboratory of Cardiovascular Science (M.C., E.G.L., J.S.), National Institute on Aging, Baltimore, Maryland 21225&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aortic Calcification 85 percent more likely if vitamin D level lower than 29 ng</title><link>/posts/aortic-calcification-85-percent-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-level-lower-than-29-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/aortic-calcification-85-percent-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-level-lower-than-29-ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>1000 mg of Calcium resulted in some problems no matter how much vitamin D</title><link>/posts/1000-mg-of-calcium-resulted-in-some-problems-no-matter-how-much-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1000-mg-of-calcium-resulted-in-some-problems-no-matter-how-much-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="incidence-of-hypercalciuria-and-hypercalcemia-during-a-vitamin-d-trial-in-postmenopausal-women">Incidence of Hypercalciuria and Hypercalcemia during a Vitamin D Trial in Postmenopausal Women&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocr Rev, Vol. 33 (03_MeetingAbstracts): OR38-1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2012 by The Endocrine Society ENDO 2012: June 23-26, 2012, Houston, Texas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vinod Yalamanchili, MBBS1 and John Gallagher, MD1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Bone Metabolism Unit, Creighton University Medical Center Omaha, NE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Long-term use of vitamin D and calcium supplements is common in older women. But there is no long-term data on hypercalcemia and hypercalciuria on supplements. In the WHI study there was a significant increase in renal stones in women on 400 IU/d dose of vitamin D3 and 1000mg extra calcium after 7 years but no biochemical data. We collected serum and urine calcium data every 3 months during a one-year trial of different doses of vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium absorption increased 18 pct with high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/calcium-absorption-increased-18-pct-with-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-absorption-increased-18-pct-with-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="doseresponse-relationship-between-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-calcium-absorption-in-postmenopausal-women">Dose–Response Relationship between Vitamin D Supplementation and Calcium Absorption in Postmenopausal Women&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocr Rev, Vol. 33 (03_MeetingAbstracts): MON-379&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2012 by The Endocrine Society ENDO 2012: June 23-26, 2012, Houston, Texas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vinod Yalamanchili, MBBS1, John C Gallagher, MD1 and Lynette M Smith, MS2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Bone Metabolism Unit, Creighton University Medical Center Omaha, NE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Public Health, UNMC College of Public Health Omaha, NE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: 1,25 dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25 OH2D3) is the major hormone that controls intestinal calcium absorption. Serum 1,25 OH2D3 decreases when serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) falls below &amp;lt;10ng/ml but it is not known at what serum 25OHD level malabsorption of calcium can occur. Based on cross sectional data, one study suggested that a threshold for normal calcium absorption occurred at a serum 25OHD level of 30 ng/ml but in another study it was 5-10ng/ml. We performed a longitudinal study of different doses of vitamin D on absorption to measure the effect on calcium absorption and look for a threshold effect.Methods: 163 Caucasian women, ages 57-85 years, were randomized to different doses of vitamin D3 - 400, 800, 1600, 2400, 3200, 4000, 4800 IU/day or placebo. Calcium intake was increased to 1200-1400mg/day from an average of 691 mg/day. Main inclusion criteria was that subjects had serum 25OHD level &amp;lt; 20ng/ml. Exclusion criteria were medical illness or medications known to affect calcium absorption. Calcium absorption was measured at baseline and after 12 months using a single isotope method with 100 mg calcium and 5 microcuries Ca45, serum Ca45 was corrected for weight or BMI. Serum 25OHD and 1,25 OH2D3 were measured by immunoassay (Diasorin). We used multivariate regression that included age, dietary calcium intake, weight, baseline and final calcium absorption and serum 25OHD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity reduction with Calcium and vitamin D – controversy</title><link>/posts/obesity-reduction-with-calcium-and-vitamin-d-controversy.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-reduction-with-calcium-and-vitamin-d-controversy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-obesity">Calcium and vitamin D in obesity&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr Res Rev. 2012 May 16:1-12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Song Q, Sergeev IN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Health and Nutritional Sciences, South Dakota State University, Brookings, SD 57007, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New and more effective nutritional measures are urgently needed for the prevention of obesity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of Ca and vitamin D in obesity has been recently implicated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low Ca intake and low vitamin D status have been linked with an increased risk of obesity in epidemiological studies; however, clinical intervention trials designed to test this association have produced &lt;strong>controversial results&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin K2 and the Calcium Paradox – 2012 book</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypocalcaemia runs in families</title><link>/posts/hypocalcaemia-runs-in-families.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypocalcaemia-runs-in-families.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="familial-hypocalcaemia--think-about-calcium-sensor-receptor-casr">Familial hypocalcaemia – think about calcium sensor receptor (CASR)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arch Dis Child 2012;97:A122 doi:10.1136/archdischild-2012-301885.291&lt;/p>
&lt;p>British Association of General Paediatrics/British Society for Paediatric Endocrinology &amp;amp; Diabetes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D Finn 1, S How Yaw 1, V Mathew 1, K Prescott 2, S Gupta 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Paediatrics, Hull Royal Infirmary, Hull, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Clinical Genetics, Chapel Allerton Hospital, Leeds, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aim Activating mutations of CaSR gene have been shown to cause hypercalciuric hypocalcaemia1. The CaSR plays a key role in maintaining calcium homeostasis by regulating parathyroid hormone (PTH) and renal calcium reabsorption. Activating mutation of CaSR causes increased sensitivity to Ca++ and hence down regulation of PTH secretion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Calcium and Vitamin D does not consistently reduce obesity</title><link>/posts/adding-calcium-and-vitamin-d-does-not-consistently-reduce-obesity.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adding-calcium-and-vitamin-d-does-not-consistently-reduce-obesity.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-obesity">Calcium and vitamin D in obesity.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr Res Rev. 2012 May 16:1-12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Song Q, Sergeev IN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Health and Nutritional Sciences, South Dakota State University, Brookings, SD 57007, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New and more effective nutritional measures are urgently needed for the prevention of obesity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of Ca and vitamin D in obesity has been recently implicated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low Ca intake and low vitamin D status have been linked with an increased risk of obesity in epidemiological studies;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interaction between Vitamin D and calcium</title><link>/posts/interaction-between-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/interaction-between-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypercalcemia in 3 children who had more than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypercalcemia-in-3-children-who-had-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypercalcemia-in-3-children-who-had-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypercalcemia-in-children-receiving-pharmacologic-doses-of-vitamin-d">Hypercalcemia in Children Receiving Pharmacologic Doses of Vitamin D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pediatrics. 2012 Mar 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vanstone MB, Oberfield SE, Shader L, Ardeshirpour L, Carpenter TO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics (Endocrinology), Yale University School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency causes rickets, requiring vitamin D at doses greater than daily dietary intake. Several treatment regimens are found in the literature, with wide dosing ranges, inconsistent monitoring schedules, and lack of age-specific guidelines.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How might Calcium and Vitamin D cause weight loss</title><link>/posts/how-might-calcium-and-vitamin-d-cause-weight-loss.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-might-calcium-and-vitamin-d-cause-weight-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mechanistic-roles-for-calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-the-regulation-of-body-weight">Mechanistic roles for calcium and vitamin D in the regulation of body weight&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Obes Rev. 2012 Mar 2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-789X.2012.00986.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1467-789X.2012.00986.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. J. Soares1 &lt;a href="mailto:m.soares@curtin.edu.au">m.soares@curtin.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>L. L. Murhadi1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. V. Kurpad2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W. L. Chan She Ping-Delfos1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>L. S. Piers3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Program of Nutrition, School of Public Health, Curtin Health Innovation Research Institute, Curtin University, Perth, Western Australia, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Physiology, St John&amp;rsquo;s National Academy of Health Sciences, Bangalore, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Centre for Health &amp;amp; Society, Melbourne School of Population Health, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium from Chocolate-Calcium chews</title><link>/posts/calcium-from-chocolate-calcium-chews.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-from-chocolate-calcium-chews.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="chocolate-actually-results-in-decreasing-the-amount-of-calcium-in-body-and-bone-density">Chocolate actually results in DECREASING the amount of Calcium in body and bone density&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="reasons">Reasons&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Oxalate in chocolate binds with Calcium to make it not bioavailable&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sugar in chocolate increases Calcium excretion&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="chocolate-chews-have-so-much-extra-calcium-that-the-above-items-are-not-a-concern">Chocolate chews have so much extra Calcium that the above items are not a concern&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>several references on this page- - - - - - - - -&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="may-clinichttpwwwmayocliniccomhealthcalciuman0129420">&lt;a href="http://www.mayoclinic.com/health/calcium/AN01294%20">May Clinic&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Chocolate: Does it impair calcium absorption?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A friend told me that chocolate impairs absorption of calcium. Is this true?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium (alone) does not reduce risk of bone fracture</title><link>/posts/calcium-alone-does-not-reduce-risk-of-bone-fracture.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-alone-does-not-reduce-risk-of-bone-fracture.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Calcium absorption</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcium-absorption.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcium-absorption.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-calcium-absorption">25-Hydroxyvitamin D and calcium absorption&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Robert P Heaney; 601 North 30th Street, no. 4841, Creighton University, Omaha, NE 68131; &lt;a href="mailto:rheaney@creighton.edu">rheaney@creighton.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr January 2011 vol. 93 no. 1 220-221&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="click-herehttpwwwajcnorgcontent931220long-for-on-line-version-with-hypertext">&lt;a href="http://www.ajcn.org/content/93/1/220.long">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for on-line version with hypertext&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="publication-being-commented-on-is-herehttpwwwncbinlmnihgovpmcarticlespmc2937584toolpubmed-in-pdf-format">Publication being commented on is &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2937584/?tool=pubmed">HERE&lt;/a> in PDF format&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dear Sir:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aloia et al (1), in a secondary analysis of data accumulated for another purpose, reported that intestinal calcium absorption efficiency is related to serum calcitriol, but not to serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>, as my colleagues and I had reported some years ago (2–4).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More than 800 mg of Calcium increases Cardiovascular events by 85 percent</title><link>/posts/more-than-800-mg-of-calcium-increases-cardiovascular-events-by-85-percent.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-800-mg-of-calcium-increases-cardiovascular-events-by-85-percent.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>High blood pressure associated with high level of Calcium in blood</title><link>/posts/high-blood-pressure-associated-with-high-level-of-calcium-in-blood.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-blood-pressure-associated-with-high-level-of-calcium-in-blood.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">(50 % more likely for the group with the highest serum calcium level)&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="serum-calcium-levels-and-hypertension-among-us-adults">Serum Calcium Levels and Hypertension Among US Adults.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich). 2011 Oct;13(10):716-21. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1751-7176.2011.00503.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1751-7176.2011.00503.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Jul 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sabanayagam C, Shankar A, Department of Community Medicine, West Virginia University School of Medicine, Morgantown, WV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum calcium levels have been shown to be associated with cardiovascular disease (CVD); however, it is not clear whether serum calcium levels are related to hypertension, a risk factor for CVD. The authors examined the association between serum calcium and hypertension in a representative sample of US adults. A cross-sectional study of 12,405 third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey participants 20?years and older was conducted. Serum total and ionized calcium levels were analyzed as quartiles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RDA upper limit etc for Vitamin D and Magnesium</title><link>/posts/rda-upper-limit-etc-for-vitamin-d-and-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rda-upper-limit-etc-for-vitamin-d-and-magnesium.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="an-excellent-article-by-bill-sardi-sept-2011">An excellent article by Bill Sardi Sept 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="which-nutrition-chart-should-you-rely-upon-the-rda-rdi-ai-ear-or-dvhttplewrockwellcomsardisardi186html">&lt;a href="http://lewrockwell.com/sardi/sardi186.html">Which Nutrition Chart Should You Rely Upon: The RDA, RDI, AI, EAR or DV?&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Or, How Much Nutrition Do You Really Need?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Weight loss and Vitamin D, Calcium, and Magnesium</title><link>/posts/weight-loss-and-vitamin-d-calcium-and-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/weight-loss-and-vitamin-d-calcium-and-magnesium.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="there-have-been-various-studies-which-have-found-weight-loss-when-increasing-one-or-more-of-the-following">There have been various studies which have found weight loss when increasing one or more of the following&lt;/h4>
&lt;h5 id="vitamin-d-nbsp-nbsp-magnesium-nbsp-nbsp-calcium">Vitamin D     Magnesium     Calcium&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>There is a lot of synergy/interaction between these nutrients in the body&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been a very large decrease in both Magnesium and Vitamin D in bodies during the past 40 years&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been a significant increase in obesity in the past 40 years&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wonder if there has been any weight loss trial using all three of the supplements&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is excess calcium harmful to health - 2010</title><link>/posts/is-excess-calcium-harmful-to-health-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-excess-calcium-harmful-to-health-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#1-introduction">1. Introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2-calcium-supplementation-cardiovascular-disease-and-mortality">2. Calcium Supplementation, Cardiovascular Disease and Mortality&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#3-calcium-supplementation-lipids-and-blood-pressure">3. Calcium Supplementation, Lipids and Blood Pressure&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#4-calcium-supplementation-and-vascular-calcification">4. Calcium Supplementation and Vascular Calcification&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#5-calcium-supplementation-and-cerebrovascular-disease-risk">5. Calcium Supplementation and Cerebrovascular Disease Risk&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#6-calcium-supplementation-and-kidney-stones">6. Calcium Supplementation and Kidney Stones&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#7-serum-calcium-and-cardiovascular-disease-risk">7. Serum Calcium and Cardiovascular Disease Risk&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#8-conclusion">8. Conclusion&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Text is extracted from PDF for ease of translation to other languages - tables not included&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="review-is-excess-calcium-harmful-to-health">Review: Is Excess Calcium Harmful to Health?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2010, 2, 505-522; doi:10.3390/nu2050505&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Body tries to activate more vitamin D when it needs more Calcium from gut</title><link>/posts/body-tries-to-activate-more-vitamin-d-when-it-needs-more-calcium-from-gut.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/body-tries-to-activate-more-vitamin-d-when-it-needs-more-calcium-from-gut.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mechanism-of-action-of-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3-on-intestinal-calcium-absorption">Mechanism of action of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) on intestinal calcium absorption.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2011 Aug 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christakos S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, New Jersey Medical School, University of Medicine and Dentistry of New Jersey, Newark, NJ, 07013, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:christak@umdnj.edu">christak@umdnj.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D(3) (1,25(OH)(2)D(3)) is the major controlling hormone of intestinal calcium absorption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>As the body&amp;rsquo;s demand for calcium increases from a diet deficient in calcium, from growth, pregnancy or lactation, the synthesis of 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) is increased resulting in the stimulation of intestinal calcium absorption.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decrease Calcium and Increase Magnesium when increasing vitamin D</title><link>/posts/decrease-calcium-and-increase-magnesium-when-increasing-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/decrease-calcium-and-increase-magnesium-when-increasing-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="quick-summary-calcium-500-mg-total-and-magnesium-100-mg-when-vitamin-d--3000-iu">Quick summary: Calcium 500 mg total and Magnesium 100 mg when Vitamin D &amp;gt; 3000 IU&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Note: 100 milligram of the Magnesium ELEMENT, not the COMPOUND&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.longecity.org/forum/topic/16932-bioavailability-elemental-of-magnesium-types/">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for a table to Magnesium content and bioavailablity&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="many-studies-have-seem-problems-when-vitamin-d-levels-were-increased-without-balancing-the-cofactor-levels">Many studies have seem problems when vitamin D levels were increased without balancing the cofactor levels&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="cofactors-should-be-adjusted-when-taking-more-than-2000-to-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d">Cofactors should be adjusted when taking more than 2,000 to 4,000 IU of vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Magnesium deficiency shows up as pain within days in fewer than 1 in 30 people.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black women lacking Calcium and Vitamin D weighed more</title><link>/posts/black-women-lacking-calcium-and-vitamin-d-weighed-more.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-women-lacking-calcium-and-vitamin-d-weighed-more.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="higher-amounts-of-body-fat-are-associated-with-inadequate-intakes-of-calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-african-american-women">Higher amounts of body fat are associated with inadequate intakes of calcium and vitamin D in African American women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrition Research; Volume 31, Issue 7, July 2011, Pages 527-536; doi:10.1016/j.nutres.2011.06.005&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diane K. Tidwell a, &lt;a href="mailto:ditdwell@fsnhp.msstate.edu">ditdwell@fsnhp.msstate.edu&lt;/a> and Melinda W. Valliant b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Food Science, Nutrition and Health Promotion, PO Box 9805, Mississippi State, MS 39762&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Nutrition and Hospitality Management, The University of Mississippi&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 11 October 2010; revised 22 June 2011; accepted 23 June 2011, online 12 August 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deficiencies of Vitamin D and Calcium – Related Chronic Diseases – 2009</title><link>/posts/deficiencies-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-related-chronic-diseases-2009.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/deficiencies-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-related-chronic-diseases-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-calcium-insufficiency-related-chronic-diseases-an-emerging-world-wide-public-health-problem">Vitamin D and Calcium Insufficiency-Related Chronic Diseases: an Emerging World-Wide Public Health Problem&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2009 October; 6(10): 2585–2607.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2009 October 2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph6102585">doi: 10.3390/ijerph6102585&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meinrad Peterlik,1 &lt;a href="mailto:meinrad.peterlik@meduniwien.ac.at">meinrad.peterlik@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Steven Boonen,2 Heide S. Cross,1 and Christel Lamberg-Allardt3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Pathophysiology, Medical University of Vienna, Waehringer Guertel 18–20, A-1090, Vienna, Austria; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:heide.cross@meduniwien.ac.at">heide.cross@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Center for Metabolic Bone Diseases and Division of Geriatric Medicine, Leuven University, Universitaire Ziekenhuizen, Herestraat 49, B-3000, Leuven, Belgium; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:steven.boonen@uz.kuleuven.ac.be">steven.boonen@uz.kuleuven.ac.be&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Calcium – Vitamin D - Cardiovascular Disease</title><link>/posts/review-of-calcium-vitamin-d-cardiovascular-disease.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-calcium-vitamin-d-cardiovascular-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="calcium-vitamin-d-and-cardiovascular-disease--review">Calcium, Vitamin D and Cardiovascular Disease – Review&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Kidney and Blood Pressure Research, Vol. 34, No. 6, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Idris Guessousa, b, Murielle Bochud b, Olivier Bonny c, Michel Burnier c&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Unit of Population Epidemiology, Division of Primary Care Medicine, Department of Community Medicine, Primary Care and Emergency Medicine, Geneva University Hospitals, Geneva,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Community Prevention Unit, University Institute of Social and Preventive Medicine (IUMSP),&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Department of Medicine, Service of Nephrology, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois (CHUV), Lausanne, Switzerland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – Optimize vitamin D at home by measuring excess Calcium in urine</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-optimize-vitamin-d-at-home-by-measuring-excess-calcium-in-urine.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-optimize-vitamin-d-at-home-by-measuring-excess-calcium-in-urine.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="it-is-difficult-to-determine-how-muchtagshow-muchhtml-vitamin-d-an-individual-needs">It is difficult to determine &lt;a href="/tags/how-much.html">how much&lt;/a> vitamin D an individual needs&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="need-to-add-vitamin-d-for-each-of-the-following-reasons">Need to add vitamin D for each of the following reasons&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" style="max-width: 500px;">
&lt;h3 id="even-within-the-same-risk-group-the-vitamin-d-needed-will-vary-by-4x">Even within the same risk group the vitamin D needed will vary by 4X&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>According to &lt;a href="/tags/dr-vieth-may-2011.html">Dr. Vieth - May 2011&lt;/a> (see charts below) the body starts dumping calcium via the urine long before serum levels of calcium become elevated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hypothesis:&lt;/strong> The body starts exponentially dumping calcium via the urine would at the top of the personal optimal serum vitamin D range.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Controversy: Too much Calcium if increase Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/controversy-too-much-calcium-if-increase-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/controversy-too-much-calcium-if-increase-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#50-percent-of-elderly-got-hypercalcimia-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d--feb-2011">50 percent of elderly got hypercalcimia with 2000 IU of vitamin D – Feb 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="50-percent-of-elderly-got-hypercalcimia-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d--feb-2011">50 percent of elderly got hypercalcimia with 2000 IU of vitamin D – Feb 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Evaluation of the effectiveness of cholecalciferol in long-term care elderly patients with hypovitaminosis d.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consult Pharm. 2011 Feb;26(2):101-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shin M, Minden C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sullivan University College of Pharmacy, Louisville, Kentucky.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To study the efficacy and safety of cholecalciferol &lt;strong>(vitamin D3) 2,000 units&lt;/strong> daily for 12 weeks in elderly patients with hypovitaminosis D. Secondarily, to postulate causes for those patients who did not return to normal 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25-OHD) levels.Design: One-group, pretest post-test. Retrospective chart review. Data collected from Computerized Patient Record System.Setting: Long-term care facility at Central Arkansas Veterans Healthcare System.Patients, Participants: Potential study subjects were elderly patients (? 65 years of age) treated with total daily dose of cholecalciferol 2,000 units daily by mouth, for at least 12 weeks&amp;rsquo; duration period between July 1, 2007, and July 31, 2009, with documented 25-OHD levels before and after treatment.Interventions: None.Main Outcome Measures: Efficacy of cholecalciferol was assessed by categorizing patients as responders (25-OHD levels ? 30 ng/mL) and nonresponders (25-OHD levels &amp;lt; 30 ng/mL).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium citrate and more than 800 IU of vitamin D to treat Osteoporosis</title><link>/posts/calcium-citrate-and-more-than-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-to-treat-osteoporosis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-citrate-and-more-than-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-to-treat-osteoporosis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="calcium-citrate-and-vitamin-d-in-the-treatment-of-osteoporosis">Calcium Citrate and Vitamin D in the Treatment of Osteoporosis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Drug Investig. 2011 Mar 15. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2165/11584940-000000000-00000">doi: 10.2165/11584940-000000000-00000&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quesada Gómez JM, Rubió JB, Curiel MD, Pérez AD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mineral Metabolism Unit, Hospital Universitario Reina Sofa, Crdoba, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The combination of calcium with vitamin D (vitamin D(3) &lt;span>[colecalciferol]&lt;/span>) forms the basis of preventive and therapeutic regimens for osteoporosis. A number of studies have suggested that the combination of calcium and vitamin D is effective when administered at respective dosages of at least &lt;strong>1200?mg and 800?IU per day&lt;/strong> , although efficacy is, as expected, affected by patient compliance. Overall, treatment with this combination appears to be effective in reducing the incidence of non-vertebral and hip fractures. Also, in all drug studies (of antiresorptive and anabolic agents and strontium ranelate) that demonstrated a reduction in risk of osteoporotic fractures, patients also took calcium and vitamin D supplements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium hazards and bioavailability</title><link>/posts/calcium-hazards-and-bioavailability.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-hazards-and-bioavailability.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#diverse-calcium-opinions">Diverse Calcium opinions&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#consensus">Consensus:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#likely-avoid-rock-calcium-especially-if-senior">Likely: Avoid rock-calcium, especially if senior&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#calcium-level-for-adults-is-85-to-102-mgdeciliter">Calcium level for adults is 8.5 to 10.2 mg/deciliter&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-vitamindwiki">See VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#calcium-supplements-increases-the-chance-of-dying--by-14-x---june-2022">Calcium supplements increases the chance of dying by 1.4 X - June 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pubmedhttpwwwncbinlmnihgovpubmedtermcalcium5btitle5dandabsorption5btitle5dorbioavailability5btitle5d--2324-articles-on-calcium-absorption-or-bioavailability---oct-2024">[PubMed](&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=(calcium%5BTitle%5D+AND+(absorption%5BTitle%5D+OR+bioavailability%5BTitle%5D+))">http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=(calcium%5BTitle%5D+AND+(absorption%5BTitle%5D+OR+bioavailability%5BTitle%5D+))&lt;/a> 2,324 articles on calcium (absorption OR bioavailability) - Oct 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#calcium-is-mainly-absorbed-in-the-ilium-vitamin-d-helps--aug-2022">Calcium is mainly absorbed in the ilium, vitamin D helps – Aug 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clipped-from-wikipediahttpenwikipediaorgwikicalciumdietary_calcium_supplements-march-2011">&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calcium#Dietary_calcium_supplements">Clipped from WikiPedia&lt;/a> March 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#global-healing-centerhttpwwwglobalhealingcentercomnatural-healthtypes-of-calcium-supplements">&lt;a href="http://www.globalhealingcenter.com/natural-health/types-of-calcium-supplements/">Global Healing Center&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#good-up-to-date-overview-from-arizona-jan-2011httpwwwagarizonaedupubshealthaz1042pdf">&lt;a href="http://www.ag.arizona.edu/pubs/health/az1042.pdf">Good up-to-date overview from Arizona Jan 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#goodnessdirecthttpbloggoodnessdirectcouk20090304calcium-absorbing-it-all-the-type-of-calcium-you-take-can-make-a-big-difference-march-2009-or-2004">&lt;a href="http://blog.goodnessdirect.co.uk/2009/03/04/calcium-absorbing-it-all-the-type-of-calcium-you-take-can-make-a-big-difference/">GoodnessDirect&lt;/a> March 2009 or 2004?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-inorganic-forms">The inorganic forms:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-organic-forms">The organic forms:&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#algaecal-is-a-much-better-form-of-calcium-to-fight-osteoporosis---video-may-2024-dr-doug-16-minuteshttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvmiicwzmoelg--dr-doug-35-minuteshttpswwwyoutubecomwatchv3fcbh2tvs5y-long-list-of-references">Algaecal is a much better form of Calcium to fight Osteoporosis - video May 2024** &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mIICWzMoelg">Dr. Doug 16 minutes&lt;/a> **** &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3fcbh2TVS5Y">Dr. Doug 35 minutes&lt;/a> **long list of references&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also Web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="diverse-calcium-opinions">Diverse Calcium opinions&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="consensus">Consensus:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Calcium Carbonate is the lowest cost, requires the most stomach acid to be digested, and is probably less bio-available&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>400 IU of vitamin D Magnesium and Calcium helped Twin bones</title><link>/posts/400-iu-of-vitamin-d-magnesium-and-calcium-helped-twin-bones.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/400-iu-of-vitamin-d-magnesium-and-calcium-helped-twin-bones.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Is the Institute of Medicine Report on Calcium and Vitamin D Good Science</title><link>/posts/is-the-institute-of-medicine-report-on-calcium-and-vitamin-d-good-science.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-the-institute-of-medicine-report-on-calcium-and-vitamin-d-good-science.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="by-dr-willam-grant">By Dr. Willam Grant&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1654]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/iom-again-fails-to-look-at-interactions">IoM again fails to look at interactions - Nov 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Which has many responses, including 2 more by Dr. Grant&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>And a link to possible Conflict of Interest by the panel members&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-overview-by-grant">Vitamin D overview by Grant - Jan 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/tags/need-30-60-ng-of-vitamin-d-for-good-health-grant-jan-2011.html">Need 30-60 ng of vitamin D for good health – Grant Jan 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/tags/increase-vitamin-d-in-germany-could-save-18000-lives-annually.html">Increase vitamin D in Germany could save 18000 lives annually&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Fractures and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-fractures-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-fractures-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/09/27/well/live/broken-bone-fracture-risk.html">&amp;quot;..only 9 percent of Medicare patients who sustained a hip or spinal fracture were tested for bone loss and offered treatment to head off a future fracture.&amp;quot;&lt;/a> NYT Sept 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Hip Fractures in Older Adults - JAMA 2019&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most estimates of risk of elderly fracture do not consider the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>    falls, cognitive impairment, urinary incontinence, neurological conditions, and medications&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Continues to recommend Vitamin D sufficiency (&amp;gt;30ng?)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/hip-fractures-in-older-adults-in-2019.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Osteoporosis and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-osteoporosis-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-osteoporosis-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bone-density-decreases-with-age">Bone Density decreases with age&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also--osteoporosis-studiescomhttposteoporosis-studiescom">See also &lt;a href="http://osteoporosis-studies.com/">Osteoporosis-studies.com&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also Web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#most-of-the-nih-article-in-jan-2011httpwwwnlmnihgovmedlineplusmagazineissueswinter11articleswinter11pg15html-was-mainly-on-exercise-to-reduce-osteoporosis">&lt;a href="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/magazine/issues/winter11/articles/winter11pg15.html">Most of the NIH article in Jan 2011&lt;/a> was mainly on exercise to reduce osteoporosis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-was-barely-mentioned">Vitamin D was barely mentioned&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-with-or-without-fosamax-is-highly-rated-to-treat-osteoporosis-at-rate-a-drughttpwwwrateadrugcomvitamin-d-side-effectsaspx-july-2011">Vitamin D, with or without Fosamax, is highly rated to TREAT Osteoporosis at &lt;a href="http://www.rateadrug.com/vitamin-d-side-effects.aspx">Rate A Drug&lt;/a> July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hypothesis-moderate-osteoporosis-itself-is-beneficial-for-bones---oct-2019">Hypothesis: Moderate osteoporosis itself is beneficial for bones - Oct 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#admin-of-vitamindwiki-put-together-a-page-on-strong-bones-in-2008-before-learning-about-vitamin-d">Admin of VitaminDWiki put together a page on Strong Bones in 2008 before learning about vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/tags/overview-bone-fractures.html">Overview - Bone Fractures&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium without vitamin D increased heart risk by 30 percent</title><link>/posts/calcium-without-vitamin-d-increased-heart-risk-by-30-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-without-vitamin-d-increased-heart-risk-by-30-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="strong-bones-equals-weak-heart">Strong Bones Equals Weak Heart&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="-abstract-and-link-to-article-is-at-the-bottom-of-this-page">&lt;strong># Abstract and link to article is at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="by-jennifer-gibson-pharmdhttpbrainbloggercom20110102strong-bones-equals-weak-heart">&lt;a href="http://brainblogger.com/2011/01/02/strong-bones-equals-weak-heart/">by Jennifer Gibson, PharmD&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Adequate calcium intake is an important nutritional factor for skeletal health. Calcium (when taken with adequate Vitamin D) prevents bone loss and decreases the risk of fractures and associated morbidity and mortality. Most adults require 1000 mg of calcium daily. (Children and postmenopausal women require slightly more.) For decades, physicians and pharmacists have been advocating calcium supplementation to ensure adequate intake for patients, particularly postmenopausal women, owing to a belief that calcium supplementation offered significant benefits without many adverse consequences. Now, a new meta-analysis in the British Medical Journal (BMJ) claims that calcium supplementation, in fact, leads to an increased risk for cardiovascular events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low cost cofactors for vitamin D</title><link>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-for-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-for-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="it-is-important-to-have-cofactors-when-taking-more-than-2000-iu-vitamin-d-average">It is IMPORTANT to have cofactors when taking more than 2000 IU vitamin D average&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/decrease-calcium-and-increase-magnesium-when-increasing-vitamin-d">Decrease Calcium and Increase Magnesium when increasing vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There is a lack of evidence of the interactions - the following are guesses based on incomplete information&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most studies are monotheraputic: e.g. supply Vitamin D, and rarely use any of the cofactors&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="update-2022-taking-most-of-my-supplements-as-pills---average-of-about-3day">Update 2022 taking most of my supplements as pills - average of about 3/day&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/herny-s-weekly-pills.jpg" alt="image" width="800">
&lt;p>Also take Magnesium Chloride as a liquid and Omega-3 as a cream&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Just 700 IU of vitamin D and 700 mg of Calcium reduces falls and fractures</title><link>/posts/just-700-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-700-mg-of-calcium-reduces-falls-and-fractures.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/just-700-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-700-mg-of-calcium-reduces-falls-and-fractures.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="optimal-use-of-vitamin-d-when-treating-osteoporosis">Optimal Use of Vitamin D When Treating Osteoporosis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Osteoporos Rep. 2010 Nov 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van den Bergh JP, Bours SP, van Geel TA, Geusens PP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, VieCuri Medical Centre Noord-Limburg, P.O. Box 1926, 5900 BX, Venlo, The Netherlands, &lt;a href="mailto:jvdbergh@hetnet.nl">jvdbergh@hetnet.nl&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inadequate serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) concentrations are associated with muscle weakness, decreased physical performance, and increased propensity in falls and fractures. This paper discusses several aspects with regard to vitamin D status and supplementation when treating patients with osteoporosis in relation to risks and prevention of falls and fractures. Based on evidence from literature, adequate supplementation with at least &lt;strong>700 IU&lt;/strong> of vitamin D, preferably cholecalciferol, is required for improving physical function and prevention of falls and fractures. Additional calcium supplementation may be considered when dietary &lt;strong>calcium intake is below 700 mg/day&lt;/strong> . For optimal bone mineral density response in patients treated with antiresorptive or anabolic therapy, adequate vitamin D and calcium supplementation is also necessary. Monitoring of 25(OH)D levels during follow-up and adjustment of vitamin D supplementation should be considered to reach and maintain adequate serum 25(OH)D levels of at least 50 nmol/L, preferably greater than 75 nmol/L in all patients. PMID: 21113692&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IoM again fails to look at interactions</title><link>/posts/iom-again-fails-to-look-at-interactions.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/iom-again-fails-to-look-at-interactions.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Middle-aged women gained weight if they did not drink fortified milk</title><link>/posts/middle-aged-women-gained-weight-if-they-did-not-drink-fortified-milk.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/middle-aged-women-gained-weight-if-they-did-not-drink-fortified-milk.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-calcium-milk-prevents-overweight-and-obesity-among-postmenopausal-women">High-calcium milk prevents overweight and obesity among postmenopausal women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Food Nutr Bull. 2010 Sep;31(3):381-90.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Angeles-Agdeppa I, Capanzana MV, Li-Yu J, Schollum LM, Kruger MC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Food and Nutrition Research Institute, Department of Science and Technology, Taguig City, Philippines. &lt;a href="mailto:imelda_agdeppa@yahoo.com">imelda_agdeppa@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The Sixth National Nutrition Survey 2003 revealed that the highest prevalence of overweight and obesity among Filipino female adults (30.8%) was found in the age group from 40 to 59 years. Obesity is associated with a number of chronic diseases, including cardiovascular disease, hypertension, and diabetes. Low calcium intake has been identified as a potential contributing factor to overweight and obesity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Too much and too little Calcium both increase death after strokes</title><link>/posts/too-much-and-too-little-calcium-both-increase-death-after-strokes.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/too-much-and-too-little-calcium-both-increase-death-after-strokes.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-calcium-levels-and-long-term-mortality-in-patients-with-acute-stroke">Serum Calcium Levels and Long-Term Mortality in Patients with Acute Stroke&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Shmuel A. Appela, Noa Molshatzkia, Yvonne Schwammenthala, Oleg Merzeliaka, Maya Toashia, Ben-Ami Selab, c, David Tannea, c&lt;/p>
&lt;p>aStroke Center, Department of Neurology, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>bInstitute of Chemical Pathology, The Chaim Sheba Medical Center, Tel Hashomer, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>cSackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prof. David Tanne; Stroke Center, Department of Neurology; The Chaim Sheba Medical Center; &lt;a href="mailto:tanne@post.tau.ac.il">tanne@post.tau.ac.il&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cerebrovasc Dis 2011;31:93-99 (DOI: 10.1159/000321335)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Strength of evidence for Calcium at NLM</title><link>/posts/strength-of-evidence-for-calcium-at-nlm.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/strength-of-evidence-for-calcium-at-nlm.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/druginfo/natural/781.html">http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/druginfo/natural/781.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="it-seems-to-consider-the-benefits-of-calcium-by-itself-and-not-in-combination-with-vitamin-d">It seems to consider the benefits of Calcium by itself, and not in combination with vitamin D&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="insufficient-evidence-seems-to-indicate-insufficient-evidence-when-not-combined-with-vitamin-d">&amp;lsquo;insufficient evidence&amp;rsquo; seems to indicate insufficient evidence when not combined with vitamin D)&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="the-following-is-a-tiny-subset-of-the-information">The following is a tiny subset of the information&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="effective-for">Effective for&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Raising calcium levels in people who have low calcium.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Preventing low calcium levels.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Reversing high potassium levels, when given intravenously (by IV).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Use as an antacid as calcium carbonate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of vitamin D and Calcium a world problem – strength of evidence etc – 2009</title><link>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-a-world-problem-strength-of-evidence-etc-2009.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-a-world-problem-strength-of-evidence-etc-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-calcium-insufficiency-related-chronic-diseases-an-emerging-world-wide-public-health-problem--review">Vitamin D and Calcium Insufficiency-Related Chronic Diseases: an Emerging World-Wide Public Health Problem – Review&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 2009, 6(10), 2585-2607; doi:10.3390/ijerph6102585&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meinrad Peterlik 1, &lt;a href="mailto:meinrad.peterlik@meduniwien.ac.at">meinrad.peterlik@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a>, Steven Boonen 2 email, Heide S. Cross 1 email and Christel Lamberg-Allardt 3 email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Pathophysiology, Medical University of Vienna, Waehringer Guertel 18-20, A-1090, Vienna, Austria&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Center for Metabolic Bone Diseases and Division of Geriatric Medicine, Leuven University, Universitaire Ziekenhuizen, Herestraat 49, B-3000, Leuven, Belgium&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4X more likely to add Calcium to diet than take supplements</title><link>/posts/4x-more-likely-to-add-calcium-to-diet-than-take-supplements.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4x-more-likely-to-add-calcium-to-diet-than-take-supplements.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-density-testing-an-under-utilised-and-under-researched-health-education-tool-for-osteoporosis-prevention">Bone Density Testing: An Under-Utilised and Under-Researched Health Education Tool for Osteoporosis Prevention?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Tania Winzenberg, Brian Oldenburg and Graeme Jones&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2010, 2(9), 985-996; doi:10.3390/nu2090985 Received: 3 August 2010; in revised form: 18 August 2010 / Accepted: 20 August 2010 / Published: 16 September 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract: Feedback of fracture risk based on bone mineral density (BMD) is an under-explored potential osteoporosis education intervention. We performed a randomised controlled trial of either an osteoporosis information leaflet or small group education (the Osteoporosis Prevention and Self-Management Course (OPSMC)), combined with individualised fracture risk feedback in premenopausal women over two years. Women with a mean T-score at spine and hip of &amp;lt; 0 were informed they were at higher risk of fracture in later life and those with T-score ? 0 were informed they were not. Women receiving feedback of high fracture risk had a greater increase in femoral neck, but not lumbar spine, BMD compared to the low risk group (1.6% p.a. vs. 0.7% p.a., p = 0.0001). Participation in the OPSMC had no greater effect on BMD than receiving the leaflet. Femoral neck BMD change was associated with starting calcium supplements (1.3% p.a., 95% CI +0.49, +2.17) and self-reported physical activity change (0.7% p.a., 95% CI +0.22, +1.22). Mother’s report of increasing their children’s calcium intake was associated with receiving the OPSMC (OR 2.3, 95% CI 1.4, 3.8) and feedback of high fracture risk (OR 2.0, 95% CI 1.2, 3.3). Fracture risk feedback based on BMD could potentially make an important contribution to osteoporosis prevention but confirmation of long-term benefits and cost effectiveness is needed before implementation can be recommended.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Both Calcium AND vitamin D needed to prevent elderly fractures</title><link>/posts/both-calcium-and-vitamin-d-needed-to-prevent-elderly-fractures.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/both-calcium-and-vitamin-d-needed-to-prevent-elderly-fractures.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prevention-of-fractures-in-older-people-with-calcium-and-vitamin-d">Prevention of Fractures in Older People with Calcium and Vitamin D&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Caryl A. Nowson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2010, 2(9), 975-984; doi:10.3390/nu2090975 Received: 3 August 2010; in revised form: 18 August 2010 / Accepted: 23 August 2010 / Published: 16 September 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract: The greatest cause of fracture in older people is osteoporosis which contributes to increased morbidity and mortality in older people. A number of meta-analyses have been performed assessing the effectiveness of calcium supplementation alone, vitamin D supplementation alone and the combined therapy on bone loss and fracture reduction in older people. The results of these meta-analyses indicate that vitamin D supplementation alone is unlikely to reduce fracture risk, calcium supplementation alone has a modest effect in reducing total fracture risk, but compliance with calcium supplements is poor in the long term. The combination of calcium supplementation with vitamin D supplementation, particularly in those at risk of marginal and low vitamin D status reduces total fractures, including hip fractures. Therefore older people would be recommended to consume adequate dietary calcium (&amp;gt;1100 mg/day) together with maintaining adequate vitamin D status (&amp;gt;60 nmol/L 25(OH)D) to reduce risk of fracture. It is a challenge to consume sufficient dietary calcium from dietary sources, but the increasing range of calcium fortified foods could assist in increasing the dietary calcium intake of older people. In addition to the usual dairy based food sources, vitamin D supplements are likely to be required for older people with reduced mobility and access to sunlight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Elderly increase Calicum intake from food with annual reminder</title><link>/posts/elderly-increase-calicum-intake-from-food-with-annual-reminder.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/elderly-increase-calicum-intake-from-food-with-annual-reminder.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="annual-feedback-is-an-effective-tool-for-a-sustained-increase-in-calcium-intake-among-older-women">Annual Feedback Is an Effective Tool for a Sustained Increase in Calcium Intake among Older Women&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Kerrie M. Sanders, Amanda L. Stuart, Mark A. Kotowicz and Geoffrey C. Nicholson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2010, 2(9), 1018-1025; doi:10.3390/nu2091018 Received: 3 August 2010; in revised form: 15 August 2010 / Accepted: 20 August 2010 / Published: 17 September 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We aimed to optimize calcium intake among the 2,000+ older women taking part in the Vital D study. Calcium supplementation was not included in the study protocol. Our hypothesis was that annual feedback of calcium intake and informing women of strategies to improve calcium intake can lead to a sustained increase in the proportion of women who consume adequate levels of the mineral. Calcium intake was assessed on an annual basis using a validated short food frequency questionnaire (FFQ). Supplemental calcium intake was added to the dietary estimate. Participants and their nominated doctor were sent a letter that the participant’s estimated daily calcium intake was adequate or inadequate based on a &lt;strong>cutoff threshold of 800 mg/day&lt;/strong> . General brief statements outlining the importance of an adequate calcium intake and bone health were included in all letters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Calcium might help reduce obesity</title><link>/posts/how-calcium-might-help-reduce-obesity.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-calcium-might-help-reduce-obesity.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="review-postprandial-energy-metabolism-in-the-regulation-of-body-weight-is-there-a-mechanistic-role-for-dietary-calcium">Review: Postprandial Energy Metabolism in the Regulation of Body Weight: Is there a Mechanistic Role for Dietary Calcium?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Mario J. Soares and Wendy L. Chan She-Ping-Delfos&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2010, 2(6), 586-598; doi:10.3390/nu2060586 Received: 16 April 2010; in revised form: 26 May 2010 / Accepted: 27 May 2010 / Published: 28 May 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract: There has been much interest in the mechanisms by which calcium may attenuate weight gain or accelerate body fat loss. This review focuses on postprandial energy metabolism and indicates that dietary calcium increases whole body fat oxidation after single and multiple meals. There is, as yet, no conclusive evidence for a greater diet induced thermogenesis, an increased lipolysis or suppression of key lipogenic enzyme systems. There is however convincing evidence that higher calcium intakes promote a modest energy loss through increased fecal fat excretion. Overall, there is a role for dietary calcium in human energy metabolism. Future studies need to define threshold intakes for metabolic and gastrointestinal outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More calcium and vitamin D resulted in weight loss</title><link>/posts/more-calcium-and-vitamin-d-resulted-in-weight-loss.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-calcium-and-vitamin-d-resulted-in-weight-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dairy-calcium-intake-serum-vitamin-d-and-successful-weight-loss">Dairy calcium intake, serum vitamin D, and successful weight loss&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr (September 1, 2010). doi:10.3945/ajcn.2010.29355&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Danit R Shahar, Dan Schwarzfuchs, Drora Fraser, Hillel Vardi, Joachim Thiery, Georg Martin Fiedler, Matthias Blüher, Michael Stumvoll, Meir J Stampfer and Iris Shai&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 From the S Daniel Abraham Center for Health and Nutrition and the Department of Epidemiology, Faculty of Health Sciences, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Beer-Sheva, Israel (DRS, DF, HV, and IS); the Nuclear Research Center Negev, Dimona, Israel (DS); the Department of Medicine and the Institute of Laboratory Medicine, University of Leipzig, Leipzig, Germany (JT, GMF, MB, and MS); the Channing Laboratory, Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA (MJS); and the Departments of Epidemiology and Nutrition, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, MA (MJS).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increasing vitamin D does not continue to increase Calcium</title><link>/posts/increasing-vitamin-d-does-not-continue-to-increase-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increasing-vitamin-d-does-not-continue-to-increase-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-vitamin-d-metabolites-and-intestinal-calcium-absorption-efficiency-in-women">Serum vitamin D metabolites and intestinal calcium absorption efficiency in women&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr 92: 835-840, 2010. First published July 21, 2010; doi:10.3945/ajcn.2010.29553&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2010 American Society for Clinical Nutrition&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John F Aloia, Ding-Geng Chen, James K Yeh and Henian Chen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 From the Bone Mineral Research Center, Winthrop University Hospital, Mineola, NY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Supported by NIH grants RO1-AR37520-05 and PO1-DK42618.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Address correspondence to JF Aloia, 222 Station Plaza North, Suite 510, Mineola, NY. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:jaloia@winthrop.org">jaloia@winthrop.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review concludes that vitamin D and Calcium help after thyroid removal</title><link>/posts/review-concludes-that-vitamin-d-and-calcium-help-after-thyroid-removal.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-concludes-that-vitamin-d-and-calcium-help-after-thyroid-removal.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="routine-postoperative-administration-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-after-total-thyroidectomy-a-meta-analysis">Routine Postoperative Administration Of Vitamin D And Calcium After Total Thyroidectomy: A Meta-Analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Alvaro Sanabria PhDCorresponding Author Contact Information, a, E-mail The Corresponding Author, Luis C. Dominguez MSca, Valentin Vega MSca, Camilo Osorio MDa and Daniel Duarte MDa&lt;/p>
&lt;p>aDepartment of Surgery. School of Medicine. Universidad de La Sabana. Bogota, Colombia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International Journal of Surgery&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 14 July 2010; accepted 15 August 2010. Available online 30 August 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presented at the World Congress of Thyroid Cancer. Toronto, Canada. August 9, 2009&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium and vitamin D aided weight loss – RCT</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-aided-weight-loss-rct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-aided-weight-loss-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dairy-calcium-intake-serum-vitamin-d-and-successful-weight-loss">Dairy calcium intake, serum vitamin D, and successful weight loss.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2010 Sep 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shahar DR, Schwarzfuchs D, Fraser D, Vardi H, Thiery J, Fiedler GM, Blüher M, Stumvoll M, Stampfer MJ, Shai I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S Daniel Abraham Center for Health and Nutrition and the Department of Epidemiology, Faculty of Health Sciences, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Beer-Sheva, Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The role of dairy calcium intake and serum vitamin D concentrations in weight loss is controversial.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>32 ng vitamin D and 500 mg of Calcium helped reduce weight by 5.6 kg</title><link>/posts/32-ng-vitamin-d-and-500-mg-of-calcium-helped-reduce-weight-by-56-kg.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/32-ng-vitamin-d-and-500-mg-of-calcium-helped-reduce-weight-by-56-kg.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dairy-calcium-intake-serum-vitamin-d-and-successful-weight-loss">Dairy calcium intake, serum vitamin D, and successful weight loss.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2010 Sep 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shahar DR, Schwarzfuchs D, Fraser D, Vardi H, Thiery J, Fiedler GM, Blüher M, Stumvoll M, Stampfer MJ, Shai I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S Daniel Abraham Center for Health and Nutrition and the Department of Epidemiology, Faculty of Health Sciences, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Beer-Sheva, Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background-the-role-of-dairy-calcium-intake-and-serum-vitamin-d-concentrations-in-weight-loss-is-controversial">BACKGROUND: The role of dairy calcium intake and serum vitamin D concentrations in weight loss is controversial.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: The objective was to assess the association of dairy calcium intake and serum vitamin D with weight loss. Design: We analyzed data from participants in the 2-y Dietary Intervention Randomized Controlled Trial (DIRECT) &lt;a href="n%20=%20322;%20mean%20body%20mass%20index%20(BMI;%20in%20kg/m(2)):%2031;%20mean%20age:%2052%20y">n = 322; mean body mass index (BMI; in kg/m(2)): 31; mean age: 52 y&lt;/a>. A representative sample (n = 126) was followed for 6 mo for serum vitamin D changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and calcium raw text of 420 page review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcium-raw-text-of-420-page-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcium-raw-text-of-420-page-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-and-calcium-a-systematic-review-of-health-outcomes">Vitamin D and calcium: a systematic review of health outcomes.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Evid Rep Technol Assess (Full Rep). 2009 Aug;(183):1-420.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chung M, Balk EM, Brendel M, Ip S, Lau J, Lee J, Lichtenstein A, Patel K, Raman G, Tatsioni A, Terasawa T, Trikalinos TA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Since the 1997 Dietary Reference Intake (DRI) values for vitamin D and calcium were established new data have become available on their relationship, both individually and combined, to a wide range of health outcomes. The Institute of Medicine/Food and Nutrition Board has constituted a DRI committee to undertake a review of the evidence and potential revision of the current DRI values for these nutrients. To support this review, several US and Canadian federal government agencies commissioned a systematic review of the scientific literature for use during the deliberations by the committee. The intent of providing a systematic review to the committee is to support transparency of the literature review process and provide a foundation for subsequent reviews of the nutrients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Systematic review of vitamin D calcium and health was inconclusive</title><link>/posts/systematic-review-of-vitamin-d-calcium-and-health-was-inconclusive.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/systematic-review-of-vitamin-d-calcium-and-health-was-inconclusive.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Vitamin D and calcium: a systematic review of health outcomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evid Rep Technol Assess (Full Rep). 2009 Aug;(183):1-&lt;span style="color:#F00;">420&lt;/span>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chung M, Balk EM, Brendel M, Ip S, Lau J, Lee J, Lichtenstein A, Patel K, Raman G, Tatsioni A, Terasawa T, Trikalinos TA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Since the 1997 Dietary Reference Intake (DRI) values for vitamin D and calcium were established new data have become available on their relationship, both individually and combined, to a wide range of health outcomes. The Institute of Medicine/Food and Nutrition Board has constituted a DRI committee to undertake a review of the evidence and potential revision of the current DRI values for these nutrients. To support this review, several US and Canadian federal government agencies commissioned a systematic review of the scientific literature for use during the deliberations by the committee. The intent of providing a systematic review to the committee is to support transparency of the literature review process and provide a foundation for subsequent reviews of the nutrients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart attacks increased by 30% in those taking 500 mg of Calcium without vitamin D</title><link>/posts/heart-attacks-increased-by-30-percent-in-those-taking-500-mg-of-calcium-without-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-attacks-increased-by-30-percent-in-those-taking-500-mg-of-calcium-without-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="research-questions-calcium-supplements">Research questions calcium supplements&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>30 July 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.rte.ie/news/2010/0730/calcium.html">http://www.rte.ie/news/2010/0730/calcium.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical research suggests that people taking calcium supplements have a higher risk of heart attack.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The study, published in the British Medical Journal, found that calcium from dietary sources did not increase the risk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calcium supplements are often taken by older people for the prevention and treatment of osteoporosis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Researchers have been analysing the results of 11 different studies carried out on some 12,000 people.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>890 IU of vitamin D and 1200 mg Calcium improved bone density</title><link>/posts/890-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-1200-mg-calcium-improved-bone-density.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/890-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-1200-mg-calcium-improved-bone-density.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-effects-of-a-30-month-dietary-intervention-on-bone-mineral-density-the-postmenopausal-health-study">The effects of a 30-month dietary intervention on bone mineral density: the Postmenopausal Health Study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Br J Nutr. 2010 Jul;104(1):100-7. Epub 2010 Apr 7.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Moschonis G, Katsaroli I, Lyritis GP, Manios Y.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutrition &amp;amp; Dietetics, Harokopio University of Athens, Athens, Greece.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low dietary Ca intake and vitamin D insufficiency have been implicated as part of the aetiology leading to osteoporosis. The aim of the present study was to examine the effects of a 30-month dietary intervention that combined supplementation of dairy products fortified with Ca and vitamin D3 and lifestyle and nutrition counselling sessions on bone mineral density (BMD) of postmenopausal women. Sixty-six postmenopausal women (aged 55-65 years) were randomised into a dietary group (DG; n 35), receiving daily and for the first 12 months 1200 mg Ca and 7.5 microg vitamin D3, while for the next 18 months of intervention &lt;strong>1200 mg Ca and 22.5 microg&lt;/strong> vitamin D3 through fortified dairy products, and a control group (CG; n 31) receiving neither counselling nor dairy products. The DG was found to have more favourable changes in arms (P &amp;lt; 0.001), total spine (P = 0.001) and total body BMD (P &amp;lt; 0.001) compared with the CG. Furthermore, a significant increase was observed for the DG in lumbar spine BMD (0.056; 95 % CI 0.009, 0.103), which was not found to differentiate significantly compared with the change observed in the CG (P = 0.075).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium and vitamin D review by AHRQ</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-review-by-ahrq.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-review-by-ahrq.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-calcium-systematic-review--of-health-outcomes">Vitamin D and Calcium: Systematic Review of Health Outcomes&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>May 2010 &lt;a href="http://www.ahrq.gov/clinic/tp/vitadcaltp.htm">http://www.ahrq.gov/clinic/tp/vitadcaltp.htm&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1289]&lt;/span>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Background:&lt;/strong> Since the 1997 Dietary Reference Intake (DRI) values for vitamin D and calcium were established new data have become available on their relationship, both individually and combined, to a wide range of health outcomes. The Institute of Medicine/Food and Nutrition Board has constituted a DRI committee to undertake a review of the evidence and potential revision of the current DRI values for these nutrients. To support this review, several U.S. and Canadian Federal Government agencies commissioned a systematic review of the scientific literature for use during the deliberations by the committee. The intent of providing a systematic review to the committee is to support transparency of the literature review process and provide a foundation for subsequent reviews of the nutrients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Constipation - Magnesium, Calcium and cofactors</title><link>/posts/constipation-magnesium-calcium-and-cofactors.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/constipation-magnesium-calcium-and-cofactors.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="increased-vitamin-d--decreases-mg--constipation">Increased Vitamin D ==&amp;gt; Decreases Mg ==&amp;gt; Constipation&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.easy-immune-health.com/vitamin-d-and-constipation.html">Vitamin D and Constipation&lt;/a> Easy Immune Health] Actually a lack of Mg due to vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.natural-indigestion-relief.com/magnesium-and-constipation.html">Magnesium and Constipation&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://realconstipationremedies.com/magnesium-for-constipation/">Magnesium For Constipation?&lt;/a> May 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The symptoms of acute magnesium deficiency that you will tend to experience include:&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Constipation; Muscle weakness, tremor, or spasm; Sleepiness, fatigue; Vomiting; Headaches; Insomnia; Irritability&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Poor memory; Rapid heartbeat; Numbness, tingling; Muscle contractions, cramps&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.doctoroz.com/videos/natural-constipation-relief">Natural Constipation Relief&lt;/a> Dr. Oz Show, March 2012, Ca and Mg&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>USDA vitamin D level more than 30ng and 600 mg Calcium</title><link>/posts/usda-vitamin-d-level-more-than-30ng-and-600-mg-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/usda-vitamin-d-level-more-than-30ng-and-600-mg-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-calcium-interplay-explored">Vitamin D and Calcium Interplay Explored&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>By Rosalie Marion Bliss&lt;/p>
&lt;p>March 12, 2010 &lt;a href="http://www.ars.usda.gov/is/pr/2010/100312.htm">http://www.ars.usda.gov/is/pr/2010/100312.htm&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Increasing calcium intake is a common—yet not always successful—strategy for reducing bone fractures. But a study supported in part by the Agricultural Research Service (ARS) underscores the importance of vitamin D and its ability to help the body utilize calcium. The study also may explain why increasing calcium alone isn’t always successful in dealing with this problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No risk of hypercalcemia with prolonged 10000 IU of vitamin D3</title><link>/posts/no-risk-of-hypercalcemia-with-prolonged-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d3.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-risk-of-hypercalcemia-with-prolonged-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d3.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-mini-symposium-the-risk-of-additional-vitamin-d">Vitamin D and cancer mini-symposium: the risk of additional vitamin D.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Epidemiol. 2009 Jul;19(7):441-5. Epub 2009 Apr 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D and cancer mini-symposium: the risk of additional vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vieth R. Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Toronto, and Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Mount Sinai Hospital, Toronto, Canada. &lt;a href="mailto:rvieth@mtsinai.on.ca">rvieth@mtsinai.on.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any benefit of vitamin D needs to be balanced against the risk of toxicity, which is characterized by hypercalcemia. Daily brief, suberythemal exposure of a substantial area of the skin to ultraviolet light, climate allowing, provides adults with a safe, physiologic amount of vitamin D, equivalent to an oral intake of about 10,000 IU vitamin D(3) per day, with the plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentration potentially reaching 220 nmol/L ( &lt;strong>88 ng/mL&lt;/strong> ).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Postmenopausal women should supplement vitamins C D K and Calcium</title><link>/posts/postmenopausal-women-should-supplement-vitamins-c-d-k-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/postmenopausal-women-should-supplement-vitamins-c-d-k-and-calcium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Calcium and vitamin D appear to be among the few ways to prevent ovarian cancer – 2010</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-appear-to-be-among-the-few-ways-to-prevent-ovarian-cancer-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-appear-to-be-among-the-few-ways-to-prevent-ovarian-cancer-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="independent-and-joint-effects-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-calcium-on-ovarian-cancer-risk-a-prospective-nested-casecontrol-study---june-2010">Independent and joint effects of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and calcium on ovarian cancer risk: A prospective nested case–control study - June 2010&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>European Journal of Cancer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.ejca.2010.05.019&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adetunji T. Toriolaa, b, Corresponding Author Contact Information, E-mail The Corresponding Author, E-mail The Corresponding Author, Helja-Marja Surcela, Agborsangaya Calypsea, b, Kjell Grankvistc, Tapio Luostarinend, Annekatrin Lukanovae, Eero Pukkalab, d and Matti Lehtinena, b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a National Institute for Health and Welfare, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Tampere School of Public Health, University of Tampere, Finland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium level somewhat higher due to vitamin D might be a problem</title><link>/posts/calcium-level-somewhat-higher-due-to-vitamin-d-might-be-a-problem.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-level-somewhat-higher-due-to-vitamin-d-might-be-a-problem.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="recent-clinical-trials-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation-and-serum-calcium-levels-in-humans-implications-for-vitamin-d-based-chemoprevention">Recent clinical trials of vitamin D3 supplementation and serum calcium levels in humans: Implications for vitamin D-based chemoprevention.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Investig Drugs. 2010 Jun;11(6):678-87.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skinner HG, Litzelman K, Schwartz GG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1University of Wisconsin-Madison, Department of Population Health Sciences, 610 Walnut Street, Madison, WI 53726, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical trials of vitamin D supplementation published from 2000 to 2009 are reviewed, with an emphasis on changes in serum calcium levels. In these trials, vitamin D supplementation often resulted in modest increases in serum calcium levels, but rarely caused hypercalcemia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I do not need vitamin D, it is in my supplements</title><link>/posts/i-do-not-need-vitamin-d-it-is-in-my-supplements.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/i-do-not-need-vitamin-d-it-is-in-my-supplements.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d--created-from-consumer-labs-jan-2010-review">Calcium and Vitamin D- Created from Consumer Labs Jan 2010 review&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note: Often multi-vitamins have even less, only 400 IU - which has only been enough to prevent rickets.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Need 2000+ IU daily to start to improve your near-term health and make substantial reductions in long-term disease&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"></description></item><item><title>Not enough Calcium in multivitamins for senior men</title><link>/posts/not-enough-calcium-in-multivitamins-for-senior-men.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/not-enough-calcium-in-multivitamins-for-senior-men.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-adult-vitamin-and-mineral-supplement-maze">The Adult Vitamin and Mineral Supplement Maze&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal	The Consultant Pharmacist&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Issue	Volume 25, Number 4 / April 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI	10.4140/TCP.n.2010.234 Pages 234-240 May 28, 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elaine D. Mackowiak, PhD1, Yelena Bernstein, PharmD2, Stephen H. Paul, PhD3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Temple University School of Pharmacy, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Chestnut Hill Hospital, Philadelphia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Temple University School of Pharmacy, Philadelphia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: The content and daily cost of 14 popular multi-vitamin/ multi-mineral (MVMM) supplements promoted for adults 50 years of age or older in the United States were compared in order to provide pharmacists with objective information, enabling them to make more informed recommendations for these products.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Muscle strength in youth increased with 60,000 IU vitamin D per week and 1 g Calcium</title><link>/posts/muscle-strength-in-youth-increased-with-60000-iu-vitamin-d-per-week-and-1-g-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/muscle-strength-in-youth-increased-with-60000-iu-vitamin-d-per-week-and-1-g-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-cholecalciferol-and-calcium-supplementation-on-muscle-strength-and-energy-metabolism-in-vitamin-d-deficient-asian-indians-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Effect of cholecalciferol and calcium supplementation on muscle strength and energy metabolism in vitamin D deficient Asian Indians: A randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2010 Apr 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gupta R, Sharma U, Gupta N, Kalaivani M, Singh U, Guleria R, Jagannathan NR, Goswami R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi 110029, India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract Context. Vitamin D deficiency is prevalent worldwide. Vitamin D supplementation has shown variable effect on skeletal muscle strength in the elderly with hypovitaminosis D. There is a paucity of similar data in young individuals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vascular calcification in chronic kidney disease</title><link>/posts/vascular-calcification-in-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vascular-calcification-in-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Clin Sci (Lond). 2010 Apr 28;119(3):111-21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Covic A, Kanbay M, Voroneanu L, Turgut F, Serban DN, Serban IL, Goldsmith DJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinic of Nephrology, C. I. Parhon University Hospital, Gr. T. Popa University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Bd. Carol I, Nr. 50, Iasi, Romania. &lt;a href="mailto:adrianccovic@gmail.com">adrianccovic@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VC (vascular calcification) is highly prevalent in patients with CKD (chronic kidney disease), but its mechanism is multifactorial and incompletely understood. In addition to increased traditional risk factors, CKD patients also have a number of non-traditional cardiovascular risk factors, which may play a prominent role in the pathogenesis of arterial calcification, such as duration of dialysis and disorders of mineral metabolism. The transformation of vascular smooth muscle cells into chondrocytes or osteoblast-like cells seems to be a key element in VC pathogenesis, in the context of passive calcium and phosphate deposition due to abnormal bone metabolism and impaired renal excretion. The process may be favoured by the low levels of circulating and locally produced VC inhibitors. VC determines increased arterial stiffness, left ventricular hypertrophy, a decrease in coronary artery perfusion, myocardial ischaemia and increased cardiovascular morbidity and mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10,000 IU vitamin D plus Calcium trial for those with MS</title><link>/posts/10000-iu-vitamin-d-plus-calcium-trial-for-those-with-ms.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10000-iu-vitamin-d-plus-calcium-trial-for-those-with-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-phase-iii-dose-escalation-trial-of-vitamin-d3-and-calcium-in-multiple-sclerosis">A phase I/II dose-escalation trial of vitamin D3 and calcium in multiple sclerosis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Neurology. 2010 Apr 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burton JM, Kimball S, Vieth R, Bar-Or A, Dosch HM, Cheung R, Gagne D, D&amp;rsquo;Souza C, Ursell M, O&amp;rsquo;Connor P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Division of Neurology (J.M.B., P.O.), St. Michael&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Toronto; University of Toronto (J.M.B., S.K., R.V., H.-M.D., R.C., C.D., P.O.), Toronto; Department of Nutritional Sciences and Laboratory Medicine and Pathology (S.K., R.V.), Mount Sinai Hospital, Toronto; Montreal Neurological Institute (A.B.-O., D.G.), Montreal; McGill University (A.B.-O., D.G.), Montreal; The Neurosciences &amp;amp; Mental Health Program (H.-M.D., R.C.), Hospital for Sick Children, Toronto; Center for Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases (C.D.), University of Toronto; and Division of Neurology (M.U.), Etobicoke General Hospital, Toronto, Canada.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium deficiency is a risk factor for overweight female teenagers</title><link>/posts/calcium-deficiency-is-a-risk-factor-for-overweight-female-teenagers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-deficiency-is-a-risk-factor-for-overweight-female-teenagers.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="obesity-prevalence-according-calcium-status-in-adolescent-women">OBESITY PREVALENCE ACCORDING CALCIUM STATUS IN ADOLESCENT WOMEN.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>FASEB (Federation of American Societies of Experimental Biology) Journal Vol 24 April 2010 917.19&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maria Esther Rio1,2, Ana Lia Felipoff1, Liliana Zago1 and Norma Piazza3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Universidad de Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 CONICET, Ciudad Autónoma de Buenos Aires, Argentina&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Epidemiologia, Vicente López, Argentina&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adolescence is a highly vulnerable period of life. Multiple changes occur which often translate into bad eating habits among them, shortcomings in the intake of calcium (Ca), problem which has received special attention since recent investigations have shown an association between high Ca intakes and prevention of adiposity. Here we study the influence of Ca status (CaS) on overweight and obesity in 130 adolescent females 10 to 18 years old. Diagnosis of Normality (N), Overweight (OW) and Obesity (O) was performed by IMC (WHO 2007) (N: zIMC &amp;lt; +1DS and &amp;gt;-2DS; OW: zIMC &amp;gt; + 1DS; O: zIMC &amp;gt; +2DS) and maturity by Tanner (T).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium in food increased much more than Magnesium in recent decades</title><link>/posts/calcium-in-food-increased-much-more-than-magnesium-in-recent-decades.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-in-food-increased-much-more-than-magnesium-in-recent-decades.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Less than 750 mg Calcium with Vitamin D to improve balance</title><link>/posts/less-than-750-mg-calcium-with-vitamin-d-to-improve-balance.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-than-750-mg-calcium-with-vitamin-d-to-improve-balance.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="letter-internal-medicine-news-volume-43-issue-7-page-9-15-april-2010">Letter Internal Medicine News Volume 43, Issue 7, Page 9 (15 April 2010)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Cindy Geyer, M.D. (Lenox, Mass), Bruce Rothschild, M.D. (Lawrence, Kan)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am writing in response to “Doubts Emerge About Widespread Use of Vitamin D Supplementation” (March 1, 2010, p. 1), particularly with regard to the possibility of increased arterial calcification. Although one study was cited as linking higher vitamin D levels in African Americans to increased calcification in the carotids and aorta, most of the article referred to a study looking at the effects of calcium supplementation, not vitamin D, on cardiovascular events. Since vitamin D deficiency is associated with an increase in PTH and an increase in osteoclast activity, it seems that supplementation of calcium alone (without adequate vitamin D) is more likely to cause the problem of soft tissue calcification. Perhaps the article should have also &lt;strong>addressed doubts about the widely recommended use of 1,000 mg of supplemental calcium daily&lt;/strong> . I think the balance of the two is important. I now aim to have people get their vitamin D levels up at least to 30 ng/mL but try to meet most of their calcium needs through food. I then try to limit supplemental calcium for most people to no more than &lt;strong>500-750 mg daily&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rare case of 3000 IU vitamin D being toxic – hypercalcemia</title><link>/posts/rare-case-of-3000-iu-vitamin-d-being-toxic-hypercalcemia.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rare-case-of-3000-iu-vitamin-d-being-toxic-hypercalcemia.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Rare Causes of Calcitriol-Mediated Hypercalcemia: A Case Report and Literature Review.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2010 Apr 28. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kallas M, Green F, Hewison M, White C, Kline G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine (M.K., G.K.), University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 4J8; Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine (F.G.), University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 2N1; Department of Orthopaedic Surgery (M.H.), University of California, Los Angeles, California 90095-7358; and Department of Clinical Neurosciences (C.W.), University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 2T9.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and calcium for the prevention of fractures</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcium-for-the-prevention-of-fractures.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcium-for-the-prevention-of-fractures.html</guid><description>&lt;p>from Essential Evidence Evidence Summaries 2009-12-30&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Level of evidence = A&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oral vitamin D 700–800 IU/day with calcium supplementation 1200 mg/day or more reduces the risk of hip and nonvertebral fractures in ambulatory or institutionalised elderly people. A vitamin D dose of 400 IU/day seems to be insufficient for fracture prevention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Cochrane review 1 (abstract &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup> , review &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup> ) included 45 randomised or quasi-randomised studies comparing vitamin D or an analogue, alone or with calcium, against placebo, no intervention, or calcium, reporting fracture outcomes, in older people, with a total of over 50 000.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Calcium after Gastric bypass</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcium-after-gastric-bypass.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcium-after-gastric-bypass.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Obes Surg. 2010 Apr 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-supplementation-after-gastric-bypass-should-be-individualized-to-improve-or-avoid-hyperparathyroidism">Calcium and Vitamin D Supplementation after Gastric Bypass Should Be Individualized to Improve or Avoid Hyperparathyroidism.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Flores L, Martínez Osaba MJ, Andreu A, Moizé V, Rodríguez L, Vidal J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obesity Unit, Hospital Clínic i Universitari, Villarroel 170, 08036, Barcelona, Spain, &lt;a href="mailto:lflores@clinic.ub.es">lflores@clinic.ub.es&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Precise calcium (Ca) and vitamin D intestinal absorption after gastric bypass (GB) remains unknown. We evaluated the effect of receiving or not Ca and vitamin D supplementation on Ca, PTH, and vitamin D axis in patients undergoing GB.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>