<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer - Other on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer---other.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer - Other on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer---other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Oral cancer risk and vitamin D status, intake, and supplementation - review</title><link>/posts/oral-cancer-risk-and-vitamin-d-status-intake-and-supplementation-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/oral-cancer-risk-and-vitamin-d-status-intake-and-supplementation-review.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Yet again, some cancers of esophagus vary with UV</title><link>/posts/yet-again-some-cancers-of-esophagus-vary-with-uv.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yet-again-some-cancers-of-esophagus-vary-with-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="editorial-shedding-some-light-on-the-etiology-of-adenocarcinomas-of-the-esophagus-and-gastric-cardia">Editorial: shedding some light on the etiology of adenocarcinomas of the esophagus and gastric cardia.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Am J Gastroenterol. 2012 Dec;107(12):1814-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ajg.2012.337.">doi: 10.1038/ajg.2012.337.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rubenstein JH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1] Veterans Affairs Center for Clinical Management Research, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2] Division of Gastroenterology, University of Michigan Medical School, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Environmental and behavioral factors likely have large roles in the etiology of adenocarcinomas of the esophagus and gastroesophageal junction. Prior ecological analyses suggest a protective effect of exposure to UV radiation for these cancers. But such analyses are prone to particular forms of bias. In this issue of The American Journal of Gastroenterology, new individual-level data is presented supporting such an association. Presumably, this is mediated by vitamin D, but definitive evidence is lacking. Supplementation with vitamin D aimed at preventing these cancers cannot be recommended at this time. More study regarding the role of vitamin D in Barrett&amp;rsquo;s esophagus and these cancers are needed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Risk of Rarer Cancers</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-risk-of-rarer-cancers.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-risk-of-rarer-cancers.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="shedding-light-on-serum-vitamin-d-concentrations-and-the-risk-of-rarer-cancers">Shedding Light on Serum Vitamin D Concentrations and the Risk of Rarer Cancers&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.65-69 (5)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Kathy J. Helzlsouer, Lisa Gallicchio&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer is a broad term for many disparate diseases with different etiologies, commonly classified by affected organ site. This review summarizes the published evidence from prospective cohort studies examining the associations between vitamin D, measured as serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) concentrations, and the risk of rarer cancer sites including&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer - Other</title><link>/posts/cancer-other.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-other.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Endometrial cancer and Vitamin D – many studies</title><link>/posts/endometrial-cancer-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/endometrial-cancer-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#14400-studies-of-endometrial-cancer-and-vitamin-d---jan-2024">14,400 studies of endometrial cancer and vitamin D - Jan 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-web">See web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#study-vitamin-d-levels-not-high-enough-to-find-an-association-with-ec---2012">Study: Vitamin D levels not high enough to find an association with EC - 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#agreed-most-cancers-are-not-hindered-when-vitamin-d-levels-30-nanograms">Agreed: Most cancers are NOT hindered when vitamin D levels &amp;lt;30 nanograms&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="14400-studies-of-endometrial-cancer-and-vitamin-d---jan-2024">14,400 studies of endometrial cancer and vitamin D - Jan 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0%2C48&amp;amp;q=%22endometrial+cancer%22+%22vitamin+d%22&amp;amp;btnG=">Google Scholar&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Prospective analysis of vitamin D and endometrial cancer risk - March 2013 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.bjc.6605149">FREE PDF&lt;/a> no association, everyone had low vitamin D levels&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X more Thyroid Cancer malignancy if less than 15 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/2x-more-thyroid-cancer-malignancy-if-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-thyroid-cancer-malignancy-if-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-potentially-modifiable-risk-factor-for-thyroid-cancer">Vitamin d deficiency as a potentially modifiable risk factor for thyroid cancer.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-receptor-and-medullary-thyroid-cancer---july-2016">Vitamin D Receptor and medullary thyroid cancer - July 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2000-studies-contain-thyroid-cancer-and-vitamin-d-receptor">2,000+ studies contain &amp;ldquo;Thyroid Cancer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;vitamin D Receptor&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-potentially-modifiable-risk-factor-for-thyroid-cancer">Vitamin d deficiency as a potentially modifiable risk factor for thyroid cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2012 Jun 1;41(3):160-3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roskies M, Dolev Y, Caglar D, Hier MP, Mlynarek A, Majdan A, Payne RJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:Vitamin D, classically involved in calcium homeostasis, has garnered recent interest for its potential role in cancer prevention and therapy. Although few risk factors have been established in the development of well-differentiated thyroid carcinoma, some would argue that no clear modifiable risk factor exists. Our study is one of the first to explore the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and thyroid cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Head and Neck Cancer associated with low vitamin D, especially with blacks</title><link>/posts/head-and-neck-cancer-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-especially-with-blacks.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/head-and-neck-cancer-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-especially-with-blacks.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="disparities-in-head-and-neck-cancer-a-case-for-chemoprevention-with-vitamin-d">Disparities in head and neck cancer: A case for chemoprevention with vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Amy Exum, Kristin D. Ezell, W. Jarrard Goodwin, Elizabeth J. Franzmann, Jennifer J. Hu, Laura A. Kresty. Univ. of Miami Sylvester Cancer Center, Miami, FL&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldwide head and neck cancer (HNC) is the sixth most frequently diagnosed cancer in men and is associated with significant morbidity, mortality and economic loss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>African Americans (AA) experience significantly more HNC compared to Caucasian Americans (CA)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X higher risk of oral cancer if CYP27B1 and CYP24A1 genes were different</title><link>/posts/3x-higher-risk-of-oral-cancer-if-cyp27b1-and-cyp24a1-genes-were-different.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-higher-risk-of-oral-cancer-if-cyp27b1-and-cyp24a1-genes-were-different.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-cyp27b1-and-cyp24a1-genes-polymorphisms-association-with-oral-cancer-risk-and-survival">Vitamin D receptor, CYP27B1 and CYP24A1 genes polymorphisms association with oral cancer risk and survival.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Oral Pathol Med. 2012 May 22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0714.2012.01164.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0714.2012.01164.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zeljic K, Supic G, Stamenkovic Radak M, Jovic N, Kozomara R, Magic Z.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute for Medical Research, Military Medical Academy, Belgrade, Serbia Faculty of Biology, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia Clinic for Maxillofacial Surgery, Military Medical Academy, Belgrade, Serbia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Genetic polymorphisms of vitamin D receptor gene (VDR) and genes involved in vitamin D metabolism pathway, CYP27B1 and CYP24B1, may affect individual susceptibility to oral squamous cell carcinoma. The purpose of this study was to evaluate the associations between VDR, CYP27B1 and CYP24A1 gene polymorphisms with oral cancer risk and survival.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gastric Cancer patients with more vitamin D more likely to live</title><link>/posts/gastric-cancer-patients-with-more-vitamin-d-more-likely-to-live.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gastric-cancer-patients-with-more-vitamin-d-more-likely-to-live.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prognostic-effects-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-gastric-cancer">Prognostic effects of 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in gastric cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Chao Ren, Miao-zhen Qiu, De-shen Wang, Hui-yan Luo, Dong-sheng Zhang, Zhi-qiang Wang, Feng-hua Wang, Yu-hong Li, Zhi-wei Zhou and Rui-hua Xu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Translational Medicine 2012, 10:16 doi:10.1186/1479-5876-10-16, Published: 27 January 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Results from large epidemiologic studies on the association between vitamin D and gastric cancer are controversial. Vitamin D significantly promotes apoptosis in the undifferentiated gastric cancer cell, but the prognostic effects of its levels are unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Osteosarcoma grows more slowly when there is enough vitamin D</title><link>/posts/osteosarcoma-grows-more-slowly-when-there-is-enough-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/osteosarcoma-grows-more-slowly-when-there-is-enough-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Osteosarcoma is a type of malignant bone tumor that mainly affects children and adolescents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>vitamin D prevented osteosarcoma cells from replicating as quickly and promoted the growth of normal bone cells.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study looked at osteosarcoma cells removed from the human body&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.kumc.edu/news-listing-page/vitamin-d-and-pediatric-bone-cancer.html">Press Release by the University&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4TMeQWFU7To">2.5 minute Video by the author&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Full article is attached as a PDF at bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="web">Web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Association of vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms with osteosarcoma risk and prognosis - 2019 &lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/osteosarcoma---2019.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D might reduce gastric cancer in humans too</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-might-reduce-gastric-cancer-in-humans-too.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-might-reduce-gastric-cancer-in-humans-too.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-upregulated-protein-1-deficiency-promotes-n-methyl-n-nitrosourea-and-helicobacter-pylori-induced-gastric-carcinogenesis-in-mice">Vitamin D3 upregulated protein 1 deficiency promotes N-methyl-N-nitrosourea and Helicobacter pylori-induced gastric carcinogenesis in mice&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Hyo-Jung Kwon 1,2, Young-Suk Won 1, Ki-Taek Nam 3, Yeo-Dae Yoon 4, Hyang Jee 2, Won-Kee Yoon 1, Ki-Hoan Nam 1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jong-Soon Kang 4, Sang-Uk Han 5, In-Pyo Choi 6, Dae-Yong Kim 2, Hyoung-Chin Kim 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Biomedical Mouse Resource Center, Korea Research Institute of Bioscience and Biotechnology, Chungbuk, Republic of Korea&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Veterinary Pathology and Research Institute for Veterinary Science, College of Veterinary Medicine, Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancers and Vitamin D Council</title><link>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>