<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer - Lung on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer---lung.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer - Lung on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer---lung/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Low vitamin D strongly related to death due to tobacco cancer, but not others</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-strongly-related-to-death-due-to-tobacco-cancer-but-not-others.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-strongly-related-to-death-due-to-tobacco-cancer-but-not-others.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="low-plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-risk-of-tobacco-related-cancer">Low Plasma 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Risk of Tobacco-Related Cancer&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Clinical Chemistry March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shoaib Afzal 1, Stig E. Bojesen 1,2,3 and Børge G. Nordestgaard 1,2,3,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 The Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Herlev Hospital,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 The Copenhagen City Heart study, Frederiksberg Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital, Copenhagen, Denmark;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵*Address correspondence to this author at: Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Herlev Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital, Herlev Ringvej 75, DK-2730 Herlev, Denmark. Fax +45-38683311; e-mail &lt;a href="mailto:Boerge.Nordestgaard@regionh.dk">Boerge.Nordestgaard@regionh.dk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer - Lung</title><link>/posts/cancer-lung.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-lung.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects against lung cancer unless there is excess vitamin A</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-lung-cancer-unless-there-is-excess-vitamin-a.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-lung-cancer-unless-there-is-excess-vitamin-a.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-vitamin-a-and-lung-cancer-mortality-in-the-us-population-a-potential-nutrient-nutrient-interaction">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D, vitamin A, and lung cancer mortality in the US population: a potential nutrient-nutrient interaction.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2012 Jul 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cheng TY, Neuhouser ML.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Public Health Sciences Division, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center, 1100 Fairview Avenue North, M4B402, Seattle, WA, 98109-1024, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:tcheng@fhcrc.org">tcheng@fhcrc.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Excess vitamin A may interrupt vitamin D-mediated transcription of target genes. This study investigated whether serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations were associated with lung cancer mortality, and whether this association varied by excess circulating vitamin A and vitamin A/?-carotene supplement use.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One third of lung disease patients in China had less than 4ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/one-third-of-lung-disease-patients-in-china-had-less-than-4ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/one-third-of-lung-disease-patients-in-china-had-less-than-4ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="lung-cancer-and-benign-lung-diseases-in-patients-with-serious-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-eastern-china">Lung cancer and benign lung diseases in patients with serious vitamin D deficiency in eastern China.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology, 2012 ASCO Annual Meeting Proceedings (Post-Meeting Edition).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol 30, No 15_suppl (May 20 Supplement), 2012: e12010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2012 American Society of Clinical Oncology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rong Li, Jing Wu, Liwen Xiong and Baohui Han&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Pulmonary Medicine of Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai, China; The Biochemical Laboratory of Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai, China; Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai, China&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting little UV is associated with 15 types of Cancer</title><link>/posts/getting-little-uv-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/getting-little-uv-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="ecological-studies-of-the-uvbvitamin-dcancer-hypothesis">Ecological Studies of the UVB–Vitamin D–Cancer Hypothesis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Anticancer Research January 2012 vol. 32 no. 1 223-236&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WILLIAM B. GRANT, Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, P.O. Box 641603, San Francisco, CA 94164-1603, U.S.A. &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aim: This paper reviews ecological studies of the ultraviolet-B (UVB)–vitamin D–cancer hypothesis based on geographical variation of cancer incidence and/or mortality rates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Materials and Methods: The review is based largely on three ecological studies of cancer rates from the United States; one each from Australia, China, France, Japan, and Spain; and eight multicountry, multifactorial studies of cancer incidence rates from &lt;strong>more than 100 countries&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lung and Vitamin D – Special Issue</title><link>/posts/lung-and-vitamin-d-special-issue.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lung-and-vitamin-d-special-issue.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces lung damage due to radiotherapy</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-lung-damage-due-to-radiotherapy.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-lung-damage-due-to-radiotherapy.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-prophylaxis-on-radiation-induced-pulmonary-damage">The effect of vitamin d prophylaxis on radiation induced pulmonary damage.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Radiat Res (Tokyo). 2011;52(5):616-21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yazici G, Yildiz F, Iskit A, Erdemli E, Surucu S, Firat P, Hayran M, Ozyigit G, Cengiz M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Radiation Oncology, Hacettepe University, Faculty of Medicine.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolor00fpdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-this-pagespan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has a selective radio and chemosensitizing effect on tumor cells. In vitro and in vivo studies have shown that vitamin D inhibits collagen gel construction, induces type II pneumocyte proliferation and surfactant synthesis in the lungs, and decreases vascular permeability caused by radiation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancers and Vitamin D Council</title><link>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lung Cancer and Vitamin D – 2 studies</title><link>/posts/lung-cancer-and-vitamin-d-2-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lung-cancer-and-vitamin-d-2-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="two-articles-this-month-one-yes-one-no">Two articles this month: one YES, one NO&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-lung-cancer--expert-review---yes">Vitamin D and lung cancer – Expert Review YES&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Expert Rev Respir Med. 2011 Jun;5(3):305-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ramnath N, Kim S, Christensen PJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Medical Oncology Department of Medicine, University of Michigan Comprehensive Cancer Center, 1500 East Medical Center Dr, Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA and Staff Physician, Veterans Administration Medical Center, 2215 Fuller Road, Ann Arbor, MI 48105, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:nithyar@umich.edu">nithyar@umich.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMID: 21702651 &lt;a href="http://www.expert-reviews.com/doi/abs/10.1586/ers.11.31">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for full text&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lung cancer not reduced when vitamin D levels were less than 40 ng</title><link>/posts/lung-cancer-not-reduced-when-vitamin-d-levels-were-less-than-40-ng.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lung-cancer-not-reduced-when-vitamin-d-levels-were-less-than-40-ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D might not TREAT lung cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-might-not-treat-lung-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-might-not-treat-lung-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="s91-the-role-of-the-vitamin-d-axis-in-lung-cancer">S91 The role of the vitamin D axis in lung cancer&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Thorax 2010;65:A42-A43 doi:10.1136/thx.2010.150938.42&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>L A McGowan1, 2. A M Wood2, 3. P Newby2, 4. B Naidu3&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>1University of Warwick, Warwick, UK, 2University of Birmingham, Birmingham, UK,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Heart of England NHS Trust, Birmingham, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with many cancers, although little is known about its role in lung cancer. This is biologically plausible since vitamin D influences apoptosis and inhibits cell proliferation. Vitamin D receptor (VDR) polymorphisms have also been suggested to play a role in genetic susceptibility, their direction being consistent with inability to respond to vitamin D. Finally, vitamin D binding protein (DBP) indirectly activates alveolar macrophages, a higher number of which within a tumour links to better prognosis in lung cancer.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>