<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Seniors on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/seniors.html</link><description>Recent content in Seniors on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/seniors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Older adults of diverse ancestry had similar vitamin D levels and were getting 1000 IU</title><link>/posts/older-adults-of-diverse-ancestry-had-similar-vitamin-d-levels-and-were-getting-1000-iu.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/older-adults-of-diverse-ancestry-had-similar-vitamin-d-levels-and-were-getting-1000-iu.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-status-of-older-adults-of-diverse-ancestry-living-in-the-greater-toronto-area">Vitamin D status of older adults of diverse ancestry living in the greater Toronto area&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>BMC Geriatrics 2013, 13:66 doi:10.1186/1471-2318-13-66&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jaime K Ginter (&lt;a href="mailto:jaime.ginter@sheridanc.on.ca">jaime.ginter@sheridanc.on.ca&lt;/a>) S Krithika (&lt;a href="mailto:krithisundar81@gmail.com">krithisundar81@gmail.com&lt;/a>) Agnes Gozdzik (&lt;a href="mailto:agnes.gozdzik@gmail.com">agnes.gozdzik@gmail.com&lt;/a>) Heather Hanwell (&lt;a href="mailto:heather.hanwell@gmail.com">heather.hanwell@gmail.com&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Susan Whiting (&lt;a href="mailto:susan.whiting@usask.ca">susan.whiting@usask.ca&lt;/a>) Esteban J Parra (&lt;a href="mailto:esteban.parra@utoronto.ca">esteban.parra@utoronto.ca&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Physiological and lifestyle factors put older adults at an increased risk of vitamin D insufficiency and resulting negative health outcomes. Here we explore the vitamin D status in a sample of community dwelling older adults of diverse ancestry living in the Greater Toronto area (GTA).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors getting noon sun had 88 percent chance of having at least 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/seniors-getting-noon-sun-had-88-percent-chance-of-having-at-least-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-getting-noon-sun-had-88-percent-chance-of-having-at-least-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="proposal-and-validation-of-a-quick-question-to-rate-the-influence-of-sun-exposure-in-geriatric-epidemiological-studies-on-vitamin-d">Proposal and Validation of a Quick Question to Rate the Influence of Sun Exposure in Geriatric Epidemiological Studies on Vitamin D.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Int J Vitam Nutr Res. 2012 Dec 1;82(6):412-416.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annweiler C &lt;a href="mailto:ceannweiler@chu-angers.fr">ceannweiler@chu-angers.fr&lt;/a> , Schott AM, Beauchet O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neuroscience, Division of Geriatric Medicine, Angers University Hospital, Angers University Memory Clinic, UNAM, Angers, France, and Robarts Research Institute, Department of Medical Biophysics, Schulich School of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Western Ontario, London, Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Frailty Call to Action: Vitamin D is one of the action items</title><link>/posts/frailty-call-to-action-vitamin-d-is-one-of-the-action-items.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/frailty-call-to-action-vitamin-d-is-one-of-the-action-items.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="frailty-consensus-a-call-to-action">Frailty Consensus: A Call to Action&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of the American Medical Directors Association; V-14, Issue 6, June 2013, Pages 392–397&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John E. Morley, MB, Bcha &lt;a href="mailto:morley@slu.edu">morley@slu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruno Vellas, MDb, c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G. Abellan van Kan, MDb, c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan D. Anker, MD, PhDd, e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Juergen M. Bauer, MD, PhDf,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roberto Bernabei, MDg,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matteo Cesari, MD, PhDb, c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W.C. Chumlea, PhDh,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wolfram Doehner, MD, PhDd, i,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jonathan Evans, MDj,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Linda P. Fried, MD, MPHk,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adult osteomalacia (rickets) pain in an individual relieved by vitamin D, etc.</title><link>/posts/adult-osteomalacia-rickets-pain-in-an-individual-relieved-by-vitamin-d-etc.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adult-osteomalacia-rickets-pain-in-an-individual-relieved-by-vitamin-d-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="adult-osteomalacia-a-treatable-cause-of-fear-of-falling">Adult osteomalacia, A treatable cause of &amp;ldquo;fear of falling&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The left hand x-ray suggested the diagnosis of osteomalacia because of the diffuse demineralization.{Image in PDF}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A 65-year-old man was hospitalized with a gait disorder, obliging him to shuffle laterally1 (video on the Neurology® Web site at &lt;a href="https://www.neurology.org">www.neurology.org&lt;/a>) because of pain and proximal limb weakness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He had a &lt;strong>gastrectomy&lt;/strong> for cancer 7 years previously, with &lt;strong>severe vitamin D deficiency&lt;/strong> ; parathormone and alkaline phosphatase were increased, with reduced serum and urine calcium and phosphate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>80 percent of the characteristics of frailty associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/80-percent-of-the-characteristics-of-frailty-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/80-percent-of-the-characteristics-of-frailty-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#associations-between-frailty-and-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-older-australian-men-the-concord-health-and-ageing-in-men-project---2013">Associations Between Frailty and Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D Concentrations in Older Australian Men: The Concord Health and Ageing in Men Project - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-vitamin-d-status-is-an-independent-predictor-of-increased-frailty-and-all-cause-mortality-in-older-men-the-health-in-men-study---2013">Low vitamin D status is an independent predictor of increased frailty and all-cause mortality in older men: the Health In Men Study - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="associations-between-frailty-and-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-older-australian-men-the-concord-health-and-ageing-in-men-project---2013">Associations Between Frailty and Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D Concentrations in Older Australian Men: The Concord Health and Ageing in Men Project - 2013&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2013 May 8.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1600 IU vitamin D was enough to get all (white, non-obese) elderly to 20 ng – RCT</title><link>/posts/1600-iu-vitamin-d-was-enough-to-get-all-white-non-obese-elderly-to-20-ng-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1600-iu-vitamin-d-was-enough-to-get-all-white-non-obese-elderly-to-20-ng-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="is-a-daily-supplementation-with-40-microgram-vitamin-d3-sufficient-a-randomised-controlled-trial">Is a daily supplementation with 40 microgram vitamin D3 sufficient? A randomised controlled trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Eur J Nutr. 2012 Dec;51(8):939-45. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00394-011-0271-7.">doi: 10.1007/s00394-011-0271-7.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Nov 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Toss G, Magnusson P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Gastroenterology, County Council of Östergötland, SE-581 85 Linköping, Sweden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: The effect of 40 μg (1,600 IU) per day of vitamin D(3) on serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and markers of bone and mineral metabolism was evaluated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: This intervention study was designed as a double-blind randomised controlled trial. Forty-five community-dwelling subjects (32 females), age 55-84 years, at 58° North latitude were supplemented for 1 year with 40 μg vitamin D(3) plus 1,000 mg calcium per day, or with 1,000 mg calcium per day for controls. Safety parameters and 25(OH)D, intact parathyroid hormone (PTH), ionized calcium, bone-specific alkaline phosphatase (BALP), and tartrate-resistant acid phosphatase isoform 5b (TRACP5b) were measured over the study period.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pneumonia 2.6X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pneumonia-26x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pneumonia-26x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-and-the-risk-of-pneumonia-in-an-ageing-general-population">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 and the risk of pneumonia in an ageing general population&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Epidemiol Community Health doi:10.1136/jech-2012-202027&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alex Aregbesola, &lt;a href="mailto:alex.aregbesola@uef.fi">alex.aregbesola@uef.fi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sari Voutilainen,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tarja Nurmi,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jyrki K Virtanen,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kimmo Ronkainen,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomi-Pekka Tuomainen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Public Health and Clinical Nutrition, University of Eastern Finland, Kuopio, North Savo, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 5 October 2012; Revised 15 February 2013; Accepted 21 March 2013; Published Online First 17 April 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background Vitamin D has been suggested to have a role in infection defence and on the immune system. We therefore investigated the effect of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25(OH)D3) on the risk of incident hospitalised pneumonia in an ageing general population in eastern Finland.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin K-2 (180 ug MK-7) helped both bone density and strength – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-k-2-180-ug-mk-7-helped-both-bone-density-and-strength-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-k-2-180-ug-mk-7-helped-both-bone-density-and-strength-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="three-year-low-dose-menaquinone-7-supplementation-helps-decrease-bone-loss-in-healthy-postmenopausal-women">Three-year low-dose menaquinone-7 supplementation helps decrease bone loss in healthy postmenopausal women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis International March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. H. J. Knapen, N. E. Drummen, E. Smit, C. Vermeer, E. Theuwissen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have investigated whether low-dose vitamin K2 supplements (menaquinone-7, MK-7) could beneficially affect bone health. Next to an improved vitamin K status, MK-7 supplementation significantly decreased the age-related decline in bone mineral density and bone strength. Low-dose MK-7 supplements may therefore help postmenopausal women prevent bone loss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Community dwelling seniors got vitamin D when outdoors gardening or biking</title><link>/posts/community-dwelling-seniors-got-vitamin-d-when-outdoors-gardening-or-biking.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/community-dwelling-seniors-got-vitamin-d-when-outdoors-gardening-or-biking.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="cross-sectional-study-on-different-characteristics-of-physical-activity-as-determinants-of-vitamin-d-status-inadequate-in-half-of-the-population">Cross-sectional study on different characteristics of physical activity as determinants of vitamin D status; inadequate in half of the population&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>European Journal of Clinical Nutrition 67, 360-365 (April 2013) | doi:10.1038/ejcn.2013.22&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E G H M van den Heuvel, N van Schoor, R T de Jongh, M Visser and P Lips&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Objectives: Physical activity (PA) may have an impact on vitamin D status. The aim of the present study is to assess the contribution of different characteristics of PA (duration, intensity as estimated by energy expenditure, location) to vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hydroaerobics added to Vitamin D and Ca significantly improved physical function</title><link>/posts/hydroaerobics-added-to-vitamin-d-and-ca-significantly-improved-physical-function.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hydroaerobics-added-to-vitamin-d-and-ca-significantly-improved-physical-function.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="high-intensity-aquatic-exercises-hydros-improve-physical-function-and-reduce-falls-among-postmenopausal-women">High-intensity aquatic exercises (HydrOS) improve physical function and reduce falls among postmenopausal women.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Menopause. 2013 Mar 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Denise Fernandes Moreira L, Fronza FC, Dos Santos RN, Teixeira LR, Kruel LF, Lazaretti-Castro M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Endocrinology, Escola Paulista de Medicina, Universidade Federal de São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Physical Education and Sport, University of São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil; and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Exercise Research Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D supplementation can cost 50 dollars a day (live longer)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-can-cost-50-dollars-a-day-live-longer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-can-cost-50-dollars-a-day-live-longer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Muscle cells differentiate into fat cells if there is low vitamin D in petrie dish</title><link>/posts/muscle-cells-differentiate-into-fat-cells-if-there-is-low-vitamin-d-in-petrie-dish.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/muscle-cells-differentiate-into-fat-cells-if-there-is-low-vitamin-d-in-petrie-dish.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="dose-dependent-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-transdifferentiation-of-skeletal-muscle-cells-to-adipose-cells">Dose-dependent effects of vitamin D on transdifferentiation of skeletal muscle cells to adipose cells&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Endocrinol April 1, 2013 217 45-58&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kevin J P Ryan, Zoe C T R Daniel, Lucinda J L Craggs, Tim Parr and John M Brameld. &lt;a href="mailto:john.brameld@nottingham.ac.uk">john.brameld@nottingham.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nutritional Sciences, School of Biosciences, University of Nottingham, Loughborough, Leics LE12 5RD, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fat infiltration within muscle is one of a number of features of vitamin D deficiency, which leads to a decline in muscle functionality. The origin of this fat is unclear, but one possibility is that it forms from myogenic precursor cells present in the muscle, which transdifferentiate into mature adipocytes. The current study examined the effect of the active form of vitamin D3, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3), on the capacity of the C2C12 muscle cell line to differentiate towards the myogenic and adipogenic lineages. Cells were cultured in myogenic or adipogenic differentiation media containing increasing concentrations (0, 10−13, 10−11, 10−9, 10−7 or 10−5 M) of 1,25(OH)2D3 for up to 6 days and markers of muscle and fat development measured. Mature myofibres were formed in both adipogenic and myogenic media, but fat droplets were only observed in adipogenic media.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Norway to double vitamin D to 400 IU for most and 800 IU for elderly</title><link>/posts/norway-to-double-vitamin-d-to-400-iu-for-most-and-800-iu-for-elderly.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/norway-to-double-vitamin-d-to-400-iu-for-most-and-800-iu-for-elderly.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-norwegian-food-safety-authority-has-requested-the-norwegian-scientific-committee-for-food-safety-vkm-to-evaluate-the-national-maximum-limits-for-vitamin-a-and-vitamin-d-in-food-supplements">The Norwegian Food Safety Authority has requested the Norwegian Scientific Committee for Food Safety (VKM) to evaluate the national maximum limits for vitamin A and vitamin D in food supplements.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.english.vkm.no/eway/default.aspx?pid=278&amp;amp;trg=Content_6390&amp;amp;Content_6390=6393:1894292::0:6745:3:::0:0">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for details&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="rda-for-vitamin-d-doubled-to">RDA for vitamin D doubled to:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>400 IU age 2-75&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>800 IU 75+&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="upper-limit-for-vitamin-d-also-doubled">Upper limit for vitamin D also doubled&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>4000 IU for age 10+&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>2000 IU age 1-10&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No correlation found between vitamin D and sarcopenia – German dissertation</title><link>/posts/no-correlation-found-between-vitamin-d-and-sarcopenia-german-dissertation.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-correlation-found-between-vitamin-d-and-sarcopenia-german-dissertation.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="research-into-the-connection-between-vitamin-d-insuffiency-sarcopenia-and-the-frailty-syndrome-based-on-a-sample-of-the-berlin-aging-study-ii-base-ii">Research into the connection between vitamin D-insuffiency, sarcopenia and the frailty-syndrome based on a sample of the Berlin Aging Study II (BASE-II)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Author(s)	Spira, Dominik&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Place of birth: Grünstadt&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Referee	Prof. Dr. med. E. Steinhagen-Thiessen&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Further Referee(s)	Priv.-Doz. Dr. med. R. Lenzen-Großimlinghaus&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prof. Dr. med. M. Pirlich&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summary	In this thesis the connection between vitamin D-insufficiency, sarcopenia and frailty-syndrome has been examined. Vitamin D-insufficiency is common in germany regardless of age but has an even higher prevalence in the elderly. Sarcopenia describes the age-associated and functional relevant loss of muscle mass -following some definitions also muscle strength- whereas the frailty-syndrome is a multidimensional syndrome leading to negative outcomes such as heightened mortality. The hypothesis was that vitamin D-insufficiency favors the incidence of sarcopenia as well as frailty and that sarcopenia is a key factor in the development of the frailty-syndrome. Vice versa it could be imagined that frailty with limited mobility could lead to vitamin d-insuffiency due to reduced time spent outside and limited sun exposure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Physical performance of seniors increases with vitamin D up to 30 ng</title><link>/posts/physical-performance-of-seniors-increases-with-vitamin-d-up-to-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/physical-performance-of-seniors-increases-with-vitamin-d-up-to-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-is-associated-with-physical-performance-the-results-of-three-independent-cohorts">Vitamin D status is associated with physical performance: the results of three independent cohorts.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2013 Jan;24(1):187-96. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-012-2124-5.">doi: 10.1007/s00198-012-2124-5.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Sep 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sohl E, de Jongh RT, Heijboer AC, Swart KM, Brouwer-Brolsma EM, Enneman AW, de Groot CP, van der Velde N, Dhonukshe-Rutten RA, Lips P, van Schoor NM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study, on the association between vitamin D status and physical performance and its decline, shows that vitamin D status is associated with physical performance in several older age groups. However, vitamin D status does not predict a decline in physical performance in individuals aged 55-65 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors with higher vitamin D levels have better physical performance</title><link>/posts/seniors-with-higher-vitamin-d-levels-have-better-physical-performance.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-with-higher-vitamin-d-levels-have-better-physical-performance.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-status-is-associated-with-physical-performance">Vitamin D status is associated with physical performance:&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="the-results-of-three-independent-cohorts">the results of three independent cohorts.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Sep 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sohl E, de Jongh RT, Heijboer AC, Swart KM, Brouwer-Brolsma EM, Enneman AW, de Groot CP, van der Velde N, Dhonukshe-Rutten RA, Lips P, van Schoor NM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study, on the association between vitamin D status and physical performance and its decline, shows that vitamin D status is associated with physical performance in several older age groups. However, vitamin D status does not predict a decline in physical performance in individuals aged 55-65 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Activity and being outdoors helps seniors – GPS and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/activity-and-being-outdoors-helps-seniors-gps-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/activity-and-being-outdoors-helps-seniors-gps-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-relationship-between-outdoor-activity-and-health-in-older-adults-using-gps">The Relationship between Outdoor Activity and Health in Older Adults Using GPS&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 2012, 9, 4615-4625; doi:10.3390/ijerph9124615&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jacqueline Kerr Simon Marshall , Suneeta Godbole , Suvi Neukam , Katie Crist , Kari Wasilenko , Shahrokh Golshan 3 and David Buchner 4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Family and Preventive Medicine, UCSD, 9500 Gilman Drive, La Jolla, CA 92093, USA; E-Mails: &lt;a href="mailto:sjmarshall@ucsd.edu">sjmarshall@ucsd.edu&lt;/a> (S.M); &lt;a href="mailto:sgodbole@ucsd.edu">sgodbole@ucsd.edu&lt;/a> (S.G.); &lt;a href="mailto:kcrist@ucsd.edu">kcrist@ucsd.edu&lt;/a> (K.C.); &lt;a href="mailto:kwasilenko@ucsd.edu">kwasilenko@ucsd.edu&lt;/a> (K.W.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 University of New England College of Osteopathic Medicine, 11 Hills Beach Rd, Biddeford, ME 04005, USA; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:sneukam@une.edu">sneukam@une.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Global analysis of disability - most are associated with vitamin D deficiency - Lancet</title><link>/posts/global-analysis-of-disability-most-are-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-lancet.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/global-analysis-of-disability-most-are-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-lancet.html</guid><description>&lt;p>A huge analysis of Disability around the world was made for the periods of 1990 and 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was a huge increase in the number of years of disability from most health problems&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The report was published in &lt;a href="http://www.thelancet.com/themed/global-burden-of-disease">Lancet&lt;/a> in Dec 2012 7 large articles behind paywall&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="i-classfas-fa-file-pdf-stylemargin-right-03emia-hrefhttpsd1bk1kqxc0symcloudfrontnetattachmentspdfglobal-burden-2013---dec-2014pdfdownload-the-2014-pdf-from-vitamindwikia">&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/global-burden-2013---dec-2014.pdf">Download the 2014 PDF from VitaminDWiki.&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="on-line-arrow-diagramshttpvizhubhealthdataorgirankarrowphp-has-the-full-database">&lt;a href="http://vizhub.healthdata.org/irank/arrow.php">On-line Arrow Diagrams&lt;/a> has the full database&lt;/h4>
&lt;h2 id="causes-of-disability-age-70-74">Causes of Disability: age 70-74&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/disability-70.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>The list is in order of the most disability to the least (e.g. back pain is the largest cause)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less weight gain by senior women if vitamin D levels over 30 ng – Kaiser</title><link>/posts/less-weight-gain-by-senior-women-if-vitamin-d-levels-over-30-ng-kaiser.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-weight-gain-by-senior-women-if-vitamin-d-levels-over-30-ng-kaiser.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#associations-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-weight-gain-in-elderly-women">Associations between 25-hydroxyvitamin D and weight gain in elderly women.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="associations-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-weight-gain-in-elderly-women">Associations between 25-hydroxyvitamin D and weight gain in elderly women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2012 Oct;21(10):1066-73. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1089/jwh.2012.3506.">doi: 10.1089/jwh.2012.3506.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jun 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LeBlanc ES, Rizzo JH, Pedula KL, Ensrud KE, Cauley J, Hochberg M, Hillier TA; Study Of Osteoporotic Fractures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Health Research, Kaiser Permanente Northwest, Portland, OR 97227, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:erin.s.leblanc@kpchr.org">erin.s.leblanc@kpchr.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>25-Hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels are lower in obese individuals. Determining whether low vitamin D status can predispose weight gain requires a longitudinal study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The problems of vitamin d insufficiency in older people</title><link>/posts/the-problems-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-older-people.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-problems-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-older-people.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-problems-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-older-people">The problems of vitamin d insufficiency in older people.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Aging Dis. 2012 Aug;3(4):313-29. Epub 2012 Jun 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boucher BJ. Queen Mary University of London, Centre for Diabetes, Blizard Institute, London, E12AT, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>(PDF is attached at the bottom of this page)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This report reviews evidence on disorders related to inadequate vitamin D repletion in older people. Vitamin D is as essential for bone health in adults as in children, preventing osteomalacia and muscle weakness and protecting against falls and low-impact fractures. Vitamin D is provided by skin synthesis by UVB-irradiation from summer sunshine and to a small extent by absorption from food. However, these processes become less efficient with age. Loss of mobility or residential care restricts solar exposure. Reduced appetite and financial problems often add to these problems. Thus, hypovitaminosis D is common world-wide, but is more common and more severe in older people.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 2 muscles, not all muscles, get benefit from Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-2-muscles-not-all-muscles-get-benefit-from-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-2-muscles-not-all-muscles-get-benefit-from-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vertigo treated by Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/vertigo-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vertigo-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vertigo-bppv-greatly-reduced-by-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-april-2025">Vertigo (BPPV) greatly reduced by Vitamin D - meta-analysis April 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#87-reduction-in-recurrence-of-bppv-with-13-weeks-of-vitamin-d-2000-iu-daily---rct-aug-2024">87% reduction in recurrence of BPPV with 13 weeks of Vitamin D (2,000 IU daily) - RCT Aug 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-greatly-reduced-by-vitamin-d-in-those-who-were-deficient--aug-2024">BPPV greatly reduced by Vitamin D in those who were deficient – Aug 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-recurrences-decreased-with-vitamin-d-supplements--4-out-of-5-studies--feb-2024">BPPV recurrences decreased with Vitamin D supplements (4 out of 5 studies) – Feb 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-associated-with-low-vitamin-d---dr-berg-video-april2023">BPPV associated with low vitamin D - Dr. Berg Video April 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#those-still-dizzy-after-bppv-treatment-were-55-x-more-likely-to-have-low-vitamin-d--june2022">Those still dizzy after BPPV treatment were 5.5 X more likely to have low vitamin D – June 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-substantially-reduced-if-raise-vitamin-d-levels--aug2021">BPPV substantially reduced if raise Vitamin D levels – Aug 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vertigo-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-supplementation-reduced-relapse-pdf-costs-36---nov2021">Vertigo associated with low vitamin D, supplementation reduced relapse (PDF costs $36) - Nov 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-has-many-risk-factors-low-vitamin-d-is-one-of-them--meta-analysis-aug2020">BPPV has many risk factors, low Vitamin D is one of them – Meta-analysis Aug 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-risk-reduced-3x-with-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-aug--2020">BPPV risk reduced 3X with Vitamin D - meta-analysis Aug 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-2x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-of-18-studies-jan2020">BPPV 2X more likely if low Vitamin D - meta-analysis of 18 studies Jan 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-is-associated-with-bppv---meta-analysis-oct2019">Vitamin D is associated with BPPV - meta-analysis Oct 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-eliminated-by-vitamin-d--april2019">BPPV eliminated by Vitamin D – April 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-meta-analysis-found-no-association-with-low-vitamin-d-in-the-blood--oct2018">BPPV Meta-analysis found no association with low vitamin D in the blood- Oct 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#calcium-carbonate-crystals-in-ear-decrease-in-elderly-with-low-vit-d---april2018">Calcium Carbonate crystals in ear decrease in elderly with low Vit D - April 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-23x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficient---oct2012">BPPV 23X more likely if vitamin D deficient - Oct 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-reduced-5-x-by-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-every-2-weeks--2016-the-effect-of-serum-vitamin-d-normalization-in-preventing-recurrences-of-benign-paroxysmal-positional-vertigo-a-case-control-study-caspian-j-intern-med-2016-summer73173-177">BPPV reduced 5 X by 50,000 IU of vitamin D every 2 weeks - 2016** The effect of serum vitamin D normalization in preventing recurrences of benign paroxysmal positional vertigo: A case-control study. **Caspian J Intern Med. 2016 Summer;7(3):173-177.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-21-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---dec2017">BPPV 2.1 X more likely if low vitamin D - Dec 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-much-more-common-with-low-vitamin-d---oct2016-serum-vitamin-d-and-recurrent-benign-paroxysmal-positional-vertigo-laryngoscope-investig-otolaryngol-2016-oct-2016150-153-doi-101002lio235httpsdoiorg101002lio235-ecollection-2016-dec">BPPV much more common with low vitamin D - Oct 2016** Serum vitamin D and recurrent benign paroxysmal positional vertigo. **Laryngoscope Investig Otolaryngol. 2016 Oct 20;1(6):150-153. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/lio2.35.">doi: 10.1002/lio2.35.&lt;/a> eCollection 2016 Dec.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vertigo-bppv-greatly-reduced-by-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-april-2025">Vertigo (BPPV) greatly reduced by Vitamin D - meta-analysis April 2025&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Association between vitamin D, vitamin D supplementation and benign paroxysmal positional vertigo: a systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D aids the aging skin</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-aids-the-aging-skin.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-aids-the-aging-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="unravelling-of-hidden-secrets-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-skin-aging">Unravelling of hidden secrets: the role of vitamin D in skin aging&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermato Endochronology Volume 4, Issue 3 July/August/September 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jörg Reichrath &lt;a href="mailto:Joerg.Reichrath@uks.eu">Joerg.Reichrath@uks.eu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Klinik für Dermatologie; Venerologie und Allergologie; Universitätsklinikum des Saarlandes; Homburg/Saar, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The skin is the only tissue in the human body that represents both a target tissue for biologically active vitamin D compounds including 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)2D) and has the capacity for the synthesis of 1,25(OH)2D from 7-dehydrocholesterol (7-DHC). Recent findings indicate that the vitamin D endocrine system (VDES), besides multiple other important functions, regulates aging in many tissues, including skin. This concept is strongly supported by several independent studies in genetically modified mice (including FGF23?/? and Klotho?/? mice) that are characterized by altered mineral homeostasis caused by a high vitamin D activity. These mice typically have phenotypic features of premature aging that include, besides short lifespan, retarded growth, ectopic calcification, immunological deficiency, osteoporosis, atherosclerosis, hypogonadism, skin and general organ atrophy. Notably, it has been demonstrated that these phenotypic features can be reversed by normalizing mineral homeostasis and/or vitamin D status. Interestingly, the aging phenotypes of mice suffering from hypovitaminosis D (VDR?/? and CYP27B1?/? mice) are quite similar to those suffering from hypervitaminosis D (including FGF-23?/? and Klotho?/? mice). Consequently, it has been hypothesized that thus, both hypo- and hypervitaminosis D may enhance aging.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Physical performance of seniors with low vitamin D dropped over 4 years</title><link>/posts/physical-performance-of-seniors-with-low-vitamin-d-dropped-over-4-years.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/physical-performance-of-seniors-with-low-vitamin-d-dropped-over-4-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-and-change-in-physical-performance-and-strength-in-older-adults-the-health-aging-and-body-composition-study">25-Hydroxyvitamin D Status and Change in Physical Performance and Strength in Older Adults: !!The Health, Aging, and Body Composition Study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Epidemiol. 2012 Nov 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Houston DK, Tooze JA, Neiberg RH, Hausman DB, Johnson MA, Cauley JA, Bauer DC, Cawthon PM, Shea MK, Schwartz GG, Williamson JD, Tylavsky FA, Visser M, Simonsick EM, Harris TB, Kritchevsky SB; for the Health ABC Study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentrations are common among older adults and are associated with poorer physical performance and strength, but results from longitudinal studies have been inconsistent. The 25(OH)D threshold for physical performance and strength was determined, and both cross-sectional and longitudinal associations between 25(OH)D and physical performance and strength were examined, in men and women aged &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">71-80 years&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> from the Health, Aging, and Body Composition Study (n = 2,641). Baseline serum 25(OH)D was measured in 1998-1999, and physical performance and strength were measured at baseline and at 2- and 4-year follow-up. Piecewise regression models were used to determine 25(OH)D thresholds. Linear regression and mixed models were used to examine cross-sectional and longitudinal associations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Frailty and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/frailty-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/frailty-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="-4-of-us-elderly-who-have-had-3-fragility-fractures-are-prescribed-to-take-vitamin-d---march-2024">&amp;lt; 4% of US elderly who have had 3 fragility fractures are prescribed to take Vitamin D - March 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Forgetting the Frail: National Trends in Vitamin D Prescription After Fragility Fracture-A Large Insurance Claims Database Study&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Am Acad Orthop &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5435/JAAOS-D-23-00932">doi: 10.5435/JAAOS-D-23-00932&lt;/a> PDF behind paywall 39 references online&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Suspect that prescriptions of 800 IU (RDA for seniors) were found to not help, so doctors have given up prescribing&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-elderly-have-a-higher-risk-of-frailty-etc-if-low-vitamin-d---jan-2024">The elderly have a higher risk of Frailty, etc. if low vitamin D - Jan 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D insufficiency and disease risk in the elderly&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Good news: Australian clinical trial for vitamin D, bad news: used a max of 2000 IU</title><link>/posts/good-news-australian-clinical-trial-for-vitamin-d-bad-news-used-a-max-of-2000-iu.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/good-news-australian-clinical-trial-for-vitamin-d-bad-news-used-a-max-of-2000-iu.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="recruitment-and-results-of-a-pilot-trial-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-the-general-population-of-australia">Recruitment and Results of a Pilot Trial of Vitamin D Supplementation in the General Population of Australia&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism October 12, 2012 jc.2012-2682&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bich Tran, Bruce K. Armstrong, John B. Carlin, Peter R. Ebeling, Dallas R. English, Michael G. Kimlin, Bayzidur Rahman, Jolieke C. van der Pols, Alison Venn, Val Gebski, David C. Whiteman, Penelope M. Webb and Rachel E. Neale&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Population Health Division! (B.T., J.C.v.d.P., D.C.W., P.M.W., R.E.N.), Queensland Institute of Medical Research, Brisbane, Queensland 4006, Australia; Sydney School of Public Health (B.K.A.) and National Health and Medical Research Council Clinical Trials Centre (V.G.), Sydney Medical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales 2006, Australia; School of Population Health (J.B.C., D.R.E.), University of Melbourne, and University of Melbourne and Western Health (P.R.E.), Parkville, Victoria 3010, Australia; Centre for Research Excellence in Sun and Health (B.T., M.G.K., D.C.W., R.E.N.) and AusSun Research Laboratory (M.G.K.), Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Queensland 4001, Australia; The School of Public Health and Community Medicine (B.R.), The University of New South Wales, Kensington, New South Wales 2052, Australia; and Menzies Research Institute Tasmania (A.V.), Hobart, Tasmania 7000, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>80 year olds had better cognition and stood better if high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/80-year-olds-had-better-cognition-and-stood-better-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/80-year-olds-had-better-cognition-and-stood-better-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-physical-and-cognitive-performance-in-older-people-with-chronic-conditions">25-hydroxyvitamin D and physical and cognitive performance in older people with chronic conditions.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pol Arch Med Wewn. 2012;122(4):162-9. Epub 2012 Feb 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skalska A, Ga?a? A, Grodzicki T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine and Gerontology, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Kraków, Poland. &lt;a href="mailto:anskal@su.krakow.pl">anskal@su.krakow.pl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and various pathologies as well as functional decline has been reported.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of the study was to assess the relationship between 25-hydroxyvitamin D, 25(OH)D, levels and functional status in elderly patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loss of muscle strength –sarcopenia – one of the suspects is vitamin D</title><link>/posts/loss-of-muscle-strength-sarcopenia-one-of-the-suspects-is-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/loss-of-muscle-strength-sarcopenia-one-of-the-suspects-is-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="sarcopenia-pharmacology-today-and-tomorrow">Sarcopenia: Pharmacology today and tomorrow&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Pharocology and Experimental Theraputics August 28, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marco P Brotto &lt;a href="mailto:brottom@umkc.edu">brottom@umkc.edu&lt;/a>, and Eduardo L Abreu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Missouri-Kansas City&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarcopenia remains largely undiagnosed and undertreated, because of the lack of a universally accepted definition, effective ways to measure it, and identification of the outcomes that should guide treatment efficacy. An ever growing number of clinicians and researchers along with funding and regulatory agencies have gradually recognized that sarcopenia is a human condition that requires both prevention and treatment. In this &amp;ldquo;Pharmacology in Perspective: article, we briefly reviewed sarcopenia; its common and less known pharmacological treatments, and attempted to define sarcopenia in its broader context, and presented some new ideas for potential future treatment for this devastating condition. ?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>8 weeks of 7000 IU vitamin D was not enough for seniors to improve insulin resistance</title><link>/posts/8-weeks-of-7000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-for-seniors-to-improve-insulin-resistance.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/8-weeks-of-7000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-for-seniors-to-improve-insulin-resistance.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-on-insulin-resistance-in-nursing-home-residents-an-interventional-study">Effects of vitamin D on insulin resistance in nursing home residents: an interventional study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Kaviani M, Abdollahian M, Almasi V, Amini M, Yamini AA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endokrynol Pol. 2012;63(3):191-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Insulin resistance is defined as reduction of insulin-stimulated glucose uptake in skeletal muscles and inadequate suppression of the production of endogenous glucose. The aim of this study was to assess the effect of vitamin D intake on insulin resistance in aged patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blackouts due to low blood pressure associated with 8 nanograms lower vitamin D</title><link>/posts/blackouts-due-to-low-blood-pressure-associated-with-8-nanograms-lower-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blackouts-due-to-low-blood-pressure-associated-with-8-nanograms-lower-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-orthostatic-hypotension">Vitamin D and orthostatic hypotension&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Kevin Gerald McCarroll1,2?, David J. Robinson3, Avril Coughlan4, Martin Healy5, Rose Anne Kenny6 and Conal Cunningham3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Age and Ageing First published online: July 11, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Gerontology, St James&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, James&amp;rsquo;s St, Dublin D8, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Mercers&amp;rsquo;s Institute for Research on Ageing, Hospital 4, Top Floor, St James&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, James&amp;rsquo;s St, Dublin D8, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Gerontology, St James&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Dublin D8, Ireland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors, like everyone else, need vitamin D and should avoid sunburns – 2011</title><link>/posts/seniors-like-everyone-else-need-vitamin-d-and-should-avoid-sunburns-2011.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-like-everyone-else-need-vitamin-d-and-should-avoid-sunburns-2011.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>2X less vitamin D from the sun for seniors</title><link>/posts/2x-less-vitamin-d-from-the-sun-for-seniors.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-less-vitamin-d-from-the-sun-for-seniors.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Intestines do not process active vitamin D as well as you age</title><link>/posts/intestines-do-not-process-active-vitamin-d-as-well-as-you-age.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/intestines-do-not-process-active-vitamin-d-as-well-as-you-age.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="age-related-changes-in-the-response-of-intestinal-cells-to-125oh2-vitamin-d3">AGE-RELATED CHANGES IN THE RESPONSE OF INTESTINAL CELLS TO 1?,25(OH)(2)-VITAMIN D(3).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ageing Res Rev. 2012 Jun 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pardo VG, Boland AR &lt;a href="mailto:aboland@criba.edu.ar">aboland@criba.edu.ar&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departamento de Biología, Bioquímica y Farmacia. Universidad Nacional del Sur. Consejo Nacional de Investigaciones Científicas y Técnicas (CONICET) 8000 Bahía Blanca, Argentina.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The hormonally active form of vitamin D(3), 1?,25(OH)(2)-Vitamin D(3), acts in intestine, its major target tissue, where its actions are of regulatory and developmental importance: regulation of intracellular calcium through modulation of second messengers and activation of mitogenic cascades leading to cell proliferation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epidemic Vitamin D Deficiency in Elderly Care Rehabilitation Facility</title><link>/posts/epidemic-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-elderly-care-rehabilitation-facility.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/epidemic-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-elderly-care-rehabilitation-facility.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="correspondence-and-reply-in-the-pdf-followed-by-the-original-article---span-stylecolor00fboth-pdf-are-attached-to-bottom-of-this-pagespan">correspondence (and reply in the PDF), followed by the original article &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">both PDF are attached to bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="correspondence-letter-to-the-editor-appeal-for-vitamin-d-therapy">Correspondence (letter to the editor): Appeal for Vitamin D Therapy&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2012 May; 109(19): 359.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Pilz, PD Dr. med.,* Andreas Tomaschitz, PD Dr. med.,** Katharina Kienreich, Dr. med.,** Astrid Fahrleitner-Pammer, PD Dr. med.,** and Winfried März, Prof. Dr. med.***&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Schilling reported that most geriatric patients in a rehabilitation facility had severe vitamin D deficiency (1). – {further down this page}&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If you cannot readily get medical treatment, consider Alternative Med such as vitamin D</title><link>/posts/if-you-cannot-readily-get-medical-treatment-consider-alternative-med-such-as-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-you-cannot-readily-get-medical-treatment-consider-alternative-med-such-as-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="having-lots-of-vitamin-d">Having lots of vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>reduces many chronic pains&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>allows the body the heal itself of some diseases&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>reduces the progress of some diseases&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>apparently increases many different “growth factors”, which help in healing&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how-much-is-a-high-level-of-vitamin-d">How much is a high level of vitamin D?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Minimum of 40 nanograms, preferably 50 nanograms and perhaps &amp;gt; 80 nanograms.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-go-about-getting-lots-of-vitamin-d-under-medical-supervision-if-you-can-afford-it">How to go about getting lots of vitamin D (under medical supervision if you can afford it)&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Make sure you are not &lt;a href="/posts/allergic-to-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2433">allergic to vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>take perhaps a single 1,000 IU dose and watch for an allergic reaction in the next few days&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors in North Indian: half have sore bones, 98 pcnt have less than 30 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/seniors-in-north-indian-half-have-sore-bones-98-pcnt-have-less-than-30-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-in-north-indian-half-have-sore-bones-98-pcnt-have-less-than-30-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-in-healthy-indians-aged-50-years-and-above">Vitamin D status in healthy Indians aged 50 years and above.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Assoc Physicians India. 2011 Nov;59:706-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marwaha RK, Tandon N, Garg MK, Kanwar R, Narang A, Sastry A, Saberwal A, Bandra K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Thyroid Research Centre, Institute of Nuclear Medicine and Allied Sciences, Delhi, India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: There is widespread prevalence of vitamin D deficiency from new-born to infancy, childhood and adult male and females (non-pregnant, pregnant and lactating). However, there is limited information of the vitamin D status in elderly Indians.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>600,000 IU vitamin D normalized virtually all seniors in 3 months (Injection better than oral)</title><link>/posts/600000-iu-vitamin-d-normalized-virtually-all-seniors-in-3-months-injection-better-than-oral.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/600000-iu-vitamin-d-normalized-virtually-all-seniors-in-3-months-injection-better-than-oral.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="efficacy-and-safety-of-high-dose-intramuscular-or-oral-cholecalciferol-in-vitamin-d-deficientinsufficient-elderly">Efficacy and safety of high dose intramuscular or oral cholecalciferol in vitamin D deficient/insufficient elderly.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Maturitas. 2012 May 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tellioglu A, Basaran S, Guzel R, Seydaoglu G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Faculty of Medicine, Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Cukurova University, Adana 01330, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: To evaluate and compare the effects and safety of high dose intramuscular (IM) or oral cholecalciferol on 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels, muscle strength and physical performance in vitamin D deficient/insufficient elderly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased growth factors with vitamin D and Vitamin K2</title><link>/posts/increased-growth-factors-with-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k2.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-growth-factors-with-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k2.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="note-wikipedia-igf-1httpenwikipediaorgwikiinsulin-like_growth_factor_120-insulin-like-growth-factor-1">Note: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insulin-like_growth_factor_1%20">Wikipedia IGF-1&lt;/a> Insulin-like growth factor 1&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="email-to-dr-cannell-at-the-vitamin-d-council">Email to Dr. Cannell at the Vitamin D Council&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Dr Cannell, in response your suggestion in your April 30 Vitamin D Newsletter, I have&lt;/p>
&lt;p>had my IGF-1 measured, with a result of 83 ng/ml, reference level of 55-166. I should&lt;/p>
&lt;p>have mentioned that I am a 91.5 year old male in reasonably good health. I have been&lt;/p>
&lt;p>taking vitamin D since I read your article about vitamin D and influenza in an 2007&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mobility Disability 1.9X more likely if had low level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mobility-disability-19x-more-likely-if-had-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mobility-disability-19x-more-likely-if-had-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Half of seniors with pain had low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/half-of-seniors-with-pain-had-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-of-seniors-with-pain-had-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Many Italian seniors garden, have high levels of vitamin D and are healthy</title><link>/posts/many-italian-seniors-garden-have-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-and-are-healthy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-italian-seniors-garden-have-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-and-are-healthy.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Some seniors do not repond to 1600 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/some-seniors-do-not-repond-to-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-seniors-do-not-repond-to-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="half-of-seniors-did-not-respond-to-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-for-a-year">Half of seniors did not respond to 1600 IU of vitamin D daily for a year&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolorf00red-square--reduction-in-serum-levelspan">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">RED square = reduction in serum level&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;2125&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>from slide presentation: &lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-index.php?page_id=2269">https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-index.php?page_id=2269&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="possible-reasons-for-non-response-include-but-are-not-limited-to-the-following">Possible reasons for non-response include, but are not limited to, the following&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Lacking &lt;a href="/posts/co-factors" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1270">co-factors&lt;/a> Magnesium, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=64&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">Surgery or other trauma&lt;/a> during the year decreased vitamin D levels&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/taking-drugs-by-seniors-was-associated-with-about-2-ng-less-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2619">Taking drugs by seniors was associated with about 2 ng less vitamin D – March 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Influenza, seniors and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/influenza-seniors-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/influenza-seniors-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="aging-adults-and-seasonal-influenza-does-the-vitamin-d-status-harm-the-body">Aging Adults and Seasonal Influenza: Does the Vitamin D Status (H)Arm the Body?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Aging Research, Volume 2012 (2012), Article ID 806198, 8 pages, doi:10.1155/2012/806198, Review Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pierre Olivier Lang1,2 and Dimitrios Samaras 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Internal Medicine, Rehabilitation and Geriatrics, Medical School and University Hospitals of Geneva, Hospital of Trois-Chêne, Chemin du Pont-Bochet 3, CH-1226 Thônex-Geneva, Switzerland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Translational Medicine Research Group, Cranfield Health, Cranfield University, Vincent Building, College Road, Cranfield MK430AL, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors with less than 12 ng of vitamin D were not stable</title><link>/posts/seniors-with-less-than-12-ng-of-vitamin-d-were-not-stable.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-with-less-than-12-ng-of-vitamin-d-were-not-stable.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-in-relation-to-postural-stability-in-the-elderly">Vitamin d status in relation to postural stability in the elderly.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Nutr Health Aging. 2012;16(3):270-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boersma D, Demontiero O, Mohtasham Amiri Z, Hassan S, Suarez H, Geisinger D, Suriyaarachchi P, Sharma A, Duque G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G. Duque, Ageing Bone Research Program, Sydney Medical School Nepean, The University of Sydney, PO Box 63 Penrith NSW 2751, Australia, Tel: +61 2 4734 4278; Facsimile: +61 2 4734 2614, Email: &lt;a href="mailto:gustavo.duque@sydney.edu.au">gustavo.duque@sydney.edu.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: Postural instability (PI) is an important risk factor for falls, especially in the frail older population. In this study, we investigated the impact of vitamin D deficiency on PI in a sample of community dwelling older subjects. Our objective was to determine the potential association between vitamin D deficiency and PI in older fallers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5000 IU vitamin D3 added daily to bread raised blood levels to 50 ng – 2009</title><link>/posts/5000-iu-vitamin-d3-added-daily-to-bread-raised-blood-levels-to-50-ng-2009.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5000-iu-vitamin-d3-added-daily-to-bread-raised-blood-levels-to-50-ng-2009.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Encourage your senior parents to take more vitamin D, you will get more inheritance</title><link>/posts/encourage-your-senior-parents-to-take-more-vitamin-d-you-will-get-more-inheritance.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/encourage-your-senior-parents-to-take-more-vitamin-d-you-will-get-more-inheritance.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>German seniors 10 pct less than 7ng, 92 pct less than 30 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/german-seniors-10-pct-less-than-7ng-92-pct-less-than-30-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/german-seniors-10-pct-less-than-7ng-92-pct-less-than-30-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-an-estimate-of-the-situation-in-germany">Vitamin D-insufficiency: An estimate of the situation in Germany&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Volume 4, Issue 1 January/February/March 2012 Dermato Endocrinology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johann Diederich Ringe and Christoph Kipshoven&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D insufficiency is increasingly recognized as an important risk factor in the pathogenesis of falls and fractures and may increase the risk of other diseases. The aim of this study was to obtain information about the vitamin D supply from a representative cohort of the German population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Women very low on vitamin D were 56 percent more likely to die in nursing home</title><link>/posts/women-very-low-on-vitamin-d-were-56-percent-more-likely-to-die-in-nursing-home.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-very-low-on-vitamin-d-were-56-percent-more-likely-to-die-in-nursing-home.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-is-associated-with-increased-mortality-in-female-nursing-home-residents">Low 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Is Associated with Increased Mortality in Female Nursing Home Residents.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012 Feb 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pilz S, Dobnig H, Tomaschitz A, Kienreich K, Meinitzer A, Friedl C, Wagner D, Piswanger-Sölkner C, März W, Fahrleitner-Pammer A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine (S.P., H.D., A.T., K.K., C.P.-S., A.F.-P.), Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism; Clinical Institute of Medical and Chemical Laboratory Diagnostics (A.M., W.M.); Division for Transplantation (C.F.), Department of Surgery; and Department of Internal Medicine (D.W.), Division of Nephrology, Medical University of Graz, 8036 Graz, Austria; Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics and EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research (S.P.), VU University Medical Center, 1081 BT Amsterdam, The Netherlands; Synlab Academy (W.M.), Synlab services LLC, D-68165 Mannheim, Germany; and Mannheim Institute of Public Health (W.M.), Ruperto Carola University Heidelberg, Medical Faculty Mannheim, D-68167 Mannheim, Germany.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Elderly surgical rehab in Germany - 67 pct have less than 10 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/elderly-surgical-rehab-in-germany-67-pct-have-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/elderly-surgical-rehab-in-germany-67-pct-have-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="epidemic-vitamin-d-deficiency-among-patients-in-an-elderly-care-rehabilitation-facility">Epidemic Vitamin D Deficiency Among Patients in an Elderly Care Rehabilitation Facility&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dtsch Arztebl Int 2012; 109(3): 33-8; DOI: 10.3238/arztebl.2012.0033&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schilling, S&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Geriatrische Rehabilitationsklinik St. Irminen, Trier: Dr. med. Schilling&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-seniors-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 28">Overview Seniors and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=64&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">All items in After Surgery or Trauma&lt;/a> 58 items Feb 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1765">Rehab patients vitamin D deficient - with chart Nov 2010.pdf&lt;/a> file&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/icu-needs-vitamin-d-vitamin-d-council">ICU needs vitamin D - Vitamin D Council Sept 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Omega 3 and Exercise are being used in controlled trial to support healthy ageing</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-omega-3-and-exercise-are-being-used-in-controlled-trial-to-support-healthy-ageing.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-omega-3-and-exercise-are-being-used-in-controlled-trial-to-support-healthy-ageing.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nursing home residents 2X more likely to die of some surgeries – perhaps lack vitamin D</title><link>/posts/nursing-home-residents-2x-more-likely-to-die-of-some-surgeries-perhaps-lack-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nursing-home-residents-2x-more-likely-to-die-of-some-surgeries-perhaps-lack-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="major-abdominal-surgery-in-nursing-home-residents-a-national-study">Major Abdominal Surgery in Nursing Home Residents: A National Study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Annals of Surgery: December 2011 - Volume 254 - Issue 6 - p 921–926&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/SLA.0b013e3182383a78">doi: 10.1097/SLA.0b013e3182383a78&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finlayson, Emily MD &lt;a href="mailto:emily.finlayson@ucsfmedctr.org">emily.finlayson@ucsfmedctr.org&lt;/a> &lt;em>,†; Wang, Li PhD‡; Landefeld, C. Seth MD§,¶; Dudley, R. Adams MD†,&lt;/em>*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To determine surgical risk in nursing home residents undergoing major abdominal surgery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Recent studies suggest that surgery can be performed safely in the very old. Surgical risk in nursing home residents is poorly understood.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Even young Caucasians do not get enough time in the sun</title><link>/posts/even-young-caucasians-do-not-get-enough-time-in-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/even-young-caucasians-do-not-get-enough-time-in-the-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="solar-uv-doses-of-adult-americans-and-vitamin-d3-production">Solar UV doses of adult Americans and vitamin D(3) production.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2011 Oct;3(4):243-50. Epub 2011 Oct 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Godar DE, Pope SJ, Grant WB, Holick MF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>US Food and Drug Administration; Center for Devices and Radiological Health; Rockville, MD USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight contains UV radiation that affects human health in both detrimental (skin cancers) and beneficial (vitamin D(3)) ways. An evaluation of the vitamin D status of adult Americans (22-40, 41-59, 60+ yr) show many have deficient or insufficient serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D, indicating they are not getting enough from dietary sources or sunlight. Those findings are in conflict with calculated values from the American Academy of Dermatology who insist people make &amp;ldquo;ample&amp;rdquo; vitamin D(3) (?1,000 IU/day) from their &amp;ldquo;casual,&amp;rdquo; or everyday, outdoor UV exposures even if they use sunscreens with sun protection factor 15.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Long term care – vitamin D most popular supplement</title><link>/posts/long-term-care-vitamin-d-most-popular-supplement.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/long-term-care-vitamin-d-most-popular-supplement.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="use-of-vitamin-and-mineral-supplements-in-long-term-care-home-residents">Use of vitamin and mineral supplements in long-term care home residents.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2012 Jan 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Viveky N, Toffelmire L, Thorpe L, Billinsky J, Alcorn J, Hadjistavropoulos T, Whiting SJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a College of Pharmacy and Nutrition, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK S7N 5C9, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin-mineral supplementation may offer older adults health and cognition-related benefits but overuse may contribute to polypharmacy. We examined the prevalence of supplement usage in long-term care facility (LTC) residents (?65 years of age). As cognition may be affected by nutrition, we also examined use in those with diagnosis of dementia and those with no dementia diagnosis. The prevalence of supplement usage and overall &amp;ldquo;pill count&amp;rdquo; from pharmaceutical use was assessed in 189 LTC residents and a subsample of 56 older adults with dementia diagnosis, respectively. Participants were residing in an LTC facility of a mid-size metropolitan area during 2009.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Allergic diseases in the elderly</title><link>/posts/allergic-diseases-in-the-elderly.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/allergic-diseases-in-the-elderly.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Victoria Cardona 1,2*, Mar Guilarte 1,2, Olga Luengo 1,2, Moises Labrador-Horrillo 1,2, Anna Sala-Cunill 1,2 and Teresa Garriga 1&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Corresponding author: Victoria Cardona &lt;a href="mailto:vcardona@comb.cat">vcardona@comb.cat&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>1 Allergy Section, Department of Internal Medicine, Hospital Universitari Vall d&amp;rsquo;Hebron, Barcelona, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Allergy Research Unit, Institut de Recerca Vall d&amp;rsquo;Hebron, Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical and Translational Allergy 2011, 1:11 doi:10.1186/2045-7022-1-11&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received:	22 August 2011; Accepted:	17 October 2011; Published:	17 October 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-page">PDF is attached at bottom of page&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Demographic distribution of the population is progressively changing with the proportion of elderly persons increasing in most societies. This entails that there is a need to evaluate the impact of common diseases, such as asthma and other allergic conditions, in this age segment. Frailty, comorbidities and polymedication are some of the factors that condition management in geriatric patients. The objective of this review is to highlight the characteristics of allergic diseases in older age groups, from the influence of immunosenescence, to particular clinical implications and management issues, such as drug interactions or age-related side effects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For seniors: taking drugs was associated with about 2 ng less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/for-seniors-taking-drugs-was-associated-with-about-2-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/for-seniors-taking-drugs-was-associated-with-about-2-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-impact-of-medication-on-vitamin-d-status-in-older-individuals">The impact of medication on vitamin D status in older individuals.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eur J Endocrinol. 2011 Dec 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sohl E, van Schoor N, De Jongh R, de Vries OJ, Lips P. &lt;a href="mailto:p.lips@vumc.nl">p.lips@vumc.nl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E Sohl, Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, VU University Medical Center, EMGO institute, Amsterdam, Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Vitamin D deficiency and polypharmacy are common in the elderly. However, knowledge on the associations between the use of specific medicines and serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) is limited. The aim of this study was to (better) define the associations between the use of specific medicines and serum 25(OH)D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breathing by seniors harder when have low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/breathing-by-seniors-harder-when-have-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breathing-by-seniors-harder-when-have-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-pulmonary-function-in-older-disabled-community-dwelling-women">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Pulmonary Function in Older Disabled Community-Dwelling Women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2011 Dec 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Semba RD, Chang SS, Sun K, Cappola AR, Ferrucci L, Fried LP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Smith Building, M015, 400 North Broadway, Baltimore, MD 21287. &lt;a href="mailto:rdsemba@jhmi.edu">rdsemba@jhmi.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent studies have expanded the functions of vitamin D to a possible role in pulmonary function.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our objective was to examine the relationship between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D), serum parathyroid hormone, and pulmonary function in older women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and falls – editorial</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-falls-editorial.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-falls-editorial.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-falls-theres-smoke-but-is-there-fire">Vitamin D deficiency and falls: There&amp;rsquo;s smoke, but is there fire?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Joseph H. Friedman, MD &lt;a href="mailto:joseph_friedman@brown.edu">joseph_friedman@brown.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Department of Neurology, Alpert Medical School of Brown University, Providence, RI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neurology. 2011 May 10;76(19):1612-3. Epub 2011 Apr 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Houston Merritt, MD, used to say that when one medicine was used in a wide variety of different diseases, it probably did not work for any of them. It is hard not to be equally skeptical about the importance of vitamin D in nonskeletal disorders when it is imputed to be helpful not only for bone-specific diseases such as rickets and osteomalacia, which are associated with vitamin D deficiency, but for diverse syndromes, such as falling, weakness, or cancer, which are themselves of diverse origins.1,–,4 Compounding this skepticism are the numbers of studies and meta-analyses producing conflicting results on the benefits of supplementing vitamin D and calcium in deficient and nondeficient people.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D workshop for seniors - images</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-workshop-for-seniors-images.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-workshop-for-seniors-images.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction-to-vitamin-d-for-seniors-living-far-from-the-equator">Introduction to Vitamin D for Seniors living far from the equator&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpostsclick-here-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1912click-herea-for-text-qa-links-etc-as-well-as-the-images-below">&lt;a href="/posts/click-here" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1912">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for text, Q&amp;amp;A, links, etc. as well as the images below&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The following images are from the workshop: which can be shown on a projector or Flat Screen display&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can use these images for your own vitamin D Workshop by saving the page as HTML&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=2007]&lt;/span> for Images from a zip of such a HTML directory&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fraser Health in Canada will be giving 20000 IU vitamin D weekly to reduce falls</title><link>/posts/fraser-health-in-canada-will-be-giving-20000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-to-reduce-falls.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fraser-health-in-canada-will-be-giving-20000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-to-reduce-falls.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="news-releasehttpwwwfraserhealthcaabout_usmedia_centrenews_releases2011_news_releasesnew_vitamin_d_protocol_helps_prevent_falls_and_fractures_in_residential_care">&lt;a href="http://www.fraserhealth.ca/about_us/media_centre/news_releases/2011_news_releases/new_vitamin_d_protocol_helps_prevent_falls_and_fractures_in_residential_care">News Release&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Optional for all Fraser Health 7,500 senior residents in Western Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cost per year to Fraser Health of providing the vitamin D is estimated to about that of the cost of a single hip fracture , $20,000&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before vitamin D they had 1,000 to 1,500 falls per year&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They hope to prevent 10% to 25% of the falls per year&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus they hope to prevent 100 to about 300 falls per year&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mood disorders 11X worse for older adults with low vitamin D – 2006</title><link>/posts/mood-disorders-11x-worse-for-older-adults-with-low-vitamin-d-2006.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mood-disorders-11x-worse-for-older-adults-with-low-vitamin-d-2006.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-low-mood-and-worse-cognitive-performance-in-older-adults">Vitamin D Deficiency Is Associated With Low Mood and Worse Cognitive Performance in Older Adults&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>American Journal of Geriatric Psychiatry: December 2006 - Volume 14 - Issue 12 - pp 1032-1040&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wilkins, Consuelo H. M.D.; Sheline, Yvette I. M.D.; Roe, Catherine M. Ph.D.; Birge, Stanley J. M.D.; Morris, John C. M.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency is common in older adults and has been implicated in psychiatric and neurologic disorders. This study examined the relationship among vitamin D status, cognitive performance, mood, and physical performance in older adults.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Senior women more physically able if vitamin D higher than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/senior-women-more-physically-able-if-vitamin-d-higher-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/senior-women-more-physically-able-if-vitamin-d-higher-than-30-ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>\"Sunlight Officers\" in some Australian senior facilities</title><link>/posts/sunlight-officers-in-some-australian-senior-facilities.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunlight-officers-in-some-australian-senior-facilities.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="factors-influencing-adherence-with-therapeutic-sunlight-exposure-in-older-people-in-intermediate-care-facilities">Factors influencing adherence with therapeutic sunlight exposure in older people in intermediate care facilities.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2011 Sep 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Durvasula S, Sambrook PN, Cameron ID.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sydney Medical School, University of Sydney, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose of research: The purpose of this study was to investigate the factors influencing low adherence with therapeutic sunlight exposure in a randomized controlled trial conducted with older people living in intermediate care facilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Materials and methods: The study involved participants in the FREEDOM (Falls Risk Epidemiology: Effect of vitamin D on skeletal Outcomes and other Measures) study, a randomized controlled trial of therapeutic sun exposure to reduce falls in older people in intermediate care facilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors Vitamin D Workshop</title><link>/posts/seniors-vitamin-d-workshop.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-vitamin-d-workshop.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction-to-vitamin-d-for-seniors-living-far-from-the-equator">Introduction to Vitamin D for Seniors living far from the equator&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This is an enhanced transcript of the 1 hour workshop held by Henry Lahore Sept, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This page provides an linear read of the importance of vitamin D and has many hyperlinks to details/supportive information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It can be read or printed out in 30 portrait pages in any of 64 languages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>     To have Google translate the text just touch the down-arrow{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;733&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;140&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}in the upper right.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Severe chronic disease associated with less than 10 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/severe-chronic-disease-associated-with-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/severe-chronic-disease-associated-with-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-geriatric-inpatients-a-marker-of-severity-of-chronic-diseases">Hypovitaminosis D in geriatric inpatients: a marker of severity of chronic diseases.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Aging Clin Exp Res. 2011 Jul 5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beauchet O, Hélard L, Montero-Odasso M, de Decker L, Berrut G, Annweiler C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine and Geriatrics, Angers University Hospital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and aims. Hypovitaminosis D is associated with adverse health outcomes including several bone and non-bone chronic diseases. It remains unclear whether hypovitaminosis D leads to more numerous or more severe chronic diseases. Our objective was to determine whether there was an association between the serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D deficiency (i.e., 25OHD -25nmol/L) and, respectively, the number and the severity of chronic diseases assessed with the &lt;strong>Kaplan-Feinstein index (KFI)&lt;/strong> among geriatric inpatients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half of the seniors needed more than 1700 IU vitamin D3 (50000 monthly)</title><link>/posts/half-of-the-seniors-needed-more-than-1700-iu-vitamin-d3-50000-monthly.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-of-the-seniors-needed-more-than-1700-iu-vitamin-d3-50000-monthly.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Elderly taking extra vitamin D should expect fewer falls AND less flu</title><link>/posts/elderly-taking-extra-vitamin-d-should-expect-fewer-falls-and-less-flu.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/elderly-taking-extra-vitamin-d-should-expect-fewer-falls-and-less-flu.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="preventing-two-birds-with-one-stone-improving-vitamin-d-levels-in-the-elderly">(Preventing) two birds with one stone: improving vitamin d levels in the elderly.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Prim Health Care. 2011 Jun 1;3(2):150-2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lawless S, White P, Murdoch P, Leitch S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amity Health Centre, 343 Highgate, Roslyn, Dunedin 9010, New Zealand. &lt;a href="mailto:susie@amityhc.co.nz">susie@amityhc.co.nz&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND CONTEXT: A majority of adults have sub-optimal vitamin D levels in the winter in southern New Zealand. This is associated with an increased risk of falls and fragility fractures in the elderly, with long-term adverse outcomes likely. Vitamin D supplementation decreases the risks of both falls and fractures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How elderly do not have to remember to take vitamin D</title><link>/posts/how-elderly-do-not-have-to-remember-to-take-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-elderly-do-not-have-to-remember-to-take-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="preventing-two-birds-with-one-stone-improving-vitamin-d-levels-in-the-elderly">(Preventing) two birds with one stone: improving vitamin d levels in the elderly.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Prim Health Care. 2011 Jun 1;3(2):150-2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lawless S, White P, Murdoch P, Leitch S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amity Health Centre, 343 Highgate, Roslyn, Dunedin 9010, New Zealand. &lt;a href="mailto:susie@amityhc.co.nz">susie@amityhc.co.nz&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND CONTEXT: A majority of adults have sub-optimal vitamin D levels in the winter in southern New Zealand. This is associated with an increased risk of falls and fragility fractures in the elderly, with long-term adverse outcomes likely. Vitamin D supplementation decreases the risks of both falls and fractures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors with more than 30ng of vitamin D walked better</title><link>/posts/seniors-with-more-than-30ng-of-vitamin-d-walked-better.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-with-more-than-30ng-of-vitamin-d-walked-better.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="biology-of-gait-control-vitamin-d-involvement">Biology of gait control: Vitamin D involvement.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Neurology. 2011 May 10;76(19):1617-22. Epub 2011 Apr 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beauchet O, Annweiler C, Verghese J, Fantino B, Herrmann FR, Allali G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine and Geriatrics, Angers University Hospitals, 49933 Angers cedex 9, France &lt;a href="mailto:olbeauchet@chu-angers.fr">olbeauchet@chu-angers.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adverse neuromuscular events have been described in case of low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) concentrations, suggesting that vitamin D may be involved in gait stability. The objective of this cross-sectional study was to examine the association between stride-to-stride variability of stride time (STV) and serum 25OHD concentration in adults aged 65 years and older.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D may help prevent macular degeneration in women younger than 75</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-may-help-prevent-macular-degeneration-in-women-younger-than-75.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-may-help-prevent-macular-degeneration-in-women-younger-than-75.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-and-early-age-related-macular-degeneration-in-postmenopausal-women">Vitamin D Status and Early Age-Related Macular Degeneration in Postmenopausal Women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arch Ophthalmol. 2011 Apr;129(4):481-489.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Millen AE, Voland R, Sondel SA, Parekh N, Horst RL, Wallace RB, Hageman GS, Chappell R, Blodi BA, Klein ML, Gehrs KM, Sarto GE, Mares JA; for the CAREDS Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Social and Preventive Medicine, University at Buffalo, Ferber Hall 240, Buffalo, NY 14214. &lt;a href="mailto:aemillen@buffal.edu">aemillen@buffal.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) concentrations (nmol/L) and the prevalence of early age-related macular degeneration (AMD) was investigated in participants of the Carotenoids in Age-Related Eye Disease Study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors with more than 20 ng of vitamin D were 14 percent stronger</title><link>/posts/seniors-with-more-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-were-14-percent-stronger.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-with-more-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-were-14-percent-stronger.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-nutritional-status-on-muscle-function-and-strength-in-healthy-women-aged-over-sixty-five-years">Effect of Vitamin D Nutritional Status on Muscle Function and Strength in Healthy Women Aged over Sixty-Five Years.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Nutr Health Aging. 2011;15(5):349-54.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mastaglia SR, Seijo M, Muzio D, Somoza J, Nuñez M, Oliveri B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S.R. Mastaglia, Av. Cordoba 2351(1120), Tel/Fax: 541159508972, Buenos Aires- Argentina, &lt;a href="mailto:Silvinamastaglia@hotmail.com">Silvinamastaglia@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D insufficiency is common in elderly adults, and leads to secondary hyperparathyroidism, bone loss, muscle weakness, and osteoporotic fractures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To evaluate the relation between vitamin D nutritional status and muscle function and muscle strength in women aged over 65 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300,000 IU vitamin D helped seniors in many ways</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-vitamin-d-helped-seniors-in-many-ways.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-vitamin-d-helped-seniors-in-many-ways.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-effect-of-oral-and-parenteral-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-the-elderly-a-prospective-double-blinded-randomized-placebo-controlled-study">The effect of oral and parenteral vitamin D supplementation in the elderly: a prospective, double-blinded, randomized, placebo-controlled study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Rheumatology International DOI: 10.1007/s00296-011-1943-6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hakan Sakalli, Didem Arslan and Ahmet Eftal Yucel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypovitaminosis D in the elderly causes falls and fractures as a result of impaired neuromuscular functions and also may be a reason for nonspecific musculosceletal pain. The aim of this study is to investigate the benefits of a single dose per os or parenterally administrated vitamin D on increasing the quality of life and functional mobility and decreasing the pain in the elderly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>70 year-olds got T2 Diabetes 2X more often when less than 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/70-year-olds-got-t2-diabetes-2x-more-often-when-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/70-year-olds-got-t2-diabetes-2x-more-often-when-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-in-relation-to-glucose-metabolism-and-type-2-diabetes-in-septuagenarians">Vitamin D Status in Relation to Glucose Metabolism and Type 2 Diabetes in Septuagenarians&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Christine Dalgård, PHD1 – &lt;a href="mailto:cdalgaard@health.sdu.dk">cdalgaard@health.sdu.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maria Skaalum Petersen, PHD2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pal Weihe, MD1,2 and Philippe Grandjean, DMSC1,3 Diabetes Care&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Institute of Public Health, Department of Environmental Medicine, University of Southern Denmark, JB Winslowsvej, Odense C, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Occupational Medicine and Public Health, Faroese Hospital System, Tórshavn, Faroe Islands, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Environmental Health, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, Massachusetts&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Controversy: Too much Calcium if increase Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/controversy-too-much-calcium-if-increase-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/controversy-too-much-calcium-if-increase-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#50-percent-of-elderly-got-hypercalcimia-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d--feb-2011">50 percent of elderly got hypercalcimia with 2000 IU of vitamin D – Feb 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="50-percent-of-elderly-got-hypercalcimia-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d--feb-2011">50 percent of elderly got hypercalcimia with 2000 IU of vitamin D – Feb 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Evaluation of the effectiveness of cholecalciferol in long-term care elderly patients with hypovitaminosis d.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consult Pharm. 2011 Feb;26(2):101-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shin M, Minden C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sullivan University College of Pharmacy, Louisville, Kentucky.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To study the efficacy and safety of cholecalciferol &lt;strong>(vitamin D3) 2,000 units&lt;/strong> daily for 12 weeks in elderly patients with hypovitaminosis D. Secondarily, to postulate causes for those patients who did not return to normal 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25-OHD) levels.Design: One-group, pretest post-test. Retrospective chart review. Data collected from Computerized Patient Record System.Setting: Long-term care facility at Central Arkansas Veterans Healthcare System.Patients, Participants: Potential study subjects were elderly patients (? 65 years of age) treated with total daily dose of cholecalciferol 2,000 units daily by mouth, for at least 12 weeks&amp;rsquo; duration period between July 1, 2007, and July 31, 2009, with documented 25-OHD levels before and after treatment.Interventions: None.Main Outcome Measures: Efficacy of cholecalciferol was assessed by categorizing patients as responders (25-OHD levels ? 30 ng/mL) and nonresponders (25-OHD levels &amp;lt; 30 ng/mL).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D associated with all-cause mortality and frailty</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-all-cause-mortality-and-frailty.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-all-cause-mortality-and-frailty.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-aging-beyond-calcium-and-bone-metabolism">Vitamin D and aging: Beyond calcium and bone metabolism&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Faustino R. Pérez-López&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Universidad de Zaragoza, Facultad de Medicina, Hospital Clínico, Zaragoza 50009, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 4 February 2011; accepted 9 February 2011. published online 08 March 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maturitas; European Menopause Journal&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels are common and may be associated with morbidity and mortality (and indeed with frailty more generally). This association is not restricted to the links between vitamin D and calcium and bone metabolism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors who increased vitamin D got more physical exercise</title><link>/posts/seniors-who-increased-vitamin-d-got-more-physical-exercise.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-who-increased-vitamin-d-got-more-physical-exercise.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="change-in-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-physical-performance-in-older-adults">Change in 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Physical Performance in Older Adults.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2011 Feb 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Change in 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Physical Performance in Older Adults.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Houston DK, Tooze JA, Hausman DB, Johnson MA, Nicklas BJ, Miller ME, Neiberg RH, Marsh AP, Newman AB, Blair SN, Kritchevsky SB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Salem, NC&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D deficiency is common among older adults and is associated with poor physical performance; however, studies examining longitudinal changes in 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) and physical performance are lacking. We examined the association between 25(OH)D and physical performance over 12 months in older adults participating in the &lt;strong>Lifestyle Interventions&lt;/strong> and Independence for Elders Pilot (LIFE-P), a multicenter physical activity intervention trial.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU vitamin D was safe and helped elderly</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d-was-safe-and-helped-elderly.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d-was-safe-and-helped-elderly.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-response-of-elderly-veterans-to-daily-vitamin-d3-supplementation-of-2000-iu-a-pilot-efficacy-study">The Response of Elderly Veterans to Daily Vitamin D3 Supplementation of 2,000? IU: A Pilot Efficacy Study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Am Geriatr Soc. 2011 Feb 2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03242.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03242.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cherniack EP, Florez HJ, Hollis BW, Roos BA, Troen BR, Levis S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the *Geriatrics Institute, Division of Gerontology and Geriatric Medicine, Department of Medicine, University of Miami Miller School of Medicine, Miami, Florida; †Geriatric Research, Education, and Clinical Center and Research Service, Bruce W. Carter Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Miami, Florida; ‡Department of Pediatrics, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina; and §Stein Gerontological Institute, Miami Jewish Health Systems, Miami, Florida.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pneumonia and low vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/pneumonia-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pneumonia-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pneumonia Risk, intensity, and mortality are all associated with low vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#6-of-85-pneumonia-and-vitamin-d-publications-pubmed--april-2025httpspubmedncbinlmnihgovterm28pneumonia5btitle5d29and2822vitamind225btitle5d29sortrelevance">6 of 85 Pneumonia and Vitamin D publications &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%28Pneumonia%5BTitle%5D%29+AND+%28%22vitamin+d%22%5BTitle%5D%29&amp;amp;sort=relevance">PubMed- April 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#future-childhood-pneumonia-cut-in-half-by-300000-iu-of-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-oct-2020">Future childhood pneumonia cut in half by 300,000 IU of Vitamin D - meta-analysis Oct 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pneumonia-elderly-death-12x-more-likely-when-vitamin-d-less-than-12-ng--2011">Pneumonia elderly death 12X more likely when vitamin D less than 12 ng – 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-bacteria-pneumonia-causality-ignores-the-vitamin-d-receptor---march-2021">Vitamin D and bacteria pneumonia causality (ignores the Vitamin D Receptor) - March 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#type-of-pneumonia-viral-bacterial-fungal">Type of Pneumonia: viral, bacterial, fungal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#high-dose-vitamin-d-reduces-recurrent-pneumonia-by-half---meta-analysis-oct-2020">High-dose Vitamin D reduces recurrent pneumonia by half - meta-analysis Oct 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pneumonia-problems-in-china-might-by-treated-by-vitamin-a---dr-campbell-videos">Pneumonia problems in China might by treated by Vitamin A - Dr. Campbell Videos&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="6-of-85-pneumonia-and-vitamin-d-publications-pubmed--april-2025httpspubmedncbinlmnihgovterm28pneumonia5btitle5d29and2822vitamind225btitle5d29sortrelevance">6 of 85 Pneumonia and Vitamin D publications &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%28Pneumonia%5BTitle%5D%29+AND+%28%22vitamin+d%22%5BTitle%5D%29&amp;amp;sort=relevance">PubMed- April 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cost-effectiveness of high-dose vitamin D supplementation to reduce the occurrence of repeat episodes of pneumonia in children Nov 2024 &lt;a href="https://10.1186/s12962-024-00589-2">FREE PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anemia associated with lower than 20 ng vitamin D among elderly</title><link>/posts/anemia-associated-with-lower-than-20-ng-vitamin-d-among-elderly.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/anemia-associated-with-lower-than-20-ng-vitamin-d-among-elderly.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-deficiency-in-subgroups-of-elderly-persons-with-anemia-association-with-anemia-of-inflammation">Prevalence of 25-hydroxyvitamin D deficiency in subgroups of elderly persons with anemia: association with anemia of inflammation.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Blood. 2011 Jan 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perlstein TS, Pande R, Berliner N, Vanasse GJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anemia and vitamin D deficiency are conditions that both result in significant morbidity and increase with age. The potential relationship between them remains poorly understood, particularly in the elderly. We utilized the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES III) to examine the association of vitamin D deficiency with anemia subtypes in individuals aged &amp;gt; 60 years. Vitamin D deficiency was defined as serum levels &lt;strong>&amp;lt; 20 ng/mL&lt;/strong> and anemia was defined according to World Health Organization criteria.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Weekly UV almost doubled elderly Vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/weekly-uv-almost-doubled-elderly-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/weekly-uv-almost-doubled-elderly-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Overview Fractures and Falls and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-fractures-and-falls-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-fractures-and-falls-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="8-of-hospitalisations--for-falls-and-hip-fractures-in-australia-were-attributable-to-vitamin-d-deficiency-20-ng">8% of hospitalisations for falls and hip fractures in Australia were attributable to vitamin D deficiency (&amp;lt;20 ng)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hospitalisations for falls and hip fractures attributable to vitamin D deficiency in older Australians - Jan 2021&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0007114521000416">doi: 10.1017/S0007114521000416&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h5 id="it-has-been-known-since-year-2000-that-nerve-conduction-velocity-speeds-up-with-increased-vitamin-d---see-following-graph">It has been known since year 2000 that nerve conduction velocity speeds up with increased vitamin D - see following graph&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;420&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="juventhttpwwwjuventcomhealth-micro-impact-platform---3500---nov-2017">&lt;a href="http://www.juvent.com/health/">Juvent&lt;/a> Micro-Impact Platform - $3,500 - Nov 2017&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Computer and software find the resonant frequency of the user in a safe range of frequencies (32Hz-37Hz) and therefore is able to use a very small level of energy (.3g) to deliver a physiologically effective energy pulse.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of vitamin D may result in elderly physical decline</title><link>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-may-result-in-elderly-physical-decline.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-may-result-in-elderly-physical-decline.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-hormone-a-multitude-of-actions-potentially-influencing-the-physical-function-decline-in-older-persons">Vitamin D hormone: A multitude of actions potentially influencing the physical function decline in older persons.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2010 Dec 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1447-0594.2010.00668.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1447-0594.2010.00668.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cesari M, Incalzi RA, Zamboni V, Pahor M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Geriatric Medicine Unit, Campus Bio-Medico University &amp;ldquo;Sacro Cuore&amp;rdquo; Hospice, Rome, Italy Department of Aging and Geriatric Research, University of Florida - Institute on Aging, Gainesville, Florida, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D, a secosteroid (pro)-hormone, has been traditionally considered as a key regulator of bone metabolism, and calcium and phosphorous homeostasis through a negative feedback with the parathyroid hormone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Frailty and vitamin D – U shaped curve</title><link>/posts/frailty-and-vitamin-d-u-shaped-curve.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/frailty-and-vitamin-d-u-shaped-curve.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-frailty-status-in-older-women">Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels and Frailty Status in Older Women.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2010 Dec;95(12):5266-5273.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ensrud KE, Ewing SK, Fredman L, Hochberg MC, Cauley JA, Hillier TA, Cummings SR, Yaffe K, Cawthon PM; for the Study of Osteoporotic Fractures Research Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M.P.H., One Veterans Drive (111-0), Minneapolis, Minnesota 55417. &lt;a href="mailto:ensru001@umn.edu">ensru001@umn.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Context: Vitamin D deficiency and frailty are common with aging, but the association between these conditions is uncertain. Objective: To determine the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels and prevalent and incident frailty status among older women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Just 700 IU of vitamin D and 700 mg of Calcium reduces falls and fractures</title><link>/posts/just-700-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-700-mg-of-calcium-reduces-falls-and-fractures.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/just-700-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-700-mg-of-calcium-reduces-falls-and-fractures.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="optimal-use-of-vitamin-d-when-treating-osteoporosis">Optimal Use of Vitamin D When Treating Osteoporosis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Osteoporos Rep. 2010 Nov 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van den Bergh JP, Bours SP, van Geel TA, Geusens PP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, VieCuri Medical Centre Noord-Limburg, P.O. Box 1926, 5900 BX, Venlo, The Netherlands, &lt;a href="mailto:jvdbergh@hetnet.nl">jvdbergh@hetnet.nl&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inadequate serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) concentrations are associated with muscle weakness, decreased physical performance, and increased propensity in falls and fractures. This paper discusses several aspects with regard to vitamin D status and supplementation when treating patients with osteoporosis in relation to risks and prevention of falls and fractures. Based on evidence from literature, adequate supplementation with at least &lt;strong>700 IU&lt;/strong> of vitamin D, preferably cholecalciferol, is required for improving physical function and prevention of falls and fractures. Additional calcium supplementation may be considered when dietary &lt;strong>calcium intake is below 700 mg/day&lt;/strong> . For optimal bone mineral density response in patients treated with antiresorptive or anabolic therapy, adequate vitamin D and calcium supplementation is also necessary. Monitoring of 25(OH)D levels during follow-up and adjustment of vitamin D supplementation should be considered to reach and maintain adequate serum 25(OH)D levels of at least 50 nmol/L, preferably greater than 75 nmol/L in all patients. PMID: 21113692&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 intervention increased elderly muscle strength</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-intervention-increased-elderly-muscle-strength.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-intervention-increased-elderly-muscle-strength.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-randomized-controlled-trial-of-the-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-muscle-strength-and-mobility-in-older-women-with-vitamin-d-insufficiency">A Randomized Controlled Trial of the Effects of Vitamin D on Muscle Strength and Mobility in Older Women with Vitamin D Insufficiency&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kun Zhu PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Nicole Austin PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Amanda Devine PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>David Bruce MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Richard L. Prince MD&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Article first published online: 4 NOV 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03142.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2010, Copyright the Authors. Journal compilation © 2010, The American Geriatrics Society&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 58, Issue 11, pages 2063–2068, November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhu, K., Austin, N., Devine, A., Bruce, D. and Prince, R. L. (2010), A Randomized Controlled Trial of the Effects of Vitamin D on Muscle Strength and Mobility in Older Women with Vitamin D Insufficiency. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society, 58: 2063–2068. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03142.x">doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03142.x&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D in elderly Irish with 800 IU did not vary with season</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-in-elderly-irish-with-800-iu-did-not-vary-with-season.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-in-elderly-irish-with-800-iu-did-not-vary-with-season.html</guid><description>&lt;p>– – – – – – Summary - - - - - -&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="supplemented-group-800-iu-had-26-ngml">Supplemented group (800 IU) had 26 ng/ml;&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="non-supplemented-group-had-seasonal-peak-of-184-down-to-seasonal-minimum-of-136-ng">Non-supplemented group had seasonal peak of 18.4 down to seasonal minimum of 13.6 ng&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="seasonal-variation-of-serum-vitamin-d-and-the-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-irish-community-dwelling-older-people">Seasonal variation of serum vitamin D and the effect of vitamin D supplementation in Irish community-dwelling older people.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Age Ageing. 2010 Nov 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Romero-Ortuno R, Cogan L, Browne J, Healy M, Casey MC, Cunningham C, Walsh JB, Kenny RA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Elderly low on vitamin D were 2X more likely to die</title><link>/posts/elderly-low-on-vitamin-d-were-2x-more-likely-to-die.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/elderly-low-on-vitamin-d-were-2x-more-likely-to-die.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D with the risk of death in a general older population in Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jyrki K. Virtanen, Tarja Nurmi, Sari Voutilainen, Jaakko Mursu and Tomi-Pekka Tuomainen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>European Journal of Nutrition&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentration, a marker of vitamin D status, and risk of all-cause and cardiovascular mortality in a general older population with relatively low average serum 25(OH)D concentrations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>