<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rheumatoid Arthritis on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/rheumatoid-arthritis.html</link><description>Recent content in Rheumatoid Arthritis on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/rheumatoid-arthritis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Just 500 IU of vitamin D helped reduce rheumatoid arthritis pain - RCT</title><link>/posts/just-500-iu-of-vitamin-d-helped-reduce-rheumatoid-arthritis-pain-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/just-500-iu-of-vitamin-d-helped-reduce-rheumatoid-arthritis-pain-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency and diabetes – rheumatoid arthritis – lupus</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-and-diabetes-rheumatoid-arthritis-lupus.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-and-diabetes-rheumatoid-arthritis-lupus.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="disease-specific-definitions-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-need-to-be-established-in-autoimmune-and-non-autoimmune-chronic-diseases-a-retrospective-comparison-of-three-chronic-diseases">Disease-specific definitions of vitamin D deficiency need to be established in autoimmune and non-autoimmune chronic diseases: a retrospective comparison of three chronic diseases&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arthritis Res Ther. 2010; 12(5): R191. 10.1186/ar3161&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anna R Broder, corresponding author1 Jonathan N Tobin,2,3 and Chaim Putterman1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Rheumatology, Albert Einstein College of Medicine/Montefiore Medical Center, 1300 Morris Park Avenue, Bronx, NY 10461, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Epidemiology and Population Health, Albert Einstein College of Medicine, 1300 Morris Park Avenue, Bronx, NY 10461, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D patent for treating immune system diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wo2008039409httpwwwwipointpatentscopesearchenwo2008039409-world-wide-patent---2008">&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/WO2008039409">(WO2008039409)&lt;/a> World-Wide patent - 2008&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="treatment-and-prevention-of-diseases-or-conditions-of-the--immune-system-or-infectious-diseases">TREATMENT AND PREVENTION OF DISEASES OR CONDITIONS OF THE &lt;strong>IMMUNE SYSTEM OR INFECTIOUS DISEASES&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>allergic rhinitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eczema,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>psoriasis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>food allergy,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>type-1 diabetes,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>ulcerative colitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>rheumatoid arthritis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>multiple sclerosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>lupus,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>tuberculosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>parasitic infection, etc,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Increased D levels responsible for Dead Sea therapy</title><link>/posts/increased-d-levels-responsible-for-dead-sea-therapy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-d-levels-responsible-for-dead-sea-therapy.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="increased-vitamin-d-serum-levels-correlate-with-clinical-improvement-of-rheumatic-diseases-after-dead-sea-climatotherapy">Increased vitamin D serum levels correlate with clinical improvement of rheumatic diseases after Dead Sea climatotherapy.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Isr Med Assoc J. 2011 Apr;13(4):212-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harari M, Dramsdahl E, Shany S, Baumfeld Y, Ingber A, Novack V, Sukenik S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DMZ Medical Center, Lot Spa Hotel, Dead Sea, Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet B (UVB) rays are required by the skin for the production of vitamin D. The intensity of UVB at the Dead Sea area is the lowest in the world. Low vitamin D levels are often associated with musculoskeletal symptoms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Arthritis inflammation in rat cells worse with low level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/arthritis-inflammation-in-rat-cells-worse-with-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/arthritis-inflammation-in-rat-cells-worse-with-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="efficacy-and-mechanisms-of-action-of-vitamin-d-in-experimental-polyarthritis">Efficacy and mechanisms of action of vitamin D in experimental polyarthritis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Immunol Cell Biol. 2011 Mar 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moghaddami M, Mayrhofer G, Anderson PH, Morris HA, Van Der Hoek M, Cleland LG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arthritis Research Laboratory, Hanson Institute, SA Pathology, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D (vit D) status has been linked to the occurrence and severity of auto-immune and inflammatory diseases. This study evaluates the effects of vit D status on adoptive transfer of adjuvant-induced arthritis (ATA). Rats maintained on diets replete or deficient in vit D3 received arthritogenic thoracic duct cells and were monitored for severity of arthritis. CD45(+) cells obtained by collagenase digestion of hind-paw synovium-rich tissues (SRTs) were analysed to observe the effects of dietary vit D3 on the inflammatory process. Arthritis was more severe in vitamin D-deficient (vit-D(-)) rats compared with vitamin D-replete (vit-D(+)) rats. Resolution was delayed in vit-D(-) rats compared with vit-D(+) rats, or rats fed standard chow. During the acute phase of ATA, numbers of CD45(+) cells were significantly increased in the SRTs of vit-D(-) rats compared with vit-D(+) rats. This increase involved T-cells, polymorphonuclear leukocytes, macrophages, dendritic cells (DCs) and MHC II(hi) cells that resemble activated monocytes. A major difference between the dietary groups was that most DCs at the peak of inflammation in vit-D(-) rats were CD4(-), whereas in convalescent vit-D(+) rats most expressed CD4. Multiple categories of genes expressed by DCs differed between deficient and replete rats, with deficiency being associated with relative upregulation of certain pro-inflammatory genes and replete status being associated with upregulation of genes associated with resolution of inflammation. The findings indicate that ATA is more severe and prolonged in vit-D deficiency, that vit-D deficiency promotes accumulation of CD4(-) DCs in synovium during ATA and that a gene-expression profile is likely to contribute to the observed increased severity and duration of arthritis.Immunology and Cell Biology advance online publication, 29 March 2011; doi:10.1038/icb.2011.22.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Rheumatoid Arthritis and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-rheumatoid-arthritis-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-rheumatoid-arthritis-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> People with Rheumatoid arthritis are often vitamin D deficient&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>REPORT:&lt;/strong> People with the most Rheumatoid arthritis pain are the most vitamin D deficient&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> Rheumatoid arthritis pain is reduced by vitamin D - sometimes as little as 500 IU&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> 24 % more likely to get RA if have consume a low amount of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ra-people-who-had-methotrexate-therapy--were-28-less-likely-to-die-if-previously-20-ng-of-vitamin-d---jan-2024">RA people who had Methotrexate Therapy were 28% less likely to die if previously &amp;gt;20 ng of Vitamin D - Jan 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2012-review-of-vitamin-d-and-ra-attached-at-the-bottom-of-this-page-has-the-following-image">2012 Review of Vitamin D and RA attached at the bottom of this page has the following image&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2014-study-on-vitamin-d-and-ra-is-attached-at-the-bottom-of-this-page">2014 study on Vitamin D and RA is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#knee-joint-with-and-without-rheumatoid-arthritis">Knee Joint with and without Rheumatoid Arthritis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="ra-people-who-had-methotrexate-therapy--were-28-less-likely-to-die-if-previously-20-ng-of-vitamin-d---jan-2024">RA people who had Methotrexate Therapy were 28% less likely to die if previously &amp;gt;20 ng of Vitamin D - Jan 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Higher Vitamin D Levels before Methotrexate Therapy Initiation Are Associated with Lower Subsequent Mortality in Patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>70 percent of rheumatology outpatients had less than 21 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/70-percent-of-rheumatology-outpatients-had-less-than-21-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/70-percent-of-rheumatology-outpatients-had-less-than-21-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-consecutive-new-patients-seen-over-a-6-month-period-in-general-rheumatology-clinics">The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in consecutive new patients seen over a 6-month period in general rheumatology clinics.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Rheumatol () (2010)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Muhammad Haroon, Ursula Bond, Niamh Quillinan, Mark J Phelan and Michael J Regan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arthritis and Osteoporosis Centre, Department of Rheumatology, South Infirmary-Victoria University Hospital, Cork, Ireland, &lt;a href="mailto:mharoon301@hotmail.com">mharoon301@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objectives of this study are to assess:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>(a) the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency among new patients attending rheumatology outpatient departments,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rheumatoid arthritis reduced with just 800 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/rheumatoid-arthritis-reduced-with-just-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rheumatoid-arthritis-reduced-with-just-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-rheumatoid-arthritis-prevalence-determinants-and-associations-with-disease-activity-and-disability">Vitamin D deficiency in rheumatoid arthritis: prevalence, determinants and associations with disease activity and disability.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arthritis Res Ther. 2010 Nov 29;12(6):R216. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rossini M, Maddali Bongi S, La Montagna G, Minisola G, Malavolta N, Bernini L, Cacace E, Sinigaglia L, Di Munno O, Adami S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: The aim of this study was to estimate the prevalence and determinants of vitamin D deficiency in patients with rheumatoid arthritis (RA) as compared to healthy controls and to analyze the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> with disease activity and disability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Very low vitamin D associated with RA in women</title><link>/posts/very-low-vitamin-d-associated-with-ra-in-women.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/very-low-vitamin-d-associated-with-ra-in-women.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-vitamin-d-intake-and-joint-symptoms-in-postmenopausal-women">25-Hydroxyvitamin D concentration, vitamin D intake and joint symptoms in postmenopausal women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Maturitas. 2010 Nov 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chlebowski RT, Johnson KC, Lane D, Pettinger M, Kooperberg CL, Wactawski-Wende J, Rohan T, O&amp;rsquo;Sullivan MJ, Yasmeen S, Hiatt RA, Shikany JM, Vitolins M, Khandekar J, Hubbell FA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Los Angeles Biomedical Research Institute at Harbor-UCLA Medical Center, Torrance, CA, United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Low 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH) D) concentrations have been associated with radiologic worsening of osteoarthritis in some reports. However, the results are mixed and few studies have evaluated associations between 25(OH) D concentrations and both total vitamin D intake and clinical joint symptoms.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>