<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Metabolic Syndrome on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/metabolic-syndrome.html</link><description>Recent content in Metabolic Syndrome on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/metabolic-syndrome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Metabolic syndrome is associated with vitamin D independently of obesity – 2012</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-independently-of-obesity-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-independently-of-obesity-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-association-of-hypovitaminosis-d-with-the-metabolic-syndrome-is-independent-of-the-degree-of-obesity">The association of hypovitaminosis d with the metabolic syndrome is independent of the degree of obesity.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>ISRN Endocrinol. 2012;2012:691803. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5402/2012/691803.">doi: 10.5402/2012/691803.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Oct 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Miñambres I, Sánchez-Hernández J, Sánchez-Quesada JL, Rodríguez J, de Leiva A, Pérez A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinology and Nutrition Department, Hospital de la Santa Creu i Sant Pau, Sant Antoni Maria Claret 167, 08025 Barcelona, Spain ; Medicine Department, Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona (UAB), 08193 Bellaterra, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background. It remains uncertain whether the metabolic syndrome (MS) or insulin resistance contribute to the association between vitamin D deficiency and obesity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Immune Function – Review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-immune-function-review.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-immune-function-review.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(7), 2502-2521; doi:10.3390/nu5072502 (doi registration under processing)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara Prietlemail, Gerlies Treiberemail, Thomas R. Pieberemail and Karin Amrein &lt;a href="mailto:karin.amrein@medunigraz.at">karin.amrein@medunigraz.at&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Internal Medicine, Medical University of Graz, Auenbruggerplatz 15, A 8036 Graz, Austria&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(This article belongs to the Special Issue Nutrients and Immune Function)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D metabolizing enzymes and vitamin D receptors are present in many cell types including various immune cells such as antigen-presenting-cells, T cells, B cells and monocytes. In vitro data show that, in addition to modulating innate immune cells, vitamin D also promotes a more tolerogenic immunological status. In vivo data from animals and from human vitamin D supplementation studies have shown beneficial effects of vitamin D on immune function, in particular in the context of autoimmunity. In this review, currently available data are summarized to give an overview of the effects of vitamin D on the immune system in general and on the regulation of inflammatory responses, as well as regulatory mechanisms connected to autoimmune diseases particularly in type 1 diabetes mellitus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fatty liver disease (NAFLD), metabolic syndrome, and perhaps vitamin D</title><link>/posts/fatty-liver-disease-nafld-metabolic-syndrome-and-perhaps-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fatty-liver-disease-nafld-metabolic-syndrome-and-perhaps-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="what-about-non-alcoholic-fatty-liver-disease-as-a-new-criterion-to-define-metabolic-syndrome">What about non-alcoholic fatty liver disease as a new criterion to define metabolic syndrome?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>World J Gastroenterol. 2013 June 14; 19(22): 3375-3384.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giovanni Tarantino &lt;a href="mailto:tarantin@unina.it">tarantin@unina.it&lt;/a> and Carmine Finelli.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giovanni Tarantino, Department of Clinical Medicine and Surgery, Federico II University Medical School of Naples, 80131 Naples, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giovanni Tarantino, Fondazione Pascale, Cancer Research Center of Mercogliano, 83013 Mercogliano, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carmine Finelli, Center of Obesity and Eating Disorders, Stella Maris Mediterraneum Foundation, Chiaromonte, 80035 Potenza, Italy&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of role of Vitamin D in Cardiometabolic diseases</title><link>/posts/review-of-role-of-vitamin-d-in-cardiometabolic-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-role-of-vitamin-d-in-cardiometabolic-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="role-of-vitamin-d-in-cardiometabolic-diseases">Role of Vitamin D in Cardiometabolic Diseases&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Hindawi Publishing Corporation, Journal of Diabetes Research, Volume 2013, Article ID 243934,10 pages&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chaoxun Wang&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology, Shanghai Pudong Hospital, 2800 Gongwei Road, Huinan Town, Pudong, Shanghai 201399, China Correspondence should be addressed to Chaoxun Wang; &lt;a href="mailto:xunshdonger@hotmail.com">xunshdonger@hotmail.com&lt;/a> Received 23 November 2012; Revised 9 January 2013; Accepted 9 January 2013 Academic Editor: T. S. Kern&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is a highly prevalent condition. Low vitamin D levels have long been associated with bone diseases, such as rickets in children and osteomalacia and osteoporosis in adults. However, it has become apparent in recent years that adequate vitamin D levels are also important for optimal functioning of many organs and tissues throughout the body, including the cardiovascular system. Evolving data indicate that vitamin D deficiency is associated with an increased risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD). Studies have shown that low vitamin D levels are associated with hypertension, diabetes, metabolic syndrome, left ventricular hypertrophy, and chronic vascular inflammation, all of which are risk factors for CVD. This paper reviews the definition and pathophysiology of vitamin D deficiency, clinical evidence linking vitamin D and CVD risk, diabetes and its complications, and metabolic syndrome.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolic Syndrome 10% less likely for every 4 ng increase in Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-10-percent-less-likely-for-every-4-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-10-percent-less-likely-for-every-4-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-parathyroid-hormone-and-their-association-with-metabolic-syndrome-in-chinese">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D, parathyroid hormone, and their association with metabolic syndrome in Chinese.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocrine. 2013 Jan 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Li LH, Yin XY, Yao CY, Zhu XC, Wu XH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Dali University School of Clinical Medicine, Jiashibo Road 32, Dali, 671000, Yunnan, China, &lt;a href="mailto:lilihuayncn@gmail.com">lilihuayncn@gmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Increasing evidence suggests that 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> and parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels are associated with metabolic syndrome (MetS). In 2010, we explored the association of serum 25(OH)D and PTH levels with MetS in 1,390 Chinese participants, aged 20-83 years. Anthropometric phenotypes, blood pressure, and the incidence of MetS were evaluated. In addition, serum lipids, 25(OH)D, and PTH were measured. The median concentration of 25(OH)D and PTH were 55.3 nmol/l and 2.8 pmol/l, respectively. The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency (&amp;lt;50 nmol/l) was 39.9 %, with 34.5 % in men and 47.8 % in women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolic Syndrome in children is associated with low vitamin D – review</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-in-children-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-in-children-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-association-between-vitamin-d-and-cardiometabolic-risk-factors-in-children---a-systematic-review">The Association Between Vitamin D and Cardiometabolic Risk Factors in Children - A Systematic Review&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>CLIN PEDIATR January 8, 2013 0009922812470742&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diana H. Dolinsky, MD, MPH&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah Armstrong, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Caren Mangarelli, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alex R. Kemper, MD, MPH, MS&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Duke University Medical Center, Durham, NC, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah Armstrong, Department of Pediatrics, Duke University Medical Center, 4020 North Roxboro Street, Durham, NC 27704, USA Email: &lt;a href="mailto:sarah.c.armstrong@dm.duke.edu">sarah.c.armstrong@dm.duke.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this systematic review was to evaluate the association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) and cardiometabolic risk in children and the effect of vitamin D supplementation on risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High cholesterol 70 percent more likely if low vitamin D with rheumatoid arthritis</title><link>/posts/high-cholesterol-70-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-with-rheumatoid-arthritis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-cholesterol-70-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-with-rheumatoid-arthritis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-metabolic-dyslipidemia-and-metabolic-syndrome-in-rheumatoid-arthritis">Vitamin D, metabolic dyslipidemia, and metabolic syndrome in rheumatoid arthritis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Med. 2012 Oct;125(10):1036.e9-1036.e15. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2012.01.025.">doi: 10.1016/j.amjmed.2012.01.025.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jul 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Baker JF, Mehta NN, Baker DG, Toedter G, Shults J, Von Feldt JM, Leonard MB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Division of Rheumatology, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA 19104, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:bakerjo@uphs.upenn.edu">bakerjo@uphs.upenn.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is a potential risk factor for cardiometabolic disease. We investigated the associations between vitamin D and dyslipidemia and the metabolic syndrome in patients with rheumatoid arthritis, a group at high risk for cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolic Syndrome</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mice getting fructose while on a low Vitamin D diet got Metabolic Syndrome and NAFLD - Sept 2020&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Metabolite profiling of mice under long-term fructose drinking and vitamin D deficiency: increased risks for metabolic syndrome and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>abstract online, study is benind a paywall     &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s13105-020-00764-y">https://doi.org/10.1007/s13105-020-00764-y&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>2.7X more likely to have low level of vitamin D if have Metabolic Syndrome</title><link>/posts/27x-more-likely-to-have-low-level-of-vitamin-d-if-have-metabolic-syndrome.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/27x-more-likely-to-have-low-level-of-vitamin-d-if-have-metabolic-syndrome.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>5700 IU vitamin D improved various growth factors in overweight people</title><link>/posts/5700-iu-vitamin-d-improved-various-growth-factors-in-overweight-people.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5700-iu-vitamin-d-improved-various-growth-factors-in-overweight-people.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="insulin-like-growth-factor-i-growth-hormone-and-insulin-sensitivity-the-effects-of-a-one-year-cholecalciferol-supplementation-in-middle-aged-overweight-and-obese-subjects">Insulin-like growth factor I, growth hormone, and insulin sensitivity: the effects of a one-year cholecalciferol supplementation in middle-aged overweight and obese subjects.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocrine. 2012 Oct 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kamycheva E, Berg V, Jorde R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, University Hospital of North Norway, 9038, Tromsø, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:elena.kamycheva@unn.no">elena.kamycheva@unn.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both altered GH-IGF-I axis and low serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) are linked to measures of metabolic syndrome. Our hypothesis was that there is a relation between GH, IGF-I, and 25(OH)D; and that vitamin D supplementation may have an effect on the levels of GH, IGF-I, and IGF-I/IGFBP-3 ratio.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolic syndrome markers in elderly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-markers-in-elderly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-markers-in-elderly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (4 in 10 seniors) and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/non-alcoholic-fatty-liver-disease-4-in-10-seniors-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/non-alcoholic-fatty-liver-disease-4-in-10-seniors-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>FACT: NAFLD (Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease) is very common and hard to diagnose&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>FACT: NAFLD is associated with somewhat lower levels of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>FACT: People with NASH (a more severe form of NAFLD) do not produce as much semi-activated vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>OBSERVATION: Loading doses of vitamin D help sub sequent NAFLD maintenance doses&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Assumption: Livers of people with NAFLD are not able to process normal Vitamin D as well&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Assumption: Other forms of Vitamin D could treat NAFLD much better than normal vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1000 IU vitamin D did not reduce cardiovascular risk factors</title><link>/posts/1000-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-reduce-cardiovascular-risk-factors.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1000-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-reduce-cardiovascular-risk-factors.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d3-supplementation-has-no-effect-on-conventional-cardiovascular-risk-factors">Vitamin D3 Supplementation Has No Effect on Conventional Cardiovascular Risk Factors.&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-parallel-group-double-blind-placebo-controlled-rct">A Parallel-Group, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled RCT&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism August 3, 2012 jc.2012-2126 Adrian D. Wood, Karen R. Secombes, Frank Thies, Lorna Aucott, Alison J. Black, Alexandra Mavroeidi, William G. Simpson, William D. Fraser, David M. Reid and Helen M. Macdonald&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Medicine and Dentistry (A.D.W., K.R.S., F.T., L.A., D.M.R., H.M.M.), Medical Sciences (A.M.), University of Aberdeen, Foresterhill, Aberdeen AB252ZD, United Kingdom; Grampian Osteoporosis Service (A.J.B.), Woolmanhill Hospital, Aberdeen AB251LD, United Kingdom; Department of Clinical Biochemistry (W.G.S.), Aberdeen Royal Infirmary, Foresterhill AB252ZD, United Kingdom; and Norwich Medical School (W.D.F.), University of East Anglia, Norwich NR47TJ, United Kingdom&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High triglycerides in Metabolic Syndrome associated with low Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/high-triglycerides-in-metabolic-syndrome-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-triglycerides-in-metabolic-syndrome-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-relationship-of-vitamin-d-with-non-traditional-risk-factors-for-cardiovascular-disease-in-subjects-with-metabolic-syndrome">The relationship of vitamin D with non-traditional risk factors for cardiovascular disease in subjects with metabolic syndrome&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Stefania Makariou 1,2, Evangelos Liberopoulos 2, Matilda Florentin 2, Konstantinos Lagos 2, Irene Gazi 2, Anna Challa 1, Moses Elisaf 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>department of Child Health, Medical School, University of Ioannina, Greece Corresponding author:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Internal Medicine, Medical School, University of Ioannina, Greece Prof. Moses Elisaf MD, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine Submitted: 20 November 2011 Medical School&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X more abdominal obesity among Korean children having low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/3x-more-abdominal-obesity-among-korean-children-having-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-more-abdominal-obesity-among-korean-children-having-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-obesity-and-the-metabolic-syndrome-among-korean-children">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels, obesity and the metabolic syndrome among Korean children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2012 Jul 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee SH, Kim SM, Park HS, Choi KM, Cho GJ, Ko BJ, Kim JH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Family Medicine, College of Medicine, Korea University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND AIM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evidence of the relationship between serum vitamin D levels and cardiovascular risk factors in children is limited. We investigated the associations between serum vitamin D levels (25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>) and obesity and metabolic syndrome and its components in Korean children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Metabolic Syndrome and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/review-of-metabolic-syndrome-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-metabolic-syndrome-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="is-vitamin-d-status-relevant-to-metabolic-syndrome">Is vitamin D status relevant to metabolic syndrome?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dermato-Endocrinology Volume 4, Issue 2 April/May/June 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara J. Boucher&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Review of the evidence on hypovitaminosis D as a risk factor for metabolic syndrome and its sequelae, T2DM and CVD, suggests long-term vitamin D repletion could reduce these risks. There is mechanistic evidence for protective effects for MetS and the balance of evidence, (cross-sectional and prospective), supports this postulate. Much of the data so far available from randomized controlled trials is weakened by inadequate power, low vitamin D dosages, starting supplementation too late in life or after MetS disorders have developed or, most importantly, by non-inclusion of many recognizable confounders. On balance, therefore, maintenance of US 2010 recommended intakes for bone protection has the potential to prove protective for MetS. Supplementation has been shown to increase survival in patients with cardiac disorders, whether higher doses would provide useful protection for apparently healthy people in the general population awaits the outcomes of ongoing randomized-controlled trials that, it is hoped, will prove or disprove causality for hypovitaminosis D in MetS and its ill-effects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Psoriasis, metabolic syndrome, and vitamin D – 2011</title><link>/posts/psoriasis-metabolic-syndrome-and-vitamin-d-2011.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/psoriasis-metabolic-syndrome-and-vitamin-d-2011.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Metabolic Syndrome 70 percent more likely if vitamin D insufficient</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-70-percent-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-insufficient.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-70-percent-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-insufficient.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sudden death 6X more likely with Metabolic Syndrome and low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/sudden-death-6x-more-likely-with-metabolic-syndrome-and-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sudden-death-6x-more-likely-with-metabolic-syndrome-and-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Metabolic Syndrome reduced 2X after one year of more sunlight</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-reduced-2x-after-one-year-of-more-sunlight.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-reduced-2x-after-one-year-of-more-sunlight.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Medical Publications for Metabolic Syndrome etc. - GreenMed</title><link>/posts/medical-publications-for-metabolic-syndrome-etc-greenmed.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/medical-publications-for-metabolic-syndrome-etc-greenmed.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-green-medical-information">From Green Medical Information&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>They did a search for&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Dyslipidemias&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• High Cholesterol&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Hypertension&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Insulin Resistance&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Metabolic Syndrome X&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Abdominal Obesity (Midsection Fat)&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="spantiki-download_filephpfileid1970span">&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1970]&lt;/span>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="extensive-results-include">Extensive Results include&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="beneficial-substances">Beneficial substances&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Arginine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Curcumin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fermented&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omega 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Magnesium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oats&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="problem-substances">Problem substances&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Fructose&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Statins&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beta Blockers&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="therapeutic-actions">Therapeutic actions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Exercise&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mediterranean Diet&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/evidence-based-medical-information-greenmedinfo">Evidence based medical information - GreenMedinfo&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-diabetes-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 339">Overview Diabetes and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>70 percent increased chance of metabolic syndrome if low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/70-percent-increased-chance-of-metabolic-syndrome-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/70-percent-increased-chance-of-metabolic-syndrome-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Metabolic syndrome 50 percent more likely if under 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-50-percent-more-likely-if-under-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-50-percent-more-likely-if-under-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-the-metabolic-syndrome-in-older-persons-a-population-based-study">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels and the metabolic syndrome in older persons. A population-based study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2011 May 20. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2265.2011.04110.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2265.2011.04110.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oosterwerff MM, Eekhoff EM, Heymans MW, Lips P, van Schoor NM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Section Endocrinology EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research,VU University Medical Center, 1081 HV Amsterdam, The Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background? Recent evidence indicates that a lower plasma level of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) is associated with a higher risk of the metabolic syndrome. It has not been studied in older people with a high prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolic Syndrome adults 4X more likely to have less than 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-adults-4x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-adults-4x-more-likely-to-have-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-levels-in-northern-american-adults-with-the-metabolic-syndrome">Low vitamin d levels in northern american adults with the metabolic syndrome.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Horm Metab Res. 2011 Jan;43(1):72-4. Epub 2010 Nov 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Devaraj S, Jialal G, Cook T, Siegel D, Jialal I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, University of California, Davis, Medical Center, Sacramento, CA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Metabolic syndrome (MetS), is a constellation of cardiometabolic disease risk factors, that affects &lt;em>1 in 3 US adults and predisposes to increased risks for both diabetes and cardiovascular disease&lt;/em>_. While epidemiological studies show low vitamin D &lt;span>[(25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels in MetS, there is sparse data on vitamin D status in MetS patients in North America.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>People with metabolic syndrome were 3X more likely to have low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/people-with-metabolic-syndrome-were-3x-more-likely-to-have-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-metabolic-syndrome-were-3x-more-likely-to-have-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-levels-in-northern-american-adults-with-the-metabolic-syndrome">Low Vitamin D levels in Northern American Adults with the Metabolic Syndrome&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Horm Metab Res : DOI: 10.1055/s-0030-1268485&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. Devaraj1, G. Jialal1, T. Cook1, D. Siegel1,2, I. Jialal1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, University of California, Davis, Medical Center, Sacramento, CA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Mather, CA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Metabolic syndrome (MetS), is a constellation of cardiometabolic disease risk factors, that affects 1 in 3 US adults and predisposes to increased risks for both diabetes and cardiovascular disease. While epidemiological studies show low vitamin D &lt;span>[(25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels in MetS, there is sparse data on vitamin D status in MetS patients in North America. Thus, the aim of our study was to examine plasma vitamin D concentration among adults with MetS in Northern California (sunny climate), but without diabetes or cardiovascular disease. 25(OH)D levels were significantly decreased in MetS compared to controls. &lt;strong>8% of controls and 30% of MetS&lt;/strong> North American adult subjects were deficient in 25(OH)D ( &lt;strong>&amp;lt;20 ng/ml&lt;/strong> ; p=0.0236, Controls vs. MetS). There were no significant differences between the groups with respect to blood sampling in winter and summer months, total calcium and phosphate, and creatinine levels. Vitamin D levels were significantly inversely correlated with fasting glucose (r=?0.29, p=0.04) and HOMA (r=?0.34, p=0.04). Future studies of vitamin D supplementation in these subjects on subsequent risk of diabetes will prove instructive with respect to potential health claims in these high risk patients with MetS.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>