<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Probiotics on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/probiotics.html</link><description>Recent content in Probiotics on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/probiotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gestational Diabetes reduce 3 times by 5,000 IU of Vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/gestational-diabetes-reduce-3-times-by-5000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gestational-diabetes-reduce-3-times-by-5000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#gestational-diabetes-treated-by-50000-iu--of-vitamin-d-every-2-weeks--daily-probiotic---nov-2018">Gestational Diabetes treated by 50,000 IU of vitamin D every 2 weeks + daily probiotic - Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="gestational-diabetes-treated-by-50000-iu--of-vitamin-d-every-2-weeks--daily-probiotic---nov-2018">Gestational Diabetes treated by 50,000 IU of vitamin D every 2 weeks + daily probiotic - Nov 2018&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The effects of vitamin D and probiotic co-supplementation on glucose homeostasis, inflammation, oxidative stress and pregnancy outcomes in gestational diabetes: A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical Nutrition, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnu.2018.10.028">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnu.2018.10.028&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and aims This study was designed to assess the effects of combined vitamin D and probiotic supplementation on metabolic status and pregnancy outcomes in women with gestational diabetes (GDM).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D use increased 3.7 X, Omega-3 increased 9 X (US 1999-2012) – JAMA</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-use-increased-37-x-omega-3-increased-9-x-us-1999-2012-jama.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-use-increased-37-x-omega-3-increased-9-x-us-1999-2012-jama.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="also-reviewed-by">Also reviewed by:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/56446-supplement-trends-us.html">Supplement Trends: Multivitamin Use Down, Probiotics &amp;amp; Vitamin D Up&lt;/a> Live Science&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;All participants were asked whether they had taken any prescription or over-the-counter dietary supplements — vitamins, minerals, herbs or other supplements — within the last 30 days. Because interviewers met with each participant in their homes, they would also ask to see the supplement bottles, making the data more reliable than studies that rely primarily on a person&amp;rsquo;s memory, the researchers said.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Benefits of Omega-3 on brain development</title><link>/posts/benefits-of-omega-3-on-brain-development.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/benefits-of-omega-3-on-brain-development.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="review-of-10-studies-behind-a-50-paywall--april-2016">Review of 10 studies behind a $50 paywall – April 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Optimal Nutrition In Lactating Women And Its Effect On Later Health Of Offspring: A Systematic Review Of Current Evidence And Recommendations (Early Nutrition Project)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition. DOI:10.1080/10408398.2016.1158149&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marita de Waarda, Brigitte Brandsb, Stefanie M.P. Kouwenhovena, Joaquim Calvo Lermac, Paula Crespo-Escobarc, Berthold Koletzko Prof.2b, Bartlomiej M. Zalewskid &amp;amp; Johannes B. van Goudoever Prof.ae*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background EarlyNutrition (&lt;a href="https://www.project-earlynutrition.eu">www.project-earlynutrition.eu&lt;/a>) is an international research consortium investigating the effects of early nutrition on metabolic programming.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yogurt fortified with K-2, Vitamin D, Mg, Omega-3, etc helped</title><link>/posts/yogurt-fortified-with-k-2-vitamin-d-mg-omega-3-etc-helped.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yogurt-fortified-with-k-2-vitamin-d-mg-omega-3-etc-helped.html</guid><description>&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>I have added various supplements to yogurt for my father-in-law.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can Imagine a commercial supplement packet with&lt;/p>
&lt;p>      K2, Vitamin D, Magnesium, Omega-3, probiotics, etc which could be added to any yogurt&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-fortification-of-yogurt-meta-analysis" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Vitamin D fortification of yogurt – meta-analysis Aug 2019">Vitamin D fortification of yogurt – meta-analysis Aug 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h4 id="yogurt-drink-fortified-with-menaquinone-7-improves-vitamin-k-status-in-a-healthy-population">Yogurt drink fortified with menaquinone-7 improves vitamin K status in a healthy population.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Nutr Sci. 2015 Oct 16;4:e35. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/jns.2015.25.">doi: 10.1017/jns.2015.25.&lt;/a> eCollection 2015.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Epileptic children and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-epileptic-children-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-epileptic-children-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact:&lt;/strong> Vitamin D supplementation helps epileptics in 6 ways&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact:&lt;/strong> Anti-epilepsy drugs lower vitamin D levels&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact:&lt;/strong> Epilepsy 5X more likely if preterm birth (low vitamin D)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact:&lt;/strong> Preterm greatly decreased if add vitamin D and/or Omega-3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Recommendation:&lt;/strong> Epileptics should take vitamin D to:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>      Improve Quality of Life&lt;/p>
&lt;p>     Avoid having health problems associated with low vitamin D, such as low bone density&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Epilepsy = 4,000 years of ignorance, superstition and stigma&lt;br>
     followed by 100 years of knowledge, superstition and stigma.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D receptor functionality improved with probiotics</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-functionality-improved-with-probiotics.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-functionality-improved-with-probiotics.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-pathway-is-required-for-probiotic-protection-in-colitis">Vitamin D receptor pathway is required for probiotic protection in colitis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Physiology - Gastrointestinal and Liver Physiology Published 1 September 2015 Vol. 309 no. 5, G341-G349 DOI: 10.1152/ajpgi.00105.2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shaoping Wu, Sonia Yoon, Yong-Guo Zhang, Rong Lu, Yinglin Xia, Jiandi Wan, Elaine O. Petrof, Erika C. Claud, Di Chen, Jun Sun&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low expression of vitamin D receptor (VDR) and dysfunction of vitamin D/VDR signaling are reported in patients with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD); therefore, restoration of VDR function to control inflammation in IBD is desirable. Probiotics have been used in the treatment of IBD. However, the role of probiotics in the modulation of VDR signaling to effectively reduce inflammation is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antibiotics, even short-term, cause long-term microbiome and metabolic changes in mice</title><link>/posts/antibiotics-even-short-term-cause-long-term-microbiome-and-metabolic-changes-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/antibiotics-even-short-term-cause-long-term-microbiome-and-metabolic-changes-in-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="metabolic-and-metagenomic-outcomes-from-early-life-pulsed-antibiotic-treatment">Metabolic and metagenomic outcomes from early-life pulsed antibiotic treatment&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Yael R. Nobel1,&lt;em>, Laura M. Cox1,2,&lt;/em>, Francis F. Kirigin1, Nicholas A. Bokulich1, , Shingo Yamanishi1, Isabel Teitler1, Jennifer Chung1, Jiho Sohn1, Cecily M. Barber1, David S. Goldfarb1,3, Kartik Raju1, Sahar Abubucker4,Yanjiao Zhou4,5,9, Victoria E. Ruiz1, Huilin Li6, Makedonka Mitreva4,7, Alexander V. Alekseyenko1,8,George M. Weinstock4,9, Erica Sodergren4,9 &amp;amp; Martin J. Blaser1,2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mammalian species have co-evolved with intestinal microbial communities that can shape development and adapt to environmental changes, including antibiotic perturbation or nutrient flux. In humans, especially children, microbiota disruption is common, yet the dynamic microbiome recovery from early-life antibiotics is still uncharacterized. Here we use a mouse model mimicking paediatric antibiotic use and find that therapeutic-dose &lt;strong>pulsed antibiotic treatment (PAT)&lt;/strong> with a beta-lactam or macrolide alters both host and microbiota development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Probiotic and vitamin D synergy</title><link>/posts/probiotic-and-vitamin-d-synergy.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/probiotic-and-vitamin-d-synergy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-pathway-is-required-for-probiotic-protection-in-colitis">Vitamin D receptor pathway is required for probiotic protection in colitis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2015 Jul 9:ajpgi.00105.2015. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpgi.00105.2015.">doi: 10.1152/ajpgi.00105.2015.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wu S1, Yoon S2, Zhang YG1, Lu R, Xia Y, Wan J, Petrof EO3, Claud EC4, Chen D1, Sun J5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Rush University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Weill Cornell Medical College, Cornell University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Queen&amp;rsquo;s University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4University of Chicago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>5Rush University &lt;a href="mailto:Jun_Sun@rush.edu">Jun_Sun@rush.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low expression of vitamin D receptor (VDR) and dysfunction of vitamin D/VDR signaling are reported in patients with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD); therefore, restoration of VDR function to control inflammation in IBD is desirable. Probiotics have been used in the treatment of IBD. However, the role of probiotics in the modulation of VDR signaling to effectively reduce inflammation is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gut microbiome massively changed by weekly vitamin D</title><link>/posts/gut-microbiome-massively-changed-by-weekly-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gut-microbiome-massively-changed-by-weekly-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effects-of-high-doses-of-vitamin-d3-on-mucosa-associated-gut-microbiome-vary-between-regions-of-the-human-gastrointestinal-tract">Effects of high doses of vitamin D3 on mucosa-associated gut microbiome vary between regions of the human gastrointestinal tract.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#changes-in-small-intestine-where-vitamin-d-is-taken-into-the-body">Changes in small intestine (where vitamin D is taken into the body)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#214-studies-citied-this-study-as-of-jan-2023">214 studies citied this study as of Jan 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dr-partick-commented-july-2016-on-this-study">Dr Partick commented July 2016 on this study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="effects-of-high-doses-of-vitamin-d3-on-mucosa-associated-gut-microbiome-vary-between-regions-of-the-human-gastrointestinal-tract">Effects of high doses of vitamin D3 on mucosa-associated gut microbiome vary between regions of the human gastrointestinal tract.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Nutr. 2015 Jul 1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview of Doctor who has authored books on Vitamin K2 and Magnesium – Mercola</title><link>/posts/interview-of-doctor-who-has-authored-books-on-vitamin-k2-and-magnesium-mercola.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/interview-of-doctor-who-has-authored-books-on-vitamin-k2-and-magnesium-mercola.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-k2-the-missing-nutrient-for-heart-and-bone-health-a--special-interview-with-dr-dennis-goodman">Vitamin K2: The Missing Nutrient for Heart and Bone Health A Special Interview with Dr. Dennis Goodman&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>By Dr. Joseph Mercola&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="video-and-summary-article-by-dr-mercolahttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20150628vitamin-k2-health-benefitsaspxe_cid20150628z1_dnl_art_1utm_sourcednlutm_mediumemailutm_contentart1utm_campaign20150628z1et_ciddm78408et_rid1011718056">&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2015/06/28/vitamin-k2-health-benefits.aspx?e_cid=20150628Z1_DNL_art_1&amp;amp;utm_source=dnl&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=art1&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20150628Z1&amp;amp;et_cid=DM78408&amp;amp;et_rid=1011718056">Video and summary article by Dr. Mercola&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>See also web&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.lifeextension.com/Magazine/2014/8/Dr-Dennis-Goodman-A-Man-On-A-Mission-To-Promote-Magnesium/Page-01">Dr. Dennis Goodman: A Man On A Mission To Promote Magnesium&lt;/a> Life Extension Aug 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.dennisgoodmanmd.com/">http://www.dennisgoodmanmd.com/&lt;/a> also mentions his Krill book&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>DM:&lt;/strong> Dr. Joseph Mercola &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">DG&lt;/span>:&lt;/strong> Dr. Dennis Goodman&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>DM:&lt;/strong> Most everyone, including many conventional physicians, has begun to appreciate the importance and the value of vitamin D. But unfortunately, no one understands the importance of vitamin K2. Hi, this is Dr. Mercola, helping you take control of your health. Today we are joined by Dr. Dennis Goodman, who is double-board certified in cardiology and holistic integrative medicine. He happens to be the chairman of the Department of Integrative Medicine at the New York University (NYU).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omega-3, Vitamin D, and other nutrients decrease mental health problems</title><link>/posts/omega-3-vitamin-d-and-other-nutrients-decrease-mental-health-problems.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-vitamin-d-and-other-nutrients-decrease-mental-health-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="from-importance-of-a-balanced-diet-for-mental-healthhttpwwwsciencedailycomreleases201506150608081759htm-science-daily">From &lt;a href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2015/06/150608081759.htm">Importance of a balanced diet for mental health&lt;/a> Science Daily&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Omega-3, essential amino acids, B-group vitamins (B12 and folate), vitamin D and minerals like zinc, magnesium and iron.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A balanced and high-quality diet, such as the Mediterranean, provides all of these, the researchers note.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jerome Sarris, Alan C Logan, Tasnime N Akbaraly, G Paul Amminger, Vicent Balanzá-Martínez, Marlene P Freeman, Joseph Hibbeln, Yutaka Matsuoka, David Mischoulon, Tetsuya Mizoue, Akiko Nanri, Daisuke Nishi, Drew Ramsey, Julia J Rucklidge, Almudena Sanchez-Villegas, Andrew Scholey, Kuan-Pin Su, Felice N Jacka. Nutritional medicine as mainstream in psychiatry. The Lancet Psychiatry, 2015; 2 (3): 271 DOI:10.1016/S2215-0366(14)00051-0&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon cancer – vitamin D, probiotics, and leptin might help</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-vitamin-d-probiotics-and-leptin-might-help.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-vitamin-d-probiotics-and-leptin-might-help.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="associations-of-probiotics-with-vitamin-d-and-leptin-receptors-and-their-effects-on-colon-cancer">Associations of Probiotics with Vitamin D and Leptin Receptors and their Effects on Colon Cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2015;16(9):3621-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ranji P1, Akbarzadeh A, Rahmati-Yamchi M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Medical Biotechnology, Faculty of Advanced Medical Sciences, International Branch of Tabriz University of Medical sciences (Aras), Tabriz, Iran E-mail : &lt;a href="mailto:rahmati_bio@yahoo.com">rahmati_bio@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Colorectal cancer (CRC) is one of most common causes of cancer-related death worldwide. Recent studies have suggested that microbial and environmental factors including diet and lifestyle can impact on colon cancer development. Vitamin D deficiency and dysfunction of vitamin D receptor (VDR) also correlate with colon cancer. Moreover, leptin, a 16-kDa polypeptide, participates in the regulation of food intake and is associated with other environmental factors affecting colon cancer through the leptin receptor. Altered levels of serum leptin and patterns of expression of its receptor (LPR) may be observed in human colon tumours. Furthermore, the collected data from in vitro and in vivo studies have indicated that consuming probiotic non-pathogenic lactic acid bacteria have beneficial effects on colon cancer. Probiotics, inflammation and vitamin D/VDR have been correlated with leptin and its receptor and are also with colon cancer. Thus, in this paper, we review recent progress on the roles of probiotic, vitamin D/VDR and leptin/LPR in inflammation and colon cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Role of vitamins in gastrointestinal diseases – review</title><link>/posts/role-of-vitamins-in-gastrointestinal-diseases-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/role-of-vitamins-in-gastrointestinal-diseases-review.html</guid><description>&lt;p>World J Gastroenterol. 2015 May 7; 21(17): 5191–5209., &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3748/wjg.v21.i17.5191">doi: 10.3748/wjg.v21.i17.5191&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omar A Masri, Jean M Chalhoub, and Ala I Sharara&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A tremendous amount of data from research was published over the past decades concerning the roles of different vitamins in various gastrointestinal diseases. For instance, most vitamins showed an inverse relationship with the risk of colorectal carcinoma as well as other malignancies like gastric and esophageal cancer in observational trials, however interventional trials failed to prove a clear beneficial preventive role. On the other hand, more solid evidence was obtained from high quality studies for a role of certain vitamins in specific entities. Examples for this include the&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Supplements survey: Fish oil 1st, Vitamin D 4th, Magnesium 6th, Calcium 7th</title><link>/posts/supplements-survey-fish-oil-1st-vitamin-d-4th-magnesium-6th-calcium-7th.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/supplements-survey-fish-oil-1st-vitamin-d-4th-magnesium-6th-calcium-7th.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="consumerlabs-response-by-10000-members-who-filled-out-a-surveyhttpswwwconsumerlabcomnewsuse20of20magnesium20and20probiotics20rise2_28_2015">&lt;a href="https://www.consumerlab.com/news/Use%20of%20Magnesium%20and%20Probiotics%20Rise/2_28_2015/">ConsumerLabs response by 10,000 members who filled out a survey&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Use of Magnesium and Probiotics Rise, Multivitamins and Weight Loss Supplements Fall&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>fish oil&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>multivitamins&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>CoQ10&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>B vitamins&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>magnesium&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>calcium&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>probiotics&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>vitamin C&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The order is similar to that of last year&amp;rsquo;s survey, with exception of magnesium overtaking calcium. Use of magnesium among respondents increased to 43.1%, compared to 38.1% last year — a relative growth of 13% and the largest increase among the major supplements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Consumer Labs has great reviews of supplements– a peek at their probiotics matrix</title><link>/posts/off-topic-consumer-labs-has-great-reviews-of-supplements-a-peek-at-their-probiotics-matrix.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-consumer-labs-has-great-reviews-of-supplements-a-peek-at-their-probiotics-matrix.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="httpswwwconsumerlabcomhttpswwwconsumerlabcom">&lt;a href="https://www.consumerlab.com">https://www.consumerlab.com&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.consumerlab.com/freetrialwcc-signup.asp?CLTRKID=NEWSLETTER">Update: Consumer Labs was offering a 5 day free trial Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They have excellent extensive reviews of supplements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Provides some information about their benefits – including reviews of latest studies&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Constantly updated. (I think Vitamin D file was updated about 8 times in 2015)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Includes price information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have subscribed for 15+ years. $36 per year&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/patients-like-me-survey-found-vitamin-d-to-be-number-one-supplement" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Patients like me survey found vitamin D to be number one supplement">Patients like me survey found vitamin D to be number one supplement&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, immunity and microbiome</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-immunity-and-microbiome.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-immunity-and-microbiome.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D and immunity&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Special section of interest: &lt;span style="color:#F00;">Why doesn’t vitamin D supplementation decrease disease risks?&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>F1000Prime Rep2014, 6:118 (&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.12703/P6-118">doi: 10.12703/P6-118)&lt;/a>),&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 01 Dec 2014 © 2014 Faculty of 1000 Ltd&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robyn M. Lucas1,2 &lt;a href="mailto:robyn.lucas@telethonkids.org.au">robyn.lucas@telethonkids.org.au&lt;/a>, Shelley Gorman1, Sian Geldenhuys1 and Prue H. Hart1&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Telethon Kids Institute, University of Western Australia, 100 Roberts Road, Subiaco, Perth, Australia 6008&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>National Centre for Epidemiology and Population Health, The Australian National University, Canberra, Australia 0200&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/immunity-microbiome.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#abstract">Abstract&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clues-from-epidemiology">Clues from epidemiology&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mechanisms-by-which-l25oh2d-may-regulate-immune-cell-function">Mechanisms by which l,25(OH)2D may regulate immune cell function&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#multiple-sclerosis-a-case-study">Multiple sclerosis: a case study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#an-indirect-pathway-vitamin-d-immunity-and-the-microbiome">An indirect pathway: vitamin D, immunity and the microbiome&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#span-stylecolorf00why-doesnt-vitamin-d-supplementation-decrease-disease-risksspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Why doesn’t vitamin D supplementation decrease disease risks?&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references-in-pdf">References in PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been linked to an increased risk of a wide range of adverse health outcomes. The active form of vitamin D has an important role in calcium metabolism and in bone mineralisation, but the evidence for other health outcomes is mixed, with the strongest effects seen in the weakest epidemiological study designs. There are plausible pathways whereby vitamin D deficiency can impair immune function, resulting in both overactivity and increased risk of autoimmune disease, as well as immune suppression with poorer resistance to infection. Vitamin D status may influence the bacterial flora that constitute the microbiome and affect immune function through this route. Exposure of the skin to ultraviolet radiation causes the production of a range of chemicals, including vitamin D, and new research is exploring possible vitamin D-independent immunomodulatory pathways.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Huge increases in health problems – risk factors include Vitamin D, Antibiotics, and Roundup</title><link>/posts/huge-increases-in-health-problems-risk-factors-include-vitamin-d-antibiotics-and-roundup.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/huge-increases-in-health-problems-risk-factors-include-vitamin-d-antibiotics-and-roundup.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="during-the-past-40-years-there-have-been-big-increased-in">During the past 40 years there have been big increased in&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Incidence of 34+ diseases - &lt;a href="/posts/incidence-of-22-health-problems-related-to-vitamin-d-have-doubled-in-a-decade">diseases associated with low vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/antibiotics-and-vitamin-d-are-associated-with-many-of-the-same-diseases">use of Antibiotics&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/investigation-on-roundup-glyphosate-at-vitamindwiki">Roundup&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>There are many studies showing the risk factors for antibiotics, roundup and low vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The risk factors vary from 1.5X to 15X – depends on the disease&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Often it is the same disease: examples - autism, obesity, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="roundup">Roundup&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kills all plants (GMO = Genetically Modified Organism) which have not be designed to resist it (roundup-ready)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease perhaps due to gut microbiota</title><link>/posts/nonalcoholic-fatty-liver-disease-perhaps-due-to-gut-microbiota.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nonalcoholic-fatty-liver-disease-perhaps-due-to-gut-microbiota.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="nonalcoholic-fatty-liver-disease--for-better-or-worse-blame-the-gut-microbiota">Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease – For Better or Worse, Blame the Gut Microbiota?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr November 2013 vol. 37 no. 6 787-793&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ding-You Li, MD, PhD1,2; Min Yang, MD, PhD3; Sarah Edwards, DO1,2; Shui-Qing Ye, MD; hD1,2,4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Gastroenterology, Children’s Mercy Hospital, University of Missouri School of Medicine, Kansas City, Missouri&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Pediatrics, Children’s Mercy Hospital, University of Missouri School of Medicine, Kansas City, Missouri&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antibiotics, probiotics</title><link>/posts/antibiotics-probiotics.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/antibiotics-probiotics.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#prebiotics-probiotics-and-nutraceuticals-book---2022-only-pg-219-mentions-vitamin-d">Prebiotics, Probiotics and Nutraceuticals book - 2022 (only pg 219 mentions vitamin D)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#malnurished-chidren-given-more-food-did-gain-weight-until-after-gut-bacteria-were-improved---sept-2022">Malnurished chidren given more food did gain weight until after gut bacteria were improved - Sept 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="prebiotics-probiotics-and-nutraceuticals-book---2022-only-pg-219-mentions-vitamin-d">Prebiotics, Probiotics and Nutraceuticals book - 2022 (only pg 219 mentions vitamin D)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/prebiotics-probiotics-2022-book.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki &lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/pp-toc.jpg" alt="image" width="750">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/11/161110162840.htm">Probiotics improve cognition in Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s patients&lt;/a> RCT Nov 2016&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nothing about Vitamin D. 12 weeks of probiotics for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s patients increased mental test score from 8.7 to 10.6 (max score =30)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D absorption by the gut is not a passive process</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-absorption-by-the-gut-is-not-a-passive-process.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-absorption-by-the-gut-is-not-a-passive-process.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="intestinal-absorption-of-vitamin-d-from-the-meal-to-the-enterocyte">INTESTINAL ABSORPTION OF VITAMIN D: FROM THE MEAL TO THE ENTEROCYTE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Food and Function, Accepted Manuscript. DOI: 10.1039/C4FO00579A, First published online 13 Oct 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emmanuelle Reboul&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D plays key roles in bone, infectious, inflammatory and metabolic diseases. As most people get inadequate sun exposure for sufficient vitamin D status, they need adequate intake of dietary vitamin D. Many studies see optimizing vitamin D status as a public health priority. It is thus vital to gain deeper insight into vitamin D intestinal absorption. It was long assumed that vitamin D intestinal absorption is a &lt;strong>passive process&lt;/strong> , but new data from our laboratory showed that it is actually far more complex than previously thought.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gut flora which reduce cholesterol have been patented</title><link>/posts/gut-flora-which-reduce-cholesterol-have-been-patented.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gut-flora-which-reduce-cholesterol-have-been-patented.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="unique-probiotic-targets-cardiovascular-disease--life-extension-mag-oct-2014">Unique probiotic targets Cardiovascular Disease – Life Extension Mag Oct 2014&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A species of Lactobacillus: L. reuteri 30242 reduces cholesterol by creating an enzyme which makes cholesterol less absorbable.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/probiotics---lef.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.nutraingredients.com/Regulation/Spanish-firm-wins-cholesterol-lowering-probiotic-patent">Details on the patent&lt;/a> – apparently commercially available&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="comments-by-vitamindwiki">Comments by VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Amazing that a species existing in many humans can be patented&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Perhaps use of antibiotics wiped out L. reuteri 30242 in many guts, but now we can pay to have them restored&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What you eat is a function of what your gut flora wants</title><link>/posts/what-you-eat-is-a-function-of-what-your-gut-flora-wants.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/what-you-eat-is-a-function-of-what-your-gut-flora-wants.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-eating-behavior-manipulated-by-the-gastrointestinal-microbiota-evolutionary-pressures-and-potential-mechanisms">Is eating behavior manipulated by the gastrointestinal microbiota? Evolutionary pressures and potential mechanisms.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bioessays. 2014 Aug 8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/bies.201400071.">doi: 10.1002/bies.201400071.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joe Alcock 1, Carlo C. Maley 2,3,4, &lt;a href="mailto:cmaley@alum.mit.edu">cmaley@alum.mit.edu&lt;/a> and C. Athena Aktipis 2,3,4,5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Emergency Medicine, University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, NM, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Center for Evolution and Cancer, Helen Diller Family Comprehensive Cancer Center, San Francisco, CA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Surgery, University of California San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Probiotics reduces blood pressure, but not as much as vitamin D does – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/probiotics-reduces-blood-pressure-but-not-as-much-as-vitamin-d-does-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/probiotics-reduces-blood-pressure-but-not-as-much-as-vitamin-d-does-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="effect-of-probiotics-on-blood-pressure-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials">Effect of Probiotics on Blood Pressure: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized, Controlled Trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>HYPERTENSIONAHA.114.03469, Published online before print July 21, 2014,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1161/">doi: 10.1161/&lt;/a>​ Saman Khalesi, Jing Sun, Nicholas Buys, Rohan Jayasinghe&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Griffith Health Institute (S.K., J.S., N.B.) and School of Medicine (S.K., J.S., R.J.), Griffith University, Australia; and Australia and Cardiac Services/Cardiology, Gold Coast Health, Australia (R.J.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence to Jing Sun, School of Medicine and Griffith Health Institute, Griffith University, Gold Coast Campus, Parkland, Gold Coast, Queensland 4222, Australia. E-mail &lt;a href="mailto:j.sun@griffith.edu.au">j.sun@griffith.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Biota and Vitamin D - thoughts</title><link>/posts/biota-and-vitamin-d-thoughts.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/biota-and-vitamin-d-thoughts.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Possible interactions between biota (gut bacteria, etc), antibiotics, probiotics, prebiotics and vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Knowns:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There are some 10,000 biota in the human gut&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Antibiotics kills off gut biota. - sometimes being a species genocide (totally losing some contingency genes)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Current probiotics will restock, at least for a few weeks 1-10 species.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Antibiotics early in life (while still developing) can have profound effects on the individual&amp;rsquo;s development, even if the species is later restocked.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gut Microbiota: The Neglected Endocrine Organ (vitamin D not mentioned)</title><link>/posts/gut-microbiota-the-neglected-endocrine-organ-vitamin-d-not-mentioned.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gut-microbiota-the-neglected-endocrine-organ-vitamin-d-not-mentioned.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Molecular Endocrinology, DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1210/me.2014-1108">http://dx.doi.org/10.1210/me.2014-1108&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gerard Clarke 1,2, Roman M. Stilling 1 , Paul J Kennedy 1, Catherine Stanton 1,2,3, John F. Cryan 1,4, and Timothy G. Dinan 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Alimentary Pharmabiotic Centre, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Psychiatry, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Teagasc, Moorepark, Fermoy, Cork, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4Anatomy and Neuroscience, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The concept that the gut microbiota serves as a virtual endocrine organ arises from a number of important observations. Evidence for a direct role arises from its metabolic capacity to produce and regulate multiple compounds that reach the circulation and act to influence the function of distal organs and systems. For example, metabolism of carbohydrates results in the production of short chain fatty acids (SCFAs), such as butyrate and propionate, which provide an important source of nutrients as well as regulatory control of the host digestive system. This influence over host metabolism is also seen in the ability of the prebiotic inulin is to influence production of relevant hormones such as glucagon like peptide-1 (GLP-1), peptide YY (PYY), ghrelin and leptin. Moreover, the probiotic L. rhamnosus PL60, which produces conjugated linoleic acid, has been shown to reduce body weight gain and white adipose tissue without effects on food intake. Manipulating the microbial composition of the gastrointestinal tract modulates plasma concentrations of tryptophan, an essential amino acid and precursor to serotonin, a key neurotransmitter within both the enteric and central nervous systems. Indirectly and through as yet unknown mechanisms, the gut microbiota exerts control over the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis (HPA). This is clear from studies on animals raised in a germ-free environment, who show exaggerated responses to psychological stress, which normalises following monocolonisation by certain bacterial species including B. infantis. It is tempting to speculate that therapeutic targeting of the gut microbiota may be useful in treating stress-related disorders and metabolic diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Probiotic (L. reuteri NCIMB 30242 ) greately increased vitamin D levels for many – RCT</title><link>/posts/probiotic-l-reuteri-ncimb-30242-greately-increased-vitamin-d-levels-for-many-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/probiotic-l-reuteri-ncimb-30242-greately-increased-vitamin-d-levels-for-many-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="oral-supplementation-with-probiotic-l-reuteri-ncimb-30242-increases-mean-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-a-post-hoc-analysis-of-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Oral Supplementation With Probiotic L. reuteri NCIMB 30242 Increases Mean Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D: A Post Hoc Analysis of a Randomized Controlled Trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mitchell L. Jones*, Christopher J. Martoni*, and Satya Prakash&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism, Volume 98 Issue 7 - July 1, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1210/jc.2012-4262">http://dx.doi.org/10.1210/jc.2012-4262&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Context:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D is a risk factor for osteoporosis, cardiovascular disease, diabetes, and cancer. Disruption of noncholesterol sterol absorption due to cholesterol-lowering therapies may result in reduced fat-soluble vitamin absorption.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Probiotics reduced weight gain in mice for many weeks (proof of concept)</title><link>/posts/probiotics-reduced-weight-gain-in-mice-for-many-weeks-proof-of-concept.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/probiotics-reduced-weight-gain-in-mice-for-many-weeks-proof-of-concept.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Incorporation of therapeutically modified bacteria into gut microbiota inhibits obesity&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Clin Invest. doi:10.1172/JCI72517.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhongyi Chen1, Lilu Guo1, Yongqin Zhang1, Rosemary L. Walzem2, Julie S. Pendergast3, Richard L. Printz3, Lindsey C. Morris3, Elena Matafonova1, Xavier Stien1, Li Kang4, Denis Coulon5, Owen P. McGuinness4, Kevin D. Niswender3,4,6 and Sean S. Davies1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Clinical Pharmacology, Department of Medicine and Department of Pharmacology, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Nutrition and Food Science, Texas A&amp;amp;M University, College Station, Texas, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antibiotics and Vitamin D are associated with many of the same diseases</title><link>/posts/antibiotics-and-vitamin-d-are-associated-with-many-of-the-same-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/antibiotics-and-vitamin-d-are-associated-with-many-of-the-same-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="misc-notes-from-the-book-missing-microbes">Misc. notes from the book Missing Microbes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>100 &lt;strong>Million&lt;/strong> neurons in gut (vs 100 &lt;strong>Billion&lt;/strong> neurons in adult brain)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Author is very concerned about increased antibiotics ==&amp;gt; increased disease&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Author is extremely concerned about antibiotic resistance ==&amp;gt; world-wide pandemic - far worse than any in the past 500 years&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>17 antibiotic courses by age 20 in the US now (varies a lot with which state you live in - see map below)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One pill every two weeks gives you all the vitamin D most adults need</title><link>/posts/one-pill-every-two-weeks-gives-you-all-the-vitamin-d-most-adults-need.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/one-pill-every-two-weeks-gives-you-all-the-vitamin-d-most-adults-need.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-once-every-two-weeks-proven-to-preventtreat">50,000 IU of Vitamin D once every two weeks proven to prevent/treat:&lt;/h4>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start2 ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Diabetes + Heart Failure + Chronic Pain + Depression + Autism + Breast Cancer + Colon Cancer + Prostate Cancer + BPH (prostate) + Preeclampsia + Premature Birth + Falls + Cognitive Decline + Respiratory Tract Infection + Influenza + Tuberculosis + Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease + Lupus + Inflammatory Bowel Syndrome + Urinary Tract Infection + Poor Sleep + Growing Pain + Multiple Sclerosis + PMS + Schizophrenia + Endometriosis + Smoking&lt;/strong>     &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">27 problems&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Irritable Bowel Syndrome - can it be treated by 3000 IU of vitamin D - RCT</title><link>/posts/irritable-bowel-syndrome-can-it-be-treated-by-3000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/irritable-bowel-syndrome-can-it-be-treated-by-3000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF of proposed trial is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also trying with and without Probiotics&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using spray versions of Vitamin D and Probiotics&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See attached PDF&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-gut-and-vitamin-d">Overview Gut and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/inflammatory-bowel-diseases-are-helped-by-vitamin-d-commissioned-review">Inflammatory bowel diseases are helped by vitamin D – commissioned review Nov 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/solutions-if-have-poor-response-to-conventional-vitamin-d">Solutions if have poor response to conventional vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/irritable-bowel-syndrome-social-media-indicates-that-vitamin-d-is-a-good-treatment">Irritable Bowel Syndrome: social media indicates that vitamin D is a good treatment – Oct 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Hives treated by Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/chronic-hives-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-hives-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hives-urticaria-7x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficient-supplementation-helps--meta-analysis-april2021">Hives (Urticaria) 7X more likely if vitamin D deficient; supplementation helps – meta-analysis April 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hives-treated-by-28000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly--rct-aug2020">Hives treated by 28,000 IU of Vitamin D weekly – RCT Aug 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hives-treated-by-60000-iu-of-vitamin-d-every-two-weeks--rct-may2020">Hives treated by 60,000 IU of Vitamin D every two weeks – RCT May 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hives-treatment-augmented-by-60000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly--rct-june2015">Hives treatment augmented by 60,000 IU Vitamin D weekly – RCT June 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#beneficial-role-for-supplemental-vitamin-d3-treatment-in-chronic-urticaria-a-randomizedstudy">Beneficial role for supplemental vitamin D3 treatment in chronic urticaria: a randomized study.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-25-x-more-likely-with-hives---april2015">Vitamin D deficiency 2.5 X more likely with hives - April 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#chronic-urticaria-helped-by-300000-iu-of-vitamin-d-monthly-aug2015">Chronic Urticaria helped by 300,000 IU of vitamin D monthly Aug 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#chronic-urticaria-alternative-treatments-include-vitamin-d---march2023">Chronic Urticaria alternative treatments include vitamin D - March 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsoweb">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="hives-urticaria-7x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficient-supplementation-helps--meta-analysis-april2021">Hives (Urticaria) 7X more likely if vitamin D deficient; supplementation helps – meta-analysis April 2021&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/hives-urticaria-7x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficient-supplementation-helps-meta-analysis" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Hives (Urticaria) 7X more likely if vitamin D deficient, supplementation helps – meta-analysis April 2021">Hives (Urticaria) 7X more likely if vitamin D deficient, supplementation helps – meta-analysis April 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Toward predicting vitamin D levels without a blood test.</title><link>/posts/toward-predicting-vitamin-d-levels-without-a-blood-test.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/toward-predicting-vitamin-d-levels-without-a-blood-test.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#many-models-have-failed-to-predict-vitamin-d-levels-based-on-about-10-variables">Many models have failed to predict vitamin D levels based on about 10 variables.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki-is-considering-solving-all-of-the-above-problems">VitaminDWiki is considering solving all of the above problems&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#variablesquestions">Variables/questions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="many-models-have-failed-to-predict-vitamin-d-levels-based-on-about-10-variables">Many models have failed to predict vitamin D levels based on about 10 variables.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The problems appear to be due to:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Not enough variables in the model&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Not enough subjects&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Not powerful enough software/model&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Large variance between vitamin D testers ( 5% to 10%)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Not record other health influences - emotional stress as a child, antibiotics as a child&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Endometriosis treated, and perhaps prevented, by vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/endometriosis-treated-and-perhaps-prevented-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/endometriosis-treated-and-perhaps-prevented-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Introduction:&lt;br>
Endometrial tissue inside the uterus expands and then is shed during menstruation.&lt;br>
Sometimes the tissue attaches itself on the outside of the uterus or elsewhere in the body.&lt;br>
It continues to cycle in size with each menstrual cycle.&lt;br>
Normally the autoimmune system destroys these attachments.&lt;br>
There is some effort to call Endo an autoimmune disorder&lt;br>
Note: High-Dose Vitamin D + Magnesium + Omega-3 is claimed to &lt;a href="/posts/video-by-dr-coimbra-95-percent-of-auto-immune-cured-with-vitamin-d-in-high-doses">treat 95% of all autoimmune disorders&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of cancer and supplements includes vitamin D</title><link>/posts/review-of-cancer-and-supplements-includes-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-cancer-and-supplements-includes-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="integrating-dietary-supplements-into-cancer-care">Integrating Dietary Supplements Into Cancer Care&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Integr Cancer Ther September 2013 vol. 12 no. 5 369-384&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moshe Frenkel, MD1,2,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Donald I. Abrams, MD3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elena J. Ladas, MS, RD4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gary Deng, MD5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary Hardy, MD6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jillian L. Capodice, LAC, MS7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary F. Winegardner, PA-C, MPAS8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. K. Gubili, MS5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K. Simon Yeung, PharmD, MBA, LAc5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heidi Kussmann, ND, FABNO9&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keith I. Block, MD10&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1University of Texas, Houston, TX, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Oncology Institute, Meir Medical Center, Kfar Saba, Israel&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Probiotic (Lactobacillus reuteri) increased vitamin D levels 22 percent – RCT</title><link>/posts/probiotic-lactobacillus-reuteri-increased-vitamin-d-levels-22-percent-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/probiotic-lactobacillus-reuteri-increased-vitamin-d-levels-22-percent-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="oral-supplementation-with-probiotic-l-reuteri-ncimb-30242-increases-mean-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-a-post-hoc-analysis-of-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Oral Supplementation With Probiotic L. reuteri NCIMB 30242 Increases Mean Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D: A Post Hoc Analysis of a Randomized Controlled Trial&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Mitchell L. Jones*,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christopher J. Martoni* and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Satya Prakash&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Biomedical Technology and Cell Therapy Research Laboratory (M.L.J., S.P.), Department of Biomedical Engineering and Physiology, Artificial Cells and Organs Research Centre, Faculty of Medicine, McGill University, Montreal, Quebec H3A 2B4, Canada; and Micropharma Limited (M.L.J., C.J.M., S.P.), Montreal, Quebec H2W 2R2, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nutritional deficiencies of seasoned athletes (vitamin D is 2nd)</title><link>/posts/nutritional-deficiencies-of-seasoned-athletes-vitamin-d-is-2nd.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nutritional-deficiencies-of-seasoned-athletes-vitamin-d-is-2nd.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="clipped-from-tampa-timeshttpwwwtampabaycomnewshealtheven-health-conscious-people-can-be-nutrient-deficient-expert-says2133158">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.tampabay.com/news/health/even-health-conscious-people-can-be-nutrient-deficient-expert-says/2133158">Tampa Times&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="tackling-the-toughest-health-deficiency-of-all-motivation">Tackling the toughest health deficiency of all: motivation&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="dr-masleyhttpdrmasleycomindexhtml-spoke-at-spansportsmedconferenceorgspan-aug-3-2013">&lt;a href="http://drmasley.com/index.html">Dr. Masley&lt;/a> Spoke at &lt;span>[sportsmedconference.org]&lt;/span> Aug 3 2013&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The top 10 nutrient deficiencies that affect performance and aging in &amp;ldquo;seasoned athletes''&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fiber&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. Vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Long-chain omega-3 fats&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4. Calcium&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5. Magnesium&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>6. Vitamin K&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="7">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Trace minerals&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Probiotics&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Protein&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Mitochrondrial support&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Probiotics increased vitamin D levels 22 percent in those with excess cholesterol</title><link>/posts/probiotics-increased-vitamin-d-levels-22-percent-in-those-with-excess-cholesterol.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/probiotics-increased-vitamin-d-levels-22-percent-in-those-with-excess-cholesterol.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="oral-supplementation-with-probiotic-l-reuteri-ncimb-30242-increases-mean-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-a-post-hoc-analysis-of-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Oral supplementation with probiotic L. reuteri NCIMB 30242 increases mean circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D: a post-hoc analysis of a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013 Apr 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jones ML, Martoni CJ, Prakash S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Biomedical Technology and Cell Therapy Research Laboratory, Department of Biomedical Engineering and Physiology, Artificial Cells and Organs Research Centre, Faculty of Medicine, McGill University, 3775 University St, Montreal, QC, H3A 2B4, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Context:Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D is a risk factor for osteoporosis, cardiovascular disease, diabetes and cancer. Disruption of non-cholesterol sterol absorption due to cholesterol lowering therapies may result in reduced fat soluble vitamin absorption.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Acid Reflux drugs decrease Vitamin D and Magnesium</title><link>/posts/acid-reflux-drugs-decrease-vitamin-d-and-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/acid-reflux-drugs-decrease-vitamin-d-and-magnesium.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="acid-reflux-medications-are-big-drug-muggers-causing-many-side-effectshttpwwwhuffingtonpostcomsuzy-cohen-rphacid-reflux-medication-_b_2522466html20-huffingtonpost-jan-2013">&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/suzy-cohen-rph/acid-reflux-medication-_b_2522466.html%20">Acid Reflux Medications Are Big Drug Muggers Causing Many Side Effects&lt;/a> Huffingtonpost Jan 2013&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>PPI =&amp;ldquo;proton pump inhibitor” shut down the proton pumps in the stomach, examples are Prilosec and Prevacid.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The H2 antagonists block histamine, examples of these include Zantac and Pepcid.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Less absobtion of Folate, Iron, Vitamin B12 , Magnesium, Vitamin A, Calcium and Zinc, Probiotics, and Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Interview of Vitamin K2 and Calcium Paradox author by Dr. Mercola</title><link>/posts/interview-of-vitamin-k2-and-calcium-paradox-author-by-dr-mercola.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/interview-of-vitamin-k2-and-calcium-paradox-author-by-dr-mercola.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="youtube-2012httpwwwyoutubecomwatchvfymexqnostq-1-hour---concerning-ca-k2-and-ostoeporosis">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fYMExQNosTQ">YouTube, 2012&lt;/a> 1 hour - concerning Ca, K2 and Ostoeporosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="interview-of-author-by-mercolahttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20121216vitamin-k2aspxe_cid20121216_snl_art_1-dec-2012">&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2012/12/16/vitamin-k2.aspx?e_cid=20121216_SNL_Art_1">Interview of author by Mercola&lt;/a> Dec 2012&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostsvitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-2908vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox--2012-booka-review--and-table-of-contents-on-vitamindwiki">&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-k2-and-the-calcium-paradox-2012-book" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2908">Vitamin K2 and the Calcium Paradox – 2012 book&lt;/a> Review and table of contents on VitaminDWiki&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/kate.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostsoverview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-765overview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-da">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 765">Overview Vitamin K and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights in BLUE added by VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Little vitamin D in various types of milk</title><link>/posts/little-vitamin-d-in-various-types-of-milk.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/little-vitamin-d-in-various-types-of-milk.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="raw-or-heated-cow-milk-consumption-review-of-risks-and-benefits">Raw Or Heated Cow Milk Consumption: Review Of Risks And Benefits&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Food Control 12 October 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wendie L. Claeysa, , , Sabine Cardoena, Georges Daubeb, Jan De Blockc, Koen Dewettinckd, e, Katelijne Dierickd, f, Lieven De Zutterd, e, André Huyghebaertd, e, Hein Imberechtsd, f, Pierre Thiangeg, Yvan Vandenplash, Lieve Hermanc, d&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a DG Policy Control, Federal Agency for the Safety of the Food Chain (FASFC), Brussels, Belgium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b University of Liège, 4000 Liège, Belgium&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programmers Must Take Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/programmers-must-take-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/programmers-must-take-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-few-items-from-informed-forum-discussion-hackernewshttpnewsycombinatorcomitemid452473520">a few items from informed forum discussion: &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4524735%20">HackerNews&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="devilboy-15-days-ago-">Devilboy 15 days ago |&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Every day at about lunch time I go lie on the roof in the sun for 10 minutes - doctor&amp;rsquo;s orders. I also take D supplements but that alone was not enough to get my levels back to the normal range so I have to get some actual sun as often as I can too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a &amp;lsquo;damned if you do, damned if you don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rsquo; situation here in Australia: Approximately two in three Australians will be diagnosed with skin cancer before the age of 70, while approximately one out of three Australians have vitamin D deficiency&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D conferences and special issues - 2013</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-conferences-and-special-issues-2013.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-conferences-and-special-issues-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-graphics-and-url-links-are-in-the-doc-file-attached-at-the-bottom-of-this-page">The graphics and URL links are in the DOC file attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="started-by-dr-grant-sept-2012">Started by Dr. Grant Sept 2012&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="2014">2014&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-conference-in-england-april-23-25-2014">Vitamin D conference in England - April 23-25 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="ese--workshop-d--d1-calcium--metabolism----span-stylecolorf00janspan--2013-uae">ESE Workshop D: D1: CALCIUM METABOLISM &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Jan&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> 2013 UAE&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Disorders of the parathyroid glands, calcium, metabolism &amp;amp; bone and vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calcium handling and Vitamin D update&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypo and Hypercalcaemia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ese-hormones.org/meetings/2013/esecu2013/cases.aspx">http://www.ese-hormones.org/meetings/2013/esecu2013/cases.aspx&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cardiosource">CardioSource&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As of 09/04/12 &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">February &lt;/span>&lt;/strong> 8 - 9, 2013 Heart House Washington, D.C. &amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fertility problem (PCOS) reduced by vitamin D, etc: many studies</title><link>/posts/fertility-problem-pcos-reduced-by-vitamin-d-etc-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fertility-problem-pcos-reduced-by-vitamin-d-etc-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-risk-decreased-27-by-omega-3-mendelian-study--sept-2024">PCOS risk decreased 27% by Omega-3 (Mendelian study) – Sept 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-treatment-needs-about-3000-iu-of-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-sept-2024">PCOS treatment needs about 3,000 IU of Vitamin D - meta-analysis Sept 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#need-more-pcos-studies-with-3000-iu-dosing---meta-analysis-sept-2023">Need more PCOS studies with &amp;gt;3,000 IU dosing - meta-analysis Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-and-vitamin-d-a-clinical-appraisal---sept-2023">PCOS and vitamin D: a clinical appraisal - Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-is-more-than-just-a-fertility-problem---pcos-reduces-longevity-by-1-year---2023">PCOS is more than just a fertility problem - PCOS reduces longevity by 1 year - 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-appears-to-be-helped-by-vitamn-d-probiotics-omega-3-etc---meta-analysis-sept-2022">PCOS appears to be helped by Vitamn D, probiotics, Omega-3, etc - meta-analysis Sept 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-physiopathology-and-vitamin-d-deficiency---aug-2022">PCOS Physiopathology and Vitamin D Deficiency - Aug 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos---menstrual-frequency-improved-by-50000-iu-vitamin-dweek--low-calorie-diet---rct-may-2018">PCOS - menstrual frequency improved by 50,000 IU Vitamin D/week &amp;amp; low calorie diet - RCT May 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-problems-reduced-by-vitamin-d-plus-omega-3--rct-june-2018">PCOS problems reduced by Vitamin D plus Omega-3 – RCT June 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos--live-birth-strongly-a-function-of-vitamin-d-level--rct-may-2016">PCOS – Live birth strongly a function of vitamin D level – RCT May 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-decreased-by-23-x-with-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-feb-2017">PCOS decreased by 2.3 X with Vitamin D - meta-analysis Feb 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-problems-greatly-reduced-by-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly--oct-2015">PCOS problems greatly reduced by Vitamin D (50,000 IU weekly) – Oct 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#therapeutic-implications-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-in-overweight-women-with-polycystic-ovary-syndrome-8500-iu-2012">Therapeutic implications of vitamin D and calcium in overweight women with polycystic ovary syndrome. (8500 IU, 2012)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-seems-to-have-helped-pcos-somewhat-2012">Vitamin D seems to have helped PCOS somewhat (2012)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#probable-connection-antimüllerian-hormone-levels---april-2014-50000-iu-weekly-helped">Probable connection: antimüllerian hormone levels - April 2014 50,000 IU weekly helped&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#-30-ng-recommended-to-reduce-pcos-june-2014">&amp;gt; 30 ng recommended to reduce PCOS (June 2014)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-may-be-due-to-being-overweight---turkey-which-also-has-low-vit-d-oct-2014">PCOS may be due to being overweight - Turkey (which also has low Vit D) Oct 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#wikipedia-highlights-on-pcos">Wikipedia highlights on PCOS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-decreased-by-magnesium-zinc-calcium-and-200-iu-of-vitamind---march-2018">PCOS decreased by Magnesium, Zinc, Calcium, and 200 IU of VitaminD - March 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pcos-treatment-by-vitamin-d-is-aided-by-metformin---meta-analysis-feb-2024">PCOS treatment by Vitamin D is aided by Metformin - meta-analysis Feb 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="pcos-risk-decreased-27-by-omega-3-mendelian-study--sept-2024">PCOS risk decreased 27% by Omega-3 (Mendelian study) – Sept 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Causal relationship between fertility nutrients supplementation and PCOS risk: a Mendelian randomization study&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>