<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Genetics on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/genetics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Genetics on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/genetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Obese children have poor vitamin D genes (CYP27A1, CYP2R1, CYP27B1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/obese-children-have-poor-vitamin-d-genes-cyp27a1-cyp2r1-cyp27b1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/obese-children-have-poor-vitamin-d-genes-cyp27a1-cyp2r1-cyp27b1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;–-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;decreased-vitamin-d-bio-availability-with-altered-dna-methylation-of-its-metabolism-genes-in-association-with-the-metabolic-disorders-among-the-school-aged-children-with-degree-i-ii-and-iii-obesity&#34;&gt;Decreased vitamin D bio-availability with altered DNA methylation of its metabolism genes in association with the metabolic disorders among the school-aged children with degree I, II and III obesity&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Journal of Nutritional Biochemistry,  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnutbio.2024.109627&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnutbio.2024.109627&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Xueyi Jiang 1 †, Lulu Xia 2 †, Tiantian Tang 1, Xiuqin Fan 1, Rui Wang 1, Meichen Wang 2, Wenli Yang 2, Jie Yan 2, Kemin Qi 1, Ping Li 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obesity is strongly associated with disturbances of vitamin D (VD) metabolites in the animal models. However, the related epidemiological evidence is still controversial, especially the different degrees of obesity. Hence, in this present representative cross-sectional study, 106 obesity school-age children aged 7-12 years were included and divided into different subgroups as degree I (the age- and sex-specific BMI≥95th percentile, n=45), II (BMI ≥120% percentile, n=34) and III (BMI ≥140% percentile, n=27) obesity groups across the ranges of body mass index (BMI).. While the age- and sex-matched subjects without obesity were as the control group. Notably, it was significantly different of body composition, anthropological and clinical characteristics among the above four subgroups with the dose-response relationships (P&amp;lt;0.05). Moreover, comparing with the control group, the serum VD concentrations were higher, VD metabolites like 25(OH)D, 25(OH)D3 and 1,25(OH)2D, and related hydroxylases as CYP27A1, CYP2R1 and CYP27B1 were lower in the degree I, II and III obesity subgroups (P&amp;lt;0.05), which were more disorder with the anthropological and clinical characteristics as the obesity was worsen in a BMI-independent manner (P&amp;lt;0.05). However, there was a significant increase of CYP27B1 in the degree III obesity group than those in the degree I and II obesity subgroups. Furthermore, the methylation patterns on the genome-wide (Methylation/Hydroxymethylation) and VD metabolism genes (CYP27A1, CYP2R1 and CYP27B1) were negatively correlated with the worse obesity and their related expressions (P&amp;lt;0.05). In summary, these results indicated that obesity could affect the homeostasis of VD metabolism related genes such as CYP27A1, CYP2R1, CYP27B1 and etc through abnormal DNA methylation, resulting in the disorders of VD related metabolites to decrease VD bio-availability with the BMI-independent manner. In turn, the lower levels of VD metabolites would affect the liver function to exacerbate the progression of obesity, as the Degree II and III obesity subgroups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ischemic Stroke is 18% more likely if poor Vitamin D genes (unless take more Vitamin D)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ischemic-stroke-is-18-percent-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-genes-unless-take-more-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ischemic-stroke-is-18-percent-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-genes-unless-take-more-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;causal-effect-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-on-cardioembolic-stroke-evidence-from-two-sample-mendelian-randomization&#34;&gt;Causal effect of serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D concentration on cardioembolic stroke: Evidence from two-sample Mendelian randomization&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrition, Metabolism, and Cardiovascular Disease :&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.numecd.2024.02.013&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.numecd.2024.02.013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It seems that there are two groups of genes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genetically predicted serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D concentration is associated with the risk of cardioembolic stroke.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mendelian Randomization analysis provides suggestive evidence that increased 25(OH)D levels may play a protective role in the development of cardioembolic stroke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obese children had less gene methylation (gene not work as well)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/obese-children-had-less-gene-methylation-gene-not-work-as-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/obese-children-had-less-gene-methylation-gene-not-work-as-well/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;alterations-of-dna-methylation-profile-in-peripheral-blood-of-children-with-simple-obesity---march-2024&#34;&gt;Alterations of DNA methylation profile in peripheral blood of children with simple obesity - March 2024&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Health Inf Sci Syst. 2024 Mar 18;12(1):26. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13755-024-00275-w&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1007/s13755-024-00275-w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yi Ren # 1 2 3, Peng Huang # 1 2, Xiaoyan Huang 4, Lu Zhang 1 2, Lingjuan Liu 1 2, Wei Xiang 5 6 7, Liqun Liu 1 2, Xiaojie He 1 8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venn diagram which apparently shows differences in methylation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Purpose: To investigate the association between DNA methylation and childhood simple obesity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People with Multiple Sclerosis have blunted responses to Vitamin D supplementation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/people-with-multiple-sclerosis-have-blunted-responses-to-vitamin-d-supplementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/people-with-multiple-sclerosis-have-blunted-responses-to-vitamin-d-supplementation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;transcriptomics-identifies-blunted-immunomodulatory-effects-of-vitamin-d-in-people-with-multiple-sclerosis&#34;&gt;Transcriptomics identifies blunted immunomodulatory effects of vitamin D in people with multiple sclerosis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scientific Reports Vol 14, Article number: 1436 (2024)  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-51779-0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-51779-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wei Z. Yeh, Rodney Lea, Jim Stankovich, Sandeep Sampangi, Louise Laverick, Anneke Van der Walt, Vilija Jokubaitis, Melissa Gresle &amp;amp; Helmut Butzkueven&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D deficiency is a risk factor for developing multiple sclerosis (MS). However, the immune effects of vitamin D in people with MS are not well understood. We analyzed transcriptomic datasets generated by RNA sequencing of immune cell subsets (CD4+, CD8+ T cells, B cells, monocytes) from 33 healthy controls and 33 untreated MS cases. We utilized a traditional bioinformatic pipeline and weighted gene co-expression network analysis (WGCNA) to determine genes and pathways correlated with endogenous vitamin D. In controls, CD4+ and CD8+ T cells had 1079 and 1188 genes, respectively, whose expressions were correlated with plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D level (P &amp;lt; 0.05). Functional enrichment analysis identified association with TNF-alpha and MAPK signaling. In CD4+ T cells of controls, vitamin D level was associated with expression levels of several genes proximal to multiple sclerosis risk loci (P = 0.01). Genes differentially associated with endogenous vitamin D by case–control status were enriched in TNF-alpha signaling via NF-κB. WGCNA suggested a blunted response to vitamin D in cases relative to controls. Collectively, our findings provide further evidence for the immune effects of vitamin D, and demonstrate a differential immune response to vitamin D in cases relative to controls, highlighting a possible mechanism contributing to MS pathophysiology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D is associated with 6 genes, 7 receptors, and a new book</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-is-associated-with-6-genes-7-receptors-and-a-new-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-is-associated-with-6-genes-7-receptors-and-a-new-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;recent-advances-in-vitamin-d-biology-something-new-under-the-sun&#34;&gt;Recent Advances in Vitamin D Biology: Something New under the Sun&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J of Investigative Dermatology October 04, 2023 DOI:https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jid.2023.07.003&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Andrzej T. Slominski, Robert C. Tuckey, Anton M. Jetten. Michael F. Holick&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clinical Implications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternative pathways of vitamin D, lumisterol, and tachysterol activation were discovered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discovered secosteroidal hydroxyderivatives are biologically active in vitro and in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They can act on six nuclear receptors, alternatives to the vitamin D receptor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Many genes can restrict Vitamin D from getting to the cells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/many-genes-can-restrict-vitamin-d-from-getting-to-the-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/many-genes-can-restrict-vitamin-d-from-getting-to-the-cells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-an-overview-of-gene-regulation-ranging-from-metabolism-to-genomic-effects&#34;&gt;Vitamin D: An Overview of Gene Regulation, Ranging from Metabolism to Genomic Effects&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genes 2023, 14(9), 1691; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/genes14091691&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/genes14091691&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Giacomo Voltan 1,2ORCID,Michele Cannito 1,2ORCID,Michela Ferrarese 1,2ORCID,Filippo Ceccato 1,2,*ORCID andValentina Camozzi 1,2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Department of Medicine (DIMED), University of Padova, Via Giustiniani 2, 35128 Padova, Italy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Endocrinology Unit, Padova University Hospital, Via Ospedale Civile 105, 35128 Padova, Italy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Author to whom correspondence should be addressed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;pdf-table-of-contents&#34;&gt;PDF Table of Contents&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;vitamin-d-receptor-structure&#34;&gt;Vitamin D Receptor structure&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D is a pro-hormone characterized by an intricate metabolism and regulation. It is well known for its role in calcium and phosphate metabolism, and in bone health. However, several studies have assessed a huge number of extra-skeletal functions, ranging from cell proliferation in some oncogenic pathways to antioxidant and immunomodulatory functions. Vitamin D exerts its role by binding to VDRs (vitamin D receptors), which are located in many different tissues. Moreover, VDRs are able to bind hundreds of genomic loci, modulating the expression of various primary target genes. Interestingly, plenty of gene polymorphisms regarding VDRs are described, each one carrying a potential influence against gene expression, with relapses in several chronic diseases and metabolic complications. In this review, we provide an overview of the genetic aspects of vitamin D and VDR, emphasizing the gene regulation of vitamin D, and the genetic modulation of VDR target genes. In addition, we briefly summarize the rare genetic disease linked to vitamin D metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D and it’s related genes regulate the immune system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-and-its-related-genes-regulate-the-immune-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-and-its-related-genes-regulate-the-immune-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-review-of-the-critical-role-of-vitamin-d-axis-on-the-immune-system---aug-2023&#34;&gt;A review of the critical role of vitamin D axis on the immune system - Aug 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exp Mol Pathol. 2023 Aug 10;104866. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yexmp.2023.104866&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.yexmp.2023.104866&lt;/a&gt;   PDF not available&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gholamreza Daryabor 1, Nasser Gholijani 1, Fatemeh Rezaei Kahmini 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Autoimmune Diseases Research Center, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Autoimmune Diseases Research Center, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran; Department of Immunology, Faculty of Medical Sciences, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran. &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Fateme.rezaei@modares.ac.ir&#34;&gt;Fateme.rezaei@modares.ac.ir&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-COVID associated with 37 poor genes (no Vitamin D genes)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/long-covid-associated-with-37-poor-genes-no-vitamin-d-genes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/long-covid-associated-with-37-poor-genes-no-vitamin-d-genes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;host-genetic-polymorphisms-involved-in-long-term-symptoms-of-covid-19&#34;&gt;Host genetic polymorphisms involved in long-term symptoms of COVID-19&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; Emerging Microbes &amp;amp; Infections  Volume 12, 2023 - Issue 2 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/22221751.2023.2239952&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/22221751.2023.2239952&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wanvisa Udomsinprasert ORCID Icon ,Nuttakant Nontawong, Wacharapol Saengsiwaritt, Bhakbhoom Panthan,Poramate Jiaranai,Nartthawee Thongchompoo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Host genetic polymorphisms are recognized as a critical determinant of diversity in clinical symptoms of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Accordingly, this study aimed to determine possible associations between single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in 37 candidate genetic variants and clinical consequences of COVID-19 – especially long-term symptoms, Long COVID. A total of 260 COVID-19 patients, divided into mild (n = 239) and severe (n = 21) and further categorized based on the presence of Long COVID (no, n = 211; yes, n = 49), were recruited. Genotyping of selected polymorphisms responsible for viral entry, immune response, and inflammation was performed using MassARRAY system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telomeres and Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/telomeres-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/telomeres-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange12span-vitamindwiki-pages-with-telomere-in-the-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;12+&lt;/span&gt; VitaminDWiki pages with TELOMERE in the title&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{list max=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;TELOMERE &#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;s&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; shownbitems=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xA;&#xA;{column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=title format=&amp;ldquo;objectlink&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;plant-based-diet-associated-with-longer-telomeres---dr-greger-july-2023&#34;&gt;Plant-based diet associated with longer Telomeres - Dr. Greger July 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nutritionfacts.org/video/greens-green-tea-and-nuts-put-to-the-test-for-telomeres/?subscriber=true&amp;amp;utm_source=NutritionFacts.org&amp;amp;utm_campaign=aa18a4504e-EMAIL_CAMPAIGN_7_26_2022_12_48_COPY_01&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_term=0_40f9e497d1-aa18a4504e-25209481&amp;amp;mc_cid=aa18a4504e&amp;amp;mc_eid=b95641625a&#34;&gt;Greens, Green Tea, and Nuts Put to the Test for Telomeres&lt;/a&gt; video and transcript&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Vitamin D genes (Most are not noticed by blood test)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/12-vitamin-d-genes-most-are-not-noticed-by-blood-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/12-vitamin-d-genes-most-are-not-noticed-by-blood-test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;association-between-polymorphisms-in-vitamin-d-pathway-related-genes-vitamin-d-status-muscle-mass-and-function-a-systematic-review&#34;&gt;Association between Polymorphisms in Vitamin D Pathway-Related Genes, Vitamin D Status, Muscle Mass and Function: A Systematic Review&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2021, 13(9), 3109; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu13093109&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu13093109&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Ermira Krasniqi 1,2,3ORCID,Arben Boshnjaku 2,4ORCID, Karl-Heinz Wagner 1,3ORCID and Barbara Wessner 1,2,*ORCID&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Research Platform Active Ageing, University of Vienna, Althanstraße 14, 1090 Vienna, Austria&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Centre for Sport Science and University Sports, University of Vienna, Auf der Schmelz 6, 1150 Vienna, Austria&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Vienna, Althanstraße 14, 1090 Vienna, Austria&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D Health problems can run in families (epigenetics, they miss other reasons) – June 2023)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-health-problems-can-run-in-families-epigenetics-they-miss-other-reasons-june-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-health-problems-can-run-in-families-epigenetics-they-miss-other-reasons-june-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-epigenetics-on-vitamin-d-levels-a-systematic-review-until-december-2020&#34;&gt;Effect of epigenetics on vitamin D levels: a systematic review until December 2020&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arch Public Health. 2023 Jun 15;81(1):106. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s13690-023-01122-2.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1186/s13690-023-01122-2.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ali Forouhari 1, Motahar Heidari-Beni 2, Shaahin Veisi 3, Parnian Poursafa 4, Roya Kelishadi 5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: The association between epigenetic modification of the genes involved in the vitamin D metabolic pathway and vitamin D metabolites&amp;rsquo; status has been elucidated incompletely. This study aims to review the studies on the mentioned association and create a brighter view of this topic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off Topic: DNA data finally being used to identify diseases caused by genes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/off-topic-dna-data-finally-being-used-to-identify-diseases-caused-by-genes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/off-topic-dna-data-finally-being-used-to-identify-diseases-caused-by-genes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;new-ai-tool-searches-genetic-haystacks-to-find-disease-causing-variants&#34;&gt;New AI tool searches genetic haystacks to find disease-causing variants&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/science/2023/06/01/primate-ai-genome-variants/?utm_campaign=wp_the_optimist&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;amp;wpisrc=nl_optimist&amp;amp;carta-url=https%3A%2F%2Fs2.washingtonpost.com%2Fcar-ln-tr%2F3a2e1f3%2F647c8b64e49da13a6d45e983%2F596bdb5f9bbc0f403f990f33%2F28%2F44%2F647c8b64e49da13a6d45e983&#34;&gt;Washington Post $$&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The scientists built the algorithm, called PrimateAI-3D, using the genetic blueprints of 233 different primate species. This base brings into sharp relief the variants that can be tolerated by primates, including humans, and those that prove deadly. Scientists look for places where the sequence is the same from one primate to another, a clear sign that any change is disastrous.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cervical Cancer is prevented by Vitamin D, and treated if caught early (genes are important)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cervical-cancer-is-prevented-by-vitamin-d-and-treated-if-caught-early-genes-are-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cervical-cancer-is-prevented-by-vitamin-d-and-treated-if-caught-early-genes-are-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-preventive-role-of-the-vitamin-d-endocrine-system-in-cervical-cancer&#34;&gt;The Preventive Role of the Vitamin D Endocrine System in Cervical Cancer&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Int J Mol Sci. 2023 May 12;24(10):8665. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms24108665.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/ijms24108665.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Euclides Avila 1, Bryan Javier Noriega-Mejía 1, Jocelyn González-Macías 1, Ulises Cortes-Hernández 1, Janice García-Quiroz 1, Rocío García-Becerra 2, Lorenza Díaz 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D along with its active metabolite calcitriol and its metabolic and signaling system, known as the vitamin D endocrine system, have been widely recognized as a pivotal regulator of calcium homeostasis in addition to non-calcemic antitumoral effects in a variety of human cancers, including cervical cancer. Several studies have found an inverse relationship between the incidence of cervical neoplasia and vitamin D levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Multiple Sclerosis while younger if have a poor CYP24A1 vitamin D gene</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/get-multiple-sclerosis-while-younger-if-have-a-poor-cyp24a1-vitamin-d-gene/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/get-multiple-sclerosis-while-younger-if-have-a-poor-cyp24a1-vitamin-d-gene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-cyp24a1-gene-variant-rs2762943-is-associated-with-low-serum-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-multiple-sclerosis-patients&#34;&gt;The CYP24A1 gene variant rs2762943 is associated with low serum 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D levels in multiple sclerosis patients&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eur J Neurol . 2023 May 14. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.15866&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1111/ene.15866&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sunny Malhotra # 1, Luciana Midaglia # 1, Omar Chuquisana 2, Nikolaos A Patsopoulos 3 4 5, Roser Ferrer 6, Marina Giralt 6, Nicolas Fissolo 1, Elia Gil-Varea 1, Juan Carlos Triviño 7, Jan D Lünemann 2, Xavier Montalban 1, Manuel Comabella 1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>100 years since the discovery of Vitamin D - 23 studies - 2022, 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/100-years-since-the-discovery-of-vitamin-d-23-studies-2022-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/100-years-since-the-discovery-of-vitamin-d-23-studies-2022-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;||Carsten Carlberg| A Pleiotropic Nuclear Hormone Labelled Hundred Years Ago Vitamin D&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Michael F. Holick| The One-Hundred-Year Anniversary of the Discovery of the Sunshine Vitamin D3: Historical, Personal Experience and Evidence-Based Perspectives&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Carsten Carlberg| Vitamin D in the Context of Evolution&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shahid Hussain, Clayton Yates and Moray J. Campbell| Vitamin D and Systems Biology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Carsten Carlberg| Vitamin D and Its Target Genes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Natacha Rochel| Vitamin D and Its Receptor from a Structural Perspective&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gestational Diabetes and Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gestational-diabetes-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gestational-diabetes-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;gestational-diabetes-30-increase-in-us-since-2016-reported-july-2023&#34;&gt;Gestational Diabetes: 30% increase in US since 2016 (reported July 2023)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trialsitenews.com/a/osu-wexner-med-center-partners-lead-12m-study-targeting-rising-gestational-diabetes-aa37599d&#34;&gt;Gestational diabetes impacts nearly 75,000 pregnant individuals and their unborn babies each year in the United States, and according to the Centers for Disease Control cases have risen 30% since 2016.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which is probably similar to the increase of Diabetes in the same time period&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;disrupted-placental-vitamin-d-metabolism-and-calcium-signaling-in-gestational-diabetes-and-pre-eclampsia-patients---april-2023&#34;&gt;Disrupted placental vitamin D metabolism and calcium signaling in gestational diabetes and pre-eclampsia patients - April 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Endocrine . 2023 Apr;80(1):191-200. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s12020-022-03272-9&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1007/s12020-022-03272-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breast Cancer chemotherapy improved if able to suppress a vitamin D gene (CYP24A1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-improved-if-able-to-suppress-a-vitamin-d-gene-cyp24a1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-improved-if-able-to-suppress-a-vitamin-d-gene-cyp24a1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;suppression-of-the-vitamin-d-metabolizing-enzyme-cyp24a1-provides-increased-sensitivity-to-chemotherapeutic-drugs-in-breast-cancer&#34;&gt;Suppression of the vitamin D metabolizing enzyme CYP24A1 provides increased sensitivity to chemotherapeutic drugs in breast cancer&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oncol Rep . 2023 May;49(5):85. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3892/or.2023.8522&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3892/or.2023.8522&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sakura Kamiya 1, Yuna Nakamori 1, Akira Takasawa 1, Kumi Takasawa 1, Daisuke Kyuno 1, Yusuke Ono 1, Kazufumi Magara 1, Makoto Osanai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D is an essential nutrient for the human body not only for the metabolism of calcium but also for homeostasis. Vitamin D contributes to cell fate decisions, including cell proliferation, differentiation and viability. Accumulated epidemiological data suggest a relationship between vitamin D deficiency and carcinogenesis in numerous organs. Furthermore, it is known that the expression of the vitamin D metabolizing enzyme, cytochrome P450 family 24 subtype A1 (CYP24A1), is increased in different types of human malignancy including breast carcinoma. However, the pathological relevance of elevated CYP24A1 expression level requires further clarification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parkinson’s Disease, low vitamin D and Vit. D genetics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/parkinsons-disease-low-vitamin-d-and-vit-d-genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/parkinsons-disease-low-vitamin-d-and-vit-d-genetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-deficiency-and-genetic-polymorphisms-of-vitamin-d-associated-genes-in-parkinsons-disease&#34;&gt;Vitamin D deficiency and genetic polymorphisms of Vitamin D-associated genes in Parkinson’s Disease&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;European Journal of Neuroscience preprint DOI: 10.22541/au.167407862.25881100/v1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Barnali Ray Basu1, Randrita Pal1, Supriyo Choudhury2, Hrishikesh Kumar2, Sanjit Dey3, and Nilansu Das1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1Surendranath College&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Institute of Neurosciences Kolkata&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3University of Calcutta Faculty Council for Post-Graduate Studies in Science&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parkinson’s Disease (PD) and vitamin D share a unique link as Vitamin D deficiency (VDD) prevails in PD. Thus, an in-depth understanding of Vitamin D biology in PD might be crucial for therapeutic strategies emphasizing Vitamin D. Specifically, explicating the effect of VDD and genetic polymorphisms of vitamin D-associated genes in PD, like&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CYP2R1 gene reduces response to Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyp2r1-gene-reduces-response-to-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyp2r1-gene-reduces-response-to-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People with a poor CYP2R1 genes are poor Vitamin D responders%%%    Possible solution: take larger doses of Vitamin D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamindwiki---geneticscategoriesgenetics-chart-shows-the-vitamin-d-genes&#34;&gt;VitaminDWiki - &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/categories/genetics&#34;&gt;Genetics&lt;/a&gt; chart shows the vitamin D genes&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;genes-and-other-reasons-for-poor-blood-response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation&#34;&gt;Genes and other reasons for poor blood response to Vitamin D supplementation&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/poor-or-no-response-to-vitamin-d-was-associated-with-poor-genes-cystic-fibrosis-4-genes&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Poor or no response to vitamin D was associated with poor genes (cystic fibrosis, 4 genes) Sept 2022&#34;&gt;Poor or no response to vitamin D was associated with poor genes (cystic fibrosis, 4 genes) Sept 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
