<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Genetics on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/genetics.html</link><description>Recent content in Genetics on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/genetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unsure of association of vitamin D and prostate Cancer - 2011</title><link>/posts/unsure-of-association-of-vitamin-d-and-prostate-cancer-2011.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/unsure-of-association-of-vitamin-d-and-prostate-cancer-2011.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Learning about MS and vitamin D in offspring from mice</title><link>/posts/learning-about-ms-and-vitamin-d-in-offspring-from-mice.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/learning-about-ms-and-vitamin-d-in-offspring-from-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="seasonal-gestational-and-postnatal-influences-on-multiple-sclerosis-the-beneficial-role-of-a-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-early-life">Seasonal, gestational and postnatal influences on multiple sclerosis: The beneficial role of a vitamin D supplementation during early life.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Neurol Sci. 2011 Sep 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fernandes de Abreu DA, Landel V, Féron F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is now strong evidence linking vitamin D, the steroid hormone of sunlight, and Multiple Sclerosis (MS).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two of the most intriguing findings are the season of birth and childhood sun exposure effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They both suggest that a vitamin D deficiency during these critical imprinting periods is a risk factor for MS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast cancer and Vitamin D receptors, CP27B1, and CYP24A1</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d-receptors-cp27b1-and-cyp24a1.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d-receptors-cp27b1-and-cyp24a1.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="alterations-in-vitamin-d-signalling-and-metabolic-pathways-in-breast-cancer-progression-a-study-of-vdr-cyp27b1-and-cyp24a1-expression-in-benign-and-malignant-breast-lesions">Alterations in Vitamin D signalling and metabolic pathways in breast cancer progression: a study of VDR, CYP27B1 and CYP24A1 expression in benign and malignant breast lesions&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Cancer 2010, 10:483 doi:10.1186/1471-2407-10-483&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nair Lopes (&lt;a href="mailto:nlopes@ipatimup.pt">nlopes@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Barbara Sousa (&lt;a href="mailto:bsousa@ipatimup.pt">bsousa@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Diana Martins (&lt;a href="mailto:dianam@ipatimup.pt">dianam@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Madalena Gomes (&lt;a href="mailto:mgomes@ipatimup.pt">mgomes@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Daniella Vieira (&lt;a href="mailto:daniellavieira.hu@gmail.com">daniellavieira.hu@gmail.com&lt;/a>) Luiz A Veronese (&lt;a href="mailto:lveronese@terra.com.br">lveronese@terra.com.br&lt;/a>) Fernanda Milanezi (&lt;a href="mailto:mmilanezi@ipatimup.pt">mmilanezi@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Joana Paredes (&lt;a href="mailto:jparedes@ipatimup.pt">jparedes@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jose L Costa (&lt;a href="mailto:jcosta@ipatimup.pt">jcosta@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Fernando Schmitt (&lt;a href="mailto:fschmitt@ipatimup.pt">fschmitt@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Publication date 11 September 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nair Lopes1, Barbara Sousa1, Diana Martins1, Madalena Gomes1, Daniella Vieira2, Luiz A Veronese3, Fernanda Milanezi1, Joana Paredes1, Jose L Costa1, Fernando Schmitt1, 4&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CYP24A1 gene mutation is a cause of rare infant vitamin D toxicity</title><link>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-mutation-is-a-cause-of-rare-infant-vitamin-d-toxicity.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-mutation-is-a-cause-of-rare-infant-vitamin-d-toxicity.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mutations-in-cyp24a1-and-idiopathic-infantile-hypercalcemia">Mutations in CYP24A1 and Idiopathic Infantile Hypercalcemia.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med. 2011 Jun 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schlingmann KP, Kaufmann M, Weber S, Irwin A, Goos C, John U, Misselwitz J, Klaus G, Kuwertz-Bröking E, Fehrenbach H, Wingen AM, Güran T, Hoenderop JG, Bindels RJ, Prosser DE, Jones G, Konrad M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Muenster (K.P.S., E.K.-B., M. Konrad); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Marburg (K.P.S., C.G.); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Essen (S.W., A.M.W.); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Jena (U.J., J.M.); Kuratorium für Heimdialyse Pediatric Kidney Center, Marburg (G.K.); and Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Memmingen (H.F.) - all in Germany; Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, ON, Canada (M. Kaufmann, A.I., D.E.P., G.J.); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey (T.G.); and Radboud University, Nijmegen, the Netherlands (J.G.H., R.J.B.).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Genes varied seasonally with European but not Asian ancestors – VDBP</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-genes-varied-seasonally-with-european-but-not-asian-ancestors-vdbp.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-genes-varied-seasonally-with-european-but-not-asian-ancestors-vdbp.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-of-vitamin-d-binding-protein-vdbp-polymorphisms-and-serum-25ohd-concentrations-in-a-sample-of-young-canadian-adults-of-different-ancestry">Association of vitamin D binding protein (VDBP) polymorphisms and serum 25(OH)D concentrations in a sample of young Canadian adults of different ancestry&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Agnes Gozdzika, &lt;a href="mailto:agnes.gozdzik@utoronto.ca">agnes.gozdzik@utoronto.ca&lt;/a> , Justin Zhub, Betty Y.-L. Wongb, Lei Fub, David E.C. Coleb, and Esteban J. Parraa,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Anthropology, University of Toronto at Mississauga, 3359 Mississauga Road North, Mississauga, Ontario L5L 1C6, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathobiology, University of Toronto, Banting Institute, 100 College Street, Toronto, Ontario M5G 1L5, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prostate Cancer – Vitamin D – CYP27B1 – CYP24</title><link>/posts/prostate-cancer-vitamin-d-cyp27b1-cyp24.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prostate-cancer-vitamin-d-cyp27b1-cyp24.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-metabolism-and-action-in-the-prostate-implications-for-health-and-disease">Vitamin D metabolism and action in the prostate: Implications for health and disease.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-metabolism-and-action-in-the-prostate-implications-for-health-and-disease">Vitamin D metabolism and action in the prostate: Implications for health and disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2011 Jun 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Swami S, Krishnan AV, Feldman D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, CA 94305, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prostate cancer (PCa) is the second most common cancer in men worldwide. Epidemiological, molecular, and cellular studies have implicated vitamin D deficiency as a risk factor for the development and/or progression of PCa. Studies using cell culture systems and animal models suggest that vitamin D acts to reduce the growth of PCa through regulation of cellular proliferation and differentiation. However, although preclinical studies provide a strong indication for anti-cancer activity, proof of therapeutic benefits in men is still lacking. The anti-proliferative and pro-differentiating properties of vitamin D have been attributed to calcitriol &lt;span>[1,25(OH)(2)D(3)]&lt;/span>, the hormonally active form of vitamin D, acting through the vitamin D receptor (VDR). Metabolism of vitamin D in target tissues is mediated by two key enzymes: 1?-hydroxylase (CYP27B1), which catalyzes the synthesis of calcitriol from 25(OH)D and 24-hydroxylase (CYP24), which catalyzes the initial step in the conversion of calcitriol to less active metabolites. Many factors affect the balance of calcitriol synthesis and catabolism and several maneuvers, like combination therapy of calcitriol with other drugs, have been explored to treat PCa and reduce its risk. The current paper is an overview addressing some of the key factors that influence the biological actions of vitamin D and its metabolites in the treatment and/or prevention of PCa.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genetic influence on Vitamin D is small compared to environmental influence</title><link>/posts/genetic-influence-on-vitamin-d-is-small-compared-to-environmental-influence.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genetic-influence-on-vitamin-d-is-small-compared-to-environmental-influence.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="determinants-of-vitamin-d-status-focus-on-genetic-variations">Determinants of vitamin D status: focus on genetic variations.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens. 2011 Jul;20(4):331-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Berry D, Hyppönen E. &lt;a href="mailto:e.hypponen@ich.ucl.ac.uk">e.hypponen@ich.ucl.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Paediatric Epidemiology and Biostatistics and Medical Research Council Centre for the Epidemiology of Child Health, UCL Institute of Child Health, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE OF REVIEW:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of vitamin D beyond its importance for bone health is under much debate. In this article, we review recent evidence for genetic influences on 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> and discuss the uses of this information and its importance for public health.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D targets 4 MS genes</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-targets-4-ms-genes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-targets-4-ms-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="genetics-and-the-environment-converge-to-dysregulate-n-glycosylation-in-multiple-sclerosis">Genetics and the environment converge to dysregulate N-glycosylation in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nature Communications, Article number: 334, doi:10.1038/ncomms1333&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Haik Mkhikian, Ani Grigorian, Carey F. Li, Hung-Lin Chen, Barbara Newton, Raymond W. Zhou, Christine Beeton, Sevan Torossian, Gevork Grikor Tatarian, Sung-Uk Lee, Ken Lau, Erin Walker, Katherine A. Siminovitch, K. George Chandy, Zhaoxia Yu, James W. Dennis. &lt;strong>Michael Demetriou&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="mailto:mdemetri@uci.edu">mdemetri@uci.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received – 02 February 2011, Accepted – 04 May 2011, Published – 31 May 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Melanoma and Vitamin D genes - multiple papers</title><link>/posts/melanoma-and-vitamin-d-genes-multiple-papers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/melanoma-and-vitamin-d-genes-multiple-papers.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki-summary-melanoma-27-more-likely-with-bsmi-variant-of-vitamin-d-receptor-2011">VitaminDWiki Summary: Melanoma 27% more likely with BsmI variant of vitamin D receptor (2011)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#melanoma-risk-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-march-2014">Melanoma risk is associated with vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms (March 2014)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="vitamindwiki-summary-melanoma-27-more-likely-with-bsmi-variant-of-vitamin-d-receptor-2011">VitaminDWiki Summary: Melanoma 27% more likely with BsmI variant of vitamin D receptor (2011)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sun exposure, vitamin D receptor polymorphisms FokI and BsmI and risk of multiple primary melanoma&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiol. 2011 May 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mandelcorn-Monson R, Marrett L, Kricker A, Armstrong BK, Orlow I, Goumas C, Paine S, Rosso S, Thomas N, Millikan RC, Pole JD, Cotignola J, Rosen C, Kanetsky PA, Lee-Taylor J, Begg CB, Berwick M.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Race vs vitamin D level - Veith</title><link>/posts/race-vs-vitamin-d-level-veith.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/race-vs-vitamin-d-level-veith.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Type 1 diabetes, genes and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-genes-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-genes-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="two-abstracts-on-this-page">two abstracts on this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolor00fhypothesis--three-genes-show-why-type-1-diabetes-patients-need-more-vitamin-d--mar-2011span">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Hypothesis – Three genes show why type 1 diabetes patients need more vitamin D – Mar 2011&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="inherited-variation-in-vitamin-d-genes-is-associated-with-predisposition-to-autoimmune-disease-type-1-diabetes">Inherited Variation in Vitamin D Genes Is Associated With Predisposition to Autoimmune Disease Type 1 Diabetes.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Diabetes. 2011 Mar 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cooper JD, Smyth DJ, Walker NM, Stevens H, Burren OS, Wallace C, Greissl C, Ramos-Lopez E, Hypponen E, Dunger DB, Spector TD, Ouwehand WH, Wang TJ, Badenhoop K, Todd JA. &lt;a href="mailto:john.todd@cimr.cam.ac.uk">john.todd@cimr.cam.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unable to find a gene linking vitamin D and MS</title><link>/posts/unable-to-find-a-gene-linking-vitamin-d-and-ms.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/unable-to-find-a-gene-linking-vitamin-d-and-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-metabolic-pathway-genes-and-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-canadians">Vitamin D metabolic pathway genes and risk of multiple sclerosis in Canadians.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Neurol Sci. 2011 Mar 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Orton SM, Ramagopalan SV, Para AE, Lincoln MR, Handunnetthi L, Chao MJ, Morahan J, Morrison KM, Sadovnick AD, Ebers GC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wellcome Trust Centre for Human Genetics and Department of Clinical Neurology, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Multiple sclerosis (MS) is determined by interactions between genes and environment and the influence of vitamin D adequacy has been proposed. Previous studies have shown that serum 25-hydroxyvitaminD (25(OH)D) levels are genetically influenced. Polymorphisms in vitamin D pathway genes are candidates for association with MS susceptibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CYP24A1 gene and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;!-- ~tc~start2 ~/tc~ -->
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Proper activation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>makes sure that Vitamin D does not accumulate in the body&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Too much activation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Less vitamin D actually gets to cells&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Too little activation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Vitamin D accumulates to toxic levels ( &amp;lt;1 in 10,000 people)&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Blood test does not show when a poor CYP24A1 gene stops Vitamin D from getting to cells&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="400"> &lt;a href="/categories/genetics">Click here for more information&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several Cancers and health problems appear to protect themselves by changing CYP24A1 activation&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>People with TB and one geneotype benefited more from 10000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/people-with-tb-and-one-geneotype-benefited-more-from-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-tb-and-one-geneotype-benefited-more-from-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-dose-vitamin-d3-during-intensive-phase-antimicrobial-treatment-of-pulmonary-tuberculosis-a-double-blind-randomised-controlled-trial">High-dose vitamin D(3) during intensive-phase antimicrobial treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis: a double-blind randomised controlled trial.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Lancet. 2011 Jan 15;377(9761):242-50. Epub 2011 Jan 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martineau AR, Timms PM, Bothamley GH, Hanifa Y, Islam K, Claxton AP, Packe GE, Moore-Gillon JC, Darmalingam M, Davidson RN, Milburn HJ, Baker LV, Barker RD, Woodward NJ, Venton TR, Barnes KE, Mullett CJ, Coussens AK, Rutterford CM, Mein CA, Davies GR, Wilkinson RJ, Nikolayevskyy V, Drobniewski FA, Eldridge SM, Griffiths CJ.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolites and genes may predict responses to Calcium and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/metabolites-and-genes-may-predict-responses-to-calcium-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolites-and-genes-may-predict-responses-to-calcium-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="genomic-and-metabolomic-patterns-segregate-with-responses-to-calcium-and-vitamin-d-supplementation">Genomic and metabolomic patterns segregate with responses to calcium and vitamin D supplementation.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2011 Jan;105(1):71-9. Epub 2010 Aug 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elnenaei MO, Chandra R, Mangion T, Moniz C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical Biochemistry Department, King&amp;rsquo;s College Hospital, Denmark Hill, London SE5 9RS, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inter-individual response differences to vitamin D and Ca supplementation may be under genetic control through vitamin D and oestrogen receptor genes, which may influence their absorption and/or metabolism. Metabolomic studies on blood and urine from subjects supplemented with Ca and vitamin D reveal different metabolic profiles that segregate with genotype. Genotyping was performed for oestrogen receptor 1 gene (ESR1) and vitamin D receptor gene (VDR) in fifty-six postmenopausal women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twins reduction in vitamin D in the winter or summer</title><link>/posts/twins-reduction-in-vitamin-d-in-the-winter-or-summer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/twins-reduction-in-vitamin-d-in-the-winter-or-summer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="heritability-and-seasonal-variability-of-vitamin-d-concentrations-in-male-twins">Heritability and seasonal variability of vitamin D concentrations in male twins.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2010 Oct 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karohl C, Su S, Kumari M, Tangpricha V, Veledar E, Vaccarino V, Raggi P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Medicine and the Division of Endocrinology, Metabolism and Lipids, Department of Medicine, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, and the Division of Nephrology, Hospital de Clínicas de Porto Alegre, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schizophrenia and vitamin D have latitude-related genes</title><link>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-related-genes-could-have-been-subject-to-latitude-driven-adaptation">Schizophrenia and Vitamin D Related Genes Could Have Been Subject to Latitude-driven Adaptation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Roberto Amato email, Michele Pinelli email, Antonella Monticelli email, Gennaro Miele email and Sergio Cocozza email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Evolutionary Biology 2010, 10:351doi:10.1186/1471-2148-10-351; Published: 	11 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many natural phenomena are directly or indirectly related to latitude. Living at different latitudes, indeed, has its consequences with being exposed to different climates, diets, light/dark cycles, etc. In humans, one of the best known examples of genetic traits following a latitudinal gradient is skin pigmentation. Nevertheless, also several diseases show latitudinal clinals such as hypertension, cancer, dismetabolic conditions, schizophrenia, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease and many more.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>