<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Genetics on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/genetics.html</link><description>Recent content in Genetics on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/genetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Response to Vitamin D3 varied with rs4588, D2 less response than D3 and did not change</title><link>/posts/response-to-vitamin-d3-varied-with-rs4588-d2-less-response-than-d3-and-did-not-change.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/response-to-vitamin-d3-varied-with-rs4588-d2-less-response-than-d3-and-did-not-change.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="changes-in-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-according-to-vitamin-d-binding-protein-genotypes-after-vitamin-d-or-d-supplementation">Changes in circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D according to vitamin D binding protein genotypes after vitamin D₃ or D₂ supplementation.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nutr J. 2013 Apr 4;12:39. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1475-2891-12-39.">doi: 10.1186/1475-2891-12-39.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nimitphong H, Saetung S, Chanprasertyotin S, Chailurkit LO, Ongphiphadhanakul B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Ramathibodi Hospital, Mahidol University, Rama 6 Rd, Rajthevi, Bangkok 10400, Thailand. &lt;a href="mailto:hataikarnn@hotmail.com">hataikarnn@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: It is not known whether genetic variation in the vitamin D binding protein (DBP) influences 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> after vitamin D supplementation. We aimed to investigate the changes of total 25(OH)D, 25(OH)D₃ and 25(OH)D₂ in a Thai cohort, according to type of vitamin D supplement (vitamin D₃ or D₂) and DBP genotype, after receiving vitamin D₃ or D₂ for 3 months.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>40 percent less likely to get adequate vitamin D response if have certain genes</title><link>/posts/40-percent-less-likely-to-get-adequate-vitamin-d-response-if-have-certain-genes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/40-percent-less-likely-to-get-adequate-vitamin-d-response-if-have-certain-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-intake-and-season-modify-the-effects-of-the-gc-and-cyp2r1-genes-on-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations">Vitamin D intake and season modify the effects of the GC and CYP2R1 genes on 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2013 Jan;143(1):17-26. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3945/jn.112.169482.">doi: 10.3945/jn.112.169482.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Nov 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Engelman CD, Meyers KJ, Iyengar SK, Liu Z, Karki CK, Igo RP Jr, Truitt B, Robinson J, Sarto GE, Wallace R, Blodi BA, Klein ML, Tinker L, LeBlanc ES, Jackson RD, Song Y, Manson JE, Mares JA, Millen AE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Population Health Sciences, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, Madison, WI, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:cengelman@wisc.edu">cengelman@wisc.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migration to Northern Latitudes enabled by mutation of gene: DHCR7 resulting in more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/migration-to-northern-latitudes-enabled-by-mutation-of-gene-dhcr7-resulting-in-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/migration-to-northern-latitudes-enabled-by-mutation-of-gene-dhcr7-resulting-in-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="dhcr7-mutations-linked-to-higher-vitamin-d-status-allowed-early-human-migration-to-northern-latitudes">DHCR7 Mutations linked to higher vitamin D status allowed early human migration to Northern Latitudes.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>BMC Evol Biol. 2013 Jul 9;13(1):144.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kuan V, Martineau AR, Griffiths CJ, Hyppönen E, Walton R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D is essential for a wide range of physiological processes including immune function and calcium homeostasis. Recent investigations have identified candidate genes which are strongly linked to concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D. Since there is insufficient UVB radiation to induce year-round cutaneous synthesis of vitamin D at latitudes distant from the equator it is likely that these genes were subject to forces of natural selection. We used the fixation index (FST) to measure differences in allele frequencies in 993 individuals from ten populations to identify the presence of evolutionary selection in genes in the vitamin D pathway. We then explored the length of haplotypes in chromosomes to confirm recent positive selection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets: Calcium, Genes, etc</title><link>/posts/rickets-calcium-genes-etc.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-calcium-genes-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span class="citation-abbreviation">Indian J Endocrinol Metab. &lt;/span>&lt;span class="citation-publication-date">2013 Jan-Feb; &lt;/span>&lt;span class="citation-volume">17&lt;/span>&lt;span class="citation-issue">(1)&lt;/span>&lt;span class="citation-flpages">: 1–4. &lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="fm-citation-pmcid">
&lt;p>&lt;span class="doi">doi:  &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.4103%2F2230-8210.107789">10.4103/2230-8210.107789&lt;/a>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="fm-citation-ids-label">PMCID: &lt;/span>&lt;span>PMC3659873&lt;/span>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 class="content-title">
&lt;p>Rickets: Twists and turns in the Gordian knot&lt;/h1>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="half_rhythm">
&lt;div class="contrib-group fm-author">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=Garg%20MK%5Bauth%5D">M. K. Garg&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=Kalra%20S%5Bauth%5D">Sanjay Kalra&lt;/a>&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="fm-panel small half_rhythm">
&lt;div class="fm-authors-info fm-panel half_rhythm">
&lt;div class="fm-affl">
&lt;p>&lt;em>Department of Endocrinology, Command Hospital, Southern Command, Pune, Maharashtra, India&lt;/em>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="fm-affl">
&lt;p>&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>&lt;em>Department of Endocrinology, Bharti Hospital and B.R.I.D.E., Karnal, Haryana, India&lt;/em>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;div id="cor1">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Corresponding Author:&lt;/strong> Col. M. K. Garg, Department of Endocrinology, Command Hospital, Southern Command, Pune, Maharashtra, India. E-mail: &lt;span class="e_id352731">&lt;a href="mailto:mkgargs@gmail.com">&lt;a href="mailto:mkgargs@gmail.com">mkgargs@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/span>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="fm-cpl-info fm-panel half_rhythm">
&lt;div class="fm-copyright half_rhythm">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/about/copyright.html">Copyright&lt;/a> : © Indian Journal of Endocrinology and Metabolism&lt;/div>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D roles in obesity: genetics and cell signaling</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-roles-in-obesity-genetics-and-cell-signaling.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-roles-in-obesity-genetics-and-cell-signaling.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-beneficial-role-of-vitamin-d-in-obesity-possible-genetic-and-cell-signaling-mechanisms">The beneficial role of vitamin D in obesity: possible genetic and cell signaling mechanisms.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr J. 2013 Jun 25;12(1):89.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vinh Qu C L Ng K, Nguy N LT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The prevalence rates of overweight and obesity are considered an important public issue in the United States, and both of these conditions are increasing among both children and adults. There is evidence of aberrations in the vitamin D-endocrine system in obese subjects. Vitamin D deficiency is highly prevalent in patients with obesity, and many studies have demonstrated the significant effect of calcitriol on adipocytes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets-vitamin D deficiency and dependency</title><link>/posts/rickets-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-dependency.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-dependency.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Indian J Endocrinol Metab. 2012 Mar;16(2):164-76. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4103/2230-8210.93732.">doi: 10.4103/2230-8210.93732.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sahay M, Sahay R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nephrology, Osmania Medical College and General Hospital, Hyderabad, Andhra Pradesh, India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rickets is an important problem even in countries with adequate sun exposure. The causes of rickets/osteomalacia are varied and include nutritional deficiency, especially poor dietary intake of vitamin D and calcium. Non-nutritional causes include hypophosphatemic rickets primarily due to renal phosphate losses and rickets due to renal tubular acidosis. In addition, some varieties are due to inherited defects in vitamin D metabolism and are called vitamin D dependent rickets. This chapter highlights rickets/osteomalacia related to vitamin D deficiency or to inherited defects in vitamin D metabolism. Hypophosphatemic rickets and rickets due to renal tubular acidosis are discussed in other sections of the journal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased risk of multiple sclerosis risk in African Americans due to genes</title><link>/posts/increased-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-risk-in-african-americans-due-to-genes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-risk-in-african-americans-due-to-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="genetic-risk-variants-in-african-americans-with-multiple-sclerosis">Genetic risk variants in African Americans with multiple sclerosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Neurology 10.1212/WNL.0b013e31829bfe2f&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Noriko Isobe, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pierre-Antoine Gourraud, PhD, MPH,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hanne F. Harbo, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stacy J. Caillier, BS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adam Santaniello, BS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pouya Khankhanian, BA,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martin Maiers, MS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen Spellman, MBS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nezih Cereb, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SooYoung Yang, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marcelo J. Pando, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laura Piccio, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anne H. Cross, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Philip L. De Jager, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce A.C. Cree, MD, PhD, MCR,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>98 pcnt of genes that Vitamin D activates to reduce MS are also activated by Interferon</title><link>/posts/98-pcnt-of-genes-that-vitamin-d-activates-to-reduce-ms-are-also-activated-by-interferon.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/98-pcnt-of-genes-that-vitamin-d-activates-to-reduce-ms-are-also-activated-by-interferon.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-ms-activity-during-therapy-with-interferon-beta-1b">25-Hydroxyvitamin D and MS Activity During Therapy with Interferon Beta-1b&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cmscactrims.confex.com/cmscactrims/2013/webprogram/Paper1448.html%20">CMSC Conference, May 30, 2013 &lt;/a> Florida&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alberto Ascherio, MD , Harvard University, Boston, MA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kassandra Munger, ScD , Harvard University, Boston, MA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Claire Simon, ScD , Harvard University, Boston, MA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ludwig Kappos, MD , University Hospital, Basel Neurology, Basel, Switzerland, Basel, Switzerland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chris H Polman, MD , VU Medical Center, Amsterdam, Netherlands&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mark Freedman, MD , University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trying to understand the effect of genetics vitamin D levels in the blood</title><link>/posts/trying-to-understand-the-effect-of-genetics-vitamin-d-levels-in-the-blood.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/trying-to-understand-the-effect-of-genetics-vitamin-d-levels-in-the-blood.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="exploring-the-genetic-architecture-of-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d">Exploring the genetic architecture of circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Genet Epidemiol. 2013 Jan;37(1):92-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/gepi.21694.">doi: 10.1002/gepi.21694.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Nov 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hiraki LT, Major JM, Chen C, Cornelis MC, Hunter DJ, Rimm EB, Simon KC, Weinstein SJ, Purdue MP, Yu K, Albanes D, Kraft P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Program in Molecular and Genetic Epidemiology, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, Massachusetts 02215, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:lindahiraki@mail.harvard.edu">lindahiraki@mail.harvard.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary circulating form of vitamin D is 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25(OH)D), a modifiable trait linked with a growing number of chronic diseases. In addition to environmental determinants of 25(OH)D, including dietary sources and skin ultraviolet B (UVB) exposure, twin- and family-based studies suggest that genetics contribute substantially to vitamin D variability with heritability estimates ranging from 43% to 80%.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus in blacks associated with low vitamin D AND short telomeres</title><link>/posts/lupus-in-blacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-short-telomeres.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-in-blacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-short-telomeres.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="systemic-lupus-erythematosus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-are-associated-with-shorter-telomere-length-among-african-americans-a-case-control-study">Systemic Lupus Erythematosus and Vitamin D Deficiency Are Associated with Shorter Telomere Length among African Americans: A Case-Control Study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2013 May 20;8(5):e63725. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0063725.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0063725.&lt;/a> Print 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hoffecker BM, Raffield LM, Kamen DL, Nowling TK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina, United States of America.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a chronic systemic autoimmune disease that disproportionately affects African American females. The causes of SLE are unknown but postulated to be a combination of genetic predisposition and environmental triggers. Vitamin D deficiency is one of the possible environmental triggers. In this study we evaluated relationships between vitamin D status, cellular aging (telomere length) and anti-telomere antibodies among African American Gullah women with SLE. The study population included African American female SLE patients and unaffected controls from the Sea Island region of South Carolina. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were measured using a nonchromatographic radioimmunoassay. Telomere length was measured in genomic DNA of peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) by monochrome multiplex quantitative PCR. Anti-telomere antibody levels were measured by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). Patients with SLE had significantly shorter telomeres and higher anti-telomere antibody titers compared to age- and gender-matched unaffected controls. There was a positive correlation between anti-telomere antibody levels and disease activity among patients and a significant correlation of shorter telomeres with lower 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in both patients and controls. In follow-up examination of a subset of the patients, the patients who remained vitamin D deficient tended to have shorter telomeres than those patients whose 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were repleted. Increasing 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in African American patients with SLE may be beneficial in maintaining telomere length and preventing cellular aging. Moreover, anti-telomere antibody levels may be a promising biomarker of SLE status and disease activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Macular degeneration 4X more likely if low vitamin D and a particular gene</title><link>/posts/macular-degeneration-4x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-and-a-particular-gene.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/macular-degeneration-4x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-and-a-particular-gene.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="genetics-factor-in-vitamin-d-amd-link">Genetics factor in vitamin D, AMD link&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://ophthalmologytimes.modernmedicine.com/node/369696%20">Ophthalmology Times Staff Reports&lt;/a> MAY 05, 2013&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seattle—Adequate levels of vitamin D can decrease the risk of age-related macular degeneration (AMD), but most markedly in individuals with two risk alleles for the CFH Y402H genotype, said Amy Millen, PhD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Specifically, the association between serum &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> and AMD is modified by the presence of the CFH Y402H polymorphism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Previous studies have shown a relationship between vitamin D and AMD,” said Dr. Millen, assistant professor, Department of Social and Preventive Medicine at the University at Buffalo, New York. “We looked to see if it was modified by the genetic risk of AMD.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese have 50 percent less of two enzymes in fatty tissue to process vitamin D</title><link>/posts/obese-have-50-percent-less-of-two-enzymes-in-fatty-tissue-to-process-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-have-50-percent-less-of-two-enzymes-in-fatty-tissue-to-process-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="expression-of-vitamin-d-metabolizing-enzymes-in-human-adipose-tissue-the-effect-of-obesity-and-diet-induced-weight-loss">Expression of vitamin D-metabolizing enzymes in human adipose tissue-the effect of obesity and diet-induced weight loss.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Obes (Lond). 2013 May;37(5):651-7. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ijo.2012.112.">doi: 10.1038/ijo.2012.112.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jul 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wamberg L, Christiansen T, Paulsen SK, Fisker S, Rask P, Rejnmark L, Richelsen B, Pedersen SB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Internal Medicine MEA, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: Low vitamin D (VD) levels are common in obesity. We hypothesized that this may be due to metabolism of VD in &lt;strong>adipose tissue&lt;/strong> (AT). Thus, we studied (1) whether the VD-metabolizing enzymes were expressed differently in AT of lean and obese individuals and in visceral adipose tissue (VAT) and subcutaneous adipose tissue (SAT), and (2) whether their expression was influenced by weight loss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poorly functioning Vitamin D Receptor (VDR) was 5X more likely in children with low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/poorly-functioning-vitamin-d-receptor-vdr-was-5x-more-likely-in-children-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poorly-functioning-vitamin-d-receptor-vdr-was-5x-more-likely-in-children-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="association-of-vitamin-d-related-gene-polymorphisms-with-manifestation-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-children">Association of vitamin D-related gene polymorphisms with manifestation of vitamin D deficiency in children.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocr J. 2012;59(11):1007-14. Epub 2012 Jul 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kitanaka S, Isojima T, Takaki M, Numakura C, Hayasaka K, Igarashi T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Graduate School of Medicine, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo 113-8655, Japan. &lt;a href="mailto:sachi-tky@umin.ac.jp">sachi-tky@umin.ac.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency, presenting as hypocalcemic seizures or rickets in children, is increasing worldwide due to insufficient vitamin D intake and lack of exposure to sunshine. However, considering that relatively few children with low 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels manifest symptoms, it is possible that genetic factors may predispose individuals to vitamin D deficiency. Recent twin studies have reported that the level of serum of 25(OH)D is influenced by genetic factors. In addition, genome-wide association studies and candidate gene studies have revealed that several vitamin D-related genes, including VDR, GC, NADSYN1, CYP2R1, CYP24A1, CYP27B1, and C10orf88 contribute to variations in serum 25(OH)D levels. To investigate whether genetic predisposition contributes to vitamin D deficiency, we analyzed polymorphisms in vitamin D-related genes in 30 Japanese patients with vitamin D deficiency presenting at less than 4 years of age, along with 66 controls. A χ(2) test showed that the genotype frequencies of BsmI polymorphism in VDR and rs10898191 in NADSYN1 were significantly different between the two groups. The allele frequencies of BsmI, ApaI, TaqI in VDR, rs10898191 in NADSYN1, and rs705117 in GC were also significantly different. In particular, the frequency of the BAtS haplotype in VDR was significantly increased in the patient group relative to controls (p = 0.0014; odds ratio, &lt;strong>5.61&lt;/strong> ; 95% confidence interval 1.92 - 16.40). Although this is a small study, our findings suggest that VDR, NADSYN1, and GC polymorphisms may be linked to the manifestation of vitamin D deficiency in Japanese children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low frequency hearing loss (Otosclerosis) associated with vitamin D genes</title><link>/posts/low-frequency-hearing-loss-otosclerosis-associated-with-vitamin-d-genes.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-frequency-hearing-loss-otosclerosis-associated-with-vitamin-d-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="otosclerosis-and-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphism">Otosclerosis and vitamin D receptor gene polymorphism&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Otolaryngology. Available online 29 April 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yavuz Selim Yıldırım, MDa, b, &lt;a href="mailto:dryavuzselim@yahoo.com">dryavuzselim@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tayfun Apuhan, MD c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Selma Düzenli, MD d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ali Osman Arslan, MD d&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Otorhinolaryngology and Head and Neck Surgery, Bezmialem Vakif University, Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Otorhinolaryngology and Head and Neck Surgery, Haseki Training and Research Hospital, Istanbul&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c Department of Ear Nose Throat Clinics, Abant Izzet Baysal University, Medical Faculty, Bolu, Turkey&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes in white blood cells of blacks associated with vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/genes-in-white-blood-cells-of-blacks-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-in-white-blood-cells-of-blacks-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-genome-wide-methylation-study-of-severe-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-african-american-adolescents">A Genome-Wide Methylation Study of Severe Vitamin D Deficiency in African American Adolescents&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Journal of Pediatrics. Volume 162, Issue 5 , Pages 1004-1009.e1, May 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Haidong Zhu, MD, PhD email address , Xiaoling Wang, MD, PhD , Huidong Shi, PhD ,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shaoyong Su, PhD , Gregory A. Harshfield, PhD , Bernard Gutin, PhD , Harold Snieder, PhD , Yanbin Dong, MD, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 2 July 2012; received in revised form 13 September 2012; accepted 31 October 2012. published online 10 December 2012.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Melanoma reduces by half the amount of vitamin D activated by the skin</title><link>/posts/melanoma-reduces-by-half-the-amount-of-vitamin-d-activated-by-the-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/melanoma-reduces-by-half-the-amount-of-vitamin-d-activated-by-the-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="expression-of-the-vitamin-d-activating-enzyme-1α-hydroxylase-cyp27b1-decreases-during-melanoma-progression">Expression of the vitamin D-activating enzyme 1α-hydroxylase (CYP27B1) decreases during melanoma progression.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Hum Pathol. 2013 Mar;44(3):374-87. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.humpath.2012.03.031.">doi: 10.1016/j.humpath.2012.03.031.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Sep 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brożyna AA, Jóźwicki W, Janjetovic Z, Slominski AT &lt;a href="mailto:aslominski@uthsc.edu">aslominski@uthsc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Tumor Pathology and Pathomorphology, Oncology Centre-Prof. Franciszek Łukaszczyk Memorial Hospital, The Ludwik Rydygier Collegium Medicum, Nicolaus Copernicus University, 85-796 Bydgoszcz, Poland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1α-Hydroxylase (CYP27B1), the enzyme responsible for the synthesis of the biologically active form of vitamin D (1,25(OH)(2)D(3)), is expressed in the skin. To assess the correlation between progression of melanocytic tumors and CYP27B1, we analyzed its expression in 29 benign nevi, 75 primary cutaneous melanomas, 40 metastases, and 4 re-excision and 6 normal skin biopsies. Immunoreactivity for CYP27B1 was significantly lower in the vertical growth phase and metastatic melanomas (0.6 and 0.5 arbitrary units, respectively) in comparison with nevi and radial growth phase tumors (1.2 and 1.1 arbitrary units, respectively); and expression was reduced in more advanced lesions (Clark levels III-V, Breslow thickness ≥2.1 mm; 0.8 and 0.7 arbitrary units, respectively). There was an inverse correlation between CYP27B1 and Ki-67 expression. Furthermore, CYP27B1 expression was reduced in primary melanomas that created metastases in comparison with non-metastasizing melanomas. Reduced CYP27B1 expression in radial growth phase was related to shorter overall survival (810 versus 982 versus 1151 days in melanomas with absent, low, and high CYP27B1 immunoreactivity), and low CYP27B1 expression in radial growth phase and vertical growth phase was related to shorter disease-free survival (114 versus 339 versus 737 days and 129 versus 307 versus 737 days, respectively, in melanomas with absent, low, and high CYP27B1). Also, CYP27B1 expression was inversely related to melanin in melanoma cells in vivo and melanoma cells cultured in vitro. Thus, reduction of CYP27B1 correlates with melanoma phenotype and behavior, and its lack affects the survival of melanoma patients, indicating a role in the pathogenesis and progression of this cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Common Vitamin D gene variants and resulting diseases</title><link>/posts/common-vitamin-d-gene-variants-and-resulting-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/common-vitamin-d-gene-variants-and-resulting-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The vitamin D binding protein (DBP) is the major plasma carrier for vitamin D and its metabolites, but it is also an actin scavenger, and is the precursor to the immunomodulatory protein, Gc-MAF. Two missense variants of the DBP gene - rs7041 encoding Asp432Glu and rs4588 encoding Thr436Lys - change the amino acid sequence and alter the protein function.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They are common enough to generate population-wide constitutive differences in vitamin D status, based on assay of the serum metabolite, 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D - Health panacea or false prophet (Klotho gene)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-health-panacea-or-false-prophet-klotho-gene.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-health-panacea-or-false-prophet-klotho-gene.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-health-panacea-or-false-prophet">Vitamin D: Health panacea or false prophet?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nutrition 29 (2013) 37-41, Article history: Received 27 March 2012 Accepted 11 May 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael J. Glade h.D., F.A.C.N., C.N.S. &lt;a href="mailto:the_nutrition_doctor@yahoo.com">the_nutrition_doctor@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Nutrition Doctor, Skokie, Illinois, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency, diagnosed when the serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD3) concentration is less than 20 ng/mL, has joined vitamin A deficiency as two of the most common nutrition-responsive medical conditions worldwide. &lt;strong>There have been more scientific articles published about vitamin D in the 21st century than about any other vitamin&lt;/strong> , reflecting the massive expansion of the field of vitamin D research. Adequate vitamin D status has been linked to decreased risks of developing&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes and different vitamin D related substances in the skin</title><link>/posts/genes-and-different-vitamin-d-related-substances-in-the-skin.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-and-different-vitamin-d-related-substances-in-the-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="novel-vitamin-d-photoproducts-and-their-precursors-in-the-skin">Novel vitamin D photoproducts and their precursors in the skin&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dermato Endencronology Volume 5, Issue 1 January/February/March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.4161/derm.23938">http://dx.doi.org/10.4161/derm.23938&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keywords: 5,7-dienes, dermal fibroblasts, keratinocytes, melanocytes, melanoma cells, skin, vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Andrzej T. Slominski, Tae-Kang Kim, Michal A. Zmijewski, Zorica Janjetovic, Wei Li, Jianjun Chen, Ekaterina I. Kusniatsova, Igor Semak, Arnold Postlethwaite, Duane D. Miller, Jordan K. Zjawiony and Robert C. Tuckey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Novel metabolic pathways initiated by the enzymatic action of CYP11A1 on 7DHC (7-dehydrocholesterol), ergosterol, vitamins D3 and D2 were characterized with help of chemical synthesis, UV and mass spectrometry and NMR analyses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>291 genes improved expression by 2000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/291-genes-improved-expression-by-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/291-genes-improved-expression-by-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="influence-of-vitamin-d-status-and-vitamin-d3-supplementation-on-genome-wide-expression-of-white-blood-cells-a-randomized-double-blind-clinical-trial">Influence of Vitamin D Status and Vitamin D3 Supplementation on Genome Wide Expression of White Blood Cells: A Randomized Double-Blind Clinical Trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(3): e58725. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0058725&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arash Hossein-nezhad, Avrum Spira, Michael F. Holick&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Although there have been numerous observations of vitamin D deficiency and its links to chronic diseases, no studies have reported on how vitamin D status and vitamin D3 supplementation affects broad gene expression in humans. The objective of this study was to determine the effect of vitamin D status and subsequent vitamin D supplementation on broad gene expression in healthy adults. (Trial registration: ClinicalTrials.gov NCT01696409).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D receptor gene associated with 50 percent more type 2 Diabetes – meta-analyses 2013, 2016</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-gene-associated-with-50-percent-more-type-2-diabetes-meta-analyses-2013-2016.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-gene-associated-with-50-percent-more-type-2-diabetes-meta-analyses-2013-2016.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#type-2-diabetes-in-chinese-is-50-percent-more-likely-if-have-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-problem--meta-analysis-2016">Type 2 Diabetes in Chinese is 50 percent more likely if have Vitamin D Receptor gene problem – meta-analysis 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-and-type-2-diabetes-a-meta-analysis--march-2013">Vitamin D Receptor Gene Polymorphisms and Type 2 Diabetes: A Meta-analysis.- March 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="type-2-diabetes-in-chinese-is-50-percent-more-likely-if-have-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-problem--meta-analysis-2016">Type 2 Diabetes in Chinese is 50 percent more likely if have Vitamin D Receptor gene problem – meta-analysis 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The genetic polymorphisms in vitamin D receptor and the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus: an updated meta-analysis.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No apparent genetic association between vitamin D and obesity</title><link>/posts/no-apparent-genetic-association-between-vitamin-d-and-obesity.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-apparent-genetic-association-between-vitamin-d-and-obesity.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="genetic-association-analysis-of-vitamin-d-pathway-with-obesity-traits">Genetic association analysis of vitamin D pathway with obesity traits.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Int J Obes (Lond). 2013 Feb 5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ijo.2013.6.">doi: 10.1038/ijo.2013.6.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vimaleswaran KS, Cavadino A, Berry DJ; The Genetic Investigation of Anthropometric Traits (GIANT) Consortium, Whittaker JC, Power C, Järvelin MR, Hyppönen E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Paediatric Epidemiology and Biostatistics, MRC Centre of Epidemiology for Child Health, UCL Institute of Child Health, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective:Observational studies have examined the link between vitamin D deficiency and obesity traits. Some studies have reported associations between vitamin D pathway genes such as VDR, GC and CYP27B1 with body mass index (BMI) and waist circumference (WC); however, the findings have been inconsistent. Therefore, we investigated the involvement of vitamin D metabolic pathway genes in obesity-related traits in a large population-based study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D gene expression associated with diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-gene-expression-associated-with-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-gene-expression-associated-with-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-and-blood-gene-expression-profiles-a-cross-sectional-study-of-the-norwegian-women-and-cancer-post-genome-cohort">Plasma 25 hydroxyvitamin D level and blood gene expression profiles: a cross-sectional study of the Norwegian Women and Cancer Post-genome Cohort.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2013 Mar 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2013.53.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2013.53.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Standahl Olsen K, Rylander C, Brustad M, Aksnes L, Lund E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Community Medicine, University of Tromsø, Tromsø, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Objectives:Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with increased risk of developing several diseases, but much is unknown about the molecular effects involved. Gene expression technology is increasingly being used to elucidate molecular mechanisms related to nutritional factors, and in this study of free-living, middle-aged Norwegian women, we aimed at identifying gene expression pathways in the blood associated with vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D level can be high, but little benefit: due to kidney, genes, low Magnesium etc.</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Genes indicate that Obesity causes vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/genes-indicate-that-obesity-causes-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-indicate-that-obesity-causes-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="causal-relationship-between-obesity-and-vitamin-d-status-bi-directional-mendelian-randomization-analysis-of-multiple-cohorts">Causal Relationship between Obesity and Vitamin D Status: Bi-Directional Mendelian Randomization Analysis of Multiple Cohorts&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLOS One&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karani S. Vimaleswaran equal contributor, Diane J. Berry equal contributor, Chen Lu,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emmi Tikkanen, Stefan Pilz, Linda T. Hiraki, Jason D. Cooper, Zari Dastani,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rui Li, Denise K. Houston, Andrew R. Wood, Karl Michaëlsson, Liesbeth Vandenput, Elina Hyppönen equal contributor mail&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="background">Background&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Obesity is associated with vitamin D deficiency, and both are areas of active public health concern. We explored the causality and direction of the relationship between body mass index (BMI) and 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> using genetic markers as instrumental variables (IVs) in bi-directional Mendelian randomization (MR) analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mutations in CYP24A1 gene (vitamin D) associated with kidney problems</title><link>/posts/mutations-in-cyp24a1-gene-vitamin-d-associated-with-kidney-problems.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mutations-in-cyp24a1-gene-vitamin-d-associated-with-kidney-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="125-oh2d-24-hydroxylase-cyp24a1-deficiency-as-a-cause-of-nephrolithiasis">1,25-(OH)2D-24 Hydroxylase (CYP24A1) Deficiency as a Cause of Nephrolithiasis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2013 Jan 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nesterova G, Malicdan MC, Yasuda K, Sakaki T, Vilboux T, Ciccone C, Horst R, Huang Y, Golas G, Introne W, Huizing M, Adams D, Boerkoel CF, Collins MT, Gahl WA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical Genetics Branch, National Human Genome Research Institute, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland;,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>†Department of Biotechnology, Faculty of Engineering, Toyama Prefectural University, Toyama, Japan;,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7 genes associated with low vitamin D levels in China – 2012, 2013</title><link>/posts/gc-cyp2r1-and-dhcr7-genes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels-in-china-2012-2013.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gc-cyp2r1-and-dhcr7-genes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels-in-china-2012-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolorf00two-articles-from-china-on-this-page-have-the-same-conclusionspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Two articles from China on this page have the same conclusion&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="the-gc-cyp2r1-and-dhcr7-genes-are-associated-with-vitamin-d-levels-in-northeastern-han-chinese-children">The GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7 genes are associated with vitamin D levels in northeastern Han Chinese children.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Swiss Med Wkly. &lt;strong>2012 July&lt;/strong> 16;142:w13636. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4414/smw.2012.13636.">doi: 10.4414/smw.2012.13636.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhang Y, Wang X, Liu Y, Qu H, Qu S, Wang W, Ren L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, Heilongjiang Province, PR China. &lt;a href="mailto:zhangyuling0000@yahoo.com.cn">zhangyuling0000@yahoo.com.cn&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is associated with risk in several diseases. Vitamin D status has high heritability, yet the genetic epidemiology of vitamin D or its metabolites has not been well studied. Our objective was to identify the relationship among three vitamin D-related genes (GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7/NADSYN1) and the levels of 25(OH)D in northeastern Han Chinese children. A total of 506 northeastern Han Chinese children were enrolled in this study. Linear regression was used to examine the impact of 12 SNPs on 25(OH)D concentrations after adjustment for age, gender, BMI and regular usage of vitamin D, and Bonferroni&amp;rsquo;s method was adopted for multiple corrections. The two SNPs in GC (rs222020, rs2298849), four SNPs in CYP2R1 (rs10741657, rs10766197, rs12794714 and rs1562902) and two SNPs in DHCR7/NADSYN1 (rs3829251, rs12785878) were significantly associated with plasma 25(OH)D concentrations under both additive and recessive models (P &amp;lt;0.05). The genotypes of the CYP2R1 rs2060793 polymorphism showed positive association with serum 25(OH)D status under all of the three genetic models even after correction for multiple comparison. This population-based study was the first to confirm the strong effects of the GC, CYP2R1 and DHCR7/NADSYN1 loci on circulating 25(OH)D concentrations in northeastern Han Chinese children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Anti-cancer Actions of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/the-anti-cancer-actions-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-anti-cancer-actions-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.126-139 (14)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Kun-Chun Chiang, Tai C. Chen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D3 is biologically inert. To become active, it requires two successive hydroxylation steps catalyzed by two cytochrome P450 enzymes, first to synthesize the pro-hormone 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 &lt;span>[25(OH)D3]&lt;/span> and then the active hormone 1α,25- dihydroxyvitamin D3 &lt;span>[1α,25(OH)2D3]&lt;/span>. 1α,25(OH)2D3 has high affinity for the vitamin D receptor (VDR), a transcription factor and a member of the steroid receptor superfamily. Through VDR, 1α,25(OH)2D3 regulates more than 200 genes in mammals, including those involved in the calcium and phosphorus homeostasis, immune function, reproduction, cardiovascular, central nerve system, inflammation, angiogenesis, and cellular proliferation, differentiation and apoptosis. Due to its versatile roles in maintaining and regulating normal cellular phenotypes and functions, 1α,25(OH)2D3 has been implicated as an anti-cancer agent. In fact, ecological and epidemiologic data have linked vitamin D deficiency with the incidence and mortality of many types of cancer. More importantly, in vitro and in vivo animal model studies have clearly demonstrated the anti-tumor effects of vitamin D. In this review, we describe the anticancer actions of vitamin D, with special emphasis on different pathways underlying the VDR-mediated genomic as well as less-defined non-genomic actions of vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Receptor genes bb and BB and Osteoporosis, esp. for blacks – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-genes-bb-and-bb-and-osteoporosis-esp-for-blacks-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-genes-bb-and-bb-and-osteoporosis-esp-for-blacks-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-bsmi-polymorphism-and-osteoporosis-risk-a-meta-analysis-from-26-studies">Vitamin D Receptor BsmI Polymorphism and Osteoporosis Risk: A Meta-Analysis from 26 Studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Genetic Testing and Molecular Biomarkers – Nov 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rui-Fen Sun,2,* Qun-Hui Li,1 Da-Xing Wang,1 Feng Zhao,1 Jun-Min Li,1 Qi Pu,1 Zhong-Zi Zhang,1 Yan Jin,1 Bai-Lian Liu,1 and Ying Xiong1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Orthopedics, Kunming Medical University, National Clinical Key Specialty, Yanan Hospital, Kunming, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Central Laboratory, Yunnan University of Chinese Traditional Medicine, Kunming, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GC and CYP2R1 genes associated with higher summer vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/gc-and-cyp2r1-genes-associated-with-higher-summer-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gc-and-cyp2r1-genes-associated-with-higher-summer-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-intake-and-season-modify-the-effects-of-the-gc-and-cyp2r1-genes-on-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations123">Vitamin D Intake and Season Modify the Effects of the GC and CYP2R1 Genes on 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentrations1,2,3&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J. Nutr. January 1, 2013 jn.112.169482&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corinne D. Engelman4, &lt;a href="mailto:cengelman@wisc.edu">cengelman@wisc.edu&lt;/a>, Kristin J. Meyers5, Sudha K. Iyengar7, Zhe Liu5, Chitra K. Karki5, Robert P. Igo Jr7, Barbara Truitt7, Jennifer Robinson8,9, Gloria E. Sarto6, Robert Wallace9, Barbara A. Blodi5, Michael L. Klein10, Lesley Tinker11, Erin S. LeBlanc12, Rebecca D. Jackson13, Yiqing Song14, JoAnn E. Manson14,15, Julie A. Mares5, and Amy E. Millen16&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Vitamin D prevents many cancers (c-MYC)</title><link>/posts/how-vitamin-d-prevents-many-cancers-c-myc.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-vitamin-d-prevents-many-cancers-c-myc.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-receptor-as-a-master-regulator-of-the-c-mycmxd1-network">Vitamin D receptor as a master regulator of the c-MYC/MXD1 network&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-receptor-as-a-master-regulator-of-the-c-mycmxd1-network">Vitamin D receptor as a master regulator of the c-MYC/MXD1 network&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PNAS November 13, 2012 vol. 109 no. 46 18827-18832&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reyhaneh Salehi-Tabara, Loan Nguyen-Yamamotoa, Luz E. Tavera-Mendozaa, Thomas Quailb, Vassil Dimitrovb, Beum-Soo Anb,c, Leon Glassb, David Goltzmana,b, and John H. Whitea,b, &lt;a href="mailto:john.white@mcgill.ca">john.white@mcgill.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Departments of Medicine and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Physiology, McGill University, Montreal, QC, Canada H3G 1Y6; and&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Transgeneration vitamin D deficiency related to MS was found in mice</title><link>/posts/transgeneration-vitamin-d-deficiency-related-to-ms-was-found-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/transgeneration-vitamin-d-deficiency-related-to-ms-was-found-in-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prenatal-vitamin-d-deficiency-induces-an-early-and-more-severe-experimental-autoimmune-encephalomyelitis-in-the-second-generation">Prenatal Vitamin D Deficiency Induces an Early and More Severe Experimental Autoimmune Encephalomyelitis in the Second Generation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2012, 13(9), 10911-10919; doi:10.3390/ijms130910911&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diana Andrea Fernandes de Abreu 1 , Véréna Landel 1 , Adrian G. Barnett 2 , John McGrath 3,4 , Darryl Eyles 3,4 and Francois Feron 1,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Neurobiology of Cell Interactions and Neurophysiopathology, Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, UMR 7259, Aix Marseille Université, Marseille 13015, France&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epigenetics, vitamin D, and Multiple Sclerosis</title><link>/posts/epigenetics-vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/epigenetics-vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epigenetic-changes-in-patients-with-multiple-sclerosis---nov-2012">Epigenetic changes in patients with multiple sclerosis - Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epigenetics---is-it-real-new-york-times-review-of-plos-genetics-article---july-2016">Epigenetics - is it real: New York Times review of PLOS Genetics article - July 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="epigenetic-changes-in-patients-with-multiple-sclerosis---nov-2012">Epigenetic changes in patients with multiple sclerosis - Nov 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Neurol. 2012 Nov 20. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2012.226.">doi: 10.1038/nrneurol.2012.226.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Koch MW, Metz LM, Kovalchuk O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Calgary, Foothills Hospital, 1403-29th Street N. W., Calgary, AB T2N 2T9, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epigenetic changes influence gene expression without altering the DNA sequence. DNA methylation, histone modification and microRNA-associated post-transcriptional gene silencing are three key epigenetic mechanisms. Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a disease of the CNS with both inflammatory and neurodegenerative features. Although studies on epigenetic changes in MS only began in the past decade, a growing body of literature suggests that epigenetic changes may be involved in the development of MS, possibly by mediating the effects of environmental risk factors, such as&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Difference in Fok gene reduced response to vitamin D by 35 percent</title><link>/posts/difference-in-fok-gene-reduced-response-to-vitamin-d-by-35-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/difference-in-fok-gene-reduced-response-to-vitamin-d-by-35-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-receptor-fok-i-polymorphism-modulates-diabetic-host-response-to-vitamin-d-intake">Vitamin D Receptor Fok-I Polymorphism Modulates Diabetic Host Response to Vitamin D Intake&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Need for a nutrigenetic approach&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care November 16, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tirang R. Neyestani, PHD1⇓, Abolghassem Djazayery, PHD2, Sakineh Shab-Bidar, MSC2, Mohammad Reza Eshraghian, PHD3, Ali Kalayi, BSC1, Nastaran Shariátzadeh, BSC1, Niloufar Khalaji, MSC1, Malihe Zahedirad, MSC1, A’zam Gharavi, BSC1, Anahita Houshiarrad, MSC1, Maryam Chamari, MSC2 and Sepideh Asadzadeh, BSC1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Nutrition Research, National Nutrition and Food Technology Research Institute, and Faculty of Nutrition Science and Food Technology, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes such as CYP27B1, CYP24A1 and Vitamin D – JAMA</title><link>/posts/genes-such-as-cyp27b1-cyp24a1-and-vitamin-d-jama.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-such-as-cyp27b1-cyp24a1-and-vitamin-d-jama.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="genetic-variants-and-associations-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-with-major-clinical-outcomes">Genetic Variants and Associations of 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentrations With Major Clinical Outcomes&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>JAMA. 2012;308(18):1898-1905. doi:10.1001/jama.2012.17304.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gregory P. Levin, PhD; Cassianne Robinson-Cohen, PhD; Ian H. de Boer, MD, MS; Denise K. Houston, PhD; Kurt Lohman, MS; Yongmei Liu, PhD; Stephen B. Kritchevsky, PhD; Jane A. Cauley, DrPh; Toshiko Tanaka, PhD; Luigi Ferrucci, MD, PhD; Stefania Bandinelli, MD; Kushang V. Patel, PhD, MPH; Emil Hagström, MD, PhD; Karl Michaëlsson, MD, PhD; Håkan Melhus, MD, PhD; Thomas Wang, MD; Myles Wolf, MD, MMSc; Bruce M. Psaty, MD, PhD; David Siscovick, MD, MPH; Bryan Kestenbaum, MD, MS&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>600 mg of Calcium and a gene increases probability of Prostate Cancer by 50 pcnt</title><link>/posts/600-mg-of-calcium-and-a-gene-increases-probability-of-prostate-cancer-by-50-pcnt.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/600-mg-of-calcium-and-a-gene-increases-probability-of-prostate-cancer-by-50-pcnt.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="protective-effects-of-low-calcium-intake-and-low-calcium-absorption-vitamin-d-receptor-genotype-in-the-california-collaborative-prostate-cancer-study">Protective effects of low calcium intake and low calcium absorption vitamin D receptor genotype in the California Collaborative Prostate Cancer Study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Calcium Epidemiology Biomarkers and Prevention, November 5, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glovioell W Rowland 1, Gary G. Schwartz 2, Esther M. John 3, and Sue Ann Ingles 4,ingles@usc.edu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Preventive Medicine, University of Southern California&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Cancer Biology, Urology, and Epidemiology and Prevention, Wake Forest Baptist Medical Center&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Epidemiology, Cancer Prevention Institute of California&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels are strongly associated with genes: overview of twin studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-are-strongly-associated-with-genes-overview-of-twin-studies.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-are-strongly-associated-with-genes-overview-of-twin-studies.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>CYP24A1 gene, kidney disease, and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-kidney-disease-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cyp24a1-and-kidney-disease">CYP24A1 and kidney disease&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens. 2011 May 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Petkovich M, Jones G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>aDivision of Cancer Biology and Genetics, Cancer Research Institute, Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, Canada bDepartment of Research and Development, Cytochroma Inc., Markham, Canada cDepartments of Biochemistry and Medicine, Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE OF REVIEW:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patients with chronic renal disease have elevated serum phosphate levels, elevated fibroblast-like growth factor 23 (FGF-23), and declining vitamin D status. These changes are related and may be responsible for elevated 25-hydroxyvitamin D-24-hydroxylase (CYP24A1) and dysfunctional vitamin D metabolism. This review focuses on the biochemistry and pathophysiology of CYP24A1 and the utility of blocking this enzyme with CYP24A1 inhibitors in chronic kidney disease (CKD) patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CYP24A1 gene in cancer cells may actually remove vitamin D from the blood</title><link>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-in-cancer-cells-may-actually-remove-vitamin-d-from-the-blood.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-in-cancer-cells-may-actually-remove-vitamin-d-from-the-blood.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="24-hydroxylase-in-cancer-impact-on-vitamin-d-based-anticancer-therapeutics">24-Hydroxylase in Cancer: Impact on Vitamin D-based Anticancer Therapeutics.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2012 Oct 8. pii: S0960-0760(12)00200-2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2012.09.031">doi: 10.1016/j.jsbmb.2012.09.031&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luo W, Hershberger PA, Trump DL, Johnson CS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The active vitamin D hormone 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) (1,25(OH)(2)D(3)) plays a major role in regulating calcium homeostasis and bone mineralization. 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) also modulates cellular proliferation and differentiation in a variety of cell types. 24-hydroxylase, encoded by the CYP24A1 gene, is the key enzyme which converts 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) to less active calcitroic acid.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Shows Promise in Curing Baldness</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-shows-promise-in-curing-baldness.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-shows-promise-in-curing-baldness.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3-modulates-the-hair-inductive-capacity-of-dermal-papilla-cells-therapeutic-potential-for-hair-regeneration">1?,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D3 Modulates the Hair-Inductive Capacity of Dermal Papilla Cells: Therapeutic Potential for Hair Regeneration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Noriyuki Aoia, Keita Inouea, Toshihiro Chikanishib,c, Ryoji Fujikic, Hanako Yamamotod, Harunosuke Katoa, Hitomi Etoa, Kentaro Doia, Satoshi Itamie, Shigeaki Katob,c and Kotaro Yoshimuraa&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Plastic Surgery and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>d Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, University of Tokyo School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b ERATO, Japan Science and Technology Agency, Saitama, Japan;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c Institute of Molecular and Cellular Biosciences, University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, Allergy, and genetics</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-allergy-and-genetics.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-allergy-and-genetics.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="evidence-for-a-genetic-interaction-in-allergy-related-responsiveness-to-vitamin-d-deficiency">Evidence for a genetic interaction in allergy-related responsiveness to vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Allergy. 2012 Jun 12. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1398-9995.2012.02856.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1398-9995.2012.02856.x.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vimaleswaran KS, Cavadino A, Hyppönen E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Paediatric Epidemiology and Biostatistics and MRC Centre for the Epidemiology of Child Health, UCL Institute of Child Health, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The hormonal form of vitamin D affects both adaptive and innate immune functions involved in the development of allergies. Certain genotypes have been seen to alter the association between vitamin D deficiency (VDD) and the risk of food sensitization in children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X higher risk of oral cancer if CYP27B1 and CYP24A1 genes were different</title><link>/posts/3x-higher-risk-of-oral-cancer-if-cyp27b1-and-cyp24a1-genes-were-different.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-higher-risk-of-oral-cancer-if-cyp27b1-and-cyp24a1-genes-were-different.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-cyp27b1-and-cyp24a1-genes-polymorphisms-association-with-oral-cancer-risk-and-survival">Vitamin D receptor, CYP27B1 and CYP24A1 genes polymorphisms association with oral cancer risk and survival.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Oral Pathol Med. 2012 May 22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0714.2012.01164.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0714.2012.01164.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zeljic K, Supic G, Stamenkovic Radak M, Jovic N, Kozomara R, Magic Z.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute for Medical Research, Military Medical Academy, Belgrade, Serbia Faculty of Biology, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia Clinic for Maxillofacial Surgery, Military Medical Academy, Belgrade, Serbia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Genetic polymorphisms of vitamin D receptor gene (VDR) and genes involved in vitamin D metabolism pathway, CYP27B1 and CYP24B1, may affect individual susceptibility to oral squamous cell carcinoma. The purpose of this study was to evaluate the associations between VDR, CYP27B1 and CYP24A1 gene polymorphisms with oral cancer risk and survival.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Macular Degeneration decreased with UV and perhaps Vitamin D genetics</title><link>/posts/macular-degeneration-decreased-with-uv-and-perhaps-vitamin-d-genetics.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/macular-degeneration-decreased-with-uv-and-perhaps-vitamin-d-genetics.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="systems-biology-based-analysis-implicates-a-novel-role-for-vitamin-d-metabolism-in-the-pathogenesis-of-age-related-macular-degeneration">Systems biology-based analysis implicates a novel role for vitamin D metabolism in the pathogenesis of age-related macular degeneration.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Hum Genomics. 2011 Oct;5(6):538-68.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morrison MA, Silveira AC, Huynh N, Jun G, Smith SE, Zacharaki F, Sato H, Loomis S, Andreoli MT, Adams SM, Radeke MJ, Jelcick AS, Yuan Y, Tsiloulis AN, Chatzoulis DZ, Silvestri G, Kotoula MG, Tsironi EE, Hollis BW, Chen R, Haider NB, Miller JW, Farrer LA, Hageman GS, Kim IK, Schaumberg DA, DeAngelis MM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Novel vitamin D gene regulation – CYP21A2</title><link>/posts/novel-vitamin-d-gene-regulation-cyp21a2.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/novel-vitamin-d-gene-regulation-cyp21a2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-mediated-regulation-of-cyp21a2-transcription">Vitamin D-mediated regulation of CYP21A2 transcription&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-novel-mechanism-for-vitamin-d-action">A novel mechanism for vitamin D action.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Biochim Biophys Acta. 2012 Apr 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lundqvist J, Wikvall K, Norlin M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1?,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D(3) has recently been reported to decrease expression and activity of CYP21A2. In this paper, we have studied the mechanisms for the 1?,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3)-mediated effect on CYP21A2 transcriptional rate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have studied the effects of 1?,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) using luciferase reporter constructs containing different lengths of the CYP21A2 promoter. These constructs were transfected into cell lines derived from human and mouse adrenal cortex. The mechanism for the effects of vitamin D on the CYP21A2 promoter was studied using chromatin immunoprecipitation assay, mutagenesis and gene silencing by siRNA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Asthma strongly associated with modification in vitamin D genes</title><link>/posts/asthma-strongly-associated-with-modification-in-vitamin-d-genes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/asthma-strongly-associated-with-modification-in-vitamin-d-genes.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fructose reduces blood levels of active vitamin D</title><link>/posts/fructose-reduces-blood-levels-of-active-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fructose-reduces-blood-levels-of-active-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#chronic-high-fructose-intake-reduces-serum-125-oh2d3-levels-in-calcium-sufficient-rodents---2014">Chronic high fructose intake reduces serum 1,25 (OH)2D3 levels in calcium-sufficient rodents - 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="chronic-high-fructose-intake-reduces-serum-125-oh2d3-levels-in-calcium-sufficient-rodents---2014">Chronic high fructose intake reduces serum 1,25 (OH)2D3 levels in calcium-sufficient rodents - 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2014 Apr 9;9(4):e93611. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0093611">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0093611&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Douard V1, Patel C1, Lee J1, Tharabenjasin P1, Williams E2, Fritton JC3, Sabbagh Y4, Ferraris RP1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/fructose-2014a.jpg" alt="image" width="300">&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/fructose-2014b.jpg" alt="image" width="100">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Excessive fructose consumption inhibits adaptive increases in intestinal Ca2+ transport in lactating and weanling rats with increased Ca2+ requirements by preventing the increase in serum levels of 1,25(OH)2D3. Here we tested the hypothesis that chronic fructose intake decreases 1,25(OH)2D3 levels independent of increases in Ca2+ requirements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes may account for some of AA Breast Cancer</title><link>/posts/genes-may-account-for-some-of-aa-breast-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-may-account-for-some-of-aa-breast-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="variants-in-the-vitamin-d-pathway-serum-levels-of-vitamin-d">Variants in the vitamin D pathway, serum levels of vitamin D,&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="and-estrogen-receptor-negative-breast-cancer-among-african-american-women-a-case-control-study">and estrogen receptor negative breast cancer among African-American women: a case-control study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Song Yao, Gary Zirpoli, Dana H Bovbjerg, Lina Jandorf, Chi-Chen Hong, Hua Zhao, Lara E Sucheston, Li Tang, Michelle Roberts, Gregory Ciupak, Warren Davis, Helena Hwang, Candace S Johnson, Donald L Trump, Susan E McCann, Foluso Ademuyiwa, Karen S Pawlish, Elisa V Bandera and Christine B Ambrosone&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Ribosomes also contain genetic information</title><link>/posts/off-topic-ribosomes-also-contain-genetic-information.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-ribosomes-also-contain-genetic-information.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="new-layer-of-genetic-information-discoveredhttpwwwkurzweilainetnew-layer-of-genetic-information-discovered-kurzweilainet--march-2012">&lt;a href="http://www.kurzweilai.net/new-layer-of-genetic-information-discovered">New layer of genetic information discovered&lt;/a> Kurzweilai.net March 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Example:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tiny changes in the ribosome can slow the protein production process to one-tenth of its normal speed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ribosomes are in every single living cell&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ribosome">Wikipedia has the following image&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;1180&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dr-gerald-lewis---new-zealand-cardiologist--has-a-presentation-which-includes-the-following">Dr. Gerald Lewis - New Zealand Cardiologist -has a presentation which includes the following&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;1181&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="spantiki-download_filephpfileid2087span-for-his-presentation">&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=2087]&lt;/span> for his presentation&lt;/h3></description></item><item><title>Telomeres longer for dialysis patients having higher levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/telomeres-longer-for-dialysis-patients-having-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/telomeres-longer-for-dialysis-patients-having-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>People 2 cm taller had different Calcium and Vitamin D genotypes</title><link>/posts/people-2-cm-taller-had-different-calcium-and-vitamin-d-genotypes.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-2-cm-taller-had-different-calcium-and-vitamin-d-genotypes.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="associations-between-polymorphisms-related-to-calcium-metabolism-and-human-height-the-tromsø-study">Associations between Polymorphisms Related to Calcium Metabolism and Human Height: The Tromsø Study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ann Hum Genet. 2012 Mar 5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-1809.2012.00703.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1469-1809.2012.00703.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorde R, Svartberg J, Joakimsen RM, Grimnes G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tromsø Endocrine Research Group, Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, Tromsø, Norway; and Division of Internal Medicine, University Hospital of North Norway, Tromsø, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A number of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) related to height have been detected. Calcium metabolism is important for the skeleton and accordingly also for adult height. Therefore, in the present study, nine SNPs related to the vitamin D receptor (VDR) gene and serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D), calcium, phosphate and parathyroid hormone (PTH) were related to height in 9471 subjects. Relation with height was evaluated with linear regression for trend across SNP genotypes with age and gender as covariates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lung disease, vitamin D, and epigenetics</title><link>/posts/lung-disease-vitamin-d-and-epigenetics.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lung-disease-vitamin-d-and-epigenetics.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-susceptibility-of-chronic-lung-diseases-role-of-epigenetics">Vitamin D and susceptibility of chronic lung diseases: role of epigenetics.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Front Pharmacol. 2011;2:50. Epub 2011 Aug 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sundar IK, Rahman I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lung Biology and Disease Program, Department of Environmental Medicine, University of Rochester Medical Center Rochester, NY, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is linked to accelerated decline in lung function, increased inflammation, and reduced immunity in chronic lung diseases. Epidemiological studies have suggested that vitamin D insufficiency is associated with low lung function in susceptible subjects who are exposed to higher levels of environmental agents (airborne particulates). Recent studies have highlighted the role of vitamin D and vitamin D receptor (VDR) in regulation of several genes that are involved in inflammation, immunity, cellular proliferation, differentiation, and apoptosis. Vitamin D has also been implicated in reversal of steroid resistance and airway remodeling, which are the hallmarks of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and severe asthma. VDR protein level is decreased in lungs of patients with COPD. VDR deficient mice develop an abnormal lung phenotype with characteristics of COPD, such as airspace enlargement and decline in lung function associated with increased lung inflammatory cellular influx, and immune-lymphoid aggregates formation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Food allergy 80 percent more likely if have certain genes and vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/food-allergy-80-percent-more-likely-if-have-certain-genes-and-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/food-allergy-80-percent-more-likely-if-have-certain-genes-and-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="gene-vitamin-d-interactions-on-food-sensitization-a-prospective-birth-cohort-study">Gene-vitamin D interactions on food sensitization: a prospective birth cohort study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Allergy. 2011 Nov;66(11):1442-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1398-9995.2011.02681.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1398-9995.2011.02681.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Aug 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liu X, Wang G, Hong X, Wang D, Tsai HJ, Zhang S, Arguelles L, Kumar R, Wang H, Liu R, Zhou Y, Pearson C, Ortiz K, Schleimer R, Holt PG, Pongracic J, Price HE, Langman C, Wang X.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary Ann and J. Milburn Smith Child Health Research Program, Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Hospital, Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Research Center, Department of Pediatrics, Feinberg School of Medicine, Northwestern University, Chicago, IL, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:xnliu@childrensmemorial.org">xnliu@childrensmemorial.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Stem cells need vitamin D too</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-stem-cells-need-vitamin-d-too.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-stem-cells-need-vitamin-d-too.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-autoimmunity-and-graft-versus-host-disease-riskimplication-for-preventive-therapy">Vitamin-D deficiency, autoimmunity and graft-versus-host-disease risk:Implication for preventive therapy&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Experimental Hematology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mona Benrashid1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim Moyers1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohamad Mohty2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bipin N. Savani3, Corresponding author contact information, E-mail the corresponding author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Clinical Pharmacy division, Department of Pharmacy, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville, TN, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Hematology Department, CHU de Nantes, Universite de Nantes, and INSERM U892, Nantes, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Hematology and Stem Cell Transplantation Section, Division of Hematology/ Oncology, Department of Medicine, Vanderbilt University Medical Center and Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Nashville, TN, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pharmacology of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pharmacology-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pharmacology-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Genetic differences explain some of vitamin D variation in African-Americans</title><link>/posts/genetic-differences-explain-some-of-vitamin-d-variation-in-african-americans.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genetic-differences-explain-some-of-vitamin-d-variation-in-african-americans.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="common-variation-in-vitamin-d-pathway-genes-predicts-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-among-african-americans">Common Variation in Vitamin D Pathway Genes Predicts Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels among African Americans&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Lisa B. Signorello 1, 2*, Jiajun Shi 2, Qiuyin Cai 2, Wei Zheng 2, Scott M. Williams 3, Jirong Long 2, Sarah S. Cohen 1, Guoliang Li 2, Bruce W. Hollis 4, Jeffrey R. Smith5, William J. Blot1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International Epidemiology Institute, Rockville, Maryland, United States of America, Division of Epidemiology, Department of Medicine, Vanderbilt Epidemiology Center, Vanderbilt University School of Medicine and the Vanderbilt-Ingram Cancer Center, Nashville, Tennessee, United States of America, Division of Human Genomics, Department of Molecular Physiology and Biophysics, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, United States of America, Department of Pediatrics, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina, United States of America, Division of Genetic Medicine, Department of Medicine, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville, Tennessee, United States of America&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Possible ways that vitamin D does its magic</title><link>/posts/possible-ways-that-vitamin-d-does-its-magic.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/possible-ways-that-vitamin-d-does-its-magic.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Expect that within a few years we will know that the vitamin D magic is&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>One of these ways&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Several of these ways&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Some nnumber of these ways + ways not yet proposed&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Personally, I am rooting for DNA repair&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>because it sounds so good, not because any better case has been made. Henry Lahore March 2012&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-cancer-a-review-of-molecular-mechanisms-jan-2012">Vitamin D and cancer: a review of molecular mechanisms. (Jan 2012)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cellular-and-molecular-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-carcinogenesis-nov-2011">Cellular and molecular effects of vitamin D on carcinogenesis (Nov 2011)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#does-vitamin-d-protect-against-dna-damage-feb-2012">Does vitamin D protect against DNA damage? (Feb 2012)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-a-review-of-molecular-mechanisms-jan-2012">Vitamin D and cancer: a review of molecular mechanisms. (Jan 2012)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Biochem J. 2012 Jan 1;441(1):61-76.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unsure of association of vitamin D and prostate Cancer - 2011</title><link>/posts/unsure-of-association-of-vitamin-d-and-prostate-cancer-2011.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/unsure-of-association-of-vitamin-d-and-prostate-cancer-2011.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Learning about MS and vitamin D in offspring from mice</title><link>/posts/learning-about-ms-and-vitamin-d-in-offspring-from-mice.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/learning-about-ms-and-vitamin-d-in-offspring-from-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="seasonal-gestational-and-postnatal-influences-on-multiple-sclerosis-the-beneficial-role-of-a-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-early-life">Seasonal, gestational and postnatal influences on multiple sclerosis: The beneficial role of a vitamin D supplementation during early life.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Neurol Sci. 2011 Sep 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fernandes de Abreu DA, Landel V, Féron F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is now strong evidence linking vitamin D, the steroid hormone of sunlight, and Multiple Sclerosis (MS).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two of the most intriguing findings are the season of birth and childhood sun exposure effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They both suggest that a vitamin D deficiency during these critical imprinting periods is a risk factor for MS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast cancer and Vitamin D receptors, CP27B1, and CYP24A1</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d-receptors-cp27b1-and-cyp24a1.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d-receptors-cp27b1-and-cyp24a1.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="alterations-in-vitamin-d-signalling-and-metabolic-pathways-in-breast-cancer-progression-a-study-of-vdr-cyp27b1-and-cyp24a1-expression-in-benign-and-malignant-breast-lesions">Alterations in Vitamin D signalling and metabolic pathways in breast cancer progression: a study of VDR, CYP27B1 and CYP24A1 expression in benign and malignant breast lesions&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Cancer 2010, 10:483 doi:10.1186/1471-2407-10-483&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nair Lopes (&lt;a href="mailto:nlopes@ipatimup.pt">nlopes@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Barbara Sousa (&lt;a href="mailto:bsousa@ipatimup.pt">bsousa@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Diana Martins (&lt;a href="mailto:dianam@ipatimup.pt">dianam@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Madalena Gomes (&lt;a href="mailto:mgomes@ipatimup.pt">mgomes@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Daniella Vieira (&lt;a href="mailto:daniellavieira.hu@gmail.com">daniellavieira.hu@gmail.com&lt;/a>) Luiz A Veronese (&lt;a href="mailto:lveronese@terra.com.br">lveronese@terra.com.br&lt;/a>) Fernanda Milanezi (&lt;a href="mailto:mmilanezi@ipatimup.pt">mmilanezi@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Joana Paredes (&lt;a href="mailto:jparedes@ipatimup.pt">jparedes@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jose L Costa (&lt;a href="mailto:jcosta@ipatimup.pt">jcosta@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>) Fernando Schmitt (&lt;a href="mailto:fschmitt@ipatimup.pt">fschmitt@ipatimup.pt&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Publication date 11 September 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nair Lopes1, Barbara Sousa1, Diana Martins1, Madalena Gomes1, Daniella Vieira2, Luiz A Veronese3, Fernanda Milanezi1, Joana Paredes1, Jose L Costa1, Fernando Schmitt1, 4&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CYP24A1 gene mutation is a cause of rare infant vitamin D toxicity</title><link>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-mutation-is-a-cause-of-rare-infant-vitamin-d-toxicity.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-mutation-is-a-cause-of-rare-infant-vitamin-d-toxicity.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mutations-in-cyp24a1-and-idiopathic-infantile-hypercalcemia">Mutations in CYP24A1 and Idiopathic Infantile Hypercalcemia.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med. 2011 Jun 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schlingmann KP, Kaufmann M, Weber S, Irwin A, Goos C, John U, Misselwitz J, Klaus G, Kuwertz-Bröking E, Fehrenbach H, Wingen AM, Güran T, Hoenderop JG, Bindels RJ, Prosser DE, Jones G, Konrad M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Muenster (K.P.S., E.K.-B., M. Konrad); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Marburg (K.P.S., C.G.); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Essen (S.W., A.M.W.); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Jena (U.J., J.M.); Kuratorium für Heimdialyse Pediatric Kidney Center, Marburg (G.K.); and Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Memmingen (H.F.) - all in Germany; Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, ON, Canada (M. Kaufmann, A.I., D.E.P., G.J.); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey (T.G.); and Radboud University, Nijmegen, the Netherlands (J.G.H., R.J.B.).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Genes varied seasonally with European but not Asian ancestors – VDBP</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-genes-varied-seasonally-with-european-but-not-asian-ancestors-vdbp.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-genes-varied-seasonally-with-european-but-not-asian-ancestors-vdbp.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-of-vitamin-d-binding-protein-vdbp-polymorphisms-and-serum-25ohd-concentrations-in-a-sample-of-young-canadian-adults-of-different-ancestry">Association of vitamin D binding protein (VDBP) polymorphisms and serum 25(OH)D concentrations in a sample of young Canadian adults of different ancestry&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Agnes Gozdzika, &lt;a href="mailto:agnes.gozdzik@utoronto.ca">agnes.gozdzik@utoronto.ca&lt;/a> , Justin Zhub, Betty Y.-L. Wongb, Lei Fub, David E.C. Coleb, and Esteban J. Parraa,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Anthropology, University of Toronto at Mississauga, 3359 Mississauga Road North, Mississauga, Ontario L5L 1C6, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathobiology, University of Toronto, Banting Institute, 100 College Street, Toronto, Ontario M5G 1L5, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prostate Cancer – Vitamin D – CYP27B1 – CYP24</title><link>/posts/prostate-cancer-vitamin-d-cyp27b1-cyp24.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prostate-cancer-vitamin-d-cyp27b1-cyp24.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-metabolism-and-action-in-the-prostate-implications-for-health-and-disease">Vitamin D metabolism and action in the prostate: Implications for health and disease.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-metabolism-and-action-in-the-prostate-implications-for-health-and-disease">Vitamin D metabolism and action in the prostate: Implications for health and disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2011 Jun 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Swami S, Krishnan AV, Feldman D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, CA 94305, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prostate cancer (PCa) is the second most common cancer in men worldwide. Epidemiological, molecular, and cellular studies have implicated vitamin D deficiency as a risk factor for the development and/or progression of PCa. Studies using cell culture systems and animal models suggest that vitamin D acts to reduce the growth of PCa through regulation of cellular proliferation and differentiation. However, although preclinical studies provide a strong indication for anti-cancer activity, proof of therapeutic benefits in men is still lacking. The anti-proliferative and pro-differentiating properties of vitamin D have been attributed to calcitriol &lt;span>[1,25(OH)(2)D(3)]&lt;/span>, the hormonally active form of vitamin D, acting through the vitamin D receptor (VDR). Metabolism of vitamin D in target tissues is mediated by two key enzymes: 1?-hydroxylase (CYP27B1), which catalyzes the synthesis of calcitriol from 25(OH)D and 24-hydroxylase (CYP24), which catalyzes the initial step in the conversion of calcitriol to less active metabolites. Many factors affect the balance of calcitriol synthesis and catabolism and several maneuvers, like combination therapy of calcitriol with other drugs, have been explored to treat PCa and reduce its risk. The current paper is an overview addressing some of the key factors that influence the biological actions of vitamin D and its metabolites in the treatment and/or prevention of PCa.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genetic influence on Vitamin D is small compared to environmental influence</title><link>/posts/genetic-influence-on-vitamin-d-is-small-compared-to-environmental-influence.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genetic-influence-on-vitamin-d-is-small-compared-to-environmental-influence.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="determinants-of-vitamin-d-status-focus-on-genetic-variations">Determinants of vitamin D status: focus on genetic variations.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens. 2011 Jul;20(4):331-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Berry D, Hyppönen E. &lt;a href="mailto:e.hypponen@ich.ucl.ac.uk">e.hypponen@ich.ucl.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Paediatric Epidemiology and Biostatistics and Medical Research Council Centre for the Epidemiology of Child Health, UCL Institute of Child Health, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE OF REVIEW:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of vitamin D beyond its importance for bone health is under much debate. In this article, we review recent evidence for genetic influences on 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> and discuss the uses of this information and its importance for public health.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D targets 4 MS genes</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-targets-4-ms-genes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-targets-4-ms-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="genetics-and-the-environment-converge-to-dysregulate-n-glycosylation-in-multiple-sclerosis">Genetics and the environment converge to dysregulate N-glycosylation in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nature Communications, Article number: 334, doi:10.1038/ncomms1333&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Haik Mkhikian, Ani Grigorian, Carey F. Li, Hung-Lin Chen, Barbara Newton, Raymond W. Zhou, Christine Beeton, Sevan Torossian, Gevork Grikor Tatarian, Sung-Uk Lee, Ken Lau, Erin Walker, Katherine A. Siminovitch, K. George Chandy, Zhaoxia Yu, James W. Dennis. &lt;strong>Michael Demetriou&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="mailto:mdemetri@uci.edu">mdemetri@uci.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received – 02 February 2011, Accepted – 04 May 2011, Published – 31 May 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Melanoma and Vitamin D genes - multiple papers</title><link>/posts/melanoma-and-vitamin-d-genes-multiple-papers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/melanoma-and-vitamin-d-genes-multiple-papers.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki-summary-melanoma-27-more-likely-with-bsmi-variant-of-vitamin-d-receptor-2011">VitaminDWiki Summary: Melanoma 27% more likely with BsmI variant of vitamin D receptor (2011)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#melanoma-risk-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-march-2014">Melanoma risk is associated with vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms (March 2014)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="vitamindwiki-summary-melanoma-27-more-likely-with-bsmi-variant-of-vitamin-d-receptor-2011">VitaminDWiki Summary: Melanoma 27% more likely with BsmI variant of vitamin D receptor (2011)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sun exposure, vitamin D receptor polymorphisms FokI and BsmI and risk of multiple primary melanoma&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiol. 2011 May 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mandelcorn-Monson R, Marrett L, Kricker A, Armstrong BK, Orlow I, Goumas C, Paine S, Rosso S, Thomas N, Millikan RC, Pole JD, Cotignola J, Rosen C, Kanetsky PA, Lee-Taylor J, Begg CB, Berwick M.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Race vs vitamin D level - Veith</title><link>/posts/race-vs-vitamin-d-level-veith.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/race-vs-vitamin-d-level-veith.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Type 1 diabetes, genes and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-genes-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-genes-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="two-abstracts-on-this-page">two abstracts on this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolor00fhypothesis--three-genes-show-why-type-1-diabetes-patients-need-more-vitamin-d--mar-2011span">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Hypothesis – Three genes show why type 1 diabetes patients need more vitamin D – Mar 2011&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="inherited-variation-in-vitamin-d-genes-is-associated-with-predisposition-to-autoimmune-disease-type-1-diabetes">Inherited Variation in Vitamin D Genes Is Associated With Predisposition to Autoimmune Disease Type 1 Diabetes.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Diabetes. 2011 Mar 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cooper JD, Smyth DJ, Walker NM, Stevens H, Burren OS, Wallace C, Greissl C, Ramos-Lopez E, Hypponen E, Dunger DB, Spector TD, Ouwehand WH, Wang TJ, Badenhoop K, Todd JA. &lt;a href="mailto:john.todd@cimr.cam.ac.uk">john.todd@cimr.cam.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unable to find a gene linking vitamin D and MS</title><link>/posts/unable-to-find-a-gene-linking-vitamin-d-and-ms.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/unable-to-find-a-gene-linking-vitamin-d-and-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-metabolic-pathway-genes-and-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-canadians">Vitamin D metabolic pathway genes and risk of multiple sclerosis in Canadians.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Neurol Sci. 2011 Mar 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Orton SM, Ramagopalan SV, Para AE, Lincoln MR, Handunnetthi L, Chao MJ, Morahan J, Morrison KM, Sadovnick AD, Ebers GC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wellcome Trust Centre for Human Genetics and Department of Clinical Neurology, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Multiple sclerosis (MS) is determined by interactions between genes and environment and the influence of vitamin D adequacy has been proposed. Previous studies have shown that serum 25-hydroxyvitaminD (25(OH)D) levels are genetically influenced. Polymorphisms in vitamin D pathway genes are candidates for association with MS susceptibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CYP24A1 gene and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;!-- ~tc~start2 ~/tc~ -->
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Proper activation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>makes sure that Vitamin D does not accumulate in the body&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Too much activation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Less vitamin D actually gets to cells&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Too little activation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Vitamin D accumulates to toxic levels ( &amp;lt;1 in 10,000 people)&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Blood test does not show when a poor CYP24A1 gene stops Vitamin D from getting to cells&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="400"> &lt;a href="/categories/genetics">Click here for more information&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several Cancers and health problems appear to protect themselves by changing CYP24A1 activation&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>People with TB and one geneotype benefited more from 10000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/people-with-tb-and-one-geneotype-benefited-more-from-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/people-with-tb-and-one-geneotype-benefited-more-from-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-dose-vitamin-d3-during-intensive-phase-antimicrobial-treatment-of-pulmonary-tuberculosis-a-double-blind-randomised-controlled-trial">High-dose vitamin D(3) during intensive-phase antimicrobial treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis: a double-blind randomised controlled trial.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Lancet. 2011 Jan 15;377(9761):242-50. Epub 2011 Jan 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martineau AR, Timms PM, Bothamley GH, Hanifa Y, Islam K, Claxton AP, Packe GE, Moore-Gillon JC, Darmalingam M, Davidson RN, Milburn HJ, Baker LV, Barker RD, Woodward NJ, Venton TR, Barnes KE, Mullett CJ, Coussens AK, Rutterford CM, Mein CA, Davies GR, Wilkinson RJ, Nikolayevskyy V, Drobniewski FA, Eldridge SM, Griffiths CJ.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolites and genes may predict responses to Calcium and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/metabolites-and-genes-may-predict-responses-to-calcium-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolites-and-genes-may-predict-responses-to-calcium-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="genomic-and-metabolomic-patterns-segregate-with-responses-to-calcium-and-vitamin-d-supplementation">Genomic and metabolomic patterns segregate with responses to calcium and vitamin D supplementation.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2011 Jan;105(1):71-9. Epub 2010 Aug 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elnenaei MO, Chandra R, Mangion T, Moniz C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical Biochemistry Department, King&amp;rsquo;s College Hospital, Denmark Hill, London SE5 9RS, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inter-individual response differences to vitamin D and Ca supplementation may be under genetic control through vitamin D and oestrogen receptor genes, which may influence their absorption and/or metabolism. Metabolomic studies on blood and urine from subjects supplemented with Ca and vitamin D reveal different metabolic profiles that segregate with genotype. Genotyping was performed for oestrogen receptor 1 gene (ESR1) and vitamin D receptor gene (VDR) in fifty-six postmenopausal women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twins reduction in vitamin D in the winter or summer</title><link>/posts/twins-reduction-in-vitamin-d-in-the-winter-or-summer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/twins-reduction-in-vitamin-d-in-the-winter-or-summer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="heritability-and-seasonal-variability-of-vitamin-d-concentrations-in-male-twins">Heritability and seasonal variability of vitamin D concentrations in male twins.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2010 Oct 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karohl C, Su S, Kumari M, Tangpricha V, Veledar E, Vaccarino V, Raggi P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Medicine and the Division of Endocrinology, Metabolism and Lipids, Department of Medicine, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, and the Division of Nephrology, Hospital de Clínicas de Porto Alegre, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schizophrenia and vitamin D have latitude-related genes</title><link>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-have-latitude-related-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="schizophrenia-and-vitamin-d-related-genes-could-have-been-subject-to-latitude-driven-adaptation">Schizophrenia and Vitamin D Related Genes Could Have Been Subject to Latitude-driven Adaptation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Roberto Amato email, Michele Pinelli email, Antonella Monticelli email, Gennaro Miele email and Sergio Cocozza email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Evolutionary Biology 2010, 10:351doi:10.1186/1471-2148-10-351; Published: 	11 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many natural phenomena are directly or indirectly related to latitude. Living at different latitudes, indeed, has its consequences with being exposed to different climates, diets, light/dark cycles, etc. In humans, one of the best known examples of genetic traits following a latitudinal gradient is skin pigmentation. Nevertheless, also several diseases show latitudinal clinals such as hypertension, cancer, dismetabolic conditions, schizophrenia, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease and many more.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>