<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Telomere on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/telomere.html</link><description>Recent content in Telomere on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/telomere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Low vitamin D in pregnancy – epigenetic pancreas problems in offspring (mice)</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-epigenetic-pancreas-problems-in-offspring-mice.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-epigenetic-pancreas-problems-in-offspring-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-restricted-diet-has-consequences-in-the-formation-of-pancreatic-isletinsulin-signaling-in-the-adult-offspring-of-mice">Maternal vitamin D-restricted diet has consequences in the formation of pancreatic islet/insulin-signaling in the adult offspring of mice.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocrine. 2016 May 3. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maia-Ceciliano TC1, Barreto-Vianna AR1, Barbosa-da-Silva S1, Aguila MB1, Faria TS1, Mandarim-de-Lacerda CA2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Laboratorio de Morfometria, Metabolismo e Doenca Cardiovascular, Centro Biomedico, Instituto de Biologia, Universidade do Estado de Rio de Janeiro - UERJ, Av. 28 de Setembro, 87 fds, Rio de Janeiro, RJ, 20551-030, Brazil.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Centenarians have good Vitamin D Receptor genes (or take lots of vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/centenarians-have-good-vitamin-d-receptor-genes-or-take-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/centenarians-have-good-vitamin-d-receptor-genes-or-take-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="impact-of-vitamin-d-receptor-polymorphisms-in-centenarians">Impact of vitamin D receptor polymorphisms in centenarians&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cristina Gussago , Beatrice Arosio , Franca Rosa Guerini, Evelyn Ferri, Andrea Saul Costa, Martina Casati, Elisa Mariadele Bollini, Francesco Ronchetti, Elena Colombo and 3 more&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrine, pp 1-7, First online: 08 March 2016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a seco-sterol produced endogenously in the skin or obtained from certain foods. It exerts its action through binding to intracellular vitamin D receptor (VDR). Lately, the role of vitamin D has been revised regarding its potential advantage on delaying the process of aging. The aim of this study was to assess the contribution of VDR gene polymorphisms in healthy aging and longevity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rotterdam Vitamin D dissertation text</title><link>/posts/rotterdam-vitamin-d-dissertation-text.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rotterdam-vitamin-d-dissertation-text.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Summary and PDF is at &lt;a href="/posts/more-vitamin-d-makes-for-better-health-dissertation-based-on-rotterdam-studies">More vitamin D makes for better health – dissertation based on Rotterdam studies – Oct 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following is a rough dump of the text from the dissertation - for ease of translation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D and Cardio-metabolic Health in the Elderly - The Rotterdam Study&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamine D en cardiometabole gezondheid in ouderen: De - Rotterdam Studie&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thesis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>to obtain the degree of Doctor from the&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Erasmus University Rotterdam&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Telomeres (which extend life) appear to be extended by Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/telomeres-which-extend-life-appear-to-be-extended-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/telomeres-which-extend-life-appear-to-be-extended-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Update: Telemeres in boys were 2.5% longer if 9 ng higher vitamin D – July 2018&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D as predictor of telomere length in the transition from child to adolescent&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Revue d&amp;rsquo;Épidémiologie et de Santé Publique, Volume 66, Supplement 5, July 2018, Page S237, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respe.2018.05.015">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respe.2018.05.015&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Van AartaN. MichelsaI.SioenabD .MartenscT.NawrotcS.De Henauwa&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Results&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telomere length was shorter with increasing age (P = 0.01). Vitamin D was not associated with telomere length in cross-sectional analysis combining both sexes, but in boys higher vitamin D was related to longer telomeres. An interquartile increase in vitamin D (9.4 ng/mL) was associated with a 2.5% (95% confidence interval: 0.1 to 4.9%; P = 0.04) increase in telomere length. Longitudinal analysis showed similar results for boys (P = 0.02).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Handbook of Vitamin D – 700 pages – 2013</title><link>/posts/handbook-of-vitamin-d-700-pages-2013.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/handbook-of-vitamin-d-700-pages-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#handbook-of-vitamin-d-in-human-health-vitamin-d-in-human-health-prevention-treatment-and-toxicity">Handbook of vitamin D in human health: vitamin D in human health, Prevention, treatment and toxicity&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#overview-of-key-vitamin-d-modified-conditions">Overview of key vitamin D modified conditions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-musculoskeletal-health">Vitamin D and musculoskeletal health&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-chronic-disease">Vitamin D and chronic disease&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-infectious-disease">Vitamin D and infectious disease&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-cancer">Vitamin D and cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#women-and-children">Women and children&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#index">Index&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="handbook-of-vitamin-d-in-human-health-vitamin-d-in-human-health-prevention-treatment-and-toxicity">Handbook of vitamin D in human health: vitamin D in human health, Prevention, treatment and toxicity&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Edited by: Ronald Ross Watson&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus in blacks associated with low vitamin D AND short telomeres</title><link>/posts/lupus-in-blacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-short-telomeres.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-in-blacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-short-telomeres.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="systemic-lupus-erythematosus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-are-associated-with-shorter-telomere-length-among-african-americans-a-case-control-study">Systemic Lupus Erythematosus and Vitamin D Deficiency Are Associated with Shorter Telomere Length among African Americans: A Case-Control Study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2013 May 20;8(5):e63725. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0063725.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0063725.&lt;/a> Print 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hoffecker BM, Raffield LM, Kamen DL, Nowling TK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina, United States of America.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a chronic systemic autoimmune disease that disproportionately affects African American females. The causes of SLE are unknown but postulated to be a combination of genetic predisposition and environmental triggers. Vitamin D deficiency is one of the possible environmental triggers. In this study we evaluated relationships between vitamin D status, cellular aging (telomere length) and anti-telomere antibodies among African American Gullah women with SLE. The study population included African American female SLE patients and unaffected controls from the Sea Island region of South Carolina. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were measured using a nonchromatographic radioimmunoassay. Telomere length was measured in genomic DNA of peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) by monochrome multiplex quantitative PCR. Anti-telomere antibody levels were measured by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). Patients with SLE had significantly shorter telomeres and higher anti-telomere antibody titers compared to age- and gender-matched unaffected controls. There was a positive correlation between anti-telomere antibody levels and disease activity among patients and a significant correlation of shorter telomeres with lower 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in both patients and controls. In follow-up examination of a subset of the patients, the patients who remained vitamin D deficient tended to have shorter telomeres than those patients whose 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were repleted. Increasing 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in African American patients with SLE may be beneficial in maintaining telomere length and preventing cellular aging. Moreover, anti-telomere antibody levels may be a promising biomarker of SLE status and disease activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>60 percent chance of longer white blood cell (leukocyte) telomere if have lots of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/60-percent-chance-of-longer-white-blood-cell-leukocyte-telomere-if-have-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/60-percent-chance-of-longer-white-blood-cell-leukocyte-telomere-if-have-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#plasma-vitamin-d-biomarkers-and-leukocyte-telomere-length">Plasma Vitamin D Biomarkers and Leukocyte Telomere Length.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="plasma-vitamin-d-biomarkers-and-leukocyte-telomere-length">Plasma Vitamin D Biomarkers and Leukocyte Telomere Length.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Epidemiol. 2013 May 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liu JJ, Prescott J, Giovannucci E, Hankinson SE, Rosner B, Han J, De Vivo I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D may reduce telomere shortening through anti-inflammatory and anti-cell proliferation mechanisms. In the present study, we examined the association between vitamin D and relative leukocyte telomere length by using both plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)2D) biomarkers. Vitamin D biomarker levels and leukocyte telomere length were measured using plasma samples collected in 1989-1990 from participants of the Nurses&amp;rsquo; Health Study, a study of nurses from 11 US states. In total, 1,424 participants had their 25(OH)D levels assessed and 837 had their 1,25(OH)2D levels assessed. Genotyping was performed on 480 participants on 12 single nucleotide polymorphisms in vitamin D-related genes. Linear and logistic regression models were used. Higher 25(OH)D levels were significantly associated with longer telomere length (P for trend = 0.05), and the odds ratio increased from 1.07 (P = 0.65) when comparing the second lowest quartile of 25(OH)D with the lowest to &lt;strong>1.59 (P = 0.01) when comparing the highest quartile with the lowest&lt;/strong> . Vitamin D-related single nucleotide polymorphisms and 1,25(OH)2D levels were not significantly associated with telomere length. Total calcium intake significantly modified the association between 25(OH)D and telomere length (P for interaction = 0.05). Higher plasma 25(OH)D levels may be associated with longer telomeres, and this association may be modified by calcium intake.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The problems of vitamin d insufficiency in older people</title><link>/posts/the-problems-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-older-people.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-problems-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-older-people.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-problems-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-older-people">The problems of vitamin d insufficiency in older people.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Aging Dis. 2012 Aug;3(4):313-29. Epub 2012 Jun 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boucher BJ. Queen Mary University of London, Centre for Diabetes, Blizard Institute, London, E12AT, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>(PDF is attached at the bottom of this page)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This report reviews evidence on disorders related to inadequate vitamin D repletion in older people. Vitamin D is as essential for bone health in adults as in children, preventing osteomalacia and muscle weakness and protecting against falls and low-impact fractures. Vitamin D is provided by skin synthesis by UVB-irradiation from summer sunshine and to a small extent by absorption from food. However, these processes become less efficient with age. Loss of mobility or residential care restricts solar exposure. Reduced appetite and financial problems often add to these problems. Thus, hypovitaminosis D is common world-wide, but is more common and more severe in older people.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects DNA against UV skin damage – 5 studies 2012-2013</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-dna-against-uv-skin-damage-5-studies-2012-2013.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-dna-against-uv-skin-damage-5-studies-2012-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Extensive proof that Vitamin D protects DNA in skin from UV damage&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Observation:&lt;/strong> People get a sunburn when getting lots of sun after months of little sun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Question:&lt;/strong> Would they not get a sunburn if they first stocked up on vitamin D?&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sunlight-and-vitamin-d-affect-dna-damage-cell-division-and-cell-death-in-human-lymphocytes-a-cross-sectional-study-in-south-australia">Sunlight and vitamin D affect DNA damage, cell division and cell death in human lymphocytes: a cross-sectional study in South Australia.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3-enhances-cellular-defences-against-uv-induced-oxidative-and-other-forms-of-dna-damage-in-skin">1?,25 Dihydroxyvitamin D(3) enhances cellular defences against UV-induced oxidative and other forms of DNA damage in skin.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#perspective-protective-actions-of-vitamin-d-in-uvb-induced-skin-cancer">Perspective Protective actions of vitamin D in UVB induced skin cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#active-vitamin-d-protects-skin-against-sunlight-damage--nov-2012">Active vitamin D protects skin against sunlight damage – Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-death-by-sunshine">Vitamin D and Death by Sunshine&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biologically-efficient-solar-radiation-vitamin-d-production-and-induction-of-cutaneous-malignant-melanoma">Biologically efficient solar radiation: Vitamin D production and induction of cutaneous malignant melanoma&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="sunlight-and-vitamin-d-affect-dna-damage-cell-division-and-cell-death-in-human-lymphocytes-a-cross-sectional-study-in-south-australia">Sunlight and vitamin D affect DNA damage, cell division and cell death in human lymphocytes: a cross-sectional study in South Australia.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mutagenesis. 2012 Sep;27(5):609-14. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/mutage/ges026.">doi: 10.1093/mutage/ges026.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Apr 29.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Correcting magnesium deficiencies may prolong life – Space Station</title><link>/posts/correcting-magnesium-deficiencies-may-prolong-life-space-station.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/correcting-magnesium-deficiencies-may-prolong-life-space-station.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Clin Interv Aging. 2012;7:51-4. Epub 2012 Feb 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rowe WJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical University of Ohio at Toledo, Ohio, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:rowerun@aol.com">rowerun@aol.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The International Space Station provides an extraordinary facility to study the accelerated aging process in microgravity, which could be triggered by significant reductions in magnesium (Mg) ion levels with, in turn, elevations of catecholamines and vicious cycles between the two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With space flight there are significant reductions of serum Mg (P &amp;lt; 0.0001) that have been shown in large studies of astronauts and cosmonauts.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>