<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>How Much Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/how-much-vitamin-d.html</link><description>Recent content in How Much Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/how-much-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2400 IU raised both black and white women to 40 ng of vitamin D – RCT 2013</title><link>/posts/2400-iu-raised-both-black-and-white-women-to-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-rct-2013.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2400-iu-raised-both-black-and-white-women-to-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-rct-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-young-caucasian-and-african-american-women">Vitamin D supplementation in young Caucasian and African American women&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Journal of Bone and Mineral Research Vol. 28 Issue 7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christopher J Gallagher MD1,*,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prachi S Jindal MBBS1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lynette M Smith MS2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is limited information on the effects of vitamin D on serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D in young people and none on African Americans. The main objective of this trial was to measure the effect of different doses of Vitamin D3 on serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) and serum PTH (parathyroid hormone) in young women with vitamin D insufficiency (serum 25OHD&amp;lt; 20ngml (50nmol/L). A randomized double blind placebo controlled trial of vitamin D3 was conducted in young Caucasian and African American women, age 25–45 years. 198 healthy Caucasian (60 percent) and African American (40 percent) women were randomly assigned to placebo, vitamin D3 &lt;strong>400, 800, 1600 or 2400 IU&lt;/strong> daily. Calcium supplements were added to maintain a total calcium intake of 1200–1400 mg daily. The primary outcomes of the study were the final serum 25OHD and PTH levels at 12 months. The absolute increase in serum 25OHD with vitamin D 400, 800, 1600 and 2400 IU daily was slightly greater in African Americans than Caucasian women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Took 4 months of 400 IU vitamin D for Iranian infants to get serum level of 30 ng</title><link>/posts/took-4-months-of-400-iu-vitamin-d-for-iranian-infants-to-get-serum-level-of-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/took-4-months-of-400-iu-vitamin-d-for-iranian-infants-to-get-serum-level-of-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="attaining-sufficient-levels-of-vitamind-in-deficient-neonates-with-two-regimens-of-vitamin-d-supplementation">ATTAINING SUFFICIENT LEVELS OF VITAMIND IN DEFICIENT NEONATES WITH TWO REGIMENS OF VITAMIN D SUPPLEMENTATION&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Presented at 6th Europaediatrics Conference, June 2013, Scotland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mehrdad Shakiba ; Ali Pahlosaye Shahid Sadoughi Hospital, Iran&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is common in pregnancy and human milk is not adequate for delivering of vitamin D so supplementation is necessary, but how long it takes to have sufficient level of vitamin D in infants who are delivered from deficient mothers and finding an alternative way to supply it in the first month are the aims of this study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Even with 400 IU of vitamin D in winter, 1 in 6 were still vitamin D deficient – RCT</title><link>/posts/even-with-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-in-winter-1-in-6-were-still-vitamin-d-deficient-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/even-with-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-in-winter-1-in-6-were-still-vitamin-d-deficient-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="randomized-controlled-trial-of-the-effects-of-vitamin-dfortified-milk-and-bread-on-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-families-in-denmark-during-winter-the-vitmad-study">Randomized controlled trial of the effects of vitamin D–fortified milk and bread on serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations in families in Denmark during winter: the VitmaD study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr August 2013 ajcn.059469&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katja H Madsen &lt;a href="mailto:kjma@food.dtu.dk">kjma@food.dtu.dk&lt;/a> , Lone B Rasmussen, Rikke Andersen, Christian Mølgaard, Jette Jakobsen, Poul J Bjerrum, Elisabeth W Andersen, Heddie Mejborn, and Inge Tetens&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Divisions of Nutrition (KHM, LBR, RA, HM, and IT) and Food Chemistry (JJ), National Food Institute, Technical University of Denmark, Søborg, Denmark; the Department of Applied Mathematics and Computer Science, Technical University of Denmark, Lyngby, Denmark (EWA); the Clinical Biochemical Department, Holbæk Hospital, Holbæk, Denmark (PJB); the Department of Nutrition, Exercise and Sports, Faculty of Science, University of Copenhagen, Frederiksberg C, Denmark (CM); and the Hans Christian Andersen Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Odense University Hospital, Odense C, Denmark (CM).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5,000 IU daily was just enough vitamin D for Irish athletes in the winter</title><link>/posts/5000-iu-daily-was-just-enough-vitamin-d-for-irish-athletes-in-the-winter.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5000-iu-daily-was-just-enough-vitamin-d-for-irish-athletes-in-the-winter.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-supplementation-in-elite-irish-athletes">Vitamin D Status and Supplementation in Elite Irish Athletes.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2013 Mar 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pamela J. Magee 1, L. Kirsty Pourshahidi 1, Julie M.W. Wallace 1, John Cleary 2, 3, Joe Conway 4, Edward Harney 5 and Sharon M. Madigan 2, 3&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1 Northern Ireland Centre for Food and Health, University of Ulster, Coleraine, Northern Ireland, 2 High Performance Unit, National Boxing Stadium, Dublin,Ireland,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>3 Irish Institute of Sport, Sports Campus Ireland, Abbottstown, Dublin Ireland,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Response to Vitamin D: summary chart of 8 studies</title><link>/posts/response-to-vitamin-d-summary-chart-of-8-studies.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/response-to-vitamin-d-summary-chart-of-8-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="all-source-basal-vitamin-d-inputs-are-greater-than-previously-thought-and-cutaneous-inputs-are-smaller">All-Source Basal Vitamin D Inputs Are Greater Than Previously Thought and Cutaneous Inputs Are Smaller.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2013 Mar 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heaney RP, Armas LA, French C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creighton University, Omaha, NE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The magnitude of vitamin D inputs in individuals not taking supplements is unknown; however, there is a great deal of information on quantitative response to varying supplement doses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We reanalyzed individual 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentration data from 8 studies involving cholecalciferol supplementation (total sample size = 3000). We extrapolated individual study dose-response curves to zero concentration values for serum 25(OH)D by using both linear and curvilinear approaches and measured seasonal oscillation in the serum 25(OH)D concentration. The total basal input (food plus solar) was calculated to range from a low of 778 iu/d in patients with end-stage renal disease to a high of 2667 iu/d in healthy Caucasian adults. Consistent with expectations, obese individuals had lower baseline, unsupplemented 25(OH)D concentrations and a smaller response to supplements. Similarly, African Americans had both lower baseline concentrations and lower calculated basal, all-source inputs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Endocrine Society Guideline should be raised to 2 ng per 100 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/endocrine-society-guideline-should-be-raised-to-2-ng-per-100-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/endocrine-society-guideline-should-be-raised-to-2-ng-per-100-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-dose-response-is-underestimated-by-endocrine-societys-clinical-practice-guideline">Vitamin D dose response is underestimated by Endocrine Society&amp;rsquo;s Clinical Practice Guideline&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Endocr Connect 2013 EC-13-0008&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Malachi J McKenna &lt;a href="mailto:mjmckenn@iol.ie">mjmckenn@iol.ie&lt;/a> and Barbara F Murray&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M McKenna, St. Michael&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Dun Laoghaire, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Murray, St. Michael&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Dun Laoghaire, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: The recommended daily intakes of vitamin D according to the recent Clinical Practice Guideline (CPG) of the Endocrine Society are 3-to-5-fold higher than the Institute of Medicine (IOM) report. We speculated that these differences could be explained by different mathematical approaches to the vitamin D dose response.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D level can be high, but little benefit: due to kidney, genes, low Magnesium etc.</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Huge increase in UK vitamin D prescriptions by</title><link>/posts/huge-increase-in-uk-vitamin-d-prescriptions-by.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/huge-increase-in-uk-vitamin-d-prescriptions-by.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="httpsunlightscientifictumblrcom-nbsp-nbsphas-the-following">&lt;a href="http://sunlightscientific.tumblr.com/">http://sunlightscientific.tumblr.com/&lt;/a>    Has the following&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{SPLIT(colsize=50%|50%)}&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolorf00vitamin-d-prescriptions-rare-in-july-2011span">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Vitamin D prescriptions rare in July 2011&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/2011.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D on average was about 600th in terms of frequency&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Some PCTs wrote no prescriptions for vitamin D that month.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Let 1000 die from vitamin D deficiency rather than incur 1 lawsuit</title><link>/posts/let-1000-die-from-vitamin-d-deficiency-rather-than-incur-1-lawsuit.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/let-1000-die-from-vitamin-d-deficiency-rather-than-incur-1-lawsuit.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D creates autophagy, as does calorie restriction and high intensity exercise</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-creates-autophagy-as-does-calorie-restriction-and-high-intensity-exercise.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-creates-autophagy-as-does-calorie-restriction-and-high-intensity-exercise.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="an-alternative-to-vitamin-d-supplementshttpgettingstrongerorg201302an-alternative-to-vitamin-d-supplementsmore-412520-getting-stronger-feb-2013">&lt;a href="http://gettingstronger.org/2013/02/an-alternative-to-vitamin-d-supplements/#more-4125%20">An alternative to vitamin D supplements?&lt;/a> Getting Stronger Feb 2013&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Author considers Vitamin D supplements to be like hormone supplements –in that there could be a danger in taking too much, since the body only limits internally generated hormones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author cites three recent studies which indicate that one of the key functions of the vitamin D receptor is to regulate autophagy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author fails to notice that the body does NOT accumulate hormone d.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off Topic: Smaller people may live longer due to more benefit from supplements and drugs</title><link>/posts/off-topic-smaller-people-may-live-longer-due-to-more-benefit-from-supplements-and-drugs.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-smaller-people-may-live-longer-due-to-more-benefit-from-supplements-and-drugs.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hypothesis-the-same-pill-vitamin-d-multivitamin-drug-is-likely-to-have-2x-the-affect-if-the-person-weighs-12-as-much--it-probably-does-not-matter-if-the-pill-is-for-prevention-or-treatment">Hypothesis: The same pill (Vitamin D, multivitamin, drug) is likely to have 2X the affect if the person weighs 1/2 as much. It probably does not matter if the pill is for prevention or treatment&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="note-smaller-people-includes-both">Note: smaller people includes both&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>shorter in height&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>same height but less weight/BMI&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-veterinary-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Veterinary and vitamin D">Overview Veterinary and vitamin D&lt;/a> Most animal supplements are computed per pound of animal weight&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A vet does not give a fixed amount to a cat, but rather bases the drug amount on weight of cat&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D DRI for children lowered to 200 IU in Korea</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-dri-for-children-lowered-to-200-iu-in-korea.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-dri-for-children-lowered-to-200-iu-in-korea.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="adequate-vitamin-d-status-and-adiposity-contribute-to-bone-health-in-peripubertal-nonobese-children">Adequate vitamin D status and adiposity contribute to bone health in peripubertal nonobese children.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Metab. 2013 Jan 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee YA, Kim JY, Kang MJ, Chung SJ, Shin CH, Yang SW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Pediatrics, Seoul National University College of Medicine, 101 Daehak-ro, Jongno-gu, Seoul, 110-769, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dietary reference intake (DRI) of vitamin D for Korean children was &lt;strong>reduced from 400 IU/day in 2005 to 200 IU/day in 2010.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pathways that vitamin D prevents and treats colon cancer discovered, 2000 IU needed</title><link>/posts/pathways-that-vitamin-d-prevents-and-treats-colon-cancer-discovered-2000-iu-needed.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pathways-that-vitamin-d-prevents-and-treats-colon-cancer-discovered-2000-iu-needed.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="using-components-of-the-vitamin-d-pathway-to-prevent-and-treat-colon-cancer">Using components of the vitamin D pathway to prevent and treat colon cancer.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutr Rev. 2012 Dec;70(12):721-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1753-4887.2012.00522.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1753-4887.2012.00522.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Oct 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stubbins RE, Hakeem A, Núñez NP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas 78712, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this review was to analyze the components of vitamin D and their potential usefulness in preventing and treating colorectal cancer. The active form of vitamin D, 1α,25(OH(2) )D(3) , targets the &lt;strong>wnt/β-catenin pathway&lt;/strong> by upregulating key tumor suppressor genes such as E-cadherin, which promotes an epithelial phenotype, but this is only possible when the vitamin D receptor (VDR) is present. Colorectal cell lines have shown that VDR expression levels decrease in the later stages of colon cancer. In colorectal cancers with low VDR expression, treatments to increase VDR expression could target alterations at the genomic and epigenomic levels by modulating transcription factors such as SNAIL1 and by utilizing histone deacetyltransferase inhibitors, respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>European Osteo group recommends 20-50 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/european-osteo-group-recommends-20-50-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/european-osteo-group-recommends-20-50-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-elderly-or-postmenopausal-women">Vitamin D supplementation in elderly or postmenopausal women:&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="a-2013-update-of-the-2008-recommendations-from-the-european-society-for-clinical-and-economic-aspects-of-osteoporosis-and-osteoarthritis-esceo">A 2013 update of the 2008 recommendations from the European Society for Clinical and Economic Aspects of Osteoporosis and Osteoarthritis (ESCEO).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Curr Med Res Opin. 2013 Jan 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rizzoli R, Boonen S, Brandi ML, Bruyère O, Cooper C, Kanis JA, Kaufman JM, Ringe JD, Weryha G, Reginster J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background Vitamin D insufficiency has deleterious consequences on health outcomes. In elderly or postmenopausal women, it may exacerbate osteoporosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Even taking as much as 4200 IU vitamin D 43 percent had less than 30 ng in blood – RCT</title><link>/posts/even-taking-as-much-as-4200-iu-vitamin-d-43-percent-had-less-than-30-ng-in-blood-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/even-taking-as-much-as-4200-iu-vitamin-d-43-percent-had-less-than-30-ng-in-blood-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a---randomised---double-blinded---placebo-controlled---parallel---study--of--vitamin-d3-supplementation-with-different-schemes-based-on-multiples-of-25000-iu-doses">A randomised, double-blinded, placebo-controlled, parallel study of Vitamin D3 supplementation with different schemes based on multiples of 25,000 IU doses.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Etienne Cavalier*(1), Werner Fache (2), Jean-Claude Souberbielle (3).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(1) Department of Clinical Chemistry, University of Liege, CHU Sart-Tilman, Liege Belgium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(2) Zuidstationstraat, Gent, Belgium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(3) Laboratoire d&amp;rsquo;Explorations fonctionnelles, Hopital Necker-Enfants malades, Paris, France&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Corresponding Author: Dr Etienne Cavalier Department of Clinical Chemistry University of Liege, CHU Sart-Tilman B-4000 Liege, Belgium Tel: +32 4 3667692 Fax:+3243667691 &lt;a href="mailto:Etienne.cavalier@chu.ulg.ac.be">Etienne.cavalier@chu.ulg.ac.be&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Vitamin D (VTD) treatment is recommended in patients presenting different causes of diseases. To treat these patients, physicians rely on the different available pharmaceutical forms present in their country. Unfortunately, even in a given country, there is no consensus on the best way to treat the patients. In Belgium, VTD is mostly prescribed as ampoules containing 25,000 IU of VTD. In this randomised controlled study, we evaluated whether four therapeutic schemes using multiples of 25,000 IU of VTD according to basal vitamin D concentration were able to increase or maintain the 25(OH)D serum level above 30 ng/mL. We randomized 175 subjects who received the drug (n=140) or placebo (n=35). Total duration of the study was 12 weeks. Doses ranged from 4167 to 1667 IU/day. Blood sampling was performed at baseline and each 4 visits. In the treated (placebo) subjects, mean 25(OH)D serum concentration was 18.7 (19.1) ng/ml at baseline and 31.5 (20.7) ng/ml at w-12. At the end of the study, 57.1% of subjects treated with VTD presented 25(OH)D serum concentration &amp;gt; 30 ng/ml whereas 94.3% were &amp;gt;20 ng/ml.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D supplementation - Grassroots</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-grassroots.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-grassroots.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="httpwwwgrassrootshealthnethttpwwwgrassrootshealthnet">&lt;a href="http://www.grassrootshealth.net">http://www.grassrootshealth.net&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A great summary chart&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>other charts are attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-how-much-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview How Much vitamin D">Overview How Much vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/is-50-ng-of-vitamin-d-too-high-just-right-or-not-enough">Is 50 ng of vitamin D too high, just right, or not enough&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/how-you-might-double-your-response-to-vitamin-d">How you might double your response to vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/how-often-might-50000-iu-vitamin-d-be-taken-results-of-clinical-trials">How often might 50,000 IU vitamin D be taken - results of clinical trials&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prevention and Treatment of Vitamin D Deficiency</title><link>/posts/prevention-and-treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prevention-and-treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Calcif Tissue Int. 2012 Nov 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sinha A, Cheetham TD, Pearce SH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Genetic Medicine, Newcastle University, International Centre for Life, Central Parkway, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE1 3BZ, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D insufficiency and deficiency are widespread in many countries. We review the evidence pertaining to its prevention and treatment. Deficiency may be adequately treated with many different therapeutic regimens of either cholecalciferol or ergocalciferol, owing to the high therapeutic index of both compounds. Nevertheless, the current evidence suggests that regular dosing with oral cholecalciferol (e.g., 60,000 IU weekly) may have slight advantages over other regimens when replenishing vitamin D stores following deficiency. For long-term supplementation, smaller regular doses, such as cholecalciferol 1,000 IU daily, or 10,000 IU weekly, are suitable. Giving reliable and specific advice about appropriate sunlight exposure remains difficult because of differing interindividual skin pigmentation and variable sunlight UVB content at different latitudes, at different times of year, and in different terrestrial environments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is High Dose Vitamin D Harmful</title><link>/posts/is-high-dose-vitamin-d-harmful.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-high-dose-vitamin-d-harmful.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-high-dose-vitamin-d-harmful">Is High Dose Vitamin D Harmful?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Calcif Tissue Int Dec 2012 DOI 10.1007/s00223-012-9679-1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kerrie M. Sanders • Geoffrey C. Nicholson • Peter R. Ebeling&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K. M. Sanders (&amp;amp;) • G. C. Nicholson • P. R. Ebeling Department of Medicine, Western Health, NorthWest Academic Centre, University of Melbourne, PO Box 294, St Albans, VIC 3021, Australia e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:ksanders@unimelb.edu.au">ksanders@unimelb.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G. C. Nicholson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rural Clinical School, School of Medicine, University of Queensland, Toowoomba, QLD, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets cured for 3 months with 10,000 IU per kg vitamin D (600,000 IU max)</title><link>/posts/rickets-cured-for-3-months-with-10000-iu-per-kg-vitamin-d-600000-iu-max.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-cured-for-3-months-with-10000-iu-per-kg-vitamin-d-600000-iu-max.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="clinical-biochemical-and-radiological-manifestations-of-severe-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-adolescents-versus-children-response-to-therapy">Clinical, biochemical and radiological manifestations of severe vitamin d deficiency in adolescents versus children: response to therapy.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Georgian Med News. 2012 Sep;(210):58-64.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[Article in English, Georgian]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soliman A, De Sanctis V, Adel A, El Awwa A, Bedair S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics and Radiology, Hamad Medical Center, Doha, Qatar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: to compare clinical, biochemical and radiological manifestations of severe vitamin D deficiency (VDD - serum 25 OH - vitamin D level &amp;lt;10 ng/ml) in adolescents and children and to investigate the effects of an intramuscular injection (IM) of vitamin D3 megadose.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30 percent of vitamin D sold now has more than 2000 IU</title><link>/posts/30-percent-of-vitamin-d-sold-now-has-more-than-2000-iu.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/30-percent-of-vitamin-d-sold-now-has-more-than-2000-iu.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nordic countries considering raising vitamin D to US recommended levels</title><link>/posts/nordic-countries-considering-raising-vitamin-d-to-us-recommended-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nordic-countries-considering-raising-vitamin-d-to-us-recommended-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="current-recommended-minimum--300-iu-for-age-2-60--400-iu-for-60">Current recommended minimum 300 IU for age 2-60, 400 IU for &amp;gt;60&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="nordic-countries-includedenmark-finland-iceland-norway--and-sweden">Nordic Countries include:Denmark, Finland, Iceland, Norway, and Sweden&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/germany-span-stylecolor00f800-iuspan-as-of" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2304">Germany = &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">800 IU&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> as of Jan 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/french-society-of-paediatics-vitamin-d-recommendations">French Society of Paediatics Vitamin D recommendations – Jan 2012&lt;/a> lots of details, example: breastfed infants: &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">1000 to 1200 IU&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-recommendations-around-the-world-iu-and-ng">Vitamin D Recommendations around the world - IU and ng&lt;/a> which has the following graph&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Best heart geometry associated with vitamin D of 30-37 ng</title><link>/posts/best-heart-geometry-associated-with-vitamin-d-of-30-37-ng.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/best-heart-geometry-associated-with-vitamin-d-of-30-37-ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Programmers Must Take Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/programmers-must-take-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/programmers-must-take-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-few-items-from-informed-forum-discussion-hackernewshttpnewsycombinatorcomitemid452473520">a few items from informed forum discussion: &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4524735%20">HackerNews&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="devilboy-15-days-ago-">Devilboy 15 days ago |&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Every day at about lunch time I go lie on the roof in the sun for 10 minutes - doctor&amp;rsquo;s orders. I also take D supplements but that alone was not enough to get my levels back to the normal range so I have to get some actual sun as often as I can too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a &amp;lsquo;damned if you do, damned if you don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rsquo; situation here in Australia: Approximately two in three Australians will be diagnosed with skin cancer before the age of 70, while approximately one out of three Australians have vitamin D deficiency&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Factors Influencing Vitamin D Status</title><link>/posts/factors-influencing-vitamin-d-status.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/factors-influencing-vitamin-d-status.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Acta Dermato-Venereologica&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William Tsiaras, Martin A. Weinstock&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The steroid hormone vitamin D is required for normal calcium and phosphorus metabolism and is thus an important contributor to musculoskeletal health. Recent data have linked low vitamin D levels to a wide range of diseases, including cancer, cardiovascular disease, autoimmune disease and infection. Adequate levels of vitamin D are maintained through its cutaneous photosynthesis and oral ingestion. By some estimates, one billion people worldwide have vitamin D deficiency or insufficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How often might 50,000 IU vitamin D be taken - results of clinical trials</title><link>/posts/how-often-might-50000-iu-vitamin-d-be-taken-results-of-clinical-trials.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-often-might-50000-iu-vitamin-d-be-taken-results-of-clinical-trials.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>1700 IU daily average restored HIV vitamin D levels (50000 monthly)</title><link>/posts/1700-iu-daily-average-restored-hiv-vitamin-d-levels-50000-monthly.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1700-iu-daily-average-restored-hiv-vitamin-d-levels-50000-monthly.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-response-to-vitamin-d3-supplementation-50000-iu-monthly-in-youth-with-hiv-1-infection">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Response to Vitamin D3 Supplementation 50,000 IU Monthly in Youth with HIV-1 Infection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism August 29, 2012 jc.2012-2600&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter L. Havens, Kathleen Mulligan, Rohan Hazra, Patricia Flynn, Brandy Rutledge, Marta D. Van Loan, Jorge Lujan-Zilbermann, Bill G. Kapogiannis, Craig M. Wilson, Charles B. Stephensen and the Adolescent Medicine Trials Network for HIV/AIDS Interventions (ATN) 063 Study Team&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Children’s Research Institute (P.L.H.), Medical College of Wisconsin, Children’s Hospital of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, Wisconsin 53201; University of California at San Francisco (K.M.), San Francisco, California 94110; Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (R.H., B.G.K.), Bethesda, Maryland 20892; St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital (P.F.), Memphis, Tennessee 38105; Westat (B.R.), Rockville, Maryland 20850; United States Department of Agriculture Agricultural Research Service (M.D.V.L., C.B.S.), Western Human Nutrition Research Center, Davis, California 95616; University of South Florida College of Medicine (J.L.-Z.), Tampa, Florida 33606; and University of Alabama at Birmingham (C.M.W.), Birmingham, Alabama 35294&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NASA thinks spacestation personnel only need 800 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/nasa-thinks-spacestation-personnel-only-need-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nasa-thinks-spacestation-personnel-only-need-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>7100 IU (50000 weekly) got most women to 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/7100-iu-50000-weekly-got-most-women-to-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7100-iu-50000-weekly-got-most-women-to-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="management-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-young-women-with-1-year-follow-up">Management of vitamin D deficiency in young women with 1-year follow up&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>C. Perdrix , O. Large , R. Fauche , C. Dupraz , MF. LeGoaziou *&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Lecturer. College des Enseignants Generalistes, Universite Claude Bernard LYON 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>General practitioner LYON&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Lecturer. College des Enseignants Generalistes, Universite Claude Bernard LYON 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Lecturer. College des Enseignants Generalistes, Universite Claude Bernard LYON 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Associate Professor. College des Enseignants Generalistes, Universite Claude Bernard LYON1; Corresponding Author: &lt;a href="mailto:mf.legoaziou@medsyn.fr">mf.legoaziou@medsyn.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ABSTRACT&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is very frequently observed among young women. This study reports the follow up of 68 women over a period of 1 year. The objective of this study was to observe doses of vitamin D can correct and preserve blood levels of vitamin D near 75 nmol/L. It was found that large amounts of vitamin D are needed to correct and then maintain vitamin D blood levels (&amp;gt;530,000 units), particularly in veiled women (~720,000 units). Parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels decreased as blood levels of vitamin D increased. Quality of life measured with the SF12® Health Survey questionnaire, improved when the patients&amp;rsquo; vitamin D deficiencies were corrected. This work highlights the need for the development of guidelines to treat and correct vitamin D deficiency for the long term in young adult women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>85% achieved 20 ng with avg of 3300 IU of vitamin D - oral and injection</title><link>/posts/85-percent-achieved-20-ng-with-avg-of-3300-iu-of-vitamin-d-oral-and-injection.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/85-percent-achieved-20-ng-with-avg-of-3300-iu-of-vitamin-d-oral-and-injection.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Every 400 IU increase of vitamin D3 increases serum level about 8 ng– Systematic Review</title><link>/posts/every-400-iu-increase-of-vitamin-d3-increases-serum-level-about-8-ng-systematic-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/every-400-iu-increase-of-vitamin-d3-increases-serum-level-about-8-ng-systematic-review.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>2900 IU of vitamin D (20000 weekly) kept levels above 20 ng during the winter</title><link>/posts/2900-iu-of-vitamin-d-20000-weekly-kept-levels-above-20-ng-during-the-winter.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2900-iu-of-vitamin-d-20000-weekly-kept-levels-above-20-ng-during-the-winter.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="what-is-needed-to-keep-persons-with-multiple-sclerosis-vitamin-d-sufficient-throughout-the-year">What is needed to keep persons with multiple sclerosis vitamin D-sufficient throughout the year?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Neurol. 2012 Aug 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Steffensen LH, Brustad M, Kampman MT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, University Hospital of North Norway, P.O. Box 33, 9038, Tromsø, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:linn.hofsoy.steffensen@unn.no">linn.hofsoy.steffensen@unn.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D sufficiency has been associated with lower risk of multiple sclerosis and may also have a favorable effect on the course of the disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this work was to identify predictors of serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels in persons with multiple sclerosis (MS) and to assess the effect of high-dose vitamin D(3) supplementation on vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>European adults can take 4000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/european-adults-can-take-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/european-adults-can-take-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="table-of-contents">Table of contents&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Abstract &amp;hellip;. 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summary .. 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Table of contents&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background as provided by the European Commission &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;. 5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Terms of reference as provided by the European Commission&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Assessment &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; 6&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Introduction&amp;hellip;..6&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Dietary intakes.7&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>2.1. Adults&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2.2. Infants (&amp;lt;1 year)&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2.3. Children (approximately 1-14 years)&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2.4. Adolescents &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;. 8&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>Hazard identification &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;. 8&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>3.1. Vitamin D physiology&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3.2. Biomarkers of vitamin D intake&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..9&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3.3. Biomarkers of vitamin D status and activity&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.9&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3.4. Mechanisms of toxicity&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;10&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>With just 200 IU vitamin D in intravenous feeds, deficiency results</title><link>/posts/with-just-200-iu-vitamin-d-in-intravenous-feeds-deficiency-results.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/with-just-200-iu-vitamin-d-in-intravenous-feeds-deficiency-results.html</guid><description>&lt;p>!!Recommendations for Changes in Commercially Available Parenteral Multivitamin and Multi–Trace Element Products
&lt;strong>A.S.P.E.N. Position Paper&lt;/strong>
Nutr Clin Pract August 2012 vol. 27 no. 4 440-491
Vincent W. Vanek, MD, FACS, FASPEN (Chair)1
Peggy Borum, PhD, FASPEN2
Alan Buchman, MD, MSPH, FACP, FACG, FACN, AGAF3
Theresa A. Fessler, MS, RD, CNSC4
Lyn Howard, MB, FRCP5
Khursheed Jeejeebhoy, MBBS, PhD, FRCPC6
Marty Kochevar, MS, RPh, BCNSP7
Alan Shenkin, MB, ChB, PhD, FRCP, FRCPath8
Christina J. Valentine, MD, MS, RD9
&lt;strong>Novel Nutrient Task Force, Parenteral Multi-Vitamin and Multi–Trace Element Working Group&lt;/strong>
American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition (A.S.P.E.N.) Board of Directors
1 St. Elizabeth Health Center, Youngstown, Ohio
2 University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida
3 Northwestern University School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois
4 University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia
5 Albany Medical College, Albany, New York
6 Polyclinic, Toronto, Ontario
7 A.S.P.E.N., Silver Spring, Maryland
8 Royal Liverpool University Hospital, Liverpool, England
9 University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, Ohio
Vincent W. Vanek, St. Elizabeth Health Center, 1044 Belmont Ave, PO Box 1790, Youngstown, OH 44501-1790; e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:vince_vanek@hmis.org">vince_vanek@hmis.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>400 iu of vitamin D is like 24 seconds of sun in a swimsuit in Los Angeles</title><link>/posts/400-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-like-24-seconds-of-sun-in-a-swimsuit-in-los-angeles.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/400-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-like-24-seconds-of-sun-in-a-swimsuit-in-los-angeles.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-medpagetoday-june-2012httpwwwmedpagetodaycomprimarycaredietnutrition33442">From &lt;a href="http://www.medpagetoday.com/PrimaryCare/DietNutrition/33442">MedPageToday June 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Others suggested that the levels of vitamin D in studies (400 IUs) are &amp;ldquo;the equivalent of about 24 seconds of sun in your swimming suit at a Los Angeles beach in the summer. No wonder there is no benefit.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-of-time-in-the-sun" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1689">Overview of Time in the Sun&lt;/a> Close!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>4,000 IU in 7 minutes ==&amp;gt; 400 IU in 42 seconds in shorts&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Have getting 50000 IU Vitamin D weekly for 8 weeks got to 30 ng level</title><link>/posts/have-getting-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-for-8-weeks-got-to-30-ng-level.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/have-getting-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-for-8-weeks-got-to-30-ng-level.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="evaluation-of-response-to-treatment-with-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d3-in-deficient-patients">Evaluation of Response to Treatment with 50,000 IU of Vitamin D3 in Deficient Patients&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocr Rev, Vol. 33 (03_MeetingAbstracts): MON-350&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2012 by The Endocrine Society ENDO 2012: June 23-26, 2012, Houston, Texas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tatiane Vilaca, MD1, Marilia Camargo, MD1 and Marise Lazaretti-Castro, MD, PhD1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Ambulatório de Doenças Osteometabólicas - Disciplina Endocrinologia, Universidade Federal de São Paulo - UNIFESP São Paulo, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Inadequate vitamin D status has been associated with an increased risk of several diseases, including osteoporosis, cardiovascular disease, diabetes, cancer, multiple sclerosis and infections. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D is the classic marker of vitamin D status and is determined by environmental (season, latitude, sunlight, diet), demographic (ethnicity, body mass index) and genetic (polymorphism in metabolism and transport genes) factors. (1) However, the features that modify the response to vitamin D supplementation remain unclear. The Endocrine Society suggests the use of 50,000 IU of vitamin D2 or D3 weekly over eight weeks for the treatment of deficient adults to achieve a blood level of 25-hydroxyvitamin D above 30 ng/mL. (2)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>40 ng response plateau to 2000 to 4,000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/40-ng-response-plateau-to-2000-to-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/40-ng-response-plateau-to-2000-to-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-of-female-healthcare-employees-of-childbearing-age">Vitamin D status of female healthcare employees of childbearing age&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>G Plotnikoff 1*, K Mullin 2, L Mahlke 2, S Calvin 3, M Finch 4 and J Dusek 1&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Corresponding author&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>1 Allina Center for Healthcare Innovation, Minneapolis, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Allina Healthcare Employee Benefits , Minneapolis, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Minnesota Perinatal Physicians, Minneapolis, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 University of Minnesota Carlson School of Business, Minneapolis, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Complementary and Alternative Medicine 2012, 12(Suppl 1):P157 doi:10.1186/1472-6882-12-S1-P157; Published:	12 June 2012&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X variation in response to dose of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/3x-variation-in-response-to-dose-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-variation-in-response-to-dose-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-systematic-review">A Systematic Review:&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="influence-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration">Influence of Vitamin D Supplementation on Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism June 14, 2012 jc.2012-1238&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Philippe Autier, Sara Gandini and Patrick Mullie&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International Prevention Research Institute (P.A., P.M.), 69006 Lyon, France; and European Institute of Oncology (S.G.), 20139 Milano, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address all correspondence and requests for reprints to: Philippe Autier, M.D., International Prevention Research Institute (iPRI), 95 Cours Lafayette, 69006 Lyon, France. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:philippe.autier@i-pri.org">philippe.autier@i-pri.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Germans, Austrians, and Swiss declare that 800 IU and 20 ng vitamin D is enough</title><link>/posts/germans-austrians-and-swiss-declare-that-800-iu-and-20-ng-vitamin-d-is-enough.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/germans-austrians-and-swiss-declare-that-800-iu-and-20-ng-vitamin-d-is-enough.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Benefits and risks of Vitamin D - Vieth</title><link>/posts/benefits-and-risks-of-vitamin-d-vieth.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/benefits-and-risks-of-vitamin-d-vieth.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="implications-for-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-testing-of-public-health-policies-about-the-benefits-and-risks-of-vitamin-d-fortification-and-supplementation">Implications for 25-Hydroxyvitamin D testing of public health policies about the benefits and risks of Vitamin D fortification and supplementation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Scandinavian Journal of Clinical &amp;amp; Laboratory Investigation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>April 2012, Vol. 72, No. S243 , Pages 144-153&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reinhold Vieth&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutritional Sciences and Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathobiology, University of Toronto, and Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Mount Sinai Hospital, Toronto, Canada M5G 1X5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Reinhold Vieth, Department of Nutritional Sciences and Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathobiology, University of Toronto, and Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Mount Sinai Hospital, 600 University Ave Toronto, Ontario M5G 1X5 Canada. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:rvieth@mtsinai.on.ca">rvieth@mtsinai.on.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guidelines on prevention and treatment of vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/guidelines-on-prevention-and-treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/guidelines-on-prevention-and-treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Reumatismo. 2011 Nov 9;63(3):129-47. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4081/reumatismo.2011.129.">doi: 10.4081/reumatismo.2011.129.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adami S, Romagnoli E, Carnevale V, Scillitani A, Giusti A, Rossini M, Gatti D, Nuti R, Minisola S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unità di Reumatologia, Dipartimento di Medicina, Università di Verona. &lt;a href="mailto:Silvano.adami@univr.it">Silvano.adami@univr.it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Italian Society for Osteoporosis, Mineral Metabolism and Bone Diseases (SIOMMMS) has elaborated the following guidelines about the definition, prevention and treatment of inadequate vitamin D status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The highlights are presented here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMID: 22257914&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>HTML from PDF is in &lt;strong>Italian&lt;/strong> – the Chrome Browser will ask if you want it translated&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Huge gap between vitamin D advice and actual prescriptions</title><link>/posts/huge-gap-between-vitamin-d-advice-and-actual-prescriptions.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/huge-gap-between-vitamin-d-advice-and-actual-prescriptions.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-divergence-between-clinical-practice-and-expert-advice">Treatment of vitamin D deficiency: divergence between clinical practice and expert advice&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Postgrad Med J 2012;88:255-260 doi:10.1136/postgradmedj-2011-130243&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mark Findlay 1, Julia Anderson 2, Susan Roberts 3, Alison Almond 4, Chris Isles 1 &lt;a href="mailto:chris.isles@nhs.net">chris.isles@nhs.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Medicine, Dumfries and Galloway Royal Infirmary, Dumfriesshire, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Biochemistry, Dumfries and Galloway Royal Infirmary, Dumfriesshire, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Pharmacy Department, Dumfries and Galloway Royal Infirmary, Dumfriesshire, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Renal Unit, Dumfries and Galloway Royal Infirmary, Dumfriesshire, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dosing error gave 12000 IU daily vitamin D to infant, but no indication of any problem</title><link>/posts/dosing-error-gave-12000-iu-daily-vitamin-d-to-infant-but-no-indication-of-any-problem.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dosing-error-gave-12000-iu-daily-vitamin-d-to-infant-but-no-indication-of-any-problem.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dosing-error-with-over-the-counter-vitamin-d-supplement-a-risk-for-vitamin-d-toxicity-in-infants">Dosing Error With Over-the-Counter Vitamin D Supplement: A Risk for Vitamin D Toxicity in Infants.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2012 Apr 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rajakumar K, Reis EC, Holick MF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of 400 IU an infant was given 12,000 IU of vitamin D daily for 20 days&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to parents giving 1 mil liter as they were used to instead of 1 drop, from the new product&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors were extremely concerned about infant toxicity&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>100000 IU of vitamin D every three months had problems – 2011</title><link>/posts/100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-every-three-months-had-problems-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-every-three-months-had-problems-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="study-to-evaluate-two-dosage-regimens-of-vitamin-d-through-an-academic-year-in-middle-school-girls-a-randomized-trial">Study to evaluate two dosage regimens of vitamin D through an academic year in middle school girls: a randomized trial.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Shakiba M, Ghadir M, Nafei Z, Akhavan Karbasi S, Lotfi MH, Shajari A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatric, Shahid Sadoghi University of Medical Sciences, Yazd, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. 	Acta Med Iran. 2011;49(12):780-3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is an essential hormone for growth and development of bones in children. There is a lot of evidence for deficiency of this vitamin in Middle East females. This study conduct to find a way to combat deficiency in girls during rapid growth phase of puberty in academic year. One hundred and two Middle School girls who had not consumed any vitamins supplement have been participated in this randomized clinical trial. They allocated randomly in two case groups who received 50,000 or 100,000 IU vitamin D3 in October and three months later in January or in control group who received vitamin E. At the end of winter blood samples for 25-hydroxyvitamin D were checked. The mean of 25-hydroxyvitamin D were&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Endocrinology Guidelines for vitamin D revisited – no abstract</title><link>/posts/endocrinology-guidelines-for-vitamin-d-revisited-no-abstract.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/endocrinology-guidelines-for-vitamin-d-revisited-no-abstract.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="guidelines-for-preventing-and-treating-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-insufficiency-revisited">Guidelines for Preventing and Treating Vitamin D Deficiency and Insufficiency Revisited&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism March 22, 2012 jc.2011-2601&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael F. Holick, &lt;a href="mailto:mfholick@bu.edu">mfholick@bu.edu&lt;/a> Neil C. Binkley, Heike A. Bischoff-Ferrari, Catherine M. Gordon, David A. Hanley, Robert P. Heaney, M. Hassan Murad and Connie M. Weaver&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boston University School of Medicine (M.F.H.), Boston, Massachusetts 02118-2526; Osteoporosis Research Program (N.C.B.), University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wisconsin 53706; Department of Rheumatology and Institute for Physical Medicine (H.A.B.-F.), University Hospital Zurich, 8091 Zurich, Switzerland; Divisions of Adolescent Medicine and Endocrinology (C.M.G.), Childrens Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts 02115; Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism (D.A.H.), Health Science Centre, University of Calgary Faculty of Medicine (R.P.H.), Calgary, Canada AB T2N 4N1; Creighton University (R.P.H.), Omaha, Nebraska 68131; Division of Preventative, Occupational, and Aerospace Medicine Mayo Clinic (M.H.M.), Rochester, Minnesota 55905; and Department of Foods and Nutrition (C.M.W.), Purdue University, West Lafayette, Indiana 47907&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D response: 800 IU: 20 ng, 3200 IU: 45 ng – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-response-800-iu-20-ng-3200-iu-45-ng-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-response-800-iu-20-ng-3200-iu-45-ng-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dose-response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-postmenopausal-women-a-randomized-trial">Dose response to vitamin d supplementation in postmenopausal women: a randomized trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Intern Med. 2012 Mar 20;156(6):425-37.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gallagher JC &lt;a href="mailto:jcg@creighton.edu">jcg@creighton.edu&lt;/a>, Sai A, Templin T 2nd, Smith L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone Metabolism Unit, Creighton University School of Medicine, and College of Public Health, University of Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha, Nebraska.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:>70%">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Abstract fails to mention how much to achieve their original goal of 30 ng: which is no longer politically correct&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The clinical trial entry had speculated that 4400 IU would be needed to achieve 30 ng&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IoM voted for 20 ng of vitamin D – a member hints at 30 ng</title><link>/posts/iom-voted-for-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-a-member-hints-at-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/iom-voted-for-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-a-member-hints-at-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sun-exposure-not-enough-to-correct-vitamin-d-deficiencyhttpwwwmedscapecomviewarticle76045620">&lt;a href="http://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/760456%20">Sun Exposure Not Enough to Correct Vitamin D Deficiency&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Medscape Medical News &amp;gt; Conference News ; Kate Johnson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>March 17, 2012 (San Diego, California) — &amp;ldquo;The &amp;rsquo;epidemic&amp;rsquo; in vitamin D deficiency is clearly not from too little sun exposure,&amp;rdquo; and dermatologists can be confident in insisting that their patients continue their sun protection efforts, said Richard Gallo, MD, PhD, here at the American Academy of Dermatology (AAD) 70th Annual Meeting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1500 IU vitamin D minimum - 10,000 IU is safe – review</title><link>/posts/1500-iu-vitamin-d-minimum-10000-iu-is-safe-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1500-iu-vitamin-d-minimum-10000-iu-is-safe-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-21st-century-evaluation-of-the-safety-of-oral-vitamin-d">A 21st century evaluation of the safety of oral vitamin D&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Michael J. Glade, Ph.D. &lt;a href="mailto:the_nutrition_doctor@yahoo.com">the_nutrition_doctor@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Nutrition Doctor, Skokie, Illinois, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrition. Volume 28, Issue 4 , Pages 344-356, April 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 31 March 2011; accepted 9 November 2011. PMID: 22414585&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The safety of daily consumption of vitamin D was examined. A detailed literature search was conducted using the search term vitamin D; primary and secondary sources of original data and meta-analyses and systematic reviews were evaluated and summarized.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intervention of 400 IU of vitamin D raised infant blood levels 14 ng</title><link>/posts/intervention-of-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-raised-infant-blood-levels-14-ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/intervention-of-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-raised-infant-blood-levels-14-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-ethnicity-and-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-vitamin-d-status-and-changes-in-bone-mineral-content-in-infants">Effects of ethnicity and vitamin D supplementation on vitamin D status and changes in bone mineral content in infants.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>BMC Pediatr. 2012 Jan 16;12:6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abrams SA, Hawthorne KM, Rogers SP, Hicks PD, Carpenter TO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Baylor College of Medicine and Texas Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Houston, Texas 77030, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:sabrams@bcm.edu">sabrams@bcm.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To evaluate the effects on serum 25(OH)D and bone mineralization of supplementation of &lt;strong>breast-fed&lt;/strong> Hispanic and non-Hispanic Caucasian infants with vitamin D in infants in Houston, Texas.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Take vitamin D3 daily, weekly, or bi-weekly</title><link>/posts/take-vitamin-d3-daily-weekly-or-bi-weekly.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/take-vitamin-d3-daily-weekly-or-bi-weekly.html</guid><description>&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Notional chart for Vitamin D supplementation for levels &amp;lt; 30 nanograms&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;!-- ~tc~ end ~/tc~ -->
&lt;h4 id="annual--not-good">Annual = Not good&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>During the past decade research studies have found that annual doses of vitamin D do not provide much benefit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are far fewer studies publishing results with annual doses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mostly the studies being published since 2010 are ones which were started many years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are unaware of any new &lt;a href="http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/results?term=annual+%22vitamin+d%22">Clinical Trials using annual doses&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>930 IU vitamin D should get most people to 20 ng – Possible Europe standard</title><link>/posts/930-iu-vitamin-d-should-get-most-people-to-20-ng-possible-europe-standard.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/930-iu-vitamin-d-should-get-most-people-to-20-ng-possible-europe-standard.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-systematic-review-and-meta-regression-analysis-of-the-vitamin-d-intake-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-relationship-to-inform-european-recommendations">A systematic review and meta-regression analysis of the vitamin D intake-serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D relationship to inform European recommendations.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2011 Dec;106(11):1638-48. Epub 2011 Oct 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cashman KD, Fitzgerald AP, Kiely M, Seamans KM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Food and Nutritional Sciences, University College Cork, Republic of Ireland. &lt;a href="mailto:k.cashman@ucc.ie">k.cashman@ucc.ie&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The present study used a systematic review approach to identify relevant randomised control trials (RCT) with vitamin D and then apply meta-regression to explore the most appropriate model of the vitamin D intake-serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) relationship to underpin setting reference intake values.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IU of vitamin D – a roundup of recent news items</title><link>/posts/iu-of-vitamin-d-a-roundup-of-recent-news-items.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/iu-of-vitamin-d-a-roundup-of-recent-news-items.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/300-iu-finland-rda-2011" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2250">300 IU Finland RDA – 2011&lt;/a> includes differences for age, pregnancy, UL,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/800-iu-germany-increased-from-200-iu" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2304">800 IU Germany increased from 200 IU - Jan 2012&lt;/a> no indication of upper limit&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/800-iu-european-menopause-group" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2293">800 IU European Menopause Group – Jan 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/800-iu-cochrane-decreased-mortality-by-6-percent" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1830">800 IU: Cochrane – decreased mortality by 6 percent – July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Germany increases vitamin D to 800 IU</title><link>/posts/germany-increases-vitamin-d-to-800-iu.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/germany-increases-vitamin-d-to-800-iu.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The German Nutrition Society published new estimated requirements for daily vitamin D intake&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For all age groups &lt;strong>beyond infancy&lt;/strong> , a daily intake of 20 µg is recommended in case of absent UV-B-exposure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With respect to the prevention of vitamin D deficiency (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D &amp;lt; 30 nmol/l) this is a clear progress compared to the former recommendation of 5 µg per day.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="translation-by-google-from-spanwwwdgedespan">Translation by Google from &lt;span>[www.dge.de]&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Research results in recent years provided evidence for a role of vitamin D for the prevention of several chronic diseases. A working group of the German Society for Nutrition Association (DGE) has evaluated the scientific data on this. Current evidence clearly confirms that a good vitamin D intake may reduce the risk in older people for falls, fractures, loss of strength, mobility and balance loss, and premature death. Hypotheses such as a reduction in risk for cancer or diabetes mellitus with vitamin D could not be proved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reasons for low response to vitamin D</title><link>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#detailed-reasons-for-poor-response">Detailed Reasons for poor response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reasons-for-not-getting-benefits---span-stylecolorf00even-if-blood-tests-are-okspan">Reasons for not getting benefits - &lt;span style="color:#F00;">even if blood tests are OK&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsuv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual--2010big-differences-in-uvb-responsesa-20-to-36-ng-after-6-weeks">&lt;a href="/posts/uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: UV production of Vitamin D varies with the individual – 2010">Big differences in UVB responses&lt;/a>: 20 to 36 ng after 6 weeks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#alternate-sources-of-vitamin-d">Alternate sources of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/h4>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>~ 50% of all people have a low response to vitamin D3&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1700 IU vitamin D (50000 monthly) helped antarctic explorers – RCT</title><link>/posts/1700-iu-vitamin-d-50000-monthly-helped-antarctic-explorers-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1700-iu-vitamin-d-50000-monthly-helped-antarctic-explorers-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="skeletal-and-hormonal-responses-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-sunlight-deprivation-in-antarctic-expeditioners">Skeletal and hormonal responses to vitamin D supplementation during sunlight deprivation in Antarctic expeditioners.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Jan 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Iuliano-Burns S, Ayton J, Hillam S, Jones G, King K, Macleod S, Seeman E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Austin Health, University of Melbourne, Parkville, Australia, &lt;a href="mailto:sandraib@unimelb.edu.au">sandraib@unimelb.edu.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight deprivation results in vitamin D deficiency but serum vitamin D levels can be maintained above 50nmol/L when supplemented with 50,000IU at least every alternate month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Antarctic expeditioners are exposed to prolonged sunlight deprivation resulting in vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D levels even when taking 800 IU vitamin D</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-levels-even-when-taking-800-iu-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-levels-even-when-taking-800-iu-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-prevalence-of-hypovitaminosis-d-in-a-swiss-rheumatology-outpatient-population">High prevalence of hypovitaminosis D in a Swiss rheumatology outpatient population.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Swiss Med Wkly. 2011 May 27;141:w13196. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4414/smw.2011.13196.">doi: 10.4414/smw.2011.13196.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stoll D, Dudler J, Lamy O, Hans D, So A, Krieg MA, Aubry-Rozier B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Bone Diseases, Lausanne University Hospital-DAL, Avenue Pierre Decker 4, 1011 Lausanne, Switzerland. &lt;a href="mailto:delphine.stoll@chuv.ch">delphine.stoll@chuv.ch&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is important for bone metabolism and neuromuscular function. While a routine dosage is often proposed in osteoporotic patients, it is not so evident in rheumatology outpatients where it has been shown that the prevalence of hypovitaminosis D is high. The aim of the current study was to systematically evaluate the vitamin D status in our outpatient rheumatology population to define the severity of the problem according to rheumatologic diseases. During November 2009, all patients were offered[a screening test for 25-OH vitamin D levels and categorised as deficient (&amp;lt;10 µg/l [ng/ml](%20a%20screening%20test%20for%2025-OH%20vitamin%20D%20levels%20and%20categorised%20as%20deficient%20(&amp;lt;10%20µg/l%20[ng/ml) &lt;a href="25%20nmol/l">25 nmol/l&lt;/a>), insufficient (10 µg/l to 30 µg/l &lt;a href="25%20to%2075%20nmol/l">25 to 75 nmol/l&lt;/a>) or normal (&amp;gt;30 µg/l &lt;a href="75%20nmol/l">75 nmol/l&lt;/a>). A total of 272 patients were included. The mean 25-OH vitamin D level was 21 µg/l (range 1.5 to 45.9). A total of 20 patients had vitamin D deficiency, 215 patients had an insufficiency and 37 patients had normal results. In the group of patients with osteoporosis mean level of 25-OH vitamin D was 25 µg/l and 31% had normal results. In patients with inflammatory rheumatic diseases (N = 219), the mean level of 25-OH vitamin D was 20.5 µg/l, and only 12% had normal 25-OH vitamin D levels. In the small group of patients with degenerative disease (N = 33), the mean level of 25-OH vitamin D was 21.8 µg/l, and 21% had normal results. Insufficiency and deficiency were even seen in 38% of the patients who were taking supplements. These results confirm that hypovitaminosis D is highly prevalent in an outpatient population of rheumatology patients, affecting 86% of subjects. Despite oral supplementation (taken in 38% of our population), only a quarter of those on oral supplementation attained normal values of 25-OH vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1600 IU daily Vitamin D raised adult blood levels above 20 ng – RCT</title><link>/posts/1600-iu-daily-vitamin-d-raised-adult-blood-levels-above-20-ng-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1600-iu-daily-vitamin-d-raised-adult-blood-levels-above-20-ng-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="is-a-daily-supplementation-with-40-microgram-vitamin-d3-sufficient-a-randomised-controlled-trial">Is a daily supplementation with 40 microgram vitamin D(3) sufficient? A randomised controlled trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Eur J Nutr. 2011 Nov 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Toss G, Magnusson P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Gastroenterology, County Council of Östergötland, SE-581 85, Linköping, Sweden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: The effect of 40 ug (1,600 IU) per day of vitamin D(3) on serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and markers of bone and mineral metabolism was evaluated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:This intervention study was designed as a double-blind randomised controlled trial. Forty-five community-dwelling subjects (32 females), age 55-84 years, at 58° North latitude were supplemented for 1 year with &lt;strong>40 ug vitamin D(3) plus 1,000 mg calcium per day&lt;/strong> , or with 1,000 mg calcium per day for controls. Safety parameters and 25(OH)D, intact parathyroid hormone (PTH), ionized calcium, bone-specific alkaline phosphatase (BALP), and tartrate-resistant acid phosphatase isoform 5b (TRACP5b) were measured over the study period.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU of vitamin D is a step in the right direction for Canada</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-a-step-in-the-right-direction-for-canada.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-a-step-in-the-right-direction-for-canada.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-step-in-the-right-direction">A step in the right direction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>CMAJ. 2010 November 9; 182(16): 1763. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1503/cmaj.110-2118">doi: 10.1503/cmaj.110-2118&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gerry K. Schwalfenberg, MD; Department of Family Medicine, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alta&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I applaud the new vitamin D in adult health and disease guideline statement. Certainly this is a step in the right direction. Average 25(OH)D levels in all studies in Canada,2 including Health Canada’s household studies, are consistently below the recommended 75 – 80 nmol/L. Supplementation with 1000IU of vitamin D3 in the general population would result in a mean 25(OH)D level slightly above 85 nmol/L still leaving 20% – 30% of Canadians below the suggested 75 nmol/L. That’s not good enough. These studies show that children and teens have significant insufficiency. Addressing osteoporosis early will influence peak bone mass and result in stronger bones for the future.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels for women</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-for-women.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-for-women.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>930 IU of Vitamin D proposed for far North after review of literature review</title><link>/posts/930-iu-of-vitamin-d-proposed-for-far-north-after-review-of-literature-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/930-iu-of-vitamin-d-proposed-for-far-north-after-review-of-literature-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-systematic-review-and-meta-regression-analysis-of-the-vitamin-d-intake-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-relationship-to-inform-european-recommendations">A systematic review and meta-regression analysis of the vitamin D intake-serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D relationship to inform European recommendations.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2011 Oct 14:1-11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cashman KD &lt;a href="mailto:k.cashman@ucc.i.e">k.cashman@ucc.i.e&lt;/a>. , Fitzgerald AP, Kiely M, Seamans KM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Food and Nutritional Sciences, University College Cork, Cork, Republic of Ireland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The present study used a systematic review approach to identify relevant randomised control trials (RCT) with vitamin D and then apply meta-regression to explore the most appropriate model of the vitamin D intake-serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) relationship to underpin setting reference intake values.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Telomeres improved when obese blacks took 2000 IU of vitamin D daily</title><link>/posts/telomeres-improved-when-obese-blacks-took-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/telomeres-improved-when-obese-blacks-took-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Endocrine Society recommend higher vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/endocrine-society-recommend-higher-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/endocrine-society-recommend-higher-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="evaluation-treatment-and-prevention-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-an-endocrine-society-clinical-practice-guideline">Evaluation, Treatment, and Prevention of Vitamin D Deficiency: an Endocrine Society Clinical Practice Guideline.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Jun 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Holick MF, Binkley NC, Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Gordon CM, Hanley DA, Heaney RP, Murad MH, Weaver CM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boston University School of Medicine (M.F.H.), Boston, Massachusetts 02118; University of Wisconsin (N.C.B.), Madison, Wisconsin 53706; University Hospital Zurich (H.A.B.-F.), CH-8091 Zurich, Switzerland; Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Boston (C.M.G.), Boston, Massachusetts 02115; University of Calgary Faculty of Medicine (D.A.H.), Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 1N4; Creighton University (R.P.H.), Omaha, Nebraska 68178; Mayo Clinic (M.H.M.), Rochester, Minnesota 55905; and Purdue University (C.M.W.), West Lafayette, Indiana 47907.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RDA upper limit etc for Vitamin D and Magnesium</title><link>/posts/rda-upper-limit-etc-for-vitamin-d-and-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rda-upper-limit-etc-for-vitamin-d-and-magnesium.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="an-excellent-article-by-bill-sardi-sept-2011">An excellent article by Bill Sardi Sept 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="which-nutrition-chart-should-you-rely-upon-the-rda-rdi-ai-ear-or-dvhttplewrockwellcomsardisardi186html">&lt;a href="http://lewrockwell.com/sardi/sardi186.html">Which Nutrition Chart Should You Rely Upon: The RDA, RDI, AI, EAR or DV?&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Or, How Much Nutrition Do You Really Need?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Four reasons why vitamin D levels should be higher than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/four-reasons-why-vitamin-d-levels-should-be-higher-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/four-reasons-why-vitamin-d-levels-should-be-higher-than-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="why-the-minimum-desirable-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-should-be-75-nmoll-30-ngml">Why the minimum desirable serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level should be 75 nmol/L (30 ng/ml).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vieth R.&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="mailto:rvieth@mtsinai.on.ca">rvieth@mtsinai.on.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Aug;25(4):681-91.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Toronto, Canada; Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathobiology, University of Toronto, Canada; Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Mount Sinai Hospital, 600 University Ave, Toronto, Ontario, Canada M5G 1X5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Institutes of Medicine (IOM) recently revised the recommended dietary allowances (RDA) for vitamin D, to maintain serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) at or above 50 nmol/L, to sustain bone density, calcium absorption, and to minimize risk of osteomalacia and rickets. However there are compelling reasons why 25(OH)D should preferably exceed 75 nmol/L:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>100 IU increases 1 ng vitamin D – recommend 3000 IU – Book 2011</title><link>/posts/100-iu-increases-1-ng-vitamin-d-recommend-3000-iu-book-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/100-iu-increases-1-ng-vitamin-d-recommend-3000-iu-book-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-pharmacology-of-vitamin-d">The Pharmacology of Vitamin D&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Vitamin D (Third Edition) 2011, Pages 1041-1066&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Vitamin-D-Third-David-Feldman/dp/0123819784/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1314453843&amp;amp;sr=8-1">Amazon $335 / Kindle $302&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/B978-0-12-381978-9.10057-5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reinhold Vieth : University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada and Mount Sinai Hospital, Toronto, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D dosage depends on the target concentration of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) desired. A useful rule of thumb is that an incremental dose of 1 ?g/day (40 IU) of vitamin D3 raises 25(OH)D by 1 nmol/L after 8 months of use. (Equivalent to 100 IU/day increases 25(OH)D by 1 ng/mL.) If the same cumulative dose of vitamin D is given, there is no difference in efficacy between daily, weekly, or monthly dose intervals. Hypercalcemia is the classic criterion for toxicity of vitamin D, its metabolites and their analogs. “Non-calcemic” doses are considered “safe” by conventional criteria. Levels of 25(OH)D &amp;gt;75 nmol/L (&amp;gt;30 ng/mL) generally relate to lower risk of colorectal cancer, bone fractures, and desirable health outcomes. To ensure levels higher than this in adults requires vitamin D3 at an average total input from sunshine, diet and/or supplements of 75 ?g/day (3000 IU/day).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D should be 48 ng to 90 ng – Heaney</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-should-be-48-ng-to-90-ng-heaney.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-should-be-48-ng-to-90-ng-heaney.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="assessing-vitamin-d-status">Assessing Vitamin D Status&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2011 Sep;14(5):440-4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heaney RP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creighton University, Omaha, Nebraska, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE OF REVIEW: To characterize methods evaluating and to summarize studies linking various serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations with health status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RECENT FINDINGS: Elucidation of the cell-biologic mechanism of vitamin D action, and numerous clinical trials and observational studies relating vitamin D status to health and disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CONCLUSION: The distinction between deficiency and insufficiency is not useful or necessary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium can create heart problems - vitamin D neutral</title><link>/posts/calcium-can-create-heart-problems-vitamin-d-neutral.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-can-create-heart-problems-vitamin-d-neutral.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-calcium-and-cardiovascular-mortality-a-perspective-from-a-plenary-lecture-given-at-the-annual-meeting-of-the-american-association-of-clinical-endocrinologists">Vitamin D, Calcium, and Cardiovascular Mortality: A Perspective from a Plenary Lecture given at the Annual Meeting of the American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2011 Aug 19:1-30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Miller PD. &lt;a href="mailto:MillerCCBR@aol.com">MillerCCBR@aol.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ColoradoCenter for Bone Research, University of Colorado Health Sciences Center.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To examine the data showing any associations between the serum levels of 25(OH) vitamin D, calcium intake and cardiovascular mortality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: The articles reviewed from the literature that form the basis of this authors opinion include published articles from 1992-2011 derived from search engines (PubMed; Scopus; MedScape) using search terms-vitamin D, calcium, cardiovascular events, cardiovascular mortality, all-cause mortality, vascular calcification, chronic-kidney disease, renal stones, hypercalciuria. Because these articles were not weighted (graded) on the level of evidence, this review reflects my own perspective on the data and how it should be applied in clinical management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cadavers with good skeletons had 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cadavers-with-good-skeletons-had-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cadavers-with-good-skeletons-had-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-mineralization-defects-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-histomorphometric-analysis-of-iliac-crest-bone-biopsies-and-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-675-patients">Bone mineralization defects and vitamin D deficiency: histomorphometric analysis of iliac crest bone biopsies and circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D in 675 patients.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2010 Feb;25(2):305-12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Priemel M, von Domarus C, Klatte TO, Kessler S, Schlie J, Meier S, Proksch N, Pastor F, Netter C, Streichert T, Püschel K, Amling M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Osteology and Biomechanics, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parathyroid hormone (PTH) is only one measurable index of skeletal health, and we reasoned that a histomorphometric analysis of iliac crest biopsies would be another and even more direct approach to assess bone health and address the required minimum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> level. A cohort from the northern European population with its known high prevalence of vitamin D deficiency therefore would be ideal to answer the latter question.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IoM error: 8 percent, not just 1 percent, had bone loss when vitamin D higher than 20 ng</title><link>/posts/iom-error-8-percent-not-just-1-percent-had-bone-loss-when-vitamin-d-higher-than-20-ng.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/iom-error-8-percent-not-just-1-percent-had-bone-loss-when-vitamin-d-higher-than-20-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="from-nature-magazine-july-2011httpwwwnaturecomnews2011110706full475023ahtml">&lt;a href="http://www.nature.com/news/2011/110706/full/475023a.html">From Nature Magazine July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/nature-july-2011.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="8-not-1-of-the-people-has-20-ngml-had-bone-loss-so-the-20ngml-voted-level-was-incorrect">8%, not 1% of the people has &amp;gt;20 ng/ml had bone loss, so the 20ng/ml voted level was incorrect&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>hashed lines and &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">red &lt;/span>&lt;/strong> were added by VitaminDWiki&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="in-addition-there-are-many-non-bone-for-diseases-that-vitamin-d-has-been-span-stylecolorf33patented-spanfor">In addition, there are many non-bone for diseases that vitamin D has been &lt;span style="color:#F33;">patented &lt;/span>for&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Breast and many other cancers,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Obesity,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fall prevention,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Stroke and other Cardiovascular,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Immune system,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>wounds and reduce scars,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recommend 100 IU of vitamin D per kg of infant - Poland</title><link>/posts/recommend-100-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-of-infant-poland.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/recommend-100-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-of-infant-poland.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-and-status-in-infants-a-prospective-cohort-observational-study">Vitamin d supplementation and status in infants: a prospective cohort observational study.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-and-status-in-infants-a-prospective-cohort-observational-study">Vitamin d supplementation and status in infants: a prospective cohort observational study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2011 Jul;53(1):93-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pludowski P, Socha P, Karczmarewicz E, Zagorecka E, Lukaszkiewicz J, Stolarczyk A, Piotrowska-Jastrzebska J, Kryskiewicz E, Lorenc RS, Socha J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Biochemistry and Experimental Medicine, Poland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Immunology, Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Health Institute, Aleja Dzieci Polskich, Poland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half of the seniors needed more than 1700 IU vitamin D3 (50000 monthly)</title><link>/posts/half-of-the-seniors-needed-more-than-1700-iu-vitamin-d3-50000-monthly.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-of-the-seniors-needed-more-than-1700-iu-vitamin-d3-50000-monthly.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypothesis – Optimize vitamin D at home by measuring excess Calcium in urine</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-optimize-vitamin-d-at-home-by-measuring-excess-calcium-in-urine.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-optimize-vitamin-d-at-home-by-measuring-excess-calcium-in-urine.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="it-is-difficult-to-determine-a-hrefpostshow-much-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-766how-mucha-vitamin-d-an-individual-needs">It is difficult to determine &lt;a href="/posts/how-much" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 766">how much&lt;/a> vitamin D an individual needs&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="need-to-add-vitamin-d-for-each-of-the-following-reasons">Need to add vitamin D for each of the following reasons&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;1683&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="even-within-the-same-risk-group-the-vitamin-d-needed-will-vary-by-4x">Even within the same risk group the vitamin D needed will vary by 4X&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>According to &lt;a href="/posts/dr-vieth" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1660">Dr. Vieth - May 2011&lt;/a> (see charts below) the body starts dumping calcium via the urine long before serum levels of calcium become elevated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yet again – vitamin D levels very low in sunny Saudia Arabia</title><link>/posts/yet-again-vitamin-d-levels-very-low-in-sunny-saudia-arabia.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yet-again-vitamin-d-levels-very-low-in-sunny-saudia-arabia.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Most people are not vitamin D deficient – Consumer Reports</title><link>/posts/most-people-are-not-vitamin-d-deficient-consumer-reports.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/most-people-are-not-vitamin-d-deficient-consumer-reports.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-vitamin-d-dilemma">The vitamin D dilemma&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="how-much-is-too-much-what-you-should-know-about-getting-tested">How much is too much? What you should know about getting tested.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Last reviewed: May 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is hot—and not just because it comes from the sun. Once prescribed only to prevent or treat outright vitamin D deficiency, rickets, and osteoporosis, doctors have increasingly recommended vitamin D supplements to treat or try to prevent a lengthy list of ills, including autism, certain cancers, diabetes, heart disease, multiple sclerosis, respiratory infections, and cognitive decline in seniors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Controversy: Too much Calcium if increase Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/controversy-too-much-calcium-if-increase-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/controversy-too-much-calcium-if-increase-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#50-percent-of-elderly-got-hypercalcimia-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d--feb-2011">50 percent of elderly got hypercalcimia with 2000 IU of vitamin D – Feb 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="50-percent-of-elderly-got-hypercalcimia-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d--feb-2011">50 percent of elderly got hypercalcimia with 2000 IU of vitamin D – Feb 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Evaluation of the effectiveness of cholecalciferol in long-term care elderly patients with hypovitaminosis d.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consult Pharm. 2011 Feb;26(2):101-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shin M, Minden C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sullivan University College of Pharmacy, Louisville, Kentucky.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To study the efficacy and safety of cholecalciferol &lt;strong>(vitamin D3) 2,000 units&lt;/strong> daily for 12 weeks in elderly patients with hypovitaminosis D. Secondarily, to postulate causes for those patients who did not return to normal 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25-OHD) levels.Design: One-group, pretest post-test. Retrospective chart review. Data collected from Computerized Patient Record System.Setting: Long-term care facility at Central Arkansas Veterans Healthcare System.Patients, Participants: Potential study subjects were elderly patients (? 65 years of age) treated with total daily dose of cholecalciferol 2,000 units daily by mouth, for at least 12 weeks&amp;rsquo; duration period between July 1, 2007, and July 31, 2009, with documented 25-OHD levels before and after treatment.Interventions: None.Main Outcome Measures: Efficacy of cholecalciferol was assessed by categorizing patients as responders (25-OHD levels ? 30 ng/mL) and nonresponders (25-OHD levels &amp;lt; 30 ng/mL).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>European call to action for vitamin D</title><link>/posts/european-call-to-action-for-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/european-call-to-action-for-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#industry-issues-eu-wide-call-to-action-to-raise-vitamin-d-deficiency-awareness-levels">Industry issues EU-wide ‘call to action’ to raise vitamin D deficiency awareness levels&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-consortium--including">The consortium – including&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiencies">Vitamin D deficiencies&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#--note-dsm-may-have-a-conflict-of-interest">* * Note: DSM may have a conflict of interest&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="industry-issues-eu-wide-call-to-action-to-raise-vitamin-d-deficiency-awareness-levels">Industry issues EU-wide ‘call to action’ to raise vitamin D deficiency awareness levels&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nutraingredients-usa.com/Industry/Industry-issues-EU-wide-call-to-action-to-raise-vitamin-D-deficiency-awareness-levels">URL&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A consortium of ingredient suppliers, food manufacturers and public health groups this week issued a ‘call to action’ raise awareness about micronutrient deficiencies among European governments, with an accent on vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D level of 50 ng may be too high</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-level-of-50-ng-may-be-too-high.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-level-of-50-ng-may-be-too-high.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="are-some-people-pushing-their-vitamin-d-levels-too-high">Are Some People Pushing Their Vitamin D Levels Too High&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Posted by: Christopher Masterjohn in WAPF Blog on 05/31/10&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="click-herehttpwwwwestonapriceorgblogsare-some-people-pushing-their-vitamin-d-levels-too-highbloggercmasterjo-for-original-article-with-hyperlinks">&lt;a href="http://www.westonaprice.org/blogs/are-some-people-pushing-their-vitamin-d-levels-too-high/blogger/CMASTERJO/">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for original article with hyperlinks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Has science proven that the minimal acceptable blood level of vitamin D, in the form of 25(OH)D, is above 50 ng/mL (125 nmol/L)? No. If you’ve been trying to maintain your levels this high because you thought this was the case, I’m sorry to break the news. There is, on the contrary, good evidence that 25(OH)D levels should be at least 30-35 ng/mL (75-88 nmol/L). Much higher levels may be better, or they could start causing harm, especially in the absence of adequate vitamins A and K2. Once we leave the land of 30-35 ng/mL, however, we enter the land of speculation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Absurdity of 600 IU vitamin D for 10 lb infant or 300 lb adult</title><link>/posts/absurdity-of-600-iu-vitamin-d-for-10-lb-infant-or-300-lb-adult.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/absurdity-of-600-iu-vitamin-d-for-10-lb-infant-or-300-lb-adult.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="heart-scan-bloghttpwwwheartscanblogorg201103270-lb-man-in-diapershtml-had-image-of-a-270-lb-man-in-diapers">&lt;a href="http://www.heartscanblog.org/2011/03/270-lb-man-in-diapers.html">Heart Scan Blog&lt;/a> had image of a 270 lb man in diapers&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>clip - - - -&lt;/p>
&lt;p>^It would be like trying to fit a large, full-grown man into the diapers of a 13-month old.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Few nutrients or hormones (in fact, I can&amp;rsquo;t think of a single one) are required in similar quantity by an infant or toddler and a full grown adult. ^&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="need-to-add-vitamin-d-for-each-of-the-following-reasons">Need to add vitamin D for each of the following reasons&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;1683&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why the IOM Recommendations for Vitamin D Are Deficient</title><link>/posts/why-the-iom-recommendations-for-vitamin-d-are-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-the-iom-recommendations-for-vitamin-d-are-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Robert P Heaney1 and Michael F Holick2&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Creighton University , Omaha, NE, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Medicine, Division of Endocrinology, Boston University Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received in original form December 6, 2010; revised form December 21, 2010; accepted December 23, 2010. Published online January 4, 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address correspondence to: Robert P Heaney, MD, Creighton University, 601 North 30th Street, Suite 4841, Omaha, NE 68131, USA. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:rheaney@creighton.edu">rheaney@creighton.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For further discussion on this topic, please see Reid and Avenell (J Bone Miner Res. 2011;452–454. DOI: 10.1002/jbmr.327).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Vitamin D Dose-Response</title><link>/posts/overview-vitamin-d-dose-response.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-vitamin-d-dose-response.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#need-9600-iu-vitamin-d-to-get-most-people-to-40-ng--with-graph-feb-2011">Need 9600 IU Vitamin D to get most people to 40 ng – with graph Feb 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dose-response-graph-from-the-paper">Dose-response graph from the paper&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#huge-variation-in-response-to-each-dose-chart-of-data-by-grassrootshealth">Huge variation in response to each dose (Chart of data by GrassrootsHealth)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#half-of-seniors-did-not-respond-to-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-for-a-year">Half of seniors did not respond to 1600 IU of vitamin D daily for a year&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsgraph-of-weekly-response-to-monthly-vitamin-d-supplementation-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-graph-of-weekly-response-to-monthly-vitamin-d-supplementation--aug-2015graph-of-weekly-response-to-monthly-vitamin-d-supplementation--aug-2015a">&lt;a href="/posts/graph-of-weekly-response-to-monthly-vitamin-d-supplementation" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Graph of weekly response to monthly vitamin D supplementation – Aug 2015">Graph of weekly response to monthly vitamin D supplementation – Aug 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="need-9600-iu-vitamin-d-to-get-most-people-to-40-ng--with-graph-feb-2011">Need 9600 IU Vitamin D to get most people to 40 ng – with graph Feb 2011&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D Supplement Doses and Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D in the Range Associated with Cancer Prevention&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU vitamin D was safe and helped elderly</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d-was-safe-and-helped-elderly.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-vitamin-d-was-safe-and-helped-elderly.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-response-of-elderly-veterans-to-daily-vitamin-d3-supplementation-of-2000-iu-a-pilot-efficacy-study">The Response of Elderly Veterans to Daily Vitamin D3 Supplementation of 2,000? IU: A Pilot Efficacy Study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Am Geriatr Soc. 2011 Feb 2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03242.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03242.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cherniack EP, Florez HJ, Hollis BW, Roos BA, Troen BR, Levis S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the *Geriatrics Institute, Division of Gerontology and Geriatric Medicine, Department of Medicine, University of Miami Miller School of Medicine, Miami, Florida; †Geriatric Research, Education, and Clinical Center and Research Service, Bruce W. Carter Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Miami, Florida; ‡Department of Pediatrics, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina; and §Stein Gerontological Institute, Miami Jewish Health Systems, Miami, Florida.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>744 IU vitamin D needed by Northern white teens to prevent Rickets</title><link>/posts/744-iu-vitamin-d-needed-by-northern-white-teens-to-prevent-rickets.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/744-iu-vitamin-d-needed-by-northern-white-teens-to-prevent-rickets.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="estimation-of-the-dietary-requirement-for-vitamin-d-in-healthy-adolescent-white-girls">Estimation of the dietary requirement for vitamin D in healthy adolescent white girls.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jan 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cashman KD, Fitzgerald AP, Viljakainen HT, Jakobsen J, Michaelsen KF, Lamberg-Allardt C, Mølgaard C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Food and Nutritional Sciences and Departments of Medicine and Epidemiology and Public Health, and Statistics, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Knowledge gaps have contributed to considerable variation (between 0 and 15 ?g/d) between international dietary recommendations for vitamin D in adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is the Institute of Medicine Report on Calcium and Vitamin D Good Science</title><link>/posts/is-the-institute-of-medicine-report-on-calcium-and-vitamin-d-good-science.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-the-institute-of-medicine-report-on-calcium-and-vitamin-d-good-science.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="by-dr-willam-grant">By Dr. Willam Grant&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1654]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/iom-again-fails-to-look-at-interactions">IoM again fails to look at interactions - Nov 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Which has many responses, including 2 more by Dr. Grant&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>And a link to possible Conflict of Interest by the panel members&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-overview-by-grant">Vitamin D overview by Grant - Jan 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/need-30-60-ng-of-vitamin-d-for-good-health-grant" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1327">Need 30-60 ng of vitamin D for good health – Grant Jan 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D level recommendations - Bosomworth</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-level-recommendations-bosomworth.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-level-recommendations-bosomworth.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-agony-of-evidence">The agony of evidence&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Can Fam Physician. 2011 January; 57(1): 16–20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3024150&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N.J. Bosomworth, MD CCFP FCFP&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical Instructor in the Department of Family Practice at the University of British Columbia in Vancouver&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Dr N.J. Bosomworth, 3413 Forsyth Dr, Penticton, BC V2A 8Z2; e-mail &lt;a href="mailto:john.bosomworth@interiorhealth.ca">john.bosomworth@interiorhealth.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;419&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="spantiki-download_filephpfileid1652span">&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1652]&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="neither-set-of-recommendations-account-for-obesitycategoriesobesity-a-hrefpostsskin-color-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1064skin-colora-time-of-year-vegetarian-eating-lactose-intolerant-different-doseresponses-between-individuals-etc">Neither set of recommendations account for &lt;a href="/categories/obesity">Obesity&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="/posts/skin-color" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1064">skin color&lt;/a>, time of year, vegetarian eating, lactose intolerant, different dose/responses between individuals, etc.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="comment-by-dr-n-john-bosomworth-md-ccfp-fcfp--jan-2011">Comment by Dr. N. John Bosomworth, MD, CCFP, FCFP Jan 2011:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The article was a commentary in the Canadian Family Physician. This category is often more of an editorial or opinion piece and always carries a disclaimer by the journal that the content is not necessarily the opinion of the editorial board. At the same time, the content is carefully peer reviewed before publication, and the information is meant to be presented to the average GP as sound science garnished with a bit of opinion. This particular article is more evidence-based than most commentaries, and does reflect the opinion of most docs working in the field. The only official buy-in so far is from the Pediatricians, who still see rickets in our northern populations. The average doc is starting to take note of these recommendations, but it comes only with repeated exposure to opinions like mine, backed up with some science.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2010 recommendations for Vitamin D are Deficient – by 1997 panelists</title><link>/posts/2010-recommendations-for-vitamin-d-are-deficient-by-1997-panelists.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2010-recommendations-for-vitamin-d-are-deficient-by-1997-panelists.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="perspective-why-the-iom-recommendations-for-vitamin-d-are-deficient">Perspective: Why the IOM Recommendations for Vitamin D are Deficient&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Robert P. Heaney Creighton University Omaha, NE &lt;a href="mailto:rheaney@creighton.edu">rheaney@creighton.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael F. Holick, Boston University Medical Center, Boston, MA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Initial Date Submitted December 6, 2010; Date Revision Submitted December 21, 2010; Date Final Disposition Set December 23, 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Bone and Mineral Research&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Â© 2011 American Society for Bone and Mineral Research, DOI 10.1002/jbmr.328&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past two years vitamin D supplement sales to consumers have increased by more than 100% per year.1 Now, following the publication of the report 2 on Dietary Reference Intakes (DRIs) for calcium and vitamin D by the Institute of Medicine (IOM), many physicians report that they are decreasing their vitamin D recommendations to patients. This change was explicitly proposed by members of the IOM panel in their various media statements. While a small fraction of consumers may well have all the vitamin D they need, on balance we consider a general downward trend to be harmful for the health of the public.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An official reviewer of the IOM vitamin D report makes his opinion known</title><link>/posts/an-official-reviewer-of-the-iom-vitamin-d-report-makes-his-opinion-known.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/an-official-reviewer-of-the-iom-vitamin-d-report-makes-his-opinion-known.html</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="comment-on-the-iom-vitamin-d-and-calcium-recommendations">Comment on the IOM Vitamin D and Calcium Recommendations&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/what-should-you-eat/vitamin-d-fracture-prevention/">HarvardSchool of Public Health – probably Jan 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For Adult Bone Health, Too Low on Vitamin D—and Too Generous on Calcium&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By Heike Bischoff-Ferrari and Walter Willett&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-bone-health">Vitamin D and Bone Health&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>^ following introduction to one of the authors is from &lt;a href="http://www.anh-usa.org/anh-usa-to-file-health-claim-for-vitamin-d-and-its-all-thanks-to-you-plus-a-vitamin-d-update/comment-page-1/#comment-40818">Alliance for Natural Health&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Dr. Walter Willett, one of the scientists who reviewed the IOM report but &lt;strong>whose comments were never made public by the IOM (nor were the comments of any of the other reviewers)&lt;/strong> , has published a summary of his concerns regarding vitamin D, calcium, and bone health. According to Dr. Willett, the randomized controlled trials (RCTs) studied by the IOM show that the daily dosage of vitamin D they recommended is too low to prevent the risk of bone fractures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>800 IU vitamin D in milk did not improve bones of middle-aged adults</title><link>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-in-milk-did-not-improve-bones-of-middle-aged-adults.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-in-milk-did-not-improve-bones-of-middle-aged-adults.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="independent-and-combined-effects-of-calcium-vitamin-d3-and-exercise-on-bone-structure-and-strength-in-older-men-an-18-month-factorial-design-randomized-controlled-trial">Independent and Combined Effects of Calcium-Vitamin D3 and Exercise on Bone Structure and Strength in Older Men: An 18-Month Factorial Design Randomized Controlled Trial&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism , doi:10.1210/jc.2010-2284&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Submitted on September 28, 2010; Accepted on December 15, 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sonja Kukuljan, Caryl A. Nowson, Kerrie M. Sanders, Geoff C. Nicholson, Markus J. Seibel, Jo Salmon, and Robin M. Daly &lt;a href="mailto:rdaly@unimelb.edu.au">rdaly@unimelb.edu.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences (S.K., C.A.N., J.S., R.M.D.), Deakin University, Victoria 3125, Australia; Department of Clinical and Biomedical Sciences: Barwon Health (K.M.S., G.C.N.), University of Melbourne, Geelong Victoria 3220, Australia; Bone Research Program (M.J.S.), ANZAC Research Institute, University of Sydney, New South Wales 2006, Australia; and Department of Medicine (R.M.D.), University of Melbourne, Western Hospital, Melbourne 3011, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Higher BMI need more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/higher-bmi-need-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/higher-bmi-need-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cross-sectional-and-longitudinal-relation-between-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-body-mass-index-the-tromsø-study">Cross-sectional and longitudinal relation between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and body mass index: the Tromsø study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Nutr. 2010 Oct;49(7):401-7. Epub 2010 Mar 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cross-sectional and longitudinal relation between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and body mass index: the Tromsø study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorde R, Sneve M, Emaus N, Figenschau Y, Grimnes G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, Tromsø, Norway. &lt;a href="mailto:rolf.jorde@unn.no">rolf.jorde@unn.no&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: The serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels are lower in obese than lean subjects. The present study examines the cross-sectional and longitudinal relations between body mass index (BMI) and serum 25(OH)D, and the serum 25(OH)D response to vitamin D supplementation in relation to BMI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The folly of a single RDA for vitamin D</title><link>/posts/the-folly-of-a-single-rda-for-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-folly-of-a-single-rda-for-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="excellent-short-articlehttpwwwtrackyourplaquecomblog201101the-folly-of-an-rda-for-vitamin-dhtml">&lt;a href="http://www.trackyourplaque.com/blog/2011/01/the-folly-of-an-rda-for-vitamin-d.html">Excellent short article&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="author-does-not-want-to-us-to-copy-the-text-here">Author does not want to us to copy the text here.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This echos a lot of documentation that is on the VitaminDWiki&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="see-vitamindwiki">See VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 889">Overview Deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-how-much-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 766">Overview How Much vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Recommendations around the world - IU and ng</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-recommendations-around-the-world-iu-and-ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-recommendations-around-the-world-iu-and-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="recommendations-around-the-world-during-the-past-50-years-have-varied-a-lot-almost-all-have-gone-up-but-a-few-have-gone-down">Recommendations around the world during the past 50 years have varied a lot. Almost all have gone up, but a few have gone down&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="this-page-is-divided-into-three-sections">This page is divided into three sections&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">How much to take = IU = International Units&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#690;">How much vitamin D in blood serum: nanograms/ml&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F90;">Toxicity - a rare thing&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="institute-of-medicine-2010-endocrine-society-2011-european-2012">Institute of Medicine 2010, Endocrine Society 2011, European 2012&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/endocrine-society-suggest-higher-vitamin-d-levels" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2039">Endocrine Society suggest higher vitamin D levels – June 2011&lt;/a> &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">NOAEL = no observed adverse effect level &lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Evaluating the vitamin D evidence - Heaney</title><link>/posts/evaluating-the-vitamin-d-evidence-heaney.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/evaluating-the-vitamin-d-evidence-heaney.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-few-images-from-a-presentation-given-in-london">A few images from a Presentation given in London&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="spantiki-download_filephpfileid1628span-to-see-entire-pdf-file">&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1628]&lt;/span> to see entire PDF file&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;367,368,369,370,371,372,373,374,375&amp;rdquo; max=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-index.php">Home page&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=86&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">All items Strength of Evidence for D&lt;/a> 7 items as of Sept 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>20000 IU vitamin D and MS – less fatigue and relapse</title><link>/posts/20000-iu-vitamin-d-and-ms-less-fatigue-and-relapse.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/20000-iu-vitamin-d-and-ms-less-fatigue-and-relapse.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="safety-and-t-cell-modulating-effects-of-high-dose-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-multiple-sclerosis">Safety and T Cell Modulating Effects of High Dose Vitamin D3 Supplementation in Multiple Sclerosis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 5(12): e15235. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0015235, Clinicaltrials.gov NCT00940719&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joost Smolders1,2,3*, Evelyn Peelen1,2,3, Mariëlle Thewissen2, Jan Willem Cohen Tervaert1,2,5, Paul Menheere4, Raymond Hupperts1,3, Jan Damoiseaux2,5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School for Mental Health and Neuroscience, Maastricht University Medical Center, Maastricht, The Netherlands,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Division of Clinical and Experimental Immunology, Department of Internal Medicine, Maastricht University Medical Center, Maastricht, The Netherlands,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 repletion – 50000 IU 3X per week is best – 2009</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-repletion-50000-iu-3x-per-week-is-best-2009.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-repletion-50000-iu-3x-per-week-is-best-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="evaluation-of-vitamin-d-repletion-regimens-to-correct-vitamin-d-status-in-adults">EVALUATION OF VITAMIN D REPLETION REGIMENS TO CORRECT VITAMIN D STATUS IN ADULTS&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2009; 15(2): 95–103., PMCID: PMC2683376, NIHMSID: NIHMS110700&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kara J. Pepper, MD,1 Suzanne E. Judd, MPH, PhD,2 Mark S. Nanes, MD, PhD,2,4 and Vin Tangpricha, MD, PhD, FACE2,3,4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of General Internal Medicine, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, Georgia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes and Lipids, Department of Medicine, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, Georgia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview of C Baggerly about IoM</title><link>/posts/interview-of-c-baggerly-about-iom.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/interview-of-c-baggerly-about-iom.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-special-interview-with-carole-baggerly">A Special Interview with Carole Baggerly&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-a-hrefpostsinterview-with-dr-cannell-on-the-same-day-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1223interview-with-dr-cannell-on-the-same-daya---along-with-video-of-both-interviews">See also: &lt;a href="/posts/interview-with-dr-cannell-on-the-same-day" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1223">Interview with Dr. Cannell on the same day&lt;/a> - along with video of both interviews&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>DM: Dr. Joseph Mercola, DO &lt;span style="color:#F00;">CB&lt;/span>: Carole Baggerly&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DM: Welcome everyone. Today, I &amp;rsquo; m with Carole Baggerly who is the founder of Grassroots Health. She has been really instrumental in managing a massive effort to help educate not only the people in the United States but those in Canada about the importance of vitamin D, and actually implement some really effective strategies to have more people adopt them especially from a governmental level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview of Dr. Cannell</title><link>/posts/interview-of-dr-cannell.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/interview-of-dr-cannell.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-special-interview-with-dr-john-cannell">A Special Interview with Dr. John Cannell&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="click-herehttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20101211vitamin-d-update-carole-baggerly-and-dr-cannellaspx-for-video-pdf-of-transcript-and-interview-with-carole-baggerly">&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2010/12/11/vitamin-d-update-carole-baggerly-and-dr-cannell.aspx">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for video, PDF of transcript and interview with Carole Baggerly&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpoststranscript-of-carole-baggerly-interview-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1230transcript-of-carole-baggerly-interviewa">&lt;a href="/posts/transcript-of-carole-baggerly-interview" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1230">Transcript of Carole Baggerly interview&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>DM: Dr. Joseph Mercola, DO    &lt;span style="color:#F00;">DC&lt;/span> Dr. John Cannell&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DM: Welcome everyone. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re here with Dr. Cannell who is the founder of the Vitamin D Council and one of the most prolific writers about vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re talking today because yesterday, which was November 30th, the Institute of Medicine released a shocking report that the amount of vitamin D is not as high as we&amp;rsquo;ve been recommending and actually, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be more than about 800 units for an adult. Really, the only evidence for the benefit of vitamin D that they could document was the improvement of bone health which is just beyond belief. Because there is literally hundreds if not thousands of studies showing that it benefits just about dozens if not hundreds of clinical conditions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why vitamin D is not a problem for some youth</title><link>/posts/why-vitamin-d-is-not-a-problem-for-some-youth.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-vitamin-d-is-not-a-problem-for-some-youth.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="youthful-skin-produces-4x-as-much-vitamin-d-per-minute-in-the-sun-as-elderly-skin">Youthful skin produces 4X as much vitamin D per minute in the sun as elderly skin&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="youth-rarely-have-diseases-that-actually-consume-vitamin-d-such-as">Youth rarely have diseases that actually consume vitamin D, such as:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpostsms-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-691msa-diabetescategoriesdiabetes-obesitycategoriesobesity-colon-cancerhttpswwwvitamindwikicomtiki-browse_categoriesphpparentid41sort_modecreated_desc-bariatric-surgery-kidney-failurehttpswwwvitamindwikicomtiki-browse_categoriesphpparentid15sort_modecreated_desc-liver-failurehttpswwwvitamindwikicomtiki-browse_categoriesphpparentid14sort_modecreated_desc-">&lt;a href="/posts/ms" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 691">MS&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="/categories/diabetes">diabetes&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="/categories/obesity">obesity&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=41&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">colon cancer&lt;/a>, bariatric surgery, &lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=15&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">kidney failure&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=14&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">liver failure&lt;/a>, &amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpostsclick-here-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-information-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-889click-here-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-informationa">&lt;a href="/posts/click-here-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-information" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 889">CLICK HERE for vitamin D deficiency information&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="youth-tend-to-be-outdoors-more---example-summer-vacation-from-school">Youth tend to be outdoors more - example: summer vacation from school&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="exceptions---probably-need-vitamin-d-if">Exceptions - probably need vitamin D if:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>sensitive skin,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>USANA found 5000 IU resulted in 50 ng - Winter 2010</title><link>/posts/usana-found-5000-iu-resulted-in-50-ng-winter-2010.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/usana-found-5000-iu-resulted-in-50-ng-winter-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="usanahttpwwwusanacom-is-a-large-supplement-provider--nutritionals-you-can-trust">&lt;a href="http://www.usana.com/">USANA&lt;/a> is a large supplement provider. &amp;ldquo;Nutritionals you can trust&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="started-in-1992-in-14-countries-in-2010-pricey-but-very-nice">Started in 1992, in 14 countries in 2010, pricey but very nice&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="they-do-not-appear-to-sell-5000-iu-capsules-yet-their-chart-shows-that-5000-is-how-much-many-people-need">They do not appear to sell 5,000 IU capsules, yet their chart shows that 5,000 is how much many people need&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="their-solid-tablet-has-2000-iu-and-30-mg-of-vitamin-k-does-not-say-k1-vs-k2">Their solid tablet has 2000 IU and 30 mg of vitamin K (does not say: K1 vs K2)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There have been several reports of problems with vitamin D in solid tablets - about 1/3 the benefit as capsule form&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IoM again fails to look at interactions</title><link>/posts/iom-again-fails-to-look-at-interactions.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/iom-again-fails-to-look-at-interactions.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>2000 IU raised black teens vitamin D level to 34 ng and they lost fat</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-raised-black-teens-vitamin-d-level-to-34-ng-and-they-lost-fat.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-raised-black-teens-vitamin-d-level-to-34-ng-and-they-lost-fat.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-16-week-randomized-clinical-trial-of-2000-international-units-daily-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-black-youth-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-adiposity-and-arterial-stiffness">A 16-week randomized clinical trial of 2000 international units daily vitamin D3 supplementation in black youth: 25-hydroxyvitamin D, adiposity, and arterial stiffness.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2010 Oct;95(10):4584-91. Epub 2010 Jul 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dong Y, Stallmann-Jorgensen IS, Pollock NK, Harris RA, Keeton D, Huang Y, Li K, Bassali R, Guo DH, Thomas J, Pierce GL, White J, Holick MF, Zhu H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Georgia Prevention Institute, Department of Pediatrics, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta, Georgia 30912, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:ydong@mail.mcg.edu">ydong@mail.mcg.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>