<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Preemie on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/preemie.html</link><description>Recent content in Preemie on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/preemie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Premature infants need 400 to 800 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/premature-infants-need-400-to-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/premature-infants-need-400-to-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="preterm-babies-have-low-vitamin-d-but-recover-with-800-iu">Preterm babies have low vitamin D, but recover with 800 IU&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>(Preterm babies have low vitamin D, but recover in 6 weeks with 800 IU supplementation – Jan 2019))&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="400-or-800-iu---letter-to-editor-march-2015">400 or 800 IU - Letter to Editor March 2015&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D Supplementation in Premature Infants&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am Fam Physician. 2015 Mar 15;91(6):352-353. Letters to the Editor&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Original article: Common Questions About Outpatient Care of Premature Infants&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Issue date: August 15, 2014&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pre-term birth - many of risk factors are associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pre-term-birth-many-of-risk-factors-are-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pre-term-birth-many-of-risk-factors-are-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/preterm-birth-rate-reduced-by-vitamin-d-78-percent-if-non-white-39-percent-if-white" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Preterm birth rate reduced by vitamin D – 78 percent if non-white, 39 percent if white – July 2017">Preterm birth rate reduced by vitamin D – 78 percent if non-white, 39 percent if white – July 2017&lt;/a> Baggerly etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-webinar-cost-of-pre-term-birth-etc-baggerly">Vitamin D Webinar - cost of pre-term birth etc- Baggerly Nov 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">$2,590 &lt;/span>reduction in cost of each pregnancy just due to reduction in preterm birth&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preemies 2.5 X more likely to get hip replacement etc. (low vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/preemies-25-x-more-likely-to-get-hip-replacement-etc-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/preemies-25-x-more-likely-to-get-hip-replacement-etc-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-of-low-birth-weight-and-preterm-birth-with-the-incidence-of-knee-and-hip-arthroplasty-for-osteoarthritis">Association of low birth weight and preterm birth with the incidence of knee and hip arthroplasty for osteoarthritis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arthritis Care &amp;amp; Research DOI: 10.1002/acr.22475&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sultana Monira Hussain1, Yuanyuan Wang1, Anita E. Wluka1, Jonathan E. Shaw2, Dianna J. Magliano2, Stephen Graves3,4 and Flavia M. Cicuttini1,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Epidemiology and Preventive Medicine, School of Public Health and Preventive Medicine, Monash University, Alfred Hospital, Melbourne, VIC, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Baker IDI Heart and Diabetes Institute, Melbourne, VIC, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heavier Babies Do Better in School (perhaps more vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/heavier-babies-do-better-in-school-perhaps-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heavier-babies-do-better-in-school-perhaps-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="heavier-babies-do-better-in-schoolhttpwwwnytimescom20141012upshotheavier-babies-do-better-in-schoolhtmlabt0002abg020-new-york-times">&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/10/12/upshot/heavier-babies-do-better-in-school.html?abt=0002&amp;amp;abg=0%20">Heavier Babies Do Better in School&lt;/a> New York Times&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:>60%">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Known: Babies with low birth weight are associated with LOW vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Known: Infants and Children with HIGH vitamin D have fewer illnesses&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>and thus probably have more as well as better quality time in school&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hypothesis: Babies with high birth weight are associates with HIGH vitamin D&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h5 id="a-few-quotes-from-new-york-times-article">A few quotes from New York Times article&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Among the top 5 percent of test scorers in elementary school, one in three weighed at least eight pounds at birth, compared with only one in four of all babies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Extremely low vitamin D in mother: early birth and low weight in children, mortality in mice</title><link>/posts/extremely-low-vitamin-d-in-mother-early-birth-and-low-weight-in-children-mortality-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/extremely-low-vitamin-d-in-mother-early-birth-and-low-weight-in-children-mortality-in-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="maternal-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-fetal-programming---lessons-learned-from-humans-and-mice">Maternal Vitamin D Deficiency and Fetal Programming - Lessons Learned from Humans and Mice&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Kidney Blood Press Res 2014;39:315-329 39, (DOI:10.1159/000355809)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reichetzeder C.a · Chen H.b · Föller M.b · Slowinski T.c · Li J.d · Chen Y.-P.e · Lang F.b · Hocher B.a&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Institute of Nutritional Science, University of Potsdam, Potsdam-Rehbrücke;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Department of Physiology, University of Tübingen;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Department of Nephrology, Campus Mitte, Charité, Berlin, Germany;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D Department of Clinical Medicine, Medical college of Hunan Normal University, Changsha;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets in half of premature births – 200 IU of vitamin D is enough – RCT</title><link>/posts/rickets-in-half-of-premature-births-200-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-enough-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-in-half-of-premature-births-200-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-enough-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prophylactic-effect-of-low-dose-vitamin-d-in-osteopenia-of-prematurity-a-clinical-trial-study">Prophylactic Effect of Low Dose Vitamin D in Osteopenia of Prematurity: A Clinical Trial Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Paymaneh Alizadeh 1, Negar Sajjadian1 &lt;a href="mailto:nsajjadian@yahoo.com">nsajjadian@yahoo.com&lt;/a>, Bahram Beyrami 1, Mamak Shariat 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Pediatrics, Bahrami Children Hospital, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Research Maternofetal Center, Vali Asr Hospital, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received: 10 Jul 2013; Accepted: 2 Nov. 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteopenia of prematurity (OOP) is a preventable disease. Improved survival of newborns with OOP is associated with an increased incidence of OOP. The purpose of this study was to compare the prophylactic effects of two low doses of vitamin D (200 and 400 IU/Day) on the clinical, biochemical and radiological indices of the rickets of prematurity. In a randomized clinical trial, 60 preterm newborns with birth weight &amp;lt; 2000 g &amp;amp; gestational age &amp;lt; 37 weeks were randomly divided in two groups. Thirty newborns received 200 IU/d of vitamin D in group one and 30 ones received 400 IU/day of vitamin D in group two. On the 6th and 8th weeks of life, serum calcium, phosphate, alkaline phosphates, and 25 - hydroxy vitamin D concentrations were measured and x- ray of left wrist and physical examination were performed. Both groups had no difference in biochemical, radiological or clinical presentation of rickets. Current study indicated that low dose vitamin D (200 IU/Day) is enough for prevention of OOP.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300 IU is not enough vitamin D for preterm infants</title><link>/posts/300-iu-is-not-enough-vitamin-d-for-preterm-infants.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300-iu-is-not-enough-vitamin-d-for-preterm-infants.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-of-early-preterm-infants-and-the-effects-of-vitamin-d-intake-during-hospital-stay">Vitamin D status of early preterm infants and the effects of vitamin D intake during hospital stay.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2014 Mar;99(2):F166-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/archdischild-2013-303999.">doi: 10.1136/archdischild-2013-303999.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Jul 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Monangi N1, Slaughter JL, Dawodu A, Smith C, Akinbi HT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Neonatal Perinatal Medicine, Perinatal Institute, Cincinnati Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Medical Center/University of Cincinnati, , Cincinnati, Ohio, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To evaluate vitamin D (vitD) status in early preterm infants (EPTIs) at birth and during birth hospitalisation on current vitD intake.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preemies have increased need for vitamin D and Calcium (Rickets)</title><link>/posts/preemies-have-increased-need-for-vitamin-d-and-calcium-rickets.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/preemies-have-increased-need-for-vitamin-d-and-calcium-rickets.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-requirements-of-enterally-fed-preterm-infants">Calcium and vitamin d requirements of enterally fed preterm infants.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pediatrics. 2013 May;131(5):e1676-83. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2013-0420.">doi: 10.1542/peds.2013-0420.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Apr 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abrams SA; Committee on Nutrition; Collaborators (6)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone health is a critical concern in managing preterm infants. Key nutrients of importance are calcium, vitamin D, and phosphorus. Although human milk is critical for the health of preterm infants, it is low in these nutrients relative to the needs of the infants during growth. Strategies should be in place to fortify human milk for preterm infants with birth weight &amp;lt;1800 to 2000 g and to ensure adequate mineral intake during hospitalization and after hospital discharge. Biochemical monitoring of very low birth weight infants should be performed during their hospitalization. Vitamin D should be provided at 200 to 400 IU/day both during hospitalization and after discharge from the hospital. Infants with radiologic evidence of rickets should have efforts made to maximize calcium and phosphorus intake by using available commercial products and, if needed, direct supplementation with these minerals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>93% of newborns of military in Hawaii had low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/93-percent-of-newborns-of-military-in-hawaii-had-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/93-percent-of-newborns-of-military-in-hawaii-had-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-at-birth-among-military-dependants-in-hawaii">Vitamin D Deficiency at Birth Among Military Dependants in Hawai&amp;rsquo;i&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>HAWAI&amp;rsquo;I JOURNAL OF MEDICINE &amp;amp; PUBLIC HEALTH, MARCH 2013, VOL 72, NO 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eldon G. Palmer MD; Emmanuel Ramirez-Enriquez MD; Sarah M. Frioux MD; and Melissa M. Tyree MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has long been known to be essential in bone mineralization as well as calcium and phosphate regulation. An increasing body ofliterature suggests that Vitamin D is also key in many other areas to include immune function, brain development, prevention of autoimmune disease, and prevention of certain types of cancers. Studies also suggest that, with decreased sun exposure due to concern for skin cancer risk, much of the world&amp;rsquo;s population is becoming increasingly deficient in vitamin D. Our hypothesis was that vitamin D deficiency exists, and can be detected, even in sunny climates such as the state ofHawaii. To test this hypothesis, eighty-six cord blood samples were collected in the process of routine clinical testing. These samples were tested for 25-hydroxy vitamin D via liquid chromatography mass spectroscopy. Percent deficiency (&amp;lt;20ng/mL) and insufficiency (20-31.9ng/mL) were determined by statistical analysis. Forty-six percent (n=37) of cord blood samples tested were deficient in vitamin D; 47 percent (n=38) of samples had insufficient 25-OH vitamin D. &lt;strong>Only 7 percent (n=6) of samples showed vitamin D concentrations at the recommended levels.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin A (Cod Liver Oil) blocks vitamin D – 2008</title><link>/posts/vitamin-a-cod-liver-oil-blocks-vitamin-d-2008.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-a-cod-liver-oil-blocks-vitamin-d-2008.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="cod-liver-oil-vitamin-a-toxicity-frequent-respiratory-infections-and-the-vitamin-d-deficiency-epidemic">Cod Liver Oil, Vitamin A Toxicity, Frequent Respiratory Infections, and the Vitamin D Deficiency Epidemic&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>COMMENTARY, Annals of Otology, Rhinology &amp;amp; Laryngology 117(ll):864-870. © 2008&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John J. Cannell, MD; Reinhold Vieth, MS, PhD; Walter Willett, MD, DrPH; Michael Zasloff, MD, PhD; John N. Hathcock, MSc, PhD; John H. White, PhD; Sherry A. Tanumihardjo, MSc, PhD; D. Enette Larson-Meyer, PhD; Heike A. Bischoff-Ferrari, MD, MPH; Christel J. Lamberg-Allardt, PhD; Joan M. Lappe, PhD, RN; Anthony W. Norman, PhD; Armin Zittermann, PhD; Susan J. Whiting, MSc, PhD; William B. Grant, PhD; Bruce W. Hollis, PhD; Edward Giovannucci, MD&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D increased probability of low birth weight by 60 percent – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increased-probability-of-low-birth-weight-by-60-percent-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increased-probability-of-low-birth-weight-by-60-percent-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-maternal-neonatal-and-infant-health-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D During Pregnancy and Maternal, Neonatal and Infant Health Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Andrew Thorne-Lyman1,*, Wafaie W. Fawzi1,2,3; Article first published online: 28 JUN 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2012 Blackwell Publishing Ltd&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paediatric and Perinatal Epidemiology, Volume 26, Issue Supplement s1, pages 75–90, July 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Special Issue: Improving maternal, newborn, and child health outcomes through better designed policies and programs that enhance the nutrition of women&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:>85%">
&lt;p>The only daily vitamin D data used in the meta-analysis was 1000 IU of vitamin &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">D2&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>