<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vitamin D2 on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/vitamin-d2.html</link><description>Recent content in Vitamin D2 on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/vitamin-d2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D2 improved sexual hormones, erectile function etc</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-improved-sexual-hormones-erectile-function-etc.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-improved-sexual-hormones-erectile-function-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-treatment-improves-levels-of-sexual-hormones-metabolic-parameters-and-erectile-function-in-middle-aged-vitamin-d-deficient-men">Vitamin D treatment improves levels of sexual hormones, metabolic parameters and erectile function in middle-aged vitamin D deficient men&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Aging Male, Early Online: 1-8 DOI: 10.1080/13685538.2016.1271783 Jan 4 2017&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onder &lt;a href="mailto:Canguven1ocanguven@yahoo.com">Canguven1ocanguven@yahoo.com&lt;/a>, Raidh A. Talib1 *, Walid El Ansari2, Dany-Jan Yassin3, and Abdullah Al Naimi1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>’Department of Urology and 2Department of Surgery, Hamad General Hospital, Hamad Medical Corporation, Doha, Qatar, and 3Institute of Urology and Andrology, Hamburg, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>Participants selected had &amp;lt;30 ng/mL and erectile dysfunction&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caution When Prescribing High Dose Vitamin D (100,000 IU D2 daily for is too much after 4 years)</title><link>/posts/caution-when-prescribing-high-dose-vitamin-d-100000-iu-d2-daily-for-is-too-much-after-4-years.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/caution-when-prescribing-high-dose-vitamin-d-100000-iu-d2-daily-for-is-too-much-after-4-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-word-of-caution-when-prescribing-high-dose-vitamin-d">A Word of Caution When Prescribing High Dose Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Medicine Nov 2016, DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2016.10.025">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2016.10.025&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matthew A. Gorris, MD, Department of Internal Medicine, Wake Forest Baptist Medical Center, Winston Salem, North Carolina, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harkesh Arora, MD, Apogee Physicians, New Mexico, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David C. Lieb, MD, Division of Endocrinology, Eastern Virginia Medical School, Norfolk, Virginia, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joseph A. Aloi, MD, Division of Endocrinology, Wake Forest Baptist Medical Center, Winston Salem, North Carolina, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Muscle Strength improved 1.4 to 19 percent by vitamin D3 (not D2) – systematic review</title><link>/posts/muscle-strength-improved-14-to-19-percent-by-vitamin-d3-not-d2-systematic-review.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/muscle-strength-improved-14-to-19-percent-by-vitamin-d3-not-d2-systematic-review.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-muscle-strength-in-athletes-a-systematic-review">Effects of Vitamin D Supplementation on Muscle Strength in Athletes A Systematic Review.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#suspect-that-most-of-the-benefits-were-associated-with-high-dose-vitamin-d">Suspect that most of the benefits were associated with high dose vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-muscle-strength-in-athletes-a-systematic-review">Effects of Vitamin D Supplementation on Muscle Strength in Athletes A Systematic Review.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Strength Cond Res. 2016 Jun 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chiang CM1, Ismaeel A, Griffis RB, Weems S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrition Sciences, Baylor University, Waco, Texas; and 2English, Baylor University, Waco, Texas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this systematic review of the literature was to investigate the effects of vitamin D supplementation on muscle strength in athletes. A computerized literature search of three databases (PubMed, Medline, and Scopus) was performed. Included in the review were randomized controlled trials, published in English, which measured serum vitamin D concentrations and muscle strength in healthy, athletic participants ages 18-45 years old. Quality was assessed using the PEDro scale.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loading dose of Vitamin D2 REDUCED vitamin D blood in a third of the patients</title><link>/posts/loading-dose-of-vitamin-d2-reduced-vitamin-d-blood-in-a-third-of-the-patients.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/loading-dose-of-vitamin-d2-reduced-vitamin-d-blood-in-a-third-of-the-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-a-10-day-course-of-a-high-dose-calciferol-versus-a-single-mega-dose-of-ergocalciferol-in-correcting-vitamin-d-deficiency">Effects of a 10-day course of a high dose calciferol versus a single mega dose of ergocalciferol in correcting vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Saudi Med. 2015 Jan-Feb;35(1):13-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5144/0256-4947.2015.13.">doi: 10.5144/0256-4947.2015.13.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Melhem SJ, Aiedeh KM, Hadidi KA1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Dr. Kamal Hadidi, Department of Pathology,, The University of Jordan,, Amman 00962, Jordan, T: +962-77 7424657, F: +962-6 5356746, &lt;a href="mailto:khadidi@ju.edu.jo">khadidi@ju.edu.jo&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The correction of vitamin D deficiency is crucial for optimal skeletal and non-skeletal health. Most regimens in current use are based on daily dosing, which may raise concerns of dosage inadequacy and suboptimal patient compliance. Vitamin D is available in 2 forms: D2 (ergocalciferol) and D3 (cholecalciferol). It has been reported that D2 supplements are less effective and may enhance the degradation of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D3) metabolite. The aim of this study was to compare the effect of 2 high-dose oral vitamin D regimens- -a 10-day course of D3 500,000 IU versus a single mega dose of 600,000 IU D2- -on serum 25(OH)D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 levels decreased by consumption of UV mushrooms – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-levels-decreased-by-consumption-of-uv-mushrooms-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-levels-decreased-by-consumption-of-uv-mushrooms-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-ultraviolet-light-exposed-mushrooms-on-vitamin-d-status-liquid-chromatography-tandem-mass-spectrometry-reanalysis-of-biobanked-sera-from-a-randomized-controlled-trial-and-a-systematic-review-plus-meta-analysis">Effect of Ultraviolet Light-Exposed Mushrooms on Vitamin D Status: Liquid Chromatography-Tandem Mass Spectrometry Reanalysis of Biobanked Sera from a Randomized Controlled Trial and a Systematic Review plus Meta-Analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2016 Feb 10. pii: jn223784. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cashman KD1, Kiely M2, Seamans KM3, Urbain P4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Cork Centre for Vitamin D and Nutrition Research, School of Food and Nutritional Sciences, Department of Medicine, &lt;a href="mailto:k.cashman@ucc.ie">k.cashman@ucc.ie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Cork Centre for Vitamin D and Nutrition Research, School of Food and Nutritional Sciences, Irish Centre for Fetal and Neonatal Translational Research, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland; and.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>50,000 IU of vitamin D weekly (D3 or D2) got two thirds of cystic fibrosis patients to 30 nanograms – RCT</title><link>/posts/50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly-d3-or-d2-got-two-thirds-of-cystic-fibrosis-patients-to-30-nanograms-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly-d3-or-d2-got-two-thirds-of-cystic-fibrosis-patients-to-30-nanograms-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-randomized-controlled-trial-of-vitamin-d-replacement-strategies-in-pediatric-cf-patients">A randomized controlled trial of vitamin D replacement strategies in pediatric CF patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Cyst Fibros. 2015 Jul 23. pii: S1569-1993(15)00166-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcf.2015.07.004.">doi: 10.1016/j.jcf.2015.07.004.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simoneau T1, Sawicki GS2, Milliren CE3, Feldman HA3, Gordon CM4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Boston Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Division of Respiratory Diseases, Harvard Medical School, 300 Longwood Ave, Boston, MA, United States. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:tsimoneau@connecticutchildrens.org">tsimoneau@connecticutchildrens.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Boston Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Division of Respiratory Diseases, Harvard Medical School, 300 Longwood Ave, Boston, MA, United States.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 from cooked mushroom added virtually no vitamin D to bloodstream - RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-from-cooked-mushroom-added-virtually-no-vitamin-d-to-bloodstream-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-from-cooked-mushroom-added-virtually-no-vitamin-d-to-bloodstream-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="bioavailability-of-vitamin-d2-from-enriched-mushrooms-in-prediabetic-adults-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Bioavailability of vitamin D2 from enriched mushrooms in prediabetic adults: a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2014 Oct;68(10):1154-60. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2014.157.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2014.157.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Aug 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mehrotra A1, Calvo MS2, Beelman RB3, Levy E1, Siuty J1, Kalaras MD3, Uribarri J1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Medicine, Mount Sinai School of Medicine, New York, NY, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition, FDA, Laurel, MD, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Food Science, The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Large dose of vitamin D2 did not help (no surprise – avg 1700 IU daily)</title><link>/posts/large-dose-of-vitamin-d2-did-not-help-no-surprise-avg-1700-iu-daily.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/large-dose-of-vitamin-d2-did-not-help-no-surprise-avg-1700-iu-daily.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="large-doses-of-vitamin-d-fail-to-increase-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-or-to-alter-cardiovascular-risk-factors-in-obese-adolescents-a-pilot-study">Large Doses of Vitamin D Fail to Increase 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels or to Alter Cardiovascular Risk Factors in Obese Adolescents: A Pilot Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Adolescent Health, doi:10.1016/j.jadohealth.2015.02.006&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sejal Shah, M.D., , Darrell M. Wilson, M.D., Laura K. Bachrach, M.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Obese adolescents were randomized to vitamin D2 (150,000 IU) or placebo for 24 weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Treatment with large doses of vitamin D2 failed to increase 25OH vitamin D levels.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Treatment with vitamin D2 failed to alter inflammatory markers or lipids.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hemodialysis not helped by weekly vitamin D2 – RCT</title><link>/posts/hemodialysis-not-helped-by-weekly-vitamin-d2-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hemodialysis-not-helped-by-weekly-vitamin-d2-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Following large doses of vitamin D2, Vitamin D3 doses were unable to achieve sufficiency</title><link>/posts/following-large-doses-of-vitamin-d2-vitamin-d3-doses-were-unable-to-achieve-sufficiency.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/following-large-doses-of-vitamin-d2-vitamin-d3-doses-were-unable-to-achieve-sufficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="differential-effects-of-different-vitamin-d-replacement-strategies-in-patients-with-diabetes">Differential effects of different vitamin D replacement strategies in patients with diabetes.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Diabetes Complications. 2014 Jan-Feb;28(1):66-70. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2013.09.003.">doi: 10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2013.09.003.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Oct 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alam U1, Chan AW2, Buazon A1, Van Zeller C1, Berry JL3, Jugdey RS4, Asghar O1, Cruickshank JK5, Petropoulos IN1, Malik RA6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Centre for Endocrinology and Diabetes, Institute of Human Development, University of Manchester and the Central Manchester University Hospitals Foundation Trust, Manchester, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Barts and The London SMD, London, UK.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>600,000 IU of Vitamin D2 is rarely toxic in infants</title><link>/posts/600000-iu-of-vitamin-d2-is-rarely-toxic-in-infants.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/600000-iu-of-vitamin-d2-is-rarely-toxic-in-infants.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="spanoverdose-or-hypersensitivity-to-vitamin-dspan-spanarticle-in-frenchspan">&lt;span>[Overdose or hypersensitivity to vitamin D?]&lt;/span> &lt;span>[Article in French]&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Arch Pediatr. 2014 Aug 13. pii: S0929-693X(14)00324-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arcped.2014.06.025.">doi: 10.1016/j.arcped.2014.06.025.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmami F1, Oulmaati A2, Amarti A3, Kottler ML4, Bouharrou A2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Service de néonatologie et réanimation néonatale, CHU Hassan II, 30000 Fès, Maroc; Université Sidi Mohammed Ben Abdellah, faculté de médecine et de pharmacie, Fès, Maroc. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:fhmami@hotmail.com">fhmami@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Service de néonatologie et réanimation néonatale, CHU Hassan II, 30000 Fès, Maroc; Université Sidi Mohammed Ben Abdellah, faculté de médecine et de pharmacie, Fès, Maroc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cooked mushrooms (Vitamin D2) did not increase vitamin D serum levels</title><link>/posts/cooked-mushrooms-vitamin-d2-did-not-increase-vitamin-d-serum-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cooked-mushrooms-vitamin-d2-did-not-increase-vitamin-d-serum-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="bioavailability-of-vitamin-d2-from-enriched-mushrooms-in-prediabetic-adults-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Bioavailability of vitamin D2 from enriched mushrooms in prediabetic adults: a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2014 Aug 13. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2014.157.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2014.157.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mehrotra A1, Calvo MS2, Beelman RB3, Levy E1, Siuty J1, Kalaras MD3, Uribarri J1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Objectives:Based on the growing evidence of risk reduction from fresh fruit and vegetable consumption and an inverse relationship between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) and the risk of type 2 diabetes (T2D), we determined the benefits of regularly consuming vitamin D-enriched mushrooms in a prediabetic cohort. Exposing edible mushrooms to ultraviolet B (UVB) light increases vitamin D2 (D2) and raises serum 25OHD2 in healthy young adults; however, their benefit to deficient prediabetics and glucose metabolism remains untested.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 from food – perhaps 80 IU daily</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-from-food-perhaps-80-iu-daily.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-from-food-perhaps-80-iu-daily.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="dietary-vitamin-d2---a-potentially-underestimated-contributor-to-vitamin-d-nutritional-status-of-adults">Dietary vitamin D2 - a potentially underestimated contributor to vitamin D nutritional status of adults?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2014 Apr 29:1-10. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cashman KD 1, Kinsella M 1, McNulty BA2, Walton J1, Gibney MJ2, Flynn A1, Kiely M1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Food and Nutritional Sciences, University College Cork, Cork, Republic of Ireland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 UCD Institute of Food and Health, University College Dublin, Dublin, Republic of Ireland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been suggested that vitamin D2 is not very prevalent in the human food chain. However, data from a number of recent intervention studies suggest that the majority of subjects had measurable serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D2 (25(OH)D2) concentrations. Serum 25(OH)D2, unlike 25(OH)D3, is not directly influenced by exposure of skin to sun and thus has dietary origins; however, quantifying dietary vitamin D2 is difficult due to the limitations of food composition data. Therefore, the present study aimed to characterise serum 25(OH)D2 concentrations in the participants of the National Adult Nutrition Survey (NANS) in Ireland, and to use these serum concentrations to estimate the intake of vitamin D2 using a mathematical modelling approach. Serum 25(OH)D2 concentration was measured by a liquid chromatography-tandem MS method, and information on diet as well as subject characteristics was obtained from the NANS. Of these participants, 78·7 % (n 884) had serum 25(OH)D2 concentrations above the limit of quantification, and the mean, maximum, 10th, 50th (median) and 90th percentile values of serum 25(OH)D2 concentrations were 3·69, 27·6, 1·71, 2·96 and 6·36 nmol/l, respectively. To approximate the intake of vitamin D2 from these serum 25(OH)D2 concentrations, we used recently published data on the relationship between vitamin D intake and the responses of serum 25(OH)D concentrations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces risk of cause specific death, unless it is D2 – meta-analysis BMJ</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-risk-of-cause-specific-death-unless-it-is-d2-meta-analysis-bmj.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-risk-of-cause-specific-death-unless-it-is-d2-meta-analysis-bmj.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/chance-of-dying-increases-by-25-percent-in-seniors-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis">Chance of dying increases by 25 percent in seniors if low vitamin D – Meta-analysis July 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-with-calcium-reduces-mortality-by-7-percent-meta-analysis" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Vitamin D with Calcium reduces mortality by 7 percent – meta-analysis May 2012">Vitamin D with Calcium reduces mortality by 7 percent – meta-analysis May 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/death-rate-reduced-8-percent-for-8-nanogram-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Death rate reduced 8 percent for 8 nanogram more vitamin D – meta-analysis Feb 2012">Death rate reduced 8 percent for 8 nanogram more vitamin D – meta-analysis Feb 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>During brown bear hibernation Vitamin D3 decreases but D2 increases (surprise)</title><link>/posts/during-brown-bear-hibernation-vitamin-d3-decreases-but-d2-increases-surprise.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/during-brown-bear-hibernation-vitamin-d3-decreases-but-d2-increases-surprise.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-and-bone-and-connective-tissue-turnover-in-brown-bears-ursus-arctos-during-hibernation-and-the-active-state">Vitamin D Status and Bone and Connective Tissue Turnover in Brown Bears (Ursus arctos) during Hibernation and the Active State&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 6(6): e21483. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0021483&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter Vestergaard mail, Ole-Gunnar Støen, Jon E. Swenson, Leif Mosekilde, Lene Heickendorff, Ole Fröbert&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Extended physical inactivity causes disuse osteoporosis in humans. In contrast, brown bears (Ursus arctos) are highly immobilised for half of the year during hibernation without signs of bone loss and therefore may serve as a model for prevention of osteoporosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>372 types of vitamin D prescriptions in France, 200,000 IU was the most popular</title><link>/posts/372-types-of-vitamin-d-prescriptions-in-france-200000-iu-was-the-most-popular.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/372-types-of-vitamin-d-prescriptions-in-france-200000-iu-was-the-most-popular.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-a-healthy-middle-aged-population-actual-practices-based-on-data-from-a-french-comprehensive-regional-health-care-database">Vitamin D supplementation in a healthy, middle-aged population: actual practices based on data from a French comprehensive regional health-care database&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Clinical Nutrition , (2 October 2013) | doi:10.1038/ejcn.2013.182&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P Caillet, J C Souberbielle, S B Jaglal, A Reymondier, E Van Ganse, R Chapurlat and A M Schott&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND/OBJECTIVES: The debate surrounding recommendations for vitamin D supplementation in middle-aged patients (that is, 20–60 years of age) with low serum concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) is growing. Our aim was to describe practices regarding vitamin D supplementation in this age group, which are basically unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300,000 IU of vitamin D2 reduced inflammation markers (cytokines and chemokines)</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-of-vitamin-d2-reduced-inflammation-markers-cytokines-and-chemokines.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-of-vitamin-d2-reduced-inflammation-markers-cytokines-and-chemokines.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-relationship-between-pro-resorptive-inflammatory-cytokines-and-the-effect-of-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-their-circulating-concentrations">The relationship between pro-resorptive inflammatory cytokines and the effect of high dose vitamin D supplementation on their circulating concentrations.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Int Immunopharmacol. 2013 Sep 2. pii: S1567-5769(13)00331-7. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intimp.2013.08.010.">doi: 10.1016/j.intimp.2013.08.010.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karim Y, Turner C, Dalton N, Roplekar R, Sankaralingam A, Ewang M, Fogelman I, Hampson G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Immunology, St Thomas&amp;rsquo; Hospital, London SE1 7EH, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inflammatory/pro-resorptive cytokines and chemokines form part of a complex inter-dependent network and may be influenced by vitamin D. We investigated their inter-relationship and the effect of a loading dose of vitamin D. We measured plasma concentrations of an array of cytokines including tumour necrosis factor-alpha (TNF-α), interleukin-1 (IL-1), IL-6, IL-17, IL-8, granulocyte macrophage colony stimulating factor (GM-CSF), and the chemokine monocyte chemoattractant protein-1 (MCP-1). Cytokines, 25 (OH) vitamin D, 1,25 (OH)2 vitamin D, the Wnt inhibitor, DKK1 concentrations and bone turnover markers were measured at baseline and 3months following a bolus dose &lt;strong>(300,000IU) of vitamin D2&lt;/strong> in 39 subjects with vitamin D insufficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 increased and Vitamin D2 decreased the D3 serum levels – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-increased-and-vitamin-d2-decreased-the-d3-serum-levels-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-increased-and-vitamin-d2-decreased-the-d3-serum-levels-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="bioavailability-of-vitamin-d2-and-d3-in-healthy-volunteers-a-randomised-placebo-controlled-trial">Bioavailability of Vitamin D2 and D3 in Healthy Volunteers, a randomised placebo-controlled trial&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism September 3, 2013 jc.2012-4287&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ulrike Lehmann 1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frank Hirche 1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gabriele I. Stangl 1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katja Hinz 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sabine Westphal 2 and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jutta Dierkes 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Institute of Agricultural and Nutritional Sciences, Martin-Luther University Halle-Wittenberg;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Institute of Clinical Chemistry and Biochemistry, Otto-von-Guericke University Magdeburg;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Bergen, Norway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address all correspondence and requests for reprints to: Jutta Dierkes PhD, Department of Clinical Medicine, Post Box 7804, N-5020 Bergen, Norway, email: &lt;a href="mailto:jutta.dierkes@med.uib.no">jutta.dierkes@med.uib.no&lt;/a>, phone: 004755977344, fax 004755975890.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Response to Vitamin D3 varied with rs4588, D2 less response than D3 and did not change</title><link>/posts/response-to-vitamin-d3-varied-with-rs4588-d2-less-response-than-d3-and-did-not-change.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/response-to-vitamin-d3-varied-with-rs4588-d2-less-response-than-d3-and-did-not-change.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="changes-in-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-according-to-vitamin-d-binding-protein-genotypes-after-vitamin-d-or-d-supplementation">Changes in circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D according to vitamin D binding protein genotypes after vitamin D₃ or D₂ supplementation.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nutr J. 2013 Apr 4;12:39. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1475-2891-12-39.">doi: 10.1186/1475-2891-12-39.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nimitphong H, Saetung S, Chanprasertyotin S, Chailurkit LO, Ongphiphadhanakul B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Ramathibodi Hospital, Mahidol University, Rama 6 Rd, Rajthevi, Bangkok 10400, Thailand. &lt;a href="mailto:hataikarnn@hotmail.com">hataikarnn@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: It is not known whether genetic variation in the vitamin D binding protein (DBP) influences 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> after vitamin D supplementation. We aimed to investigate the changes of total 25(OH)D, 25(OH)D₃ and 25(OH)D₂ in a Thai cohort, according to type of vitamin D supplement (vitamin D₃ or D₂) and DBP genotype, after receiving vitamin D₃ or D₂ for 3 months.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 did not help Lupus (no surprise, D2 was given weekly)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-did-not-help-lupus-no-surprise-d2-was-given-weekly.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-did-not-help-lupus-no-surprise-d2-was-given-weekly.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-in-sle-modest-association-with-disease-activity-and-urine-proteincreatinine-ratio">Vitamin D in SLE: Modest association with disease activity and urine protein/creatinine ratio&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Arthritis &amp;amp; Rheumatism Vol. 65 Issue 6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michelle Petri 1,†,*, Kayode J. Bello 1, Hong Fang 1, Laurence S. Magder 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: We investigated whether an increase in vitamin D levels in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus was associated with improvement in disease activity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: 1006 SLE patients were followed over 128 weeks. SLE patients with low levels of 25-hydroxy Vitamin D (&amp;lt;40 ng/mL) were supplemented with 50,000 units Vitamin D2 weekly, with Ca/D3 200 units twice daily. Longitudinal regression models were used to estimate the association between levels of vitamin D and various measures of disease activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some Infants with 400 IU daily of Vitamin D2 actually decreased serum levels</title><link>/posts/some-infants-with-400-iu-daily-of-vitamin-d2-actually-decreased-serum-levels.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-infants-with-400-iu-daily-of-vitamin-d2-actually-decreased-serum-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-change-in-plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-did-not-differ-between-breast-fed-infants-that-received-a-daily-supplement-of-ergocalciferol-or-cholecalciferol-for-3-months">The change in plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D did not differ between breast-fed infants that received a daily supplement of ergocalciferol or cholecalciferol for 3 months.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2013 Feb;143(2):148-53. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3945/jn.112.167858.">doi: 10.3945/jn.112.167858.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Dec 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gallo S, Phan A, Vanstone CA, Rodd C, Weiler HA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition, McGill University, Montréal, Québec, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The biological equivalency of ergocalciferol (D2) and cholecalciferol (D3) has been debated; several comparisons have appeared in the adult literature but are scarce in pediatrics. The objective of this study was to compare increases in plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations and attainment of 50 and 75 mol/L status cutoffs following 3 mo of daily supplementation with D2 compared with D3. Healthy, breast-fed, 1-mo-old infants (n = 52) received 10 μg (400 ic) of either D2 or D3 daily. At 1 and 4 mo of age, plasma 25-hydroxyergocalciferol and 25-hydroxycholecalciferol concentrations were determined by liquid chromatography tandem MS (LC-MS/MS) and total 25(OH)D by chemiluminescent immunoassay (DiaSorin Liaison). Data were analyzed using t tests and χ² by intent to treat. A total of 23% of infants were deficient (≤24.9 nmol/L) at baseline and 2% at follow-up on the basis of LC-MS/MS. At 4 mo, 96% were breastfed and there were no differences in compliance, breastfeeding rates, or sun exposure among groups. The change in total 25(OH)D measured by LC-MS/MS did not differ between the D2 (17.6 ± 26.7 nmol/L) and D3 (22.2 ± 20.2 nmol/L) groups. In the combined groups, the baseline plasma 25(OH)D concentration was inversely related to the change in total 25(OH)D (r = -0.52; P &amp;lt; 0.001).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>D2 may reduce academic performance</title><link>/posts/d2-may-reduce-academic-performance.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/d2-may-reduce-academic-performance.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="association-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-d-with-academic-performance-in-childhood-findings-from-a-prospective-birth-cohort">Association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D₃ and D₂ with academic performance in childhood: findings from a prospective birth cohort.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Epidemiol Community Health. 2012 Dec;66(12):1137-42. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/jech-2011-200114.">doi: 10.1136/jech-2011-200114.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Apr 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tolppanen AM, Sayers A, Fraser WD, Lawlor DA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MRC Centre for Causal Analysis in Translational Epidemiology, School of Social and Community Medicine, University of Bristol, Oakfield House, 15-23 Oakfield Grove, Clifton, Bristol BS8 2BN, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:anna-maija.tolppanen@uef.fi">anna-maija.tolppanen@uef.fi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Higher total serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentrations have been associated with better cognitive function mainly in cross-sectional studies in adults. It is unknown if the associations of different forms of 25(OH)D (25(OH)D(3) and 25(OH)D(2)) are similar.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prevention and Treatment of Vitamin D Deficiency</title><link>/posts/prevention-and-treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prevention-and-treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Calcif Tissue Int. 2012 Nov 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sinha A, Cheetham TD, Pearce SH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Genetic Medicine, Newcastle University, International Centre for Life, Central Parkway, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE1 3BZ, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D insufficiency and deficiency are widespread in many countries. We review the evidence pertaining to its prevention and treatment. Deficiency may be adequately treated with many different therapeutic regimens of either cholecalciferol or ergocalciferol, owing to the high therapeutic index of both compounds. Nevertheless, the current evidence suggests that regular dosing with oral cholecalciferol (e.g., 60,000 IU weekly) may have slight advantages over other regimens when replenishing vitamin D stores following deficiency. For long-term supplementation, smaller regular doses, such as cholecalciferol 1,000 IU daily, or 10,000 IU weekly, are suitable. Giving reliable and specific advice about appropriate sunlight exposure remains difficult because of differing interindividual skin pigmentation and variable sunlight UVB content at different latitudes, at different times of year, and in different terrestrial environments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 far better than D2 at raising infant vitamin D blood levels</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-far-better-than-d2-at-raising-infant-vitamin-d-blood-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-far-better-than-d2-at-raising-infant-vitamin-d-blood-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-change-in-plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-did-not-differ-between-breast-fed-infants-that-received-a-daily-supplement-of-ergocalciferol-or-cholecalciferol-for-3-months">The Change in Plasma 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Did Not Differ between Breast-Fed Infants That Received a Daily Supplement of Ergocalciferol or Cholecalciferol for 3 Months.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Nutr. 2012 Dec 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gallo S, Phan A, Vanstone CA, Rodd C, Weiler HA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition, McGill University, Montréal, Québec, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The biological equivalency of ergocalciferol (D2) and cholecalciferol (D3) has been debated; several comparisons have appeared in the adult literature but are scarce in pediatrics. The objective of this study was to compare increases in plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations and attainment of 50 and 75 mol/L status cutoffs following 3 mo of daily supplementation with D2 compared with D3. Healthy, breast-fed, 1-mo-old infants (n = 52) received 10 μg (400 iu) of either D2 or D3 daily. At 1 and 4 mo of age, plasma 25-hydroxyergocalciferol and 25-hydroxycholecalciferol concentrations were determined by liquid chromatography tandem MS (LC-MS/MS) and total 25(OH)D by chemiluminescent immunoassay (DiaSorin Liaison). Data were analyzed using t tests and χ(2) by intent to treat. A total of 23% of infants were deficient (≤24.9 nmol/L) at baseline and 2% at follow-up on the basis of LC-MS/MS. At 4 mo, 96% were breastfed and there were no differences in compliance, breastfeeding rates, or sun exposure among groups. The change in total 25(OH)D measured by LC-MS/MS did not differ between the D2 (17.6 ± 26.7 nmol/L) and D3 (22.2 ± 20.2 nmol/L) groups. In the combined groups, the baseline plasma 25(OH)D concentration was inversely related to the change in total 25(OH)D (r = -0.52; P &amp;lt; 0.001).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3, not D2 helps childhood bone development</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-not-d2-helps-childhood-bone-development.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-not-d2-helps-childhood-bone-development.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-levels-are-positively-related-to-subsequent-cortical-bone-development-in-childhood">25-Hydroxyvitamin-D3 levels are positively related to subsequent cortical bone development in childhood:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="findings-from-a-large-prospective-cohort-study">findings from a large prospective cohort study.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Aug;23(8):2117-28. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-011-1813-9.">doi: 10.1007/s00198-011-1813-9.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Nov 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sayers A, Fraser WD, Lawlor DA, Tobias JH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Musculoskeletal Research Unit, School of Clinical Sciences, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:adrian.sayers@bristol.ac.uk">adrian.sayers@bristol.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In exploring relationships between vitamin D status in childhood and cortical bone, little relationship was observed with plasma concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin-D(2) &lt;span>[25(OH)D(2)]&lt;/span>, whereas 25-hydroxyvitamin-D(3) &lt;span>[25(OH)D(3)]&lt;/span> was positively related to cortical bone mineral content (BMC(C)) and cortical thickness, suggesting D(3) exerts a beneficial effect on cortical bone development in contrast to D(2).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>7100 IU vitamin D2 for 3 months did not treat Coronary Artery Disease</title><link>/posts/7100-iu-vitamin-d2-for-3-months-did-not-treat-coronary-artery-disease.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7100-iu-vitamin-d2-for-3-months-did-not-treat-coronary-artery-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-effects-of-vitamin-d-repletion-on-endothelial-function-and-inflammation-in-patients-with-coronary-artery-disease">The effects of vitamin D repletion on endothelial function and inflammation in patients with coronary artery disease&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vasc Med December 2012 vol. 17 no. 6 394-404&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seth I Sokol1,2,3; Vankeepuram Srinivas1,2; Jill P Crandall4; Mimi Kim5; George Tellides6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amir Lebastchi6; Yiting Yu5; Alok K Gupta7; Michael H Alderman2,5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Medicine, Division of Cardiology, Jacobi Medical Center, Bronx, NY, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Medicine, Albert Einstein College of Medicine, Bronx, NY, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 again decreased vitamin D3 levels – RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-again-decreased-vitamin-d3-levels-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-again-decreased-vitamin-d3-levels-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="long-term-vitamin-d3-supplementation-is-more-effective-than-vitamin-d2-in-maintaining-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-over-the-winter-months">Long-term vitamin D3 supplementation is more effective than vitamin D2 in maintaining serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status over the winter months.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2012 Jul 11:1-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Logan VF, Gray AR, Peddie MC, Harper MJ, Houghton LA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Human Nutrition, University of Otago, PO Box 56, Dunedin 9054, New Zealand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Public health recommendations do not distinguish between vitamin D2 and vitamin D3, yet disagreement exists on whether these two forms should be considered equivalent. The objective of the present study was to evaluate the effect of a daily physiological dose of vitamin D2 or vitamin D3 on 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) status over the winter months in healthy adults living in Dunedin, New Zealand (latitude 46°S).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s patients not on medication have very low levels of Vitamin D2</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-patients-not-on-medication-have-very-low-levels-of-vitamin-d2.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-patients-not-on-medication-have-very-low-levels-of-vitamin-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-25oh-vitamin-d2-levels-found-in-untreated-alzheimers-patients-compared-to-acetylcholinesterase-inhibitor-treated-and-controls">Low 25OH Vitamin D2 Levels Found in Untreated Alzheimer’s Patients Compared to Acetylcholinesterase Inhibitor Treated and Controls,&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Published in &lt;a href="http://www.hindawi.com/journals/ijad/%20">International Journal Current Alzheimer Research&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As of Nov 10, the abstract and paper is not on that website&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2012/11/121108131452.htm">Vitamin D Could Hold Vital Key to Arresting Development of Alzheimer’s Disease&lt;/a> Science Daily&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 far better than D2 for hemodialysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-far-better-than-d2-for-hemodialysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-far-better-than-d2-for-hemodialysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d2-versus-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-hemodialysis-patients">Vitamin D2 versus vitamin D3 supplementation in hemodialysis patients:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>a comparative pilot study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daroux M, Shenouda M, Bacri JL, Lemaitre V, Vanhille P, Bataille P&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nephrology, Doctor Duchenne Hospital, Boulogne-sur-Mer - France; and Department of Nephrology, Regional University Hospital of Lille, Lille - France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Nephrology &lt;span>[2012:0]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: In patients with chronic kidney disease, vitamin D insufficiency is highly prevalent. It can be corrected by supplementation with either vitamin D2 or vitamin D3. Recent studies in patients without impaired kidney function suggest that vitamin D3 is more efficient than vitamin D2 in correcting vitamin D insufficiency. However, no direct comparison has been made in hemodialysis (HD) patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency somewhat treated with weekly 50000 IU Vitamin D2</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-somewhat-treated-with-weekly-50000-iu-vitamin-d2.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-somewhat-treated-with-weekly-50000-iu-vitamin-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-within-a-large-integrated-health-care-delivery-system">Treatment of vitamin d deficiency within a large integrated health care delivery system.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Manag Care Pharm. 2012 Sep;18(7):497-505.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stratton-Loeffler MJ, Lo JC, Hui RL, Coates A, Minkoff JR, Budayr A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kaiser Permanente Division of Research, 2000 Broadway, Oakland, CA, 94612. USA. &lt;a href="mailto:Joan.C.Lo@kp.org">Joan.C.Lo@kp.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: In the past decade, increasing attention has focused on identification and treatment of vitamin D deficiency although repletion ?outcomes of pharmacologic vitamin D therapy have not been examined at ?a population level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FDA raises the amount of vitamin D2 fortification in bread</title><link>/posts/fda-raises-the-amount-of-vitamin-d2-fortification-in-bread.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fda-raises-the-amount-of-vitamin-d2-fortification-in-bread.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="update---it-does-not-get-into-bloodstream">Update - it does NOT get into bloodstream&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d2-from-bread-yeast-is-4-times-less-bioaccessible-than-d2-in-milk">Vitamin D2 from bread yeast is 4 times less bioaccessible than D2 in milk – April 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="clipped-from-bakingbusinesscomhttpwwwbakingbusinesscomarticlesnews_homeregulatory201208petition_to_raise_vitamin_d_inaspxid7bda0c8d0c-93ab-4576-aa30-634106c11dac7dcck120">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.bakingbusiness.com/articles/news_home/Regulatory/2012/08/Petition_to_raise_vitamin_D_in.aspx?ID=%7BDA0C8D0C-93AB-4576-AA30-634106C11DAC%7D&amp;amp;cck=1%20">BakingBusiness.com&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Under the ruling, bakers may use the yeast at levels not to exceed 400 international units (I.U.) of vitamin D per 100 grams in the finished foods, up from 90 I.U. previously.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fda-also-recognized-as-gras-food-maximum-levels100-gram">FDA also recognized as GRAS Food Maximum levels/100 gram&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Breakfast cereal 350 I.U.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 half-life about 13 days</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-half-life-about-13-days.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-half-life-about-13-days.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="plasma-appearance-and-disappearance-of-an-oral-dose-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d2-in-healthy-adults">Plasma appearance and disappearance of an oral dose of 25-hydroxyvitamin D2 in healthy adults.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2012 Apr;107(8):1128-37. Epub 2011 Sep 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jones KS, Schoenmakers I, Bluck LJ, Ding S, Prentice A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MRC Keneba, MRC Unit, PO Box 273, Banjul, The Gambia. &lt;a href="mailto:kjones@mrc.gm">kjones@mrc.gm&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>25-Hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) half-life is a potential biomarker for investigating vitamin D metabolism and requirements. We performed a pilot study to assess the approach and practical feasibility of measuring 25(OH)D half-life after an oral dose. A total of twelve healthy Gambian men aged 18-23 years were divided into two groups to investigate the rate and timing of (1) absorption and (2) plasma disappearance after an 80 nmol oral dose of 25(OH)D2.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 associated with fewer psychotic episodes, D2 with more</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-associated-with-fewer-psychotic-episodes-d2-with-more.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-associated-with-fewer-psychotic-episodes-d2-with-more.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-and-d2-and-non-clinical-psychotic-experiences-in-childhood">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D3 and D2 and Non-Clinical Psychotic Experiences in Childhood&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Anna-Maija Tolppanen 1, Adrian Sayers 2, William D. Fraser 3, Glyn Lewis 2, Stanley Zammit 2,4, John McGrath 5, Debbie A. Lawlor 1 &lt;a href="mailto:D.A.Lawlor@bristol.ac.uk">D.A.Lawlor@bristol.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 MRC Centre for Causal Analyses in Translational Epidemiology, School of Social and Community Medicine, University of Bristol, Bristol, United Kingdom,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Social and Community Medicine, University of Bristol, Bristol, United Kingdom,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Norwich Medical School, University of East Anglia, Norwich, United Kingdom,&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>