<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microbiome on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/microbiome.html</link><description>Recent content in Microbiome on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/microbiome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Antibiotics, even short-term, cause long-term microbiome and metabolic changes in mice</title><link>/posts/antibiotics-even-short-term-cause-long-term-microbiome-and-metabolic-changes-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/antibiotics-even-short-term-cause-long-term-microbiome-and-metabolic-changes-in-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="metabolic-and-metagenomic-outcomes-from-early-life-pulsed-antibiotic-treatment">Metabolic and metagenomic outcomes from early-life pulsed antibiotic treatment&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Yael R. Nobel1,&lt;em>, Laura M. Cox1,2,&lt;/em>, Francis F. Kirigin1, Nicholas A. Bokulich1, , Shingo Yamanishi1, Isabel Teitler1, Jennifer Chung1, Jiho Sohn1, Cecily M. Barber1, David S. Goldfarb1,3, Kartik Raju1, Sahar Abubucker4,Yanjiao Zhou4,5,9, Victoria E. Ruiz1, Huilin Li6, Makedonka Mitreva4,7, Alexander V. Alekseyenko1,8,George M. Weinstock4,9, Erica Sodergren4,9 &amp;amp; Martin J. Blaser1,2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mammalian species have co-evolved with intestinal microbial communities that can shape development and adapt to environmental changes, including antibiotic perturbation or nutrient flux. In humans, especially children, microbiota disruption is common, yet the dynamic microbiome recovery from early-life antibiotics is still uncharacterized. Here we use a mouse model mimicking paediatric antibiotic use and find that therapeutic-dose &lt;strong>pulsed antibiotic treatment (PAT)&lt;/strong> with a beta-lactam or macrolide alters both host and microbiota development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gut microbiome massively changed by weekly vitamin D</title><link>/posts/gut-microbiome-massively-changed-by-weekly-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gut-microbiome-massively-changed-by-weekly-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effects-of-high-doses-of-vitamin-d3-on-mucosa-associated-gut-microbiome-vary-between-regions-of-the-human-gastrointestinal-tract">Effects of high doses of vitamin D3 on mucosa-associated gut microbiome vary between regions of the human gastrointestinal tract.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#changes-in-small-intestine-where-vitamin-d-is-taken-into-the-body">Changes in small intestine (where vitamin D is taken into the body)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#214-studies-citied-this-study-as-of-jan-2023">214 studies citied this study as of Jan 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dr-partick-commented-july-2016-on-this-study">Dr Partick commented July 2016 on this study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="effects-of-high-doses-of-vitamin-d3-on-mucosa-associated-gut-microbiome-vary-between-regions-of-the-human-gastrointestinal-tract">Effects of high doses of vitamin D3 on mucosa-associated gut microbiome vary between regions of the human gastrointestinal tract.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Nutr. 2015 Jul 1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exploring gut microbes in Human health and disease: pushing the envelope</title><link>/posts/exploring-gut-microbes-in-human-health-and-disease-pushing-the-envelope.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/exploring-gut-microbes-in-human-health-and-disease-pushing-the-envelope.html</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/gut-microbiota.jpg" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/exploring-gut-microbes.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki.&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, immunity and microbiome</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-immunity-and-microbiome.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-immunity-and-microbiome.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D and immunity&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Special section of interest: &lt;span style="color:#F00;">Why doesn’t vitamin D supplementation decrease disease risks?&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>F1000Prime Rep2014, 6:118 (&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.12703/P6-118">doi: 10.12703/P6-118)&lt;/a>),&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 01 Dec 2014 © 2014 Faculty of 1000 Ltd&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robyn M. Lucas1,2 &lt;a href="mailto:robyn.lucas@telethonkids.org.au">robyn.lucas@telethonkids.org.au&lt;/a>, Shelley Gorman1, Sian Geldenhuys1 and Prue H. Hart1&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Telethon Kids Institute, University of Western Australia, 100 Roberts Road, Subiaco, Perth, Australia 6008&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>National Centre for Epidemiology and Population Health, The Australian National University, Canberra, Australia 0200&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/immunity-microbiome.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#abstract">Abstract&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clues-from-epidemiology">Clues from epidemiology&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mechanisms-by-which-l25oh2d-may-regulate-immune-cell-function">Mechanisms by which l,25(OH)2D may regulate immune cell function&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#multiple-sclerosis-a-case-study">Multiple sclerosis: a case study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#an-indirect-pathway-vitamin-d-immunity-and-the-microbiome">An indirect pathway: vitamin D, immunity and the microbiome&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#span-stylecolorf00why-doesnt-vitamin-d-supplementation-decrease-disease-risksspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Why doesn’t vitamin D supplementation decrease disease risks?&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references-in-pdf">References in PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been linked to an increased risk of a wide range of adverse health outcomes. The active form of vitamin D has an important role in calcium metabolism and in bone mineralisation, but the evidence for other health outcomes is mixed, with the strongest effects seen in the weakest epidemiological study designs. There are plausible pathways whereby vitamin D deficiency can impair immune function, resulting in both overactivity and increased risk of autoimmune disease, as well as immune suppression with poorer resistance to infection. Vitamin D status may influence the bacterial flora that constitute the microbiome and affect immune function through this route. Exposure of the skin to ultraviolet radiation causes the production of a range of chemicals, including vitamin D, and new research is exploring possible vitamin D-independent immunomodulatory pathways.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Biota and Vitamin D - thoughts</title><link>/posts/biota-and-vitamin-d-thoughts.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/biota-and-vitamin-d-thoughts.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Possible interactions between biota (gut bacteria, etc), antibiotics, probiotics, prebiotics and vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Knowns:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There are some 10,000 biota in the human gut&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Antibiotics kills off gut biota. - sometimes being a species genocide (totally losing some contingency genes)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Current probiotics will restock, at least for a few weeks 1-10 species.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Antibiotics early in life (while still developing) can have profound effects on the individual&amp;rsquo;s development, even if the species is later restocked.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gut Microbiota: The Neglected Endocrine Organ (vitamin D not mentioned)</title><link>/posts/gut-microbiota-the-neglected-endocrine-organ-vitamin-d-not-mentioned.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gut-microbiota-the-neglected-endocrine-organ-vitamin-d-not-mentioned.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Molecular Endocrinology, DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1210/me.2014-1108">http://dx.doi.org/10.1210/me.2014-1108&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gerard Clarke 1,2, Roman M. Stilling 1 , Paul J Kennedy 1, Catherine Stanton 1,2,3, John F. Cryan 1,4, and Timothy G. Dinan 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Alimentary Pharmabiotic Centre, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Psychiatry, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Teagasc, Moorepark, Fermoy, Cork, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4Anatomy and Neuroscience, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The concept that the gut microbiota serves as a virtual endocrine organ arises from a number of important observations. Evidence for a direct role arises from its metabolic capacity to produce and regulate multiple compounds that reach the circulation and act to influence the function of distal organs and systems. For example, metabolism of carbohydrates results in the production of short chain fatty acids (SCFAs), such as butyrate and propionate, which provide an important source of nutrients as well as regulatory control of the host digestive system. This influence over host metabolism is also seen in the ability of the prebiotic inulin is to influence production of relevant hormones such as glucagon like peptide-1 (GLP-1), peptide YY (PYY), ghrelin and leptin. Moreover, the probiotic L. rhamnosus PL60, which produces conjugated linoleic acid, has been shown to reduce body weight gain and white adipose tissue without effects on food intake. Manipulating the microbial composition of the gastrointestinal tract modulates plasma concentrations of tryptophan, an essential amino acid and precursor to serotonin, a key neurotransmitter within both the enteric and central nervous systems. Indirectly and through as yet unknown mechanisms, the gut microbiota exerts control over the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis (HPA). This is clear from studies on animals raised in a germ-free environment, who show exaggerated responses to psychological stress, which normalises following monocolonisation by certain bacterial species including B. infantis. It is tempting to speculate that therapeutic targeting of the gut microbiota may be useful in treating stress-related disorders and metabolic diseases.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>