<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microbiome on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/microbiome/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microbiome on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/microbiome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autism risky if low vitamin D during pregnancy and early life (mice, fecal transplant reversed it)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-risky-if-low-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-early-life-mice-fecal-transplant-reversed-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-risky-if-low-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-early-life-mice-fecal-transplant-reversed-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;induction-of-autism-related-behavior-in-male-mice-by-early-life-vitamin-d-deficiency-association-with-disruption-of-the-gut-microbial-composition-and-homeostasis&#34;&gt;Induction of autism-related behavior in male mice by early-life vitamin D deficiency: association with disruption of the gut microbial composition and homeostasis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Food Funct . 2024 Mar 27. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1039/d4fo00279b&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1039/d4fo00279b&lt;/a&gt; PDF behind paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jingjing Cui 1 2 3, Shumin Wang 3 4, Zidan Zhai 1 2, Xiaoyue Song 5, Ting Qiu 2, Leilei Yu 3 4, Qixiao Zhai 3 4, Heng Zhang 2 5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D deficiency (VDD) during early life emerges as a potential risk factor for autism spectrum disorder (ASD). Individuals with autism commonly exhibit lower vitamin D (VD) levels compared to the general population, and VD deficiency is prevalent during pregnancy and lactation. Moreover, gastrointestinal comorbidity, prevalent in ASD patients, correlates closely with disruptions in the gut microbiota and altered intestinal permeability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fecal transplants - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fecal-transplants-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fecal-transplants-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;faecal-transplants-are-just-the-start-for-microbiome-medicine---economist-nov-2023&#34;&gt;Faecal transplants are just the start for microbiome medicine  - Economist Nov 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://click.e.economist.com/?qs=e8b52f579392a0265fa9d1975fe99347d885e5027412d904498e6571a2868f79e5d2ddb4849294576fc81d9a2b3e12e0026ed24d84865dcf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://image.e.economist.com/lib/fe8d13727c650c7976/m/4/cbe11a01-a91c-40bd-bcfb-79d237b9e4d0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;|%%% &lt;strong&gt;Gilead Amit&lt;/strong&gt;  %%% Science correspondent&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sitting in a small windowless lab watching Désirée Prossomariti strain solids through a sieve, I am reminded, despite myself, of jam-making. “I’ve never looked at it that way,” she says. “But yes, I’ve seen my mother making jam.”  %%%  %%% Dr Prossomariti is making something much more important, if much less palatable. She manufactures a medical therapeutic known as a faecal microbiota transplant (FMT)—oral capsules derived from freeze-dried human stool that are extraordinarily effective at relieving some nasty bacterial infections. %%%  %%% The logic is surprisingly sound. The gut microbiome is a complex entity, containing many hundreds of species and a total number of cells that rivals those of the host’s body. When this ecosystem is damaged, the consequences can be felt all over the body. Diabetes, obesity, Parkinson’s disease, Alzheimer’s disease and atopic dermatitis have all been linked to the (mis)activity of the gut microbiome. Some have called the microbiome an organ in its own right. And where there is an organ, there is hope of transplantation. %%% Not long ago, FMT was regarded as fringe. “People would talk about it in conferences, and people would laugh and giggle,” says Simon Goldenberg, who manages the laboratory at Guy’s and St Thomas’ Hospital in London, where Dr Prossomariti works. Then, in 2013, a Dutch clinical trial of FMTs showed such positive results that it was ended early—a supervisory board deeming it unethical to withhold the treatment from the placebo group. That was a turning-point. %%% Many patients now benefit from FMT, and their number is set to rise as more positive results filter in from clinical trials. All the same, as &lt;a href=&#34;https://click.e.economist.com/?qs=e8b52f579392a026020b3e472b3f3c017ba6b29563d2f9dfe0610ae96f1a7576e5c64c547eb4f3032eeffea433dd6a01e6da8a0a1bc9f5b7&#34;&gt;we report this week&lt;/a&gt;, its time in the Sun is likely to be short-lived. Crucially, stool is impossible to standardise, and its contents challenging to determine. Its long-term safety profile is also largely unknown. This makes FMT hard to regulate consistently.%%%At present&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nutrients, Microbiome, and Chronic Diseases</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nutrients-microbiome-and-chronic-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nutrients-microbiome-and-chronic-diseases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-microbiome-as-a-major-function-of-the-gastrointestinal-tract-and-its-implication-in-micronutrient-metabolism-and-chronic-diseases&#34;&gt;The microbiome as a major function of the gastrointestinal tract and its implication in micronutrient metabolism and chronic diseases&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutr Res . 2023 Mar 4;112:30-45. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nutres.2023.02.007&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2023.02.007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dingbo Lin 1, Denis M Medeiros 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;pdf-table-of-contents&#34;&gt;PDF Table of Contents&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Small intestine in nutrient digestion and absorption&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 Large intestine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4 Overview of the intestinal microbiome&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5 Vitamin C and other redox-active food compounds on the gut microbiome&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6 Gut microbiome-derived folate does not meet human needs&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic Syndrome prevented by Vitamin D, Phytochemicals and improved gut bacteria</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/metabolic-syndrome-prevented-by-vitamin-d-phytochemicals-and-improved-gut-bacteria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/metabolic-syndrome-prevented-by-vitamin-d-phytochemicals-and-improved-gut-bacteria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;prevention-of-metabolic-syndrome-by-phytochemicals-and-vitamin-d&#34;&gt;Prevention of Metabolic Syndrome by Phytochemicals and Vitamin D&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Review Int J Mol Sci . 2023 Jan 30;24(3):2627. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms24032627.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/ijms24032627.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kazuki Santa 1, Yoshio Kumazawa 2 3, Isao Nagaoka 3 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, attention has focused on the roles of phytochemicals in fruits and vegetables in maintaining and improving the intestinal environment and preventing metabolic syndrome. A high-fat and high-sugar diet, lack of exercise, and excess energy accumulation in the body can cause metabolic syndrome and induce obesity, diabetes, and disorders of the circulatory system and liver. Therefore, the prevention of metabolic syndrome is important. The current review shows that the simultaneous intake of phytochemicals contained in citruses and grapes together with vitamin D improves the state of gut microbiota and immunity, preventing metabolic syndrome and related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ways to improve the gut microbiome to reduce Alzheimer&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ways-to-improve-the-gut-microbiome-to-reduce-alzheimers-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ways-to-improve-the-gut-microbiome-to-reduce-alzheimers-disease/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-gut-microbiome-in-alzheimers-disease-what-we-know-and-what-remains-to-be-explored&#34;&gt;The gut microbiome in Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease: what we know and what remains to be explored&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Molecular Neurodegeneration  (2023) 18:9 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s13024-023-00595-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1186/s13024-023-00595-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sidhanth Chandra1,2, Sangram S. Sisodia and Robert J. Vassar &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:r-vassar@northwestern.edu&#34;&gt;r-vassar@northwestern.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Department of Neurobiology, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL 60637, USA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;pdf-table-of-contents&#34;&gt;PDF Table of Contents&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;700&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD), the most common cause of dementia, results in a sustained decline in cognition. There are currently few effective disease modifying therapies for AD, but insights into the mechanisms that mediate the onset and progression of disease may lead to new, effective therapeutic strategies. Amyloid beta oligomers and plaques, tau aggregates, and neuroinflammation play a critical role in neurodegeneration and impact clinical AD progression. The upstream modulators of these pathological features have not been fully clarified, but recent evidence indicates that the gut microbiome (GMB) may have an influence on these features and therefore may influence AD progression in human patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parkinson&#39;s Disease and gut microbiome - several studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/parkinsons-disease-and-gut-microbiome-several-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/parkinsons-disease-and-gut-microbiome-several-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strong association, unknown cause-affect direction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: Vitamin D massively changes the composiition of gut bacteria&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-levels-change-gut-microbiota-25-study-review&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Vitamin D levels change Gut Microbiota – 25 study review Sept 2021&#34;&gt;Vitamin D levels change Gut Microbiota – 25 study review Sept 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/gut-microbiome-massively-changed-by-weekly-vitamin-d&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Gut microbiome massively changed by weekly vitamin D – July 2015&#34;&gt;Gut microbiome massively changed by weekly vitamin D – July 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
