<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cancer - Pancreatic on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/cancer---pancreatic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cancer - Pancreatic on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/cancer---pancreatic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pancreatic Cancer survival 2.3 X more likely if good level of Vitamin D – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pancreatic-cancer-survival-23-x-more-likely-if-good-level-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pancreatic-cancer-survival-23-x-more-likely-if-good-level-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-are-2-meta-analyses-on-this-page&#34;&gt;There are 2 meta-analyses on this page&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-is-positively-associated-with-overall-survival-in-advanced-pancreatic-cancer-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis---2023&#34;&gt;25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration is positively associated with overall survival in advanced pancreatic cancer: A systematic review and meta-analysis - 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrition Research Vol 117, Sept 2023, Pages 73-82 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nutres.2023.07.001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nutres.2023.07.001&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jing Li a #, Haiyan Zhang a #, Hongda Zhu b, Zhu Dai a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Studies have shown that 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) is predictive of survival following a diagnosis of cancer. However, evidence of the relationship between 25(OH)D and the survival of patients with pancreatic cancer has been inconsistent. We hypothesized that circulating 25(OH)D concentrations may be positively correlated with better prognosis in advanced pancreatic cancer. PubMed, EMBASE, Cochrane Library, and Web of Science database entries through April 2023, along with the reference lists of related studies, were searched. Additionally, we extracted observational studies reporting the association between 25(OH)D concentrations and the outcome of interest (overall survival &lt;span&gt;[OS]&lt;/span&gt;) in advanced pancreatic cancer patients aged 18 years or older. Ultimately, 7 articles involving 2369 patients were included in this systematic review and meta-analysis. The results indicated that 25(OH)D concentrations were positively correlated with  &lt;strong&gt;OS (hazard ratio = 2.37&lt;/strong&gt; ; 95% confidence interval, 2.22–2.54; P &amp;lt; .001). No association was found between 25(OH)D and progression-free survival. There was significant heterogeneity between studies in terms of OS (I2 = 85.5%, P &amp;lt; .001). Our subgroup analysis revealed that this high heterogeneity may be attributed to the studies’ different regions, designs, sample sources, and detection methods of 25(OH)D. Additionally, Begg&amp;rsquo;s and Egger&amp;rsquo;s tests indicated the presence of publication bias. To our knowledge, this is the first meta-analysis to evaluate the association between 25(OH)D concentrations and OS among patients with pancreatic cancer. Our results suggested that circulating 25(OH)D concentrations were positively correlated with OS, indicating that 25(OH)D may be a potential prognostic marker in advanced pancreatic cancer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
