<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Calcitriol on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/calcitriol.html</link><description>Recent content in Calcitriol on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/calcitriol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Genes which regulate active vitamin D worsen with age</title><link>/posts/genes-which-regulate-active-vitamin-d-worsen-with-age.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-which-regulate-active-vitamin-d-worsen-with-age.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D for kidney disease – use native or active form</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-for-kidney-disease-use-native-or-active-form.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-for-kidney-disease-use-native-or-active-form.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kidney failure – still debating what form of vitamin D to use</title><link>/posts/kidney-failure-still-debating-what-form-of-vitamin-d-to-use.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-failure-still-debating-what-form-of-vitamin-d-to-use.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pro-should-we-correct-vitamin-d-deficiencyinsufficiency-in-chronic-kidney-disease-patients-with-inactive-forms-of-vitamin-d-or-just-treat-them-with-active-vitamin-d-forms">Pro: Should we correct vitamin D deficiency/insufficiency in chronic kidney disease patients with inactive forms of vitamin D or just treat them with active vitamin D forms?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation Volume 31, Issue 5Pp. 698-705.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David J.A. Goldsmith, &lt;a href="mailto:david.goldsmith@gstt.nhs.uk">david.goldsmith@gstt.nhs.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Guy&amp;rsquo;s and St Thomas’ Hospitals, London, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evidence for the usefulness of using vitamin D to treat ‘renal bone disease’ is now nearly six decades old. In regular clinical practice, however, it is more like three decades, at most, that we have routinely been using vitamin D to try to prevent, or reverse, the impact of hyperparathyroidism on the skeleton of patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD). The practice has been in the main to use high doses of synthetic vitamin D compounds, not naturally occurring ones. However, the pharmacological impacts of the different vitamin D species and of their different modes, and styles of administration cannot be assumed to be uniform across the spectrum. It is disappointingly true to say that even in 2016 there is a remarkable paucity of evidence concerning the clinical benefits of vitamin D supplementation to treat vitamin D insufficiency in patients with stage 3b–5 CKD. This is even more so if we consider the non-dialysis population. While there are a number of studies that report the impact of vitamin D supplementation on serum vitamin D concentrations (unsurprisingly, usually reporting an increase), and some variable evidence of parathyroid hormone concentration suppression, there has been much less focus on hard or semi-rigid clinical end point analysis (e.g. fractures, hospitalizations and overall mortality). Now, in 2016, with the practice pattern changes of first widespread clinical use of vitamin D and second widespread supplementation of cholecalciferol or ergocalciferol by patients (alone, or as multivitamins), it is now, in my view, next to impossible to run a placebo-controlled trial over a decent period of time, especially one which involved clinically meaningful (fractures, hospitalisation, parathyroidectomy, death) end-points. In this challenging situation, we need to ask what it is we are trying to achieve here, and how best to balance potential benefits with potential harm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnesium reduced calcitriol (active vitamin D) artery calcification in CKD by 50 percent</title><link>/posts/magnesium-reduced-calcitriol-active-vitamin-d-artery-calcification-in-ckd-by-50-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/magnesium-reduced-calcitriol-active-vitamin-d-artery-calcification-in-ckd-by-50-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="magnesium-modifies-the-impact-of-calcitriol-treatment-on-vascular-calcification-in-experimental-chronic-kidney-disease">Magnesium Modifies the impact of Calcitriol Treatment on Vascular Calcification in Experimental Chronic Kidney Disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2015 Oct 20. pii: jpet.115.228106. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zelt JG1, McCabe KM1, Svajger B1, Barron H1, Laverty K1, Holden RM1, Adams MA2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Queen&amp;rsquo;s University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Queen&amp;rsquo;s University &lt;a href="mailto:adams@queensu.ca">adams@queensu.ca&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) patients are commonly treated with vitamin D analogs, such as calcitriol. Recent epidemiological evidence revealed a significant interaction between vitamin D and magnesium, since an inverse relationship between vitamin D levels and mortality mainly occurs in patients with a high magnesium intake. The aim of the study was to assess the mechanisms involved by determining whether magnesium alone or combined with calcitriol treatments differentially impact vascular calcification (VC) in male Sprague-Dawley rats with adenine-induced CKD. Treatment with moderate doses of calcitriol (80ug/kg) suppressed PTH to near or slightly below control levels. Given alone, this dose of calcitriol increased the prevalence of VC; but when magnesium was given in combination, the severity of calcification was attenuated in the abdominal aorta (51% reduction), iliac (44%) and carotid arteries (46%) compared to CKD controls. The decreases in vascular calcium content were associated with 20-50% increase in vascular Mg. Calcitriol treatment alone significantly decreased TRPM7 protein (↓ to ~11%) whereas the combination treatment increased both the mRNA (1.7X) and protein (6.8X) expression compared to calcitriol alone. In summary, calcitriol increased VC in certain conditions; but magnesium prevented the reduction in TRPM7 and reduced the severity of VC, thereby increasing the bioavailable magnesium in the vascular microenvironment. These findings suggest that modifying the adverse effect profile of calcitriol with Mg may be a plausible approach to benefiting the increasing number of CKD patients being prescribed calcitriol.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer inhibited by Vitamin D and Calcitriol – mouse studies provide insight</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-inhibited-by-vitamin-d-and-calcitriol-mouse-studies-provide-insight.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-inhibited-by-vitamin-d-and-calcitriol-mouse-studies-provide-insight.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="inhibition-of-mouse-breast-tumor-initiating-cells-by-calcitriol-and-dietary-vitamin-d">Inhibition of Mouse Breast Tumor-Initiating Cells by Calcitriol and Dietary Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mol Cancer Ther August 2015 14; 1951&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Youngtae Jeong 1,2, Srilatha Swami 3, Aruna V. Krishnan 3, Jasmaine D. Williams 4,5, Shanique Martin 1,2, Ronald L. Horst 6, Megan A. Albertelli 7, Brian J. Feldman 1,2,4,5, David Feldman 1,3, &lt;a href="mailto:dfeldman@stanford.edu">dfeldman@stanford.edu&lt;/a> , and Maximilian Diehn 1,2,8, &lt;a href="mailto:diehn@stanford.edu">diehn@stanford.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Stanford Cancer Institute, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Institute for Stem Cell Biology and Regenerative Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer treated better when active vitamin d (calcitriol) is inside of PLGA nanoparticles</title><link>/posts/cancer-treated-better-when-active-vitamin-d-calcitriol-is-inside-of-plga-nanoparticles.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-treated-better-when-active-vitamin-d-calcitriol-is-inside-of-plga-nanoparticles.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="plga-nanoparticles-as-a-platform-for-vitamin-d-based-cancer-therapy">PLGA nanoparticles as a platform for vitamin D-based cancer therapy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Beilstein J. Nanotechnol. 2015, 6, 1306–1318. doi:10.3762/bjnano.6.135&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maria J. Ramalho, Joana A. Loureiro, Bárbara Gomes, Manuela F. Frasco, Manuel A. N. Coelho and M. Carmo Pereira &lt;a href="mailto:mcsp@fe.up.pt">mcsp@fe.up.pt&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LEPABE, Department of Chemical Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, University of Porto, Rua Dr. Roberto Frias, 4200-465 Porto, Portugal&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/plga-f2.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/plga-f4.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/plga-f5c.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;p>Poly(lactic-co-glycolic acid) (PLGA) nanoparticles were studied as drug delivery vehicles for calcitriol, the active form of vitamin D3. In vitro effects of calcitriol encapsulated in PLGA nanoparticles were evaluated with respect to free calcitriol on human pancreatic cell lines, S2-013 and hTERT-HPNE, and the lung cancer cell line A549. Encapsulated calcitriol retained its biological activity, reducing the cell growth. Cytotoxicity assays demonstrated that encapsulation of calcitriol enhanced its inhibitory effect on cell growth at a concentration of 2.4 μM for the S2-013 cells (91%) and for A549 cells (70%) comparared to the free calcitriol results. At this concentration the inhibitory effect on nontumor cells (hTERT-HPNE) decreased to 65%. This study highlights the ability of PLGA nanoparticles to deliver vitamin D3 into cancer cells, with major effects regarding cancer cell cycle arrest and major changes in the cell morphological features.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How active vitamin D (Calcitriol) deals with cancer</title><link>/posts/how-active-vitamin-d-calcitriol-deals-with-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-active-vitamin-d-calcitriol-deals-with-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mechanistic-effects-of-calcitriol-in-cancer-biology">Mechanistic Effects of Calcitriol in Cancer Biology.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients. 2015 Jun 19;7(6):5020-5050.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Díaz L1, Díaz-Muñoz M2, García-Gaytán AC3, Méndez I4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Departamento de Biología de la Reproducción, Instituto Nacional de Ciencias Médicas y Nutrición Salvador Zubirán, Vasco de Quiroga No. 15, Tlalpan, Mexico City 14000, Mexico. &lt;a href="mailto:lorenzadiaz@gmail.com">lorenzadiaz@gmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Departamento de Neurobiología Celular y Molecular, Instituto de Neurobiología, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM), Campus UNAM-Juriquilla, Blvd. Juriquilla 3001, Querétaro 76230, Mexico. &lt;a href="mailto:mdiaz@comunidad.unam.mx">mdiaz@comunidad.unam.mx&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Departamento de Neurobiología Celular y Molecular, Instituto de Neurobiología, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM), Campus UNAM-Juriquilla, Blvd. Juriquilla 3001, Querétaro 76230, Mexico. &lt;a href="mailto:acgarciag02@gmail.com">acgarciag02@gmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active Vitamin D (Calcitriol) reference ranges, why too high is a problem</title><link>/posts/active-vitamin-d-calcitriol-reference-ranges-why-too-high-is-a-problem.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-vitamin-d-calcitriol-reference-ranges-why-too-high-is-a-problem.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Two items by Mangin on the page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="125oh2d-calcitriol-reference-ranges">1,25(OH)2D (Calcitriol) Reference Ranges&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Apr 8, 2015	Linked-in Meg Mangin, RN&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Measurement of serum 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[1,25(OH)2D]&lt;/span> is done by radioimmunoassay (RIA). 1,25(OH)2D lab reference ranges are determined by statistical analysis of the people who have had 1,25(OH)2D measured. The &amp;ldquo;normal” range is where 95% of the people measured fall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, the current standard advises measurement of 1,25(OH)2D only in patients with, or suspected of, serious medical conditions such as&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Not as much active vitamin D if poor kidney function and low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/not-as-much-active-vitamin-d-if-poor-kidney-function-and-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/not-as-much-active-vitamin-d-if-poor-kidney-function-and-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Active vitamin D associated with Metabolic Syndrome and LDL in colon cancer patients</title><link>/posts/active-vitamin-d-associated-with-metabolic-syndrome-and-ldl-in-colon-cancer-patients.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-vitamin-d-associated-with-metabolic-syndrome-and-ldl-in-colon-cancer-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="concentrations-of-the-vitamin-d-metabolite-125oh2d-and-odds-of-metabolic-syndrome-and-its-components">Concentrations of the Vitamin D Metabolite 1,25(OH)2D and Odds of Metabolic Syndrome and its Components&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Metabolism, Volume 64, Issue 3, March 2015, Pages 447–459, doi:10.1016/j.metabol.2014.11.010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jennifer W. Beaa, Peter W. Jurutkab, Elizabeth A. Hiblerc, e, Peter Lancea, Maria E. Martínezd, Denise J. Roea, e, Christine L. Sardo Molmentif, Patricia A. Thompsona, Elizabeth T. Jacobsa, e, Corresponding author at: Mel and Enid Zuckerman College of Public Health, University of Arizona Cancer Center, 1515 N Campbell Ave., Tucson, AZ, 85724-5024, USA. Tel.: + 1 520 626 0341.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kidney disease helped by active or high dose Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/kidney-disease-helped-by-active-or-high-dose-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-disease-helped-by-active-or-high-dose-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-beneficial-impact-of-vitamin-d-treatment-in-ckd-patients-whats-next---editorial-comment">The beneficial impact of vitamin D treatment in CKD patients: what&amp;rsquo;s next? - Editorial Comment&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Kidney J (2015) 8:38-40 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ckj/sfu135">doi: 10.1093/ckj/sfu135&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) have markedly higher rates of severe vitamin D deficiency and reduced ability to convert 25-(OH)vitamin D into the active form, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. In the setting of CKD, secondary hyperparathyroidism develops as a consequence of reduced renal production of active vitamin D and phosphate retention resulting in hypocalcaemia and hyperpho- sphataemia. This is a process that is dangerously linked with metabolic bone disease, arterial calcifications and cardiovascular mortality &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>. Therefore, the conventional rationale for vitamin D treatment in CKD is to slow the progression of secondary hyperparathyroidism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcitriol (active Vitamin D) recommended after kidney transplant</title><link>/posts/calcitriol-active-vitamin-d-recommended-after-kidney-transplant.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcitriol-active-vitamin-d-recommended-after-kidney-transplant.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="therapeutic-use-of-calcitriol">Therapeutic use of calcitriol.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Curr Vasc Pharmacol. 2014 Mar;12(2):294-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rodriguez M, Munoz-Castaneda JR, Almaden Y1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The synthesis of 1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (Calcitriol) takes place mostly in the kidneys through the action of 1α-hydroxylase (CYP27B1) which converts 25(OH)D into 1,25(OH)2D3. Renal production of calcitriol is stimulated by PTH, low calcium and low phosphate and it is reduced by high phosphate and FGF23. Binding of 1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 to its receptor (VDR) causes gut absorption of calcium and phosphate, decrease in PTH synthesis, stimulation of FGF23. At the bone level calcitriol suppresses pre-osteoblasts and activates mature osteoblasts. VDR is present in a large variety of cells that do not have any direct role in the regulation of mineral metabolism. Calcitriol regulates immune and inflammatory response, cell turnover, cell differentiation, Renin production, reduces proteinuria and others. In patients with Chronic Kidney Disease (CKD) there is a decrease in calcitriol that is apparent at early stages of renal disease; this is probably due to the elevation of FGF23 which is present since very early stage of CKD. In CKD stage, 3-4 moderate doses of calcitriol are effective to control secondary hyperparathyroidism and observational studies suggest that calcitriol therapy increases survival and slows the progression of renal disease as long as phosphate and calcium levels are controlled. Calcitriol (0.5 µg calcitriol twice per week) has been effective in decreasing proteinuria in patients with IgA nephropathy. In dialysis patients, the administration of calcitriol reduces serum PTH levels but it is also known that high doses of calcitriol are associated with hypercalcemia and worse control of hyperphosphatemia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and calcidiol are not hormones, but calcitriol is a hormone</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcidiol-are-not-hormones-but-calcitriol-is-a-hormone.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-calcidiol-are-not-hormones-but-calcitriol-is-a-hormone.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="is-vitamin-d-a-hormone-or-vitaminhttpswwwresearchgatenetpostis_vitamin_d_a_hormone_or_vitamin-researchgate-aug-2014">&lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/post/Is_vitamin_D_a_hormone_or_vitamin">Is vitamin D a hormone or vitamin?&lt;/a> ResearchGate Aug 2014&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Vitamin D itself - neither cholecalciferol (Vitamin D3) nor ergocalciferol (Vitamin D2)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>is not a hormone, but rather a biomodulator vitamin (capable of gene regulation);&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>the primary active form 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (calcitriol) is a calcium-regulating hormone;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>the primary circulating non-active form 25-hydroxy-VitaminD is a &lt;strong>prehormone&lt;/strong> ,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>converted peripherally to the active hormone 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (calcitriol).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is the structural raw material that one or more hormones or prehormones (not prohormones) are made from, and meets the strict definition of a vitamin, namely an organic substance present in minute amounts in the natural diet (foodstuffs, not supplements) that is essential to normal metabolism, and insufficient amounts of which in the diet may cause deficiency diseases&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcitriol, not inactive vitamin D, associated with pain in seniors</title><link>/posts/calcitriol-not-inactive-vitamin-d-associated-with-pain-in-seniors.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcitriol-not-inactive-vitamin-d-associated-with-pain-in-seniors.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="active-vitamin-d-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-is-associated-with-chronic-pain-in-older-australian-men-the-concord-health-and-ageing-in-men-project">Active Vitamin D (1,25 Dihydroxyvitamin D) Is Associated With Chronic Pain in Older Australian Men: The Concord Health and Ageing in Men Project.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2014 Aug 7. pii: glu126. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hirani V1, Blyth FM2, Naganathan V2, Cumming RG3, Le Couteur DG4, Handelsman DJ5, Waite LM2, Seibel MJ6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Centre for Education and Research on Ageing, Concord Hospital, School of Public Health, ARC Centre of Excellence in Population Ageing Research, &lt;a href="mailto:vasant.hirani@sydney.edu.au">vasant.hirani@sydney.edu.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease study not aware of appropriate forms of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-study-not-aware-of-appropriate-forms-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-study-not-aware-of-appropriate-forms-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-resistance-in-chronic-kidney-disease-ckd">Vitamin D resistance in chronic kidney disease (CKD).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Nephrol. 2014 Mar 19;15(1):47. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2369-15-47.">doi: 10.1186/1471-2369-15-47.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parikh A, Chase HS, Vernocchi L, Stern L1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous studies have shown that treatment with ergocalciferol in patients with CKD stage 3 + 4 is not effective with less than 33% of patients achieving a 25-OH vitamin D target of &amp;gt;30 ng/ml. The aim of this study was to test the response to cholecalciferol in CKD. We attempted to replete 25-OH vitamin D to a target level of 40-60 ng/ml using the response to treatment and PTH suppression as an outcome measure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Vitamin D into your blood and cells</title><link>/posts/getting-vitamin-d-into-your-blood-and-cells.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/getting-vitamin-d-into-your-blood-and-cells.html</guid><description>&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="550">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Summary by Claude Sonnet AI - Feb 2025&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This image shows a comprehensive flow chart explaining how Vitamin D is processed and utilized in the human body.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me break it down systematically:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The chart starts at the top by identifying the main sources and products of Vitamin D, which come through three primary pathways:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Direct absorption through sun exposure&lt;/strong> (UVB rays), topical application, or sublingual supplements that enter through the skin or mouth&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Get active vitamin D by eating Solanum Glaucophyllum leaves</title><link>/posts/get-active-vitamin-d-by-eating-solanum-glaucophyllum-leaves.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/get-active-vitamin-d-by-eating-solanum-glaucophyllum-leaves.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-efficacy-of-a-standardised-product-from-dried-leaves-of-solanum-glaucophyllum-as-source-of-125-dihydroxycholecalciferol-for-poultry">The efficacy of a standardised product from dried leaves of Solanum glaucophyllum as source of 1,25-dihydroxycholecalciferol for poultry.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Br Poult Sci. 2013;54(5):642-52. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/00071668.2013.825692.">doi: 10.1080/00071668.2013.825692.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Sep 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bachmann H1, Autzen S, Frey U, Wehr U, Rambeck W, McCormack H, Whitehead CC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Herbonis AG , Augst , Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1.Chemical characterisation of an extract of Solanum glaucophyllum (SG) leaves affirmed the predominant presence of 1,25-dihydroxycholecalciferol (1,25(OH)2D3) glycosides. The compound 1-(ß-D-glucopyranosyl)-1α,25-dihydroxycholecalciferol was isolated for the first time from a natural source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Time-release form of active vitamin D granted a patent for chronic kidney disease</title><link>/posts/time-release-form-of-active-vitamin-d-granted-a-patent-for-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/time-release-form-of-active-vitamin-d-granted-a-patent-for-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Solanum glaucophyllum (a purple flower) produces active vitamin D3</title><link>/posts/solanum-glaucophyllum-a-purple-flower-produces-active-vitamin-d3.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/solanum-glaucophyllum-a-purple-flower-produces-active-vitamin-d3.html</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/sg1.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/sg2.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#update">Update&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dec-2013">Dec 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#solanum-glaucophyllum-as-source-of-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3--1977">Solanum glaucophyllum as source of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3. -1977&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sg-as-a-source-of-vitamin-d-for-chickens-oct-2013">SG as a source of Vitamin D for chickens Oct 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#us-small-business-grant-of-80000-sg-for-laying-hens--2005">US Small business grant of $80,000: SG for laying hens – 2005&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sg-for-dairy-cows---2003">SG for dairy cows - 2003&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#too-much-sg-for-pigs-can-be-a-problem-if-vitamin-d-and-calcuim-intake-are-not-reduced---feb-2017">Too much SG for pigs can be a problem if Vitamin D and Calcuim intake are not reduced - Feb 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#solanum-glaucophyllum-extraction-has-been-patented">SOLANUM GLAUCOPHYLLUM extraction has been patented&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="update">Update&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Human pharmacokinetic profile of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3-glycoside of herbal origin - Oct 2014 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2013.11.016">doi: 10.1016/j.jsbmb.2013.11.016&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colorectal cancer radiation reduced 2X by calcitriol (Vitamin D) with some genes</title><link>/posts/colorectal-cancer-radiation-reduced-2x-by-calcitriol-vitamin-d-with-some-genes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-cancer-radiation-reduced-2x-by-calcitriol-vitamin-d-with-some-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="slug-expression-inhibits-calcitriol-mediated-sensitivity-to-radiation-in-colorectal-cancer">Slug expression inhibits calcitriol-mediated sensitivity to radiation in colorectal cancer.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Mol Carcinog. 2013 Aug 31. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/mc.22054.">doi: 10.1002/mc.22054.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Findlay VJ, Moretz RE, Wang C, Vaena SG, Bandurraga SG, Ashenafi M, Marshall DT, Watson DK, Camp ER.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, a reciprocal relationship between calcitriol and epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition has been described. Therefore, we hypothesized that calcitriol (1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 ) would enhance radiation sensitivity in colorectal cancer regulated by epithelial mesenchymal transition. Vitamin-D receptor, E-cadherin and vimentin protein as well as E-cadherin, Snail and Slug mRNA levels were assessed in a panel of human colorectal cancer cell lines at baseline and in response calcitriol. We defined cell lines as calcitriol sensitive based on demonstrating an enhanced epithelial phenotype with increased E-cadherin, reduced vimentin and decreased expression of Snail and Slug as well as decreased cellular migration in response to calcitriol.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nano-encapsulated of Vitamin D3, Calcidiol, calcitriol look promising, esp time release</title><link>/posts/nano-encapsulated-of-vitamin-d3-calcidiol-calcitriol-look-promising-esp-time-release.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nano-encapsulated-of-vitamin-d3-calcidiol-calcitriol-look-promising-esp-time-release.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="nano-encapsulation-of-vitamin-d3-active-metabolites-for-application-in-chemotherapy-formulation-study-and-in-vitro-evaluation">Nano-encapsulation of Vitamin D(3) Active Metabolites for Application in Chemotherapy: Formulation Study and in Vitro Evaluation.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pharm Res. 2012 Dec 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Almouazen E, Bourgeois S, Jordheim LP, Fessi H, Briançon S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University Lyon, University Claude Bernard Lyon 1 Laboratoire d&amp;rsquo;Automatique et de Génie des Procédés, LAGEP UMR CNRS 5007, CPE-308 G, 43 bd. 11 Nov.1918, 69622, Villeurbanne, France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: Calcitriol (1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3)), the active metabolite of vitamin D(3), is a potential anticancer agent but with high risk of hypercalcemia which limits the achievement of effective serum concentrations. Thus, calcitriol targeting delivery by nanoparticles may present a good solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pre-cursor of active vitamin D made from plants is better than calcitriol</title><link>/posts/pre-cursor-of-active-vitamin-d-made-from-plants-is-better-than-calcitriol.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pre-cursor-of-active-vitamin-d-made-from-plants-is-better-than-calcitriol.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3-glycoside-of-herbal-origin-exhibits-delayed-release-pharmacokinetics-when-compared-to-its-synthetic-counterpart">1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D(3)-Glycoside Of Herbal Origin Exhibits Delayed Release Pharmacokinetics When Compared To Its Synthetic Counterpart.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2012 Sep 26. pii: S0960-0760(12)00172-0. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2012.09.016.">doi: 10.1016/j.jsbmb.2012.09.016.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bachmann H, Offord-Cavin E, Phothirath P, Horcajada MN, Romeis P, Mathis GA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Herbonis AG, Gellertstrasse 33, CH-4001 Basel, Switzerland. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:h.bachmann@herbonis.com">h.bachmann@herbonis.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D requires two metabolic steps to become biologically active. In a first step 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3) is formed, which acts as storage form.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omega 3 increases vitamin D in the blood – many studies</title><link>/posts/omega-3-increases-vitamin-d-in-the-blood-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-increases-vitamin-d-in-the-blood-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Many articles on this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omega-3 increases levels of active vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active vitamin D is the form which the body actually used&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active vitamin D is not measured by standard vitamin D tests&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omega-3 is thus especially useful to get vitamin D to the body if the kidney is not functioning properly&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-effects-of-omega-3-fatty-acid-on-vitamin-d-activation-in-hemodialysis-patients-a-pilot-study--2015">The Effects of Omega-3 Fatty Acid on Vitamin D Activation in Hemodialysis Patients: A Pilot Study- 2015&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/active-d-and-omega-3.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Mar. Drugs 2015, 13(2), 741-755; doi:10.3390/md13020741&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>