<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aging Skin on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/aging-skin.html</link><description>Recent content in Aging Skin on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/aging-skin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5X more likely to have facial skin aging if vitamin D insufficient</title><link>/posts/5x-more-likely-to-have-facial-skin-aging-if-vitamin-d-insufficient.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5x-more-likely-to-have-facial-skin-aging-if-vitamin-d-insufficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="association-of-facial-skin-aging-and-vitamin-d-levels-in-middle-aged-white-women">Association of facial skin aging and vitamin D levels in middle-aged white women.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2010 Dec;21(12):2315-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10552-010-9646-y.">doi: 10.1007/s10552-010-9646-y.&lt;/a> Epub 2010 Sep 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chang AL, Fu T, Amir O, Tang JY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Stanford University School of Medicine, 450 Broadway, Pavilion C, MC 5334, Redwood City, CA 94305, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the relationship between UV-induced skin photodamage and 25(OH) vitamin D levels, we performed a cross-sectional study in 45 female subjects aged &amp;gt;40. Menopausal status, smoking status, skin cancer history, oral supplement use, and season of blood draw were recorded and serum 25(OH)D measured. A single-blinded, dermatologist evaluated standardized digital facial images for overall photodamage, erythema/telangiectasias, hyperpigmentation, number of lentigines, and wrinkling. Adjusting for age and season of blood collection, women with lower photodamage scores were associated with a 5-fold increased odds of being vitamin D insufficient (OR 5.0, 95% CI: 1.1, 23). Low scores for specific photodamage parameters including erythema/telangiectasias, hyperpigmentation, and wrinkling were also significantly associated with vitamin D insufficiency. Our results suggest an association between skin aging and 25(OH)D levels.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>