<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Back Pain on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/back-pain.html</link><description>Recent content in Back Pain on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/back-pain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spinal disc degeneration is associated with vitamin D receptor genes, and others</title><link>/posts/spinal-disc-degeneration-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-receptor-genes-and-others.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-disc-degeneration-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-receptor-genes-and-others.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="genetic-polymorphisms-associated-with-intervertebral-disc-degeneration">Genetic polymorphisms associated with intervertebral disc degeneration.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Spine J. 2013 Mar;13(3):299-317. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.spinee.2013.01.041.">doi: 10.1016/j.spinee.2013.01.041.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mayer JE, Iatridis JC, Chan D, Qureshi SA, Gottesman O, Hecht AC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leni and Peter W. May Department of Orthopaedics, Mount Sinai Medical Center, 5 East 98th St, 9th Floor, New York, NY 10029, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND CONTEXT: Disc degeneration (DD) is a multifaceted chronic process that alters the structure and function of the intervertebral discs and can lead to painful conditions. The pathophysiology of degeneration is not well understood, but previous studies suggest that certain genetic polymorphisms may be important contributing factors leading to an increased risk of DD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lumbar spinal stenosis pain strongly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/lumbar-spinal-stenosis-pain-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lumbar-spinal-stenosis-pain-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-lumbar-spinal-stenosis-and-its-relationship-with-pain">Prevalence of vitamin d deficiency in patients with lumbar spinal stenosis and its relationship with pain.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pain Physician. 2013 Mar;16(2):165-76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim TH, Lee BH, Lee HM, Lee SH, Park JO, Kim HS, Kim SW, Moon SH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spine Center, Hallym University Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Anyang, Korea; Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Patients with lumbar spinal stenosis (LSS) are at a great risk of a fall and fracture, which vitamin D protects against. Vitamin D deficiency is expected to be highly prevalent in LSS patient, and pain is thought to have a profound effect on vitamin D status by limiting activity and sunlight exposure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back pain associated with less than 40 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/back-pain-associated-with-less-than-40-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/back-pain-associated-with-less-than-40-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-levels-appear-to-be-normal-in-danish-patients-attending-secondary-care-for-low-back-pain-and-a-weak-positive-correlation-between-serum-level-vitamin-d-and-modic-changes-was-demonstrated-a-cross-sectional-cohort-study-of-consecutive-patients-with-non-specific-low-back-pain">Vitamin D levels appear to be normal in Danish patients attending secondary care for low back pain and a weak positive correlation between serum level Vitamin D and Modic changes was demonstrated: a cross-sectional cohort study of consecutive patients with non-specific low back pain&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders, Volume 14, March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jannick Vaaben Johansen, Claus Manniche and Per Kjaer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:Hypovitaminosis D has previously been reported in both the general population, in people with chronic musculoskeletal pain, and in people with low back pain (LBP). Myopathy-related symptoms such as diffuse bone and muscle pain, weakness and paresthesia in the legs, have also been observed in people with non-specific LBP and associations with low levels of Vitamin D have been suggested. The objectives of this study were to investigate (1) Vitamin D levels in patients seeking care for LBP in a Danish out-patient secondary care setting, and (2) their possible relationship with myopathy-related symptoms, Body Mass Index (BMI), and Modic changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduced skeletal pain in 85 percent of the patients</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-skeletal-pain-in-85-percent-of-the-patients.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-skeletal-pain-in-85-percent-of-the-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-vitamin-d-deficiency-associated-with-non-specific-musculoskeletal-pain">Is Vitamin D Deficiency associated with Non Specific Musculoskeletal Pain?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Glob J Health Sci. 2012 Nov 11;5(1):107-11. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5539/gjhs.v5n1p107.">doi: 10.5539/gjhs.v5n1p107.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abbasi M, Hashemipour S, Hajmanuchehri F, Kazemifar AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Metabolic Diseases Research Center, Qazvin University of Medical Science, Qazvin, Iran. &lt;a href="mailto:Hashemipour.sima@yahoo.com">Hashemipour.sima@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUNDS: Vitamin D deficiency is common worldwide, including Iran. It has been suggested that vitamin D deficiency is associated with non-specific musculoskeletal pain. The aim of this study is evaluation of the association of musculoskeletal pain with vitamin D deficiency and the response of the patients to vitamin D supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>After back surgery failure, vitamin D greatly reduced the pain of every person</title><link>/posts/after-back-surgery-failure-vitamin-d-greatly-reduced-the-pain-of-every-person.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/after-back-surgery-failure-vitamin-d-greatly-reduced-the-pain-of-every-person.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="serum-25-hydroxy-calciferol-level-and-failed-back-surgery-syndrome">Serum 25-hydroxy-calciferol level and failed back surgery syndrome.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Orthop Surg (Hong Kong). 2012 Apr;20(1):18-22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Waikakul S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE. To assess the association of serum 25-hydroxy-calciferol levels with pain and low back function in patients with failed back surgery syndrome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS. Records of 6 men and 3 women aged 25 to 54 (mean, 39.2) years who had failed back surgery syndrome after pedicular screw and rod instrumentation for lower lumbar degenerative diseases were reviewed. They had moderate-to-severe pain (visual analogue scale &lt;span>[VAS]&lt;/span> score of &amp;gt;6) and low back function disability (Japanese Orthopaedic Association &lt;span>[JOA]&lt;/span> back score of &amp;lt;10). In all patients, the serum 25-hydroxy-calciferol level was &amp;lt;30 ng/ ml, indicating vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>100 Million Americans Have Chronic Pain – IoM</title><link>/posts/100-million-americans-have-chronic-pain-iom.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/100-million-americans-have-chronic-pain-iom.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>