<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Back Pain on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/back-pain.html</link><description>Recent content in Back Pain on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/back-pain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chronic Back Pain relieved by weekly 60,000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chronic-back-pain-relieved-by-weekly-60000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-back-pain-relieved-by-weekly-60000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Degenerative Diseases of the Spine are related to low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/degenerative-diseases-of-the-spine-are-related-to-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/degenerative-diseases-of-the-spine-are-related-to-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Back pain not relieved when vitamin D levels remained below 30 nanograms – RCT</title><link>/posts/back-pain-not-relieved-when-vitamin-d-levels-remained-below-30-nanograms-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/back-pain-not-relieved-when-vitamin-d-levels-remained-below-30-nanograms-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-nonspecific-low-back-pain">The effect of vitamin D on nonspecific low back pain&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>International Journal of Rheumatic Diseases, Volume 18, Issue 8, pages 854–858, November 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mahnaz Sandoughi 1, Zahra Zakeri 1,*, Zahra Mirhosainee 1, Mahdi Mohammadi 2 and Sogol Shahbakhsh 3&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>Randomized Controlled Trial&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D level 18 ng ==&amp;gt; 28 ng&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Similar reduction in back pain for VitD and placebo&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VitaminDWiki expects that vitamin D levels would have gotten much higher and back pain would have been relieved if trial had been 12 weeks instead of just 8 weeks&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lower back pain 3X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/lower-back-pain-3x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lower-back-pain-3x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-of-low-back-pain-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-other-common-risk-factors-a-hospital-based-case-control-study">Association of low back pain with vitamin D deficiency and other common risk factors: A hospital based case-control study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Preventive Medicine, 2015; 3(1): 1-5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ahmed M. S. Hegazy1, Basem M. M. Salama2, Ahmed M. M. Elgaml3, Ahmed Ramzy Alzyat4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Anatomy Department, Benha Faculty of Medicine, Benha University, Benha, Egypt 2Community Medicine Department, Damietta Faculty of Medicine, Al-Azhar University, Damietta, Egypt 3Clinical Pathology Department, Cairo Faculty of Medicine, Al-Azhar University, Cairo, Egypt 4Rheumatology Department, Cairo Faculty of Medicine, Al-Azhar University, Cairo, Egypt&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Backache strongly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/backache-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/backache-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="levels-of-vitamin-d-in-patients-with-low-backache">LEVELS OF VITAMIN D IN PATIENTS WITH LOW BACKACHE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Gomal Journal of Medical Sciences July-September 2014, Vol. 12, No. 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sardar Sohail Afsar, Mohammad Idrees, Mohammad Gulzar&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Pakistan International Medical College, Peshawar, Pakistan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corresponding Author: Dr. Sardar Sohail Afsar Senior Registrar Orthopaedics Pak International Medical College Hayatabad, Peshawar, Pakistan. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:dr_sardarsohail@yahoo.co.uk">dr_sardarsohail@yahoo.co.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Along with many factors vitamin D is considered to have role in lower backache.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this study was to determine the levels of vitamin D in patients of low backache.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back Pain</title><link>/posts/back-pain.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/back-pain.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#review-of-over-the-counter-treatment-for-chronic-low-back-pain---nov2020">Review of Over the Counter Treatment for Chronic Low Back Pain - Nov 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsopubmed">See also PubMed&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#back-pain-is-4th-biggest-global-cause-of-disability-ages50-69httpihmeuworg2z2k">&lt;a href="http://ihmeuw.org/2z2k">Back pain is 4th biggest global cause of disability: ages 50-69&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#back-pain-relief-experience---henry-lahore-admin-of-vitamindwiki-dec2014">Back Pain relief experience - Henry Lahore, admin of VitaminDWiki, Dec 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#uk-review-of-back-pain---asking-for-comments-march2016">UK review of Back Pain - asking for comments March 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#notes-on-low-back-pain-in-recent-timesless-exercise-outdoors-less-low-vitamind">Notes on Low back pain in recent times:less exercise, outdoors less (low vitamin D)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pain-relievers-can-extend-the-duration-of-back-pain---and-sometimes-turning-it-into-a-chronic-pain---may2022">Pain relievers can extend the duration of back pain - and sometimes turning it into a chronic pain - May 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pain-reprocessing-therapy-for-chronic-back-pain---rct-sept2021">Pain Reprocessing Therapy for Chronic Back Pain - RCT Sept 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#opioids-no-better-than-placebo-for-back-pain---rct-june2023">Opioids no better than placebo for Back Pain - RCT June 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-back-pain-clinical-trial-is-underway---trying-out-12-back-pain-remedies---to-be-completed-march2024">A Back Pain clinical trial is underway - trying out 12 back pain remedies - to be completed March 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#by-what-mechanism-does-magnesium-relieve-back-pain-perplexity-ai---may2024">By what mechanism does magnesium relieve back pain? Perplexity AI - May 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsoweb">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="review-of-over-the-counter-treatment-for-chronic-low-back-pain---nov2020">Review of Over the Counter Treatment for Chronic Low Back Pain - Nov 2020&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/webp/otc-bp-treatment.webp" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/chronic-low-back-pain-2020-compresspdf.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki &lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and rheumatic diseases. – Review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-rheumatic-diseases-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-rheumatic-diseases-review.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Reumatismo. 2014 Jul 28;66(2):153-70. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4081/reumatismo.2014.788.">doi: 10.4081/reumatismo.2014.788.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rossini M1, Gatti D, Viapiana O, Caimmi C, Idolazzi L, Fracassi E, Adami S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Rheumatology Unit, University of Verona. &lt;a href="mailto:maurizio.rossini@univr.it">maurizio.rossini@univr.it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has some well-known effects on calcium, phosphate and bone metabolism, but it has recently shown to have many other effects, which may potentially be relevant to patients with extra-skeletal rheumatic diseases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such effects may be justified by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>the presence of the vitamin D receptors also on extra-osseous cells, such as cartilage cells, sinoviocytes, muscle cells;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>the proven role of vitamin D in the control of the transcription of genes involved in rheumatic diseases;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>the evidence that vitamin D has multiple endocrine effects not only on calcium homeostasis;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>the activation of vitamin D not only in the kidneys,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>but also in monocyte-macrophage and lymphocytic cell lines&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back pain extremely associated with low level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/back-pain-extremely-associated-with-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/back-pain-extremely-associated-with-low-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#assessment-of-vitamin-d-status-in-patients-of-chronic-low-back-pain-of-unknown-etiology">Assessment of Vitamin D status In Patients of Chronic Low Back Pain of Unknown Etiology&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-lumbar-spinal-stenosis-and-its-relationship-with-pain">Prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in patients with lumbar spinal stenosis and its relationship with pain.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#women-were-24-x-more-lifely-to-have--nonspecific-low-back-pain-if-low-vitamin-d">Women Were 2.4 X more lifely to have nonspecific low back pain if low vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="assessment-of-vitamin-d-status-in-patients-of-chronic-low-back-pain-of-unknown-etiology">Assessment of Vitamin D status In Patients of Chronic Low Back Pain of Unknown Etiology&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Indian Journal of Clinical Biochemistry, May 2014&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back pain cured with vitamin D – Book</title><link>/posts/back-pain-cured-with-vitamin-d-book.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/back-pain-cured-with-vitamin-d-book.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="healed-from-chronic-painhttpwwwamazoncomhealed-chronic-pain-mark-pegram-ebookdpb00k1mslrqrefsr_1_sc_3sbooksieutf8qid1399825577sr1-3-spellkeywordsmarkbackpain20">&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Healed-Chronic-Pain-Mark-Pegram-ebook/dp/B00K1MSLRQ/ref=sr_1_sc_3?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1399825577&amp;amp;sr=1-3-spell&amp;amp;keywords=mark+backpain%20">Healed from Chronic Pain&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Amazon US May 2014, updated July 2014 Kindle $10&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/chronic-pain-book-cover.jpg" alt="image" width="200">
&lt;p>Nice description of a personal journey from low vitamin D and major chronic back pain for 10 years to high vitamin D and Magnesium and no back pain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Appears to have used dose up to 4400 IU of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His back pain did not significantly reduce until about a year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suspect would have been much faster if he had used a &lt;a href="/posts/overview-loading-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Loading of vitamin D">loading dose&lt;/a>. Graphic description of intense pain and his techniques to minimize it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinal disc degeneration is associated with vitamin D receptor genes, and others</title><link>/posts/spinal-disc-degeneration-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-receptor-genes-and-others.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-disc-degeneration-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-receptor-genes-and-others.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="genetic-polymorphisms-associated-with-intervertebral-disc-degeneration">Genetic polymorphisms associated with intervertebral disc degeneration.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Spine J. 2013 Mar;13(3):299-317. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.spinee.2013.01.041.">doi: 10.1016/j.spinee.2013.01.041.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mayer JE, Iatridis JC, Chan D, Qureshi SA, Gottesman O, Hecht AC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leni and Peter W. May Department of Orthopaedics, Mount Sinai Medical Center, 5 East 98th St, 9th Floor, New York, NY 10029, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND CONTEXT: Disc degeneration (DD) is a multifaceted chronic process that alters the structure and function of the intervertebral discs and can lead to painful conditions. The pathophysiology of degeneration is not well understood, but previous studies suggest that certain genetic polymorphisms may be important contributing factors leading to an increased risk of DD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lumbar spinal stenosis pain strongly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/lumbar-spinal-stenosis-pain-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lumbar-spinal-stenosis-pain-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-lumbar-spinal-stenosis-and-its-relationship-with-pain">Prevalence of vitamin d deficiency in patients with lumbar spinal stenosis and its relationship with pain.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pain Physician. 2013 Mar;16(2):165-76.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim TH, Lee BH, Lee HM, Lee SH, Park JO, Kim HS, Kim SW, Moon SH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spine Center, Hallym University Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Anyang, Korea; Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Patients with lumbar spinal stenosis (LSS) are at a great risk of a fall and fracture, which vitamin D protects against. Vitamin D deficiency is expected to be highly prevalent in LSS patient, and pain is thought to have a profound effect on vitamin D status by limiting activity and sunlight exposure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back pain associated with less than 40 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/back-pain-associated-with-less-than-40-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/back-pain-associated-with-less-than-40-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-levels-appear-to-be-normal-in-danish-patients-attending-secondary-care-for-low-back-pain-and-a-weak-positive-correlation-between-serum-level-vitamin-d-and-modic-changes-was-demonstrated-a-cross-sectional-cohort-study-of-consecutive-patients-with-non-specific-low-back-pain">Vitamin D levels appear to be normal in Danish patients attending secondary care for low back pain and a weak positive correlation between serum level Vitamin D and Modic changes was demonstrated: a cross-sectional cohort study of consecutive patients with non-specific low back pain&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders, Volume 14, March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jannick Vaaben Johansen, Claus Manniche and Per Kjaer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:Hypovitaminosis D has previously been reported in both the general population, in people with chronic musculoskeletal pain, and in people with low back pain (LBP). Myopathy-related symptoms such as diffuse bone and muscle pain, weakness and paresthesia in the legs, have also been observed in people with non-specific LBP and associations with low levels of Vitamin D have been suggested. The objectives of this study were to investigate (1) Vitamin D levels in patients seeking care for LBP in a Danish out-patient secondary care setting, and (2) their possible relationship with myopathy-related symptoms, Body Mass Index (BMI), and Modic changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduced skeletal pain in 85 percent of the patients</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-skeletal-pain-in-85-percent-of-the-patients.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-skeletal-pain-in-85-percent-of-the-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-vitamin-d-deficiency-associated-with-non-specific-musculoskeletal-pain">Is Vitamin D Deficiency associated with Non Specific Musculoskeletal Pain?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Glob J Health Sci. 2012 Nov 11;5(1):107-11. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5539/gjhs.v5n1p107.">doi: 10.5539/gjhs.v5n1p107.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abbasi M, Hashemipour S, Hajmanuchehri F, Kazemifar AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Metabolic Diseases Research Center, Qazvin University of Medical Science, Qazvin, Iran. &lt;a href="mailto:Hashemipour.sima@yahoo.com">Hashemipour.sima@yahoo.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUNDS: Vitamin D deficiency is common worldwide, including Iran. It has been suggested that vitamin D deficiency is associated with non-specific musculoskeletal pain. The aim of this study is evaluation of the association of musculoskeletal pain with vitamin D deficiency and the response of the patients to vitamin D supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>