<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Predict on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/predict.html</link><description>Recent content in Predict on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/predict/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple Vitamin D deficiency scoring system</title><link>/posts/simple-vitamin-d-deficiency-scoring-system.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/simple-vitamin-d-deficiency-scoring-system.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Molecular Approaches for Optimizing Vitamin D (one size does not fit all) – Carlberg</title><link>/posts/molecular-approaches-for-optimizing-vitamin-d-one-size-does-not-fit-all-carlberg.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/molecular-approaches-for-optimizing-vitamin-d-one-size-does-not-fit-all-carlberg.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="molecular-approaches-for-optimizing-vitamin-d-supplementation">Molecular Approaches for Optimizing Vitamin D Supplementation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamins &amp;amp; Hormones, online 30 November 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Carsten Carlberg&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="mailto:carsten.carlberg@uef.fi">carsten.carlberg@uef.fi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>VitaminDWiki quick-read comment on the study&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Genes are responsible for much of the individual variation in response to vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author introduces a concept of a &lt;strong>vitamin D Index&lt;/strong> which could be made based on before/after measurements of vitamin D levels along with before/after DNA analysis of 4 – 20 genes (to measure affect of Vitamin D intervention).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels should often be adjusted for season (Cosinor)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-should-often-be-adjusted-for-season-cosinor.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-should-often-be-adjusted-for-season-cosinor.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">There are THREE studies on this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="cosinor-modelling-of-seasonal-variation-in-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-cardiovascular-patients-in-norway">Cosinor modelling of seasonal variation in 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations in cardiovascular patients in Norway&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Clinical Nutrition advance online publication 25 November 2015;	&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2015.200">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2015.200&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E Degerud1, R Hoff2, O Nygård3,4, E Strand3, D W Nilsen3,5, J E Nordrehaug3,4, Ø Midttun6, P M Ueland3,7, S de Vogel8 and J Dierkes1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2The Institute of Basic Medical Sciences, University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis patients need more vitamin D to get same blood level response</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-patients-need-more-vitamin-d-to-get-same-blood-level-response.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-patients-need-more-vitamin-d-to-get-same-blood-level-response.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D more than 40 ng: 1300 IU 50% chance: 5,000 IU 80% chance</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-more-than-40-ng-1300-iu-50-percent-chance-5000-iu-80-percent-chance.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-more-than-40-ng-1300-iu-50-percent-chance-5000-iu-80-percent-chance.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="spangrassrootshealthorgspan">&lt;span>[Grassrootshealth.org]&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Goal = 40 nanogram/ml&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Daily&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Response &lt;br>&amp;gt;40 ng&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>How often to take&lt;br>50,000 IU capsule&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1,300 IU&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>50%&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>too long&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>5,000 IU&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>83%&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>once every 10 days&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>10,000 IU&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>96%&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>once every 5 days&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h3 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-dose-for-140-lb-woman">Vitamin D dose for 140 lb woman - Sept 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-cofactors-in-a-nutshell">Vitamin D Cofactors in a nutshell&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-toxicity-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Toxicity of vitamin D">Overview Toxicity of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Response to Vitamin D supplementation</title><link>/posts/response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="factors-affecting-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-in-response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation">Factors Affecting 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration in Response to Vitamin D Supplementation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2015, 7(7), 5111-5142; doi:10.3390/nu7075111&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hajar Mazahery and Pamela R. von Hurst &lt;a href="mailto:P.R.vonHurst@massey.ac.nz">P.R.vonHurst@massey.ac.nz&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Food Science and Technology-School of Food and Nutrition, Massey University,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Auckland 0632, New Zealand; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:h.mazahery@hotmail.com">h.mazahery@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sun exposure is the main source of vitamin D. Due to many lifestyle risk factors vitamin D deficiency/insufficiency is becoming a worldwide health problem. Low 25(OH)D concentration is associated with adverse musculoskeletal and non-musculoskeletal health outcomes. Vitamin D supplementation is currently the best approach to treat deficiency and to maintain adequacy. In response to a given dose of vitamin D, the effect on 25(OH)D concentration differs between individuals, and it is imperative that factors affecting this response be identified. For this review, a comprehensive literature search was conducted to identify those factors and to explore their significance in relation to circulating 25(OH)D response to vitamin D supplementation. The effect of several demographic/biological factors such as baseline 25(OH)D, aging, body mass index(BMI)/body fat percentage, ethnicity, calcium intake, genetics, oestrogen use, dietary fat content and composition, and some diseases and medications has been addressed. Furthermore, strategies employed by researchers or health care providers (type, dose and duration of vitamin D supplementation) and environment (season) are other contributing factors. With the exception of baseline 25(OH)D, BMI/body fat percentage, dose and type of vitamin D, the relative importance of other factors and the mechanisms by which these factors may affect the response remains to be determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D estimation nicely improved by neural networks</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-estimation-nicely-improved-by-neural-networks.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-estimation-nicely-improved-by-neural-networks.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="derivation-and-validation-of-a-clinical-diagnostic-tool-for-the-identification-of-older-community-dwellers-with-hypovitaminosis-d">Derivation and Validation of a Clinical Diagnostic Tool for the Identification of Older Community-Dwellers With Hypovitaminosis D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2015 Apr 23. pii: S1525-8610(15)00222-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jamda.2015.03.008.">doi: 10.1016/j.jamda.2015.03.008.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>by The Society for Post-Acute and Long-Term Care Medicine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cedric Annweiler MD, PhDa,b’ &lt;a href="mailto:CeAnnweiler@chu-angers.fr">CeAnnweiler@chu-angers.fr&lt;/a> , Anastasiia Kabeshova MSa, Mathilde Legeay MDc, Bruno Fantino MD, PhD a, Olivier Beauchet MD, PhD a&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Division of Geriatric Medicine and Memory Clinic, Department of Neuroscience, UPRES EA 4638, UNAM, Angers University Hospital, Angers, France&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes account for less than 18 percent of variation in vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/genes-account-for-less-than-18-percent-of-variation-in-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-account-for-less-than-18-percent-of-variation-in-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="exploring-the-genetic-architecture-of-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d">Exploring the genetic architecture of circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Genet Epidemiol. 2013 Jan;37(1):92-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/gepi.21694.">doi: 10.1002/gepi.21694.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Nov 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hiraki LT1, Major JM, Chen C, Cornelis MC, Hunter DJ, Rimm EB, Simon KC, Weinstein SJ, Purdue MP, Yu K, Albanes D, Kraft P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary circulating form of vitamin D is 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25(OH)D), a modifiable trait linked with a growing number of chronic diseases. In addition to environmental determinants of 25(OH)D, including dietary sources and skin ultraviolet B (UVB) exposure, twin- and family-based studies suggest that genetics contribute substantially to vitamin D variability with heritability estimates ranging from 43% to 80%. Genome-wide association studies (GWAS) have identified single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) located in four gene regions associated with 25(OH)D. These SNPs collectively explain only a fraction of the heritability in 25(OH)D estimated by twin- and family-based studies. Using 25(OH)D concentrations and GWAS data on 5,575 subjects drawn from five cohorts, we hypothesized that genome-wide data, in the form of (1) a polygenic score comprised of hundreds or thousands of SNPs that do not individually reach GWAS significance, or (2) a linear mixed model for genome-wide complex trait analysis, would explain variance in measured circulating 25(OH)D beyond that explained by known genome-wide significant 25(OH)D-associated SNPs. GWAS identified SNPs explained 5.2% of the variation in circulating 25(OH)D in these samples and there was little evidence additional markers significantly improved predictive ability. On average, a polygenic score comprised of GWAS-identified SNPs explained a larger proportion of variation in circulating 25(OH)D than scores comprised of thousands of SNPs that were on average, nonsignificant. Employing a linear mixed model for genome-wide complex trait analysis explained little additional variability (range 0-22%). The absence of a significant polygenic effect in this relatively large sample suggests an oligogenetic architecture for 25(OH)D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some people need more vitamin D to get the same response – perhaps due to genes</title><link>/posts/some-people-need-more-vitamin-d-to-get-the-same-response-perhaps-due-to-genes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-people-need-more-vitamin-d-to-get-the-same-response-perhaps-due-to-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dissecting-high-from-low-responders-in-a-vitamin-d3-intervention-study">Dissecting high from low responders in a vitamin D3 intervention study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology doi:10.1016/j.jsbmb.2014.11.012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Noora Saksaa, 1, Antonio Nemea, 1, Jussi Ryynänena, Matti Uusitupab, Vanessa D.F. de Mellob, Sari Voutilainenb, Tarja Nurmib, Jyrki K. Virtanenb, Tomi-Pekka Tuomainenb, Carsten Carlberg a, ,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The genes ASAP2, CAMP, CD14, CD97, DUSP10, G0S2, IL8, LRRC8A, NINJ1, NRIP1, SLC37A2 and THBD are primary VDR targets.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the level of the expression of primary VDR target genes only 55–62% of the study participants were vitamin D3 responders.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>200 IU needed to increase vitamin D levels by 1 ng (not 100 IU) – summary of 25 studies</title><link>/posts/200-iu-needed-to-increase-vitamin-d-levels-by-1-ng-not-100-iu-summary-of-25-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/200-iu-needed-to-increase-vitamin-d-levels-by-1-ng-not-100-iu-summary-of-25-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Effect of Oral Supplementation of Vitamin D3 on Serum Levels of Vitamin D: A Review&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Francesca Jarrett1, Gloria Michelle Ducasa2, David B Buller3 and Marianne Berwick4*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Special Student, University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, New Mexico, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 PREP Program, University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, New Mexico, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Klein Buendel, Golden, Colorado, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Professor, Department of Internal Medicine and Dermatology, University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, New Mexico, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4700 IU of vitamin D needed by most seniors – an equation</title><link>/posts/4700-iu-of-vitamin-d-needed-by-most-seniors-an-equation.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4700-iu-of-vitamin-d-needed-by-most-seniors-an-equation.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D is essential for bone health and probably the health of most nonskeletal tissues. Vitamin D deficiency is widespread, and recommended doses are usually inadequate to maintain healthy levels. We conducted a retrospective observational study to determine whether the recommended doses of vitamin D are adequate to correct deficiency and maintain normal levels in a population seeking health care. We also sought to develop a predictive equation for replacement doses of vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free Vitamin D evaluation service</title><link>/posts/free-vitamin-d-evaluation-service.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/free-vitamin-d-evaluation-service.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamindservicecomhttpwwwvitamindservicecom">&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindservice.com/">VitaminDService.com&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/vitamin-d-service.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindservice.com/">VitaminDService.com&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> is the English version of their &lt;a href="http://www.vitamindservice.de/">German version&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/ask-yourself-if-you-have-these-symptoms-of-low-vitamin-d">Ask yourself if you have these symptoms of low vitamin D&lt;/a> is a copy of the service on VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="calculator-is-based-on-about-30-mathematical-relationships---such-as">Calculator is based on about 30 mathematical relationships - such as&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/service-deviations.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor00fit-is-the-best-evaluation-service-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-on-the-internet-span">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">It is the best evaluation service for vitamin D deficiency on the internet &lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="the-questions-which-they-ask-to-determin-the-number-of-indications-that-you-might-be-vitamin-d-deficiency-as-of-april-2014">The questions which they ask to determin the number of indications that you might be Vitamin D deficiency (as of April 2014)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Each answer has a slider bar for your answer: typically ranging from NEVER to VERY OFTEN&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to predict response to a vitamin D dose – RCT</title><link>/posts/how-to-predict-response-to-a-vitamin-d-dose-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-predict-response-to-a-vitamin-d-dose-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="environmental-personal-and-genetic-determinants-of-response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-older-adults">Environmental, personal and genetic determinants of response to vitamin D supplementation in older adults&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J of Clinical Endocrenology and Metabolism, DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1210/jc.2013-4101">http://dx.doi.org/10.1210/jc.2013-4101&lt;/a>, Published Online: April 02, 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary Waterhouse 1*, Bich Tran12*, Bruce K Armstrong3, Catherine Baxter1, Peter R Ebeling24, Dallas R English5, Val Gebski6, Christine Hill1, Michael G Kimlin27, Robyn M Lucas8, Alison Venn9, Penelope M Webb1, David C Whiteman12, and Rachel E Neale12&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Population Health Division, QIMR Berghofer Medical Research Institute;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gene differences can result in 14 ng difference in vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/gene-differences-can-result-in-14-ng-difference-in-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gene-differences-can-result-in-14-ng-difference-in-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>D Minder: Vitamin D calculator for Smartphones and iPad</title><link>/posts/d-minder-vitamin-d-calculator-for-smartphones-and-ipad.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/d-minder-vitamin-d-calculator-for-smartphones-and-ipad.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-iphones-and-ipads">Vitamin D iPhones and iPads&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#d-minder-vitamin-d-status---based-on-exposure-to-sunlight">D Minder Vitamin D status - based on exposure to sunlight&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-prohttpvitamin-d-procom-based-on-vitamin-d-pth-and-calcium-tests---not-food-nor-sun-intake">&lt;a href="http://vitamin-d-pro.com/">Vitamin D Pro&lt;/a> based on Vitamin D, PTH, and Calcium tests - not food nor sun intake&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-iphones-and-ipads">Vitamin D iPhones and iPads&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="d-minder-vitamin-d-status---based-on-exposure-to-sunlight">D Minder Vitamin D status - based on exposure to sunlight&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Comments by Henry Lahore, admin of VitaminDWiki Dec 2013&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D Minder &amp;ldquo;appears&amp;rdquo; to perpetuate the mistake of showing the amount of vitamin D one would get with UVB from all directions (such as in a tanning bed).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Toward predicting vitamin D levels without a blood test.</title><link>/posts/toward-predicting-vitamin-d-levels-without-a-blood-test.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/toward-predicting-vitamin-d-levels-without-a-blood-test.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#many-models-have-failed-to-predict-vitamin-d-levels-based-on-about-10-variables">Many models have failed to predict vitamin D levels based on about 10 variables.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki-is-considering-solving-all-of-the-above-problems">VitaminDWiki is considering solving all of the above problems&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#variablesquestions">Variables/questions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="many-models-have-failed-to-predict-vitamin-d-levels-based-on-about-10-variables">Many models have failed to predict vitamin D levels based on about 10 variables.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The problems appear to be due to:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Not enough variables in the model&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Not enough subjects&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Not powerful enough software/model&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Large variance between vitamin D testers ( 5% to 10%)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Not record other health influences - emotional stress as a child, antibiotics as a child&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese need 2.5 IU of vitamin D per kg to increase 1 ng (about 3.4 X more) – RCT</title><link>/posts/obese-need-25-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-to-increase-1-ng-about-34-x-more-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-need-25-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-to-increase-1-ng-about-34-x-more-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-response-to-graded-vitamin-d3-supplementation-among-obese-adults">25-hydroxyvitamin D Response to Graded Vitamin D3 Supplementation Among Obese Adults&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism September 13, 2013 jc.2012-4103&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andjela Drincic, M.Da,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eileen Fuller, M.D b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robert P. Heaney, M.Db and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laura A.G. Armas, M.D, M.Sb&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A University of Nebraska Medical Center;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Osteoporosis Research Center, Creighton University&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address all correspondence and requests for reprints to: Andjela Drincic, M.D. 984120 Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha, NE 68198–4120, E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:andjela.drincic@unmc.edu">andjela.drincic@unmc.edu&lt;/a> or phone: 402 559 8176 or Fax: 402 559 9003.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why do gardeners live longer (vitamin D, etc.)</title><link>/posts/why-do-gardeners-live-longer-vitamin-d-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-do-gardeners-live-longer-vitamin-d-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="from-wellness-mommahttpwellnessmamacom5437why-do-gardeners-live-longer">From &lt;a href="http://wellnessmama.com/5437/why-do-gardeners-live-longer/">Wellness Momma&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>There is a lot of evidence, most anecdotal, some scientific, about how gardeners live up to 14 years longer than non-gardeners.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="outline-of-reasons">Outline of reasons:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">1. Get Enough Vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Play In the Dirt&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Getting Grounded&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Stress Relief&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>They Eat Vegetables&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>They Exercise&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Higher air pollution associated with 7 ng lower vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/higher-air-pollution-associated-with-7-ng-lower-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/higher-air-pollution-associated-with-7-ng-lower-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="independent-association-between-air-pollutants-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-young-children-in-isfahan-iran">Independent association between air pollutants and vitamin D deficiency in young children in Isfahan, Iran&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Paediatrics and International Child Health&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roya Kelishadi1; Roksana Moeini1; Parinaz Poursafa2; Sanam Farajian3; Hosseinali Yousefy2; Ali-Asghar Okhovat-Souraki1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1: Paediatrics Department, Faculty of Medicine and Child Growth and Development Research Centre, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2: Environmental Protection Department, Environment Research Centre&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3: Department of Clinical Nutrition, School of Nutrition and Food Science, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Iran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Might be able to predict who will benefit from vitamin D by just 2 genes</title><link>/posts/might-be-able-to-predict-who-will-benefit-from-vitamin-d-by-just-2-genes.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/might-be-able-to-predict-who-will-benefit-from-vitamin-d-by-just-2-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="primary-vitamin-d-target-genes-allow-a-categorization-of-possible-benefits-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation">Primary Vitamin D Target Genes Allow a Categorization of Possible Benefits of Vitamin D3 Supplementation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLOS ONE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carsten Carlberg &lt;a href="mailto:carsten.carlberg@uef.fi">carsten.carlberg@uef.fi&lt;/a>, Sabine Seuter, Vanessa D. F. de Mello, Ursula Schwab, Sari Voutilainen, Kari Pulkki, Tarja Nurmi, Jyrki Virtanen, Tomi-Pekka Tuomainen, Matti Uusitupa&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with an increased risk of developing a number of diseases. Here we investigated samples from 71 pre-diabetic individuals of the VitDmet study, a 5-month high dose vitamin D3 intervention trial during Finnish winter, for their changes in serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25(OH)D3) concentrations and the expression of primary vitamin D target genes in peripheral blood mononuclear cells and adipose tissue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Response to high dose vitamin D is limited by vitamin A</title><link>/posts/response-to-high-dose-vitamin-d-is-limited-by-vitamin-a.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/response-to-high-dose-vitamin-d-is-limited-by-vitamin-a.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>UVA decreased vitamin D levels (again)</title><link>/posts/uva-decreased-vitamin-d-levels-again.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uva-decreased-vitamin-d-levels-again.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="phototherapy-with-uvb-narrowband-uvauvbnb-and-uva1-differentially-impacts-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3">Phototherapy with UVB narrowband, UVA/UVBnb, and UVA1 differentially impacts serum 25-hydroxyvitamin-D3.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Am Acad Dermatol. 2013 Jul 11. pii: S0190-9622(13)00539-2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/0.1016/j.jaad.2013.04.058.">doi: 0.1016/j.jaad.2013.04.058.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feldmeyer L, Shojaati G, Spanaus KS, Navarini A, Theler B, Donghi D, Urosevic-Maiwald M, Glatz M, Imhof L, Barysch MJ, Dummer R, Roos M, French LE, Surber C, Hofbauer GF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, University Hospital Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:laurence.feldmeyer@chuv.ch">laurence.feldmeyer@chuv.ch&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Ultraviolet (UV) B radiation increases serum 25-hydroxyvitamin-D3 &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>, but the influence of UVA1 and UVA/narrowband UVB (UVBnb) phototherapy on serum vitamin D is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnesium may not be as available if have low stomach acid (seniors)</title><link>/posts/magnesium-may-not-be-as-available-if-have-low-stomach-acid-seniors.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/magnesium-may-not-be-as-available-if-have-low-stomach-acid-seniors.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>30 percent of variation of vitamin D levels were associated with just 3 variables</title><link>/posts/30-percent-of-variation-of-vitamin-d-levels-were-associated-with-just-3-variables.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/30-percent-of-variation-of-vitamin-d-levels-were-associated-with-just-3-variables.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="determinants-of-vitamin-d-status-in-fair-skinned-women-of-childbearing-age-at-northern-latitudes">Determinants of Vitamin D Status in Fair-Skinned Women of Childbearing Age at Northern Latitudes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(4): e60864. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0060864&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Linnea Hedlund, Petra Brembeck, Hanna Olausson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and Objective: Poor vitamin D status during pregnancy has been associated with unfavorable outcomes for mother and child. Thus, adequate vitamin D status in women of childbearing age may be important. The aim of this study is to investigate the determinants of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) serum concentrations in women of childbearing age living in Sweden, at latitude 57–58° north.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Global analysis of disability - most are associated with vitamin D deficiency - Lancet</title><link>/posts/global-analysis-of-disability-most-are-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-lancet.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/global-analysis-of-disability-most-are-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-lancet.html</guid><description>&lt;p>A huge analysis of Disability around the world was made for the periods of 1990 and 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was a huge increase in the number of years of disability from most health problems&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The report was published in &lt;a href="http://www.thelancet.com/themed/global-burden-of-disease">Lancet&lt;/a> in Dec 2012 7 large articles behind paywall&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="i-classfas-fa-file-pdf-stylemargin-right-03emia-hrefhttpsd378j1rmrlek7xcloudfrontnetattachmentspdfglobal-burden-2013---dec-2014pdfdownload-the-2014-pdf-from-vitamindwikia">&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/global-burden-2013---dec-2014.pdf">Download the 2014 PDF from VitaminDWiki.&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="on-line-arrow-diagramshttpvizhubhealthdataorgirankarrowphp-has-the-full-database">&lt;a href="http://vizhub.healthdata.org/irank/arrow.php">On-line Arrow Diagrams&lt;/a> has the full database&lt;/h4>
&lt;h2 id="causes-of-disability-age-70-74">Causes of Disability: age 70-74&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/disability-70.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>The list is in order of the most disability to the least (e.g. back pain is the largest cause)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese need more Vitamin D: Volume dilution, IU per pound, or BMI – RCT</title><link>/posts/obese-need-more-vitamin-d-volume-dilution-iu-per-pound-or-bmi-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-need-more-vitamin-d-volume-dilution-iu-per-pound-or-bmi-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-serum-25ohd-in-thin-and-obese-women">The Effect Of Vitamin D Supplementation On Serum 25OHD In Thin And Obese Women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology,2012.12.003&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. Christopher Gallagher a &lt;a href="mailto:jcg@creighton.edu">jcg@creighton.edu&lt;/a>, Vinod Yalamanchili a , Lynette M. Smith b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Bone Metabolism Unit, Creighton University Medical Center, Omaha, Nebraska&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Public Health, University of Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha, Nebraska&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obese people are known to have lower serum 25OHD levels compared to non-obese people. It is not known whether it is due to storage of vitamin D in fat, inadequate input from sunlight, diet or other unknown factors. We examined the relationship at study baseline of serum 25OHD, PTH, 1,25(OH)2D with body composition measurements using Dual energy X-ray Absorptiometry. The results showed a significant inverse relation between total body fat mass and serum 25OHD (p &amp;lt; 0.0001) and serum 1,25(OH2)D (p = 034) and an independent positive correlation between serum PTH and total body fat mass (p &amp;lt; 0.0001). In a randomized controlled study of seven doses of vitamin D (400-4800IU/d) the increase in serum 25OHD levels was compared in women with a normal body mass index to obese women. The response to the low doses of vitamin D (400-800IU/d) was significantly less than that of the medium (1600-2400IU/d) and high doses groups (3200-4800IU) (p &amp;lt; 0.0001) in all BMI categories. The increase in serum 25OHD in the medium and high dose groups was not significantly different with increasing level of obesity. But thinner women with a normal BMI (&amp;lt; 25 kg/m2) showed a much higher response to vitamin D at any dose level compared to other BMI groups. There was no significant change in total body fat mass after treatment with vitamin D or calcitriol in our randomized trials. In summary, the response to vitamin D is dependent on body weight. Women with BMI &amp;lt;25 kg/m2 develop much higher levels of serum 25OHD after vitamin D supplementation compared to those with BMI of &amp;gt;25 kg/m2 .The differences in serum 25OHD levels between normal and obese women may be due to differences in volume dilution. After vitamin D supplementation, all obese women reach adequate levels of serum 25OHD but normal women (BMI &amp;lt; 25 kg/m2) reach much higher levels of 25OHD and in this group smaller doses of vitamin D used should be used.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Timeline of Heart Disease, Diabetes, fats, lard, HFCS, and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/timeline-of-heart-disease-diabetes-fats-lard-hfcs-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/timeline-of-heart-disease-diabetes-fats-lard-hfcs-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#subset-of--illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015httpdietheartnewscom201208illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-201520-diet-heart-news-aug-2012">Subset of &lt;a href="http://dietheartnews.com/2012/08/illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015/%20">Illustrated History of Heart Disease 1825-2015&lt;/a> Diet Heart News Aug 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-trans-fats">See also trans-fats&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#more-cholesterol-is-associated-with-fewer-deaths---around-the-entire-world">MORE cholesterol is associated with FEWER deaths - around the entire world&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsoverview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-889overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-da-has-the-following-chart">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 889">Overview Deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/a> has the following chart&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="subset-of--illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015httpdietheartnewscom201208illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-201520-diet-heart-news-aug-2012">Subset of &lt;a href="http://dietheartnews.com/2012/08/illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015/%20">Illustrated History of Heart Disease 1825-2015&lt;/a> Diet Heart News Aug 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Note: &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">lard&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">butter&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> used to have lots of vitamin D and &lt;a href="/categories/omega-3">Omega-3&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1910&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Lifetime risk of type II diabetes was 1 in 30; today 1 in 3&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1910&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">butter&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> consumption = 18 pounds per capita – mortality from heart disease was below 10 percent.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1910&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Lard, the rendered fat from outdoor-living pigs, was the #1 cooking fat – enjoying 70 % of the market. &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">lard was the best source of Vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1911&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Proctor &amp;amp; Gamble introduce Crisco,&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1912&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Dr. James B. Herrick first described a form of heart disease he called “hardening of the arteries.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1924&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>American Heart Association (AHA) – founded.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1937&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Biochemists demonstrated that dietary cholesterol had very little effect on blood cholesterol. Never refuted&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1949&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Arterioslcerosis is added to the International Classification of Diseases (ICD), causing a sharp increase in reported deaths from heart disease&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1950&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Discovered several fat-like substances circulating in the blood, including LDL and VLDL. &lt;br>Reported that total cholesterol (TC) was a “dangerously poor predictor” of heart disease.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1951&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Ancel Keys, professor, University of Minnesota, attends a conference in Rome on nutrition and disease and learns that heart disease was rare in some Mediterranean populations who consumed a lower fat diet. He noted, too, that the Japanese had low fat diets and low rates of heart disease. He hypothesized from these observations that fat was the cause of heart disease.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1953&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Ancel Keys, convinced that dietary fat is the cause of heart disease, published his Six Country Analysis, suggesting an association between dietary fat and mortality from heart disease. &lt;strong>Critics pointed out that Keys had data for 22 countries, but selected data from just 6&lt;/strong> .&lt;br> (As an example, Keys excluded France, a country with a high fat diet and low rates of heart disease.) Keys selected data – he cheated!&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1956&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>American Heart Association (conducts a nationwide fundraiser on all three TV networks urging Americans to reduce their intake of total fat, saturated fat, and cholesterol.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1957&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Margarine outsold &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">butter&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> for the first time. Has no vitamin D and Excess Omega-6&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1961&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Framingham Heart Study (data from five years). Men under 50 with elevated cholesterol were at greater risk of heart disease. &lt;strong>However, this group of vulnerable middle-aged men were also more likely to smoke, be overweight, and not exercise&lt;/strong> – the famous Framingham “risk factors” and elevated cholesterol was at the top of the list.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1973&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>American Medical Association (AMA) attacks Dr. Atkins calling his high fat diet a “dangerous fraud.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1976&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>FDA gives GRAS status (generally regarded as safe) to hydrogenated soybean oil – even though lipid biochemist Mary Enig, PhD, warned the government that – among their many dangers – &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">trans fats&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> interfere with insulin receptors on cell membranes and thereby increase the risk of diabetes.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1977&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>“All hell broke loose!” in Washington DC after the proposed guidelines were released. Major players - like the American Medical Association – and scientists in federal government agencies were aghast at what McGovern and his staff of non-scientists had come up with. At this juncture, McGovern was forced to schedule six additional hearings.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1978&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>High fructose corn syrup (HFCS) enters the sweetener market.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1980&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>U.S. Department of Agriculture released the official first ever low fat Dietary Guidelines for Americans. &lt;br>In bold face on the cover: “EAT LESS FAT, SATURATED FAT, AND CHOLESTEROL.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1984&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Anthony Gotto, president, American Heart Association, said, “If everyone went ahead with cholesterol-lowering, we will conquer atherosclerosis by the year 2000.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1986&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>For the first time blood cholesterol over 200 mg/dl is treated as a disease.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1986&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>U.S. declared “War on Cholesterol,”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1987&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Another ignored finding in the Framingham Heart Study: “Framingham residents whose cholesterol levels declined over the first 14 years were more likely to die prematurely of heart disease and cancer than those whose cholesterol remained the same or increased.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1987&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Mevacor, the first cholesterol-lowering &lt;strong>statin&lt;/strong> drug, was approved in record time.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1988&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Surgeon General’s :“Highest priority is given to reducing fat intake.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1988&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>After 20 years researching carbohydrate metabolism, Gerald Reavan, MD, University of California, announces his discovery of “Syndrome X,” now referred to as Metabolic Syndrome or diabetes-related heart disease. Syndrome X is a cluster of abnormalities, including high blood sugar, high insulin levels, elevated triglycerides, and depressed protective HDL.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1990&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>In the year 2000, the CDC reported that the lifetime risk of diabetes is now 1 in 3.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1999&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>At the 14 year point in the Harvard Nurses Study, 3,000 nurses had developed cancer. According to study leader Walter Willett, the &lt;strong>less fat the nurses ate the greater their risk of cancer.&lt;/strong> Willett said, “Saturated fat seems to be protective…&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2000&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Nutritious &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">lard&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> consumption: Less than 1 pound per capita.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2000&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Sugar&lt;/strong> consumption in the US reaches 150 pounds per capita – most of it HFCS&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2000&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Butter consumption in the US goes below 4 pounds per capita.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2000&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Well over $1 billion has been spent on trials focusing on lowering LDL cholesterol.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2002&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>What if It’s All Been a Big Fat Lie? – Gary Taubes’ New York Times magazine cover story (July 07, 2002) signaled that after three decades low-fat could be on its way out. Taubes pointed out that the &lt;strong>science behind low fat was never proven and was actually based on “a leap of faith”&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2005&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>More than 30 percent of all Americans are clinically obese&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2005&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">butter&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> is making a comeback! For the first time since 1957, butter outsells margarine&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-trans-fats">See also trans-fats&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/05/22/well/the-worst-fat-in-the-food-supply.html">The Worst Fat in the Food Supply&lt;/a> NYT May 2017&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>