<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Growing Pains on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/growing-pains.html</link><description>Recent content in Growing Pains on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/growing-pains/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leg cramps in pregnant women not changed by 1,000 IU of vitamin D for 6 weeks (no surprise) – RCT</title><link>/posts/leg-cramps-in-pregnant-women-not-changed-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-6-weeks-no-surprise-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/leg-cramps-in-pregnant-women-not-changed-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-6-weeks-no-surprise-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-plus-vitamin-d-on-leg-cramps-in-pregnant-women-a-randomized-controlled-trial">The effect of Vitamin D and calcium plus Vitamin D on leg cramps in pregnant women: A randomized controlled trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>{http://jrms.mui.ac.ir/index.php/jrms/article/view/10603 |Journal of Research in Medical Science]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ameneh Mansouri, Mojgan Mirghafourvand, Sakineh Mohammad Alizadeh Charandabi, Moslem Najafi&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>It is very unlikely that only 1,000 IU for only 6 weeks could improve any condition&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is an interesting idea however.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/restless-legs-syndrome-vitamin-d-iron-etc-many-studies">Restless Legs Syndrome - Vitamin D, Iron, etc. - many studies&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UK (SACN) is ignoring scores of Vitamin D studies</title><link>/posts/uk-sacn-is-ignoring-scores-of-vitamin-d-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uk-sacn-is-ignoring-scores-of-vitamin-d-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>UK has proposed very inadequate vitamin D levels and has asked for comments&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/draft-sacn-vitamin-d-and-health-report.pdf">Download the SACN draft from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/uk-proposes-that-10-ng-level-and-400-iu-is-enough-vitamin-d-for-everybody-no-and-no">UK proposes that 10 ng level and 400 IU is enough Vitamin D for everybody (no and no)- July 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://anh-europe.org/2015/09/23/uk-government-committee-side-lines-new-vitamin-d-science/">UK Govt committee side line new Vitamin D Science&lt;/a> Sept 2015&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;ANH-Intl has filed a submission which is deeply critical of the bottom line recommendation, which &lt;strong>remains unchanged from previous reviews going back to 1991.&lt;/strong> &amp;quot;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Benefits of vitamin D experienced then described by retired Biologist</title><link>/posts/benefits-of-vitamin-d-experienced-then-described-by-retired-biologist.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/benefits-of-vitamin-d-experienced-then-described-by-retired-biologist.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Retired German Biologist had typical problems of elderly&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/goering.jpg" alt="image" width="200">
&lt;p>He got lots of vitamin D in 2013 and his health problems went way&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He currently takes 50,000 IU vitamin D3 weekly&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He researched vitamin D (while retired)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He published the following excellent Vitamin D overview in 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Appears that the overview was also published in Russian&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many excellent ideas and observations &lt;strong>(VitaminDWiki has bolded some of them)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This version uses an incorrect English word &amp;lt; 1% of the time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Growing pains associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/growing-pains-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/growing-pains-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-korean-children-presenting-with-nonspecific-lower-extremity-pain">Prevalence of Vitamin D Deficiency in Korean Children Presenting with Nonspecific Lower-Extremity Pain.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Yonsei Med J. 2015 Sep;56(5):1384-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3349/ymj.2015.56.5.1384.">doi: 10.3349/ymj.2015.56.5.1384.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Park MJ1, Lee J2, Lee JK2, Joo SY3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although interest in the role played by vitamin D in bone health is increasing, little is known about the role of this vitamin in musculoskeletal pain in children. This study aimed to assess the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in children presenting with nonspecific lower extremity pains.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Growing pains reduced 60 percent by monthly Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/growing-pains-reduced-60-percent-by-monthly-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/growing-pains-reduced-60-percent-by-monthly-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="significant-association-among-growing-pains-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-bone-mineral-status-results-from-a-pilot-cohort-study">Significant association among growing pains, vitamin D supplementation, and bone mineral status: results from a pilot cohort study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Metab. 2014 Mar 15. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morandi G1 &lt;a href="mailto:grazia.morandi@gmail.com">grazia.morandi@gmail.com&lt;/a>, Maines E, Piona C, Monti E, Sandri M, Gaudino R, Boner A, Antoniazzi F.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>Initial growing pain level &lt;strong>7.5&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D supplementation for 3 months&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D levels increased to 34 ng (an OK level)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Growing pain level dropped to &lt;strong>2.7&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Restless legs syndrome 5X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/restless-legs-syndrome-5x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/restless-legs-syndrome-5x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="possible-association-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-restless-legs-syndrome">Possible association between vitamin D deficiency and restless legs syndrome&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Neuropsychiatric Disease and Treatment 21 May 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mustafa Oran1 cuneyt Unsal2 Yakup Albayrak2 Feti Tulubas3 Keriman Oguz4 Okan Avci1 Nilda Turgut4 Recep Alp4 Ahmet Gurel3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Department of internal Medicine, 2Department of Psychiatry, 3Department of Biochemistry, 4Department of Neurology, Namik Kemal University, Faculty of Medicine, Tekirdag, Turkey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Mustafa Oran Department of Internal Medicine, School of Medicine, Namik Kemal University, Tunca Caddesi, Tekirdag, 59100, Turkey Tel +90 542 388 4317 Fax +90 282 250 0001 Email &lt;a href="mailto:oranmmd@yahoo.com">oranmmd@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Liverpool is starting universal supplementation and needs high dose vitamin D</title><link>/posts/liverpool-is-starting-universal-supplementation-and-needs-high-dose-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/liverpool-is-starting-universal-supplementation-and-needs-high-dose-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-testing-three-important-issues-letter">Vitamin D testing: three important issues (letter)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>British Journal of General Practice March 1, 2014 vol. 64 no. 620 124&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katy Gardner: GP and Clinical Lead for Vitamin D, Liverpool, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:katyagardner@btinternet.com">katyagardner@btinternet.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen Zhao: Rheumatology trainee Aintree University Hospital, Liverpool, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Liverpool we are auditing vitamin D testing and prescribing in primary care, following guidelines issued to GPs in early 2012 to encourage evidenced based testing and prescribing.1 Our data indicates that some GPs are testing in an increasingly non-targeted way. GPs in Liverpool ordered over £100 000 worth of vitamin D tests in 2012, over 10 times the amount spent in 2007. Though more people were identified as deficient, the proportion of deficient results identified decreased significantly. We feel guidance from NICE is needed for detection and treatment of vitamin D deficiency in primary care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Restless legs and growing pains may be both due to low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/restless-legs-and-growing-pains-may-be-both-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/restless-legs-and-growing-pains-may-be-both-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="restless-legs-syndrome-willis-ekbom-disease-and-growing-pains-are-they-the-same-thing">Restless legs syndrome (Willis-Ekbom disease) and growing pains: are they the same thing?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A side-by-side comparison of the diagnostic criteria for both and recommendations for future research&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sleep Medicine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arthur S. Walters a, &lt;a href="mailto:Arthur.Walters@Vanderbilt.edu">Arthur.Walters@Vanderbilt.edu&lt;/a>; David Gabelia b, Birgit Frauscher b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Neurology, Sleep Division, Vanderbilt University School of Medicine, Nashville, Tennessee, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Neurology, Innsbruck Medical University, Innsbruck, Austria&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been no previous side-by-side comparison of the diagnostic criteria for restless legs syndrome (RLS)(Willis-Ekbom disease) and growing pains. In our review, we explore this comparison emphasizing overlaps and disconnects, summarize recent literature exploring the relationship between the 2 entities, and make suggestions for future research.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epigenetics, vitamin D, and Multiple Sclerosis</title><link>/posts/epigenetics-vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/epigenetics-vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epigenetic-changes-in-patients-with-multiple-sclerosis---nov-2012">Epigenetic changes in patients with multiple sclerosis - Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epigenetics---is-it-real-new-york-times-review-of-plos-genetics-article---july-2016">Epigenetics - is it real: New York Times review of PLOS Genetics article - July 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="epigenetic-changes-in-patients-with-multiple-sclerosis---nov-2012">Epigenetic changes in patients with multiple sclerosis - Nov 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Neurol. 2012 Nov 20. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2012.226.">doi: 10.1038/nrneurol.2012.226.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Koch MW, Metz LM, Kovalchuk O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Calgary, Foothills Hospital, 1403-29th Street N. W., Calgary, AB T2N 2T9, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epigenetic changes influence gene expression without altering the DNA sequence. DNA methylation, histone modification and microRNA-associated post-transcriptional gene silencing are three key epigenetic mechanisms. Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a disease of the CNS with both inflammatory and neurodegenerative features. Although studies on epigenetic changes in MS only began in the past decade, a growing body of literature suggests that epigenetic changes may be involved in the development of MS, possibly by mediating the effects of environmental risk factors, such as&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Infant-Child</title><link>/posts/infant-child.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/infant-child.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#overview">Overview&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#search-terms-for-children-and-vitamin-d---may-2021">Search terms for Children and Vitamin D - May 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h4>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>No consensus on MINIMUM International Units (IU) for healthy infant of normal weight&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>400 IU Vitamin D is no longer enough&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Was OK in the past century, but D levels have been dropping for a great many reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/fda-doubles-the-amount-of-vitamin-d-permitted-in-milk">FDA doubles the amount of vitamin D permitted in milk – July 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>No consensus: range is 600 to 1600 IU – based on many randomized controlled trials&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D from low-cost UVB lamps</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-from-low-cost-uvb-lamps.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-from-low-cost-uvb-lamps.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolorf00must-wear-glasses-when-near-uvb---it-can-damage-your-eyes-perhaps-within-minutesspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Must wear glasses when near UVB - it can damage your eyes, perhaps within minutes.&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Plastic contact lenses might pass UVB unless you have paid for UV blocking feature&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without UV blocking contacts you must wear glasses/ski goggles/whatever if you might look at the bulb&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Light years2 - out of business - Update Jan 2019&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>Founder of VitaminDWiki bought a GE lamp fixture Jan 2019 and used UVB bulk from previous Light Year 2 fixture&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>