<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gastric Cancer on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/gastric-cancer.html</link><description>Recent content in Gastric Cancer on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/gastric-cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bibliography of Black-White health disparities linked to vitamin D - Dr. Grant</title><link>/posts/bibliography-of-black-white-health-disparities-linked-to-vitamin-d-dr-grant.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bibliography-of-black-white-health-disparities-linked-to-vitamin-d-dr-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="william-b-grant-phd--wbgrantinfionlinenet">William B. Grant, Ph.D. &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I prepared this bibliography in order to see the level of acceptance for vitamin D affecting health outcomes for black Americans. (I omitted papers on bone health.) My impression is that it is not very well accepted. One reason given by researchers is that most of the vitamin D studies were performed on white, not black people. Another likely reason is that most of the studies are ecological or observational in nature, not from clinical trials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gastric Cancer 8.8 times more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/gastric-cancer-88-times-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gastric-cancer-88-times-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">Second study on this page shows that increased stage of Gastric Cancer is associated with decreased vitamin D levels&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="association-between-serum-vitamin-d-levels-and-gastric-cancer-a-retrospective-chart-analysis">Association between serum vitamin D levels and gastric cancer: A retrospective chart analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>World J Gastrointest Oncol. 2016 Sep 15;8(9):688-94. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4251/wjgo.v8.i9.688.">doi: 10.4251/wjgo.v8.i9.688.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vyas N1, Companioni RC1, Tiba M1, Alkhawam H1, Catalano C1, Sogomonian R1, Baum J1, Walfish A1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Neil Vyas, Hassan Alkhawam, Carmine Catalano, Robert Sogomonian, Department of Internal Medicine, Elmhurst Hospital Center, Elmhurst, NY 11373, United States.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Majority of heritable diseases are associated with vitamin D (from 4 million health records)</title><link>/posts/majority-of-heritable-diseases-are-associated-with-vitamin-d-from-4-million-health-records.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/majority-of-heritable-diseases-are-associated-with-vitamin-d-from-4-million-health-records.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="estimate-of-disease-heritability-using-47-million-familial-relationships-inferred-from-electronic-health-records">Estimate of disease heritability using 4.7 million familial relationships inferred from electronic health records&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>bioRxiv preprint first posted online Jul. 28, 2016&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/health-problems-that-run-in-families-are-often-associated-with-low-vitamin-d">Health problems that run in families are often associated with low vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note: Association can be due to low blood levels and/or poor Vitamin D genes&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Reasons for low response to vitamin D">Reasons for low response to vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – Chemotherapy can be aided by Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-chemotherapy-can-be-aided-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-chemotherapy-can-be-aided-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dna-repair-in-despair-vitamin-d-is-not-fair">DNA Repair in Despair-Vitamin D Is not Fair&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="dna-repair-in-despair-vitamin-d-is-not-fair">DNA Repair in Despair-Vitamin D Is not Fair&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Cellular Biochemistry, DOI: 10.1002/jcb.25552&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elżbieta Gocek, George P. Studzinski &lt;a href="mailto:studzins@njms.rutgers.edu">studzins@njms.rutgers.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of vitamin D as a treatment option for neoplastic diseases, once considered to have a bright future, remains controversial. The preclinical studies discussed herein show compelling evidence that Vitamin D Derivatives (VDDs) can convert some cancer and leukemia cells to a benign phenotype, by differentiation/maturation, cell cycle arrest or induction of apoptosis. Further, there is considerable, though still evolving, knowledge of the molecular mechisms underlying these changes. However, the attempts to clearly document that the treatment outcomes of human neoplastic diseases can be positively influenced by VDDs have been, so far, disappointing. The clinical trials to date of VDDs, alone or combined with other agents, have not shown consistent results. It is our contention, shared by others, that there were limitations in the design or execution of these trials which have not yet been fully addressed. Based on the connection between upregulation of JNK by VDDs and DNA repair, &lt;strong>we propose a new avenue of attack on cancer cells by increasing the toxicity of the current, only partially effective, cancer chemotherapeutic drugs by combining them with VDDs&lt;/strong> . This can impair DNA repair and thus kill the malignant cells, warranting a comprehensive study of this novel concept.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Cannabis and disease studies at GreenMedInfo</title><link>/posts/off-topic-cannabis-and-disease-studies-at-greenmedinfo.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-cannabis-and-disease-studies-at-greenmedinfo.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="raw-cannabis-juice-helps-young-woman-ditch-40-medicationshttptvgreenmedinfocomraw-cannabis-juice-helps-young-woman-ditch-40-medications">&lt;a href="http://tv.greenmedinfo.com/raw-cannabis-juice-helps-young-woman-ditch-40-medications/">Raw Cannabis Juice Helps Young Woman Ditch 40 Medications&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note – There is a BIG difference between cannabis products&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most research - such as in the table below does not distinguish between THC and CBD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell :It appears that&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>| | | |
| &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; |
| | THC | CBD |
| Benefit | Get high | Pain relief |
| Typical cannabis | 50% | 50% |
| High-grade cannabis | 90% | 10% |
| Pain relief cannabis | 5% | 95% |
| Legal in US states | &amp;lt;10% | 100% |&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Receptor</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor.html</guid><description>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It appears that 1/3 of everyone with a vitamin D-related disease has a poor VDR&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A poor VDR cannot be detected by any standard Vitamin D test (nor Calcitriol nor Calcidiol)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A poor Parathyroid VDR can be detected when high Calcitriol levels fail to decrease PTH levels&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Decreasing PTH shows Vitamin D is getting to Parathyroid - but says nothing about VDRs elsewhere&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Many cancers and viruses have learned to protect themselves by deactivating the local VDR&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Role of vitamins in gastrointestinal diseases – review</title><link>/posts/role-of-vitamins-in-gastrointestinal-diseases-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/role-of-vitamins-in-gastrointestinal-diseases-review.html</guid><description>&lt;p>World J Gastroenterol. 2015 May 7; 21(17): 5191–5209., &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3748/wjg.v21.i17.5191">doi: 10.3748/wjg.v21.i17.5191&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omar A Masri, Jean M Chalhoub, and Ala I Sharara&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A tremendous amount of data from research was published over the past decades concerning the roles of different vitamins in various gastrointestinal diseases. For instance, most vitamins showed an inverse relationship with the risk of colorectal carcinoma as well as other malignancies like gastric and esophageal cancer in observational trials, however interventional trials failed to prove a clear beneficial preventive role. On the other hand, more solid evidence was obtained from high quality studies for a role of certain vitamins in specific entities. Examples for this include the&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antibiotics and Vitamin D are associated with many of the same diseases</title><link>/posts/antibiotics-and-vitamin-d-are-associated-with-many-of-the-same-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/antibiotics-and-vitamin-d-are-associated-with-many-of-the-same-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="misc-notes-from-the-book-missing-microbes">Misc. notes from the book Missing Microbes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>100 &lt;strong>Million&lt;/strong> neurons in gut (vs 100 &lt;strong>Billion&lt;/strong> neurons in adult brain)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Author is very concerned about increased antibiotics ==&amp;gt; increased disease&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Author is extremely concerned about antibiotic resistance ==&amp;gt; world-wide pandemic - far worse than any in the past 500 years&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>17 antibiotic courses by age 20 in the US now (varies a lot with which state you live in - see map below)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chemotherapy (cisplatin) and vitamin D synergistically stop stomach cancer</title><link>/posts/chemotherapy-cisplatin-and-vitamin-d-synergistically-stop-stomach-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chemotherapy-cisplatin-and-vitamin-d-synergistically-stop-stomach-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3-and-cisplatin-synergistically-induce-apoptosis-and-cell-cycle-arrest-in-gastric-cancer-cells">1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D3 and cisplatin synergistically induce apoptosis and cell cycle arrest in gastric cancer cells.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Mol Med. 2014 Feb 24. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3892/ijmm.2014.1664.">doi: 10.3892/ijmm.2014.1664.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bao A 1, Li Y 1, Tong Y 1, Zheng H 1, Wu W 1, Wei C 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Clinical Laboratory, Renmin Hospital of Wuhan University, Wuhan, Hubei 430060, P.R. China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Clinical Laboratory, Affiliated Hospital of Youjiang Medical University for Nationalities, Baise, Guangxi 533000, P.R. China.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D proven to treat or prevent many cancers in animals, but only breast cancer in humans so far</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-proven-to-treat-or-prevent-many-cancers-in-animals-but-only-breast-cancer-in-humans-so-far.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-proven-to-treat-or-prevent-many-cancers-in-animals-but-only-breast-cancer-in-humans-so-far.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#chen-abstract">Chen Abstract&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-the-promise-not-yet-fulfilled">Vitamin D and cancer: the promise not yet fulfilled&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocrine. 2014 Jan 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bikle DD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The negative association of the latitude where people live and the incidence of non cutaneous cancer in that population in North America have been demonstrated in many studies for many types of cancer. Since the intensity of UVB exposure decreases with increasing latitude, and UVB exposure provides the mechanism for vitamin D production in the skin, the hypothesis that increased vitamin D provides protection against the development of cancer has been proposed. This hypothesis has been tested in a substantial number of prospective and case control studies and in a few randomized clinical trials (RTC) assessing whether either vitamin D intake or serum levels of 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) correlate (inversely) with cancer development. Most of the studies have focused on colorectal, breast, and prostate cancer. The results have been mixed. The most compelling data for a beneficial relationship between vitamin D intake or serum 25OHD levels and cancer have been obtained for colorectal cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer and low vitamin D – which causes which</title><link>/posts/cancer-and-low-vitamin-d-which-causes-which.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-and-low-vitamin-d-which-causes-which.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-inverse-relationship-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-cáncer-survival-discussion-of-causation">The Inverse Relationship between 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Cáncer Survival: Discussion of Causation&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#review-of-survival-studies">Review of Survival Studies&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#figure-1-hazard-ratios">Figure 1. Hazard Ratios&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#breast-cancer">Breast Cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#colorectal-cancer">Colorectal Cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#prostate-cancer">Prostate Cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#lung-cancer">Lung Cancer&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hematologic-cancers">Hematologic Cancers&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#other-cancers">Other Cancers&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#discussion">Discussion&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#31temporality">3.1Temporality&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#32-strength-and-exposure-response-relationship">3.2 Strength and Exposure-Response Relationship&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biological-plausibility">Biological Plausibility&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#consistency">Consistency&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reversibility">Reversibility&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#coherence">Coherence&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#4-conclusions">4. Conclusions&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references-and-tables-are-in-pdf-at-bottom-of-this-page">References and tables are in PDF at bottom of this page&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="the-inverse-relationship-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-cáncer-survival-discussion-of-causation">The Inverse Relationship between 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Cáncer Survival: Discussion of Causation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cancers 2013, 5, 1439-1455; doi:10.3390/cancers5041439&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer incidence in 87 countries is related to food, smoking, alcohol, GDP, and UVB</title><link>/posts/cancer-incidence-in-87-countries-is-related-to-food-smoking-alcohol-gdp-and-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-incidence-in-87-countries-is-related-to-food-smoking-alcohol-gdp-and-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;div>
&lt;p>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2014, 6, 163-189; doi:10.3390/nu6010163&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="font-size:14px;">A Multicountry Ecological Study of Cáncer Incidence Rates in 2008 with Respect to Various Risk-Modifying Factors&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p align="left">
&lt;p>Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, P.O. Box 641603, San Francisco, CA 94164-1603, USA; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">&lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/a>; Tel.: +1-415-409-1980&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;p>Received: 6 November 2013; in revised form: 12 December 2013 /Accepted: 14 December 2013 / Published: 27 December 2013&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p style="margin-left:.4in;">
&lt;p>Abstract: Observational and ecological studies are generally used to determine the presence of effect of cancer risk-modifying factors. Researchers generally agree that environmental factors such as smoking, alcohol consumption, poor diet, lack of physical activity, and low serum 25-hdyroxyvitamin D levels are important cancer risk factors. This ecological study used age-adjusted incidence rates for 21 cancers for 157 countries (87 with high-quality data) in 2008 with respect to dietary supply and other factors, including per capita gross domestic product, life expectancy, lung cancer incidence rate (an index for smoking), and latitude (an index for solar ultraviolet-B doses). The factors found to correlate strongly with multiple types of cancer were lung cancer (direct correlation with 12 types of cancer), energy derived from animal products (direct correlation with 12 types of cancer, inverse with two), latitude (direct correlation with six types, inverse correlation with three), and per capita gross national product (five types). Life expectancy and sweeteners directly correlated with three cancers, animal fat with two, and alcohol with one. Consumption of animal products correlated with cancer incidence with a lag time of 15-25 years. Types of cancer which correlated strongly with animal product consumption, tended to correlate weakly with latitude; this occurred for 11 cancers for the entire set of countries. Regression results were somewhat different for the 87 high-quality country data set and the 157-country set. Single-country ecological studies have inversely correlated nearly all of these cancers with solar ultraviolet-B doses. These results can provide guidance for prevention of cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer Survival is poor if vitamin D is less than 20ng (every study showed benefit)– review</title><link>/posts/cancer-survival-is-poor-if-vitamin-d-is-less-than-20ng-every-study-showed-benefit-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-survival-is-poor-if-vitamin-d-is-less-than-20ng-every-study-showed-benefit-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-inverse-relationship-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-cancer-survival-discussion-of-causation">The Inverse Relationship between 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Cancer Survival: Discussion of Causation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancers 2013, 5(4), 1439-1455; doi:10.3390/cancers5041439&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trude E. Robsahm 1 &lt;a href="mailto:trude.eid.robsahm@kreftregisteret.no">trude.eid.robsahm@kreftregisteret.no&lt;/a> , Gary G. Schwartz 2 and Steinar Tretli 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 The Cancer Registry of Norway, Institute of Population-based Cancer Research, Oslo 0304, Norway 2 Departments of Cancer Biology, Urology, and Epidemiology and Prevention, Wake Forest University Baptist Medical Center, Winston-Salem, NC 27157, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received: 22 September 2013; in revised form: 22 October 2013 / Accepted: 24 October 2013 / Published: 5 November 2013&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 to 55 X more likely to have these health problems if low Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/3-to-55-x-more-likely-to-have-these-health-problems-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-to-55-x-more-likely-to-have-these-health-problems-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Many health problems associated with low vitamin D&lt;br>
        click to read the studies&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/bone-fractures-in-children-requiring-surgery-were-55x-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d">&lt;strong>55 X&lt;/strong> more likely to have &lt;strong>&lt;del>#00F:bone fracture requiring surgery&lt;/del>&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/copd-becoming-suddenly-worse-is-30x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d">&lt;strong>30 X&lt;/strong> more likely for &lt;strong>&lt;del>#00F:COPD becoming suddenly worse&lt;/del>&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/25-x-more-likely-to-have-span-stylecolor00fsenior-momentspan" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2415"> &lt;strong>25 X&lt;/strong> more likely to have &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">senior moment&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> &lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/23-x-more-likely-to-have-span-stylecolor00fvertigospan" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 3460"> &lt;strong>23 X&lt;/strong> more likely to have &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">vertigo&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> &lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chinese have very low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chinese-have-very-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chinese-have-very-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="updatea-hrefpostsvitamin-d-levels-are-correlated-with-6-environmental-variables-in-china-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-vitamin-d-levels-are-correlated-with-6-environmental-variables-in-china--july-2022vitamin-d-levels-are-correlated-with-6-environmental-variables-in-china--july-2022a">Update: &lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-levels-are-correlated-with-6-environmental-variables-in-china" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Vitamin D levels are correlated with 6 environmental variables in China – July 2022">Vitamin D levels are correlated with 6 environmental variables in China – July 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/map.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;h4 id="a-glimpse-of-vitamin-d-status-in-mainland-china">A glimpse of vitamin D status in Mainland China&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/journal/08999007">Nutrition&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/journal/08999007/29/7">Volume 29, Issues 7–8&lt;/a>, July–August 2013, Pages 953–957&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S089990071300052X#">Weiguo Zhang&lt;/a>, M.D., Ph.D.{ANAME()}bcor1|&lt;img src="http://cdn.els-cdn.com/sd/entities/REcor.gif" alt="image">{ANAME}&lt;sup>, &lt;/sup>,weiguo.zhang@dsm.com&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S089990071300052X#">Elisabeth Stoecklin&lt;/a>, M.D.,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S089990071300052X#">Manfred Eggersdorfer&lt;/a>, Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>DSM Nutritional Products, Human Nutrition and Health, Beijing, China and Kaiseraugst, Switzerland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: CVD: the primary cause of death in senior women, is increasing</title><link>/posts/off-topic-cvd-the-primary-cause-of-death-in-senior-women-is-increasing.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-cvd-the-primary-cause-of-death-in-senior-women-is-increasing.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="changing-long-held-beliefs-is-never-easy">Changing Long-Held Beliefs is Never Easy:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-proposal-for-multimodal-approaches-in-female-healthcare---an-integrative-view">A Proposal for Multimodal Approaches in Female Healthcare - An Integrative View&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The EPMA Journal 2012, 3:14 &lt;a href="http://www.epmajournal.eom/content/3/14">http://www.epmajournal.eom/content/3/14&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olga Golubnitschaja, Secretary-General of EPMA, and Vincenzo Costigliola, President of EPMA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>   {EPMA = European Association for Predictive, Preventive and Personalised Medicine.}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="worldwide-cardiovascular-disease-cvd-is-the-leading-cause-of-mortality-in-women-cardiovascular-health-in-females-is-not-improving-as-fast-as-that-of-males">Worldwide cardiovascular disease (CVD) is the leading cause of mortality in women: cardiovascular health in females is not improving as fast as that of males&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Worldwide a third of all deaths of women and &lt;strong>half of all deaths of women over 50 years old in developing countries are caused by CVD&lt;/strong> &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. Several studies have been recently dedicated to the question of CVD-related death with particular focus on gender-dependent aspects. Although CVD is traditionally considered as the major health burden of male subpopulations surprising statistics have been collected for worsening the situation in females. New trends obviously demonstrate a shifting of the problem into healthcare of female populations: from 25 countries selected by World Health Organisation in the years 1990-2000, more than a half (15 countries, 60%) currently demonstrate either increase in CVD-related death in females or, even if the rates are decreased then less compared to men &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>