<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sports and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/sports-and-vitamin-d.html</link><description>Recent content in Sports and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/sports-and-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fitness is associated with vitamin D, even accounting for BMI</title><link>/posts/fitness-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-even-accounting-for-bmi.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fitness-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-even-accounting-for-bmi.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cardiorespiratory-fitness-adiposity-and-serum-25-dihydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-women">Cardiorespiratory Fitness, Adiposity, and Serum 25-Dihydroxyvitamin D Levels in Women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Stephen W Farrell and Benjamin L Willis J Womens Health (Larchmt) () (2011) PMID 21970522&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2011 Oct 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cooper Institute , Dallas Texas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose: We examined the cross-sectional associations among cardiorespiratory fitness (CRF), different measures of adiposity, and serum vitamin D levels in women.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: Between 2007 and 2010, 1320 women completed a health examination. Measures included body mass index (BMI), waist circumference (WC), waist/hip ratio, percent body fat, CRF based on a maximal treadmill exercise test, and measurement of serum vitamin D. Participants were classified by CRF as unfit (lowest 20%) and fit (remaining 80%) based on age, as well as by clinical cutoff points for adiposity measures, and by categories of serum vitamin D. We examined trends of CRF and adiposity exposures across serum vitamin D categories. We calculated odds ratios (OR) of serum vitamin D insufficiency or deficiency across levels of adiposity exposures before and after adjustment for CRF.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Teenage knee injury 4X increase in last decade in Philadelphia</title><link>/posts/teenage-knee-injury-4x-increase-in-last-decade-in-philadelphia.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/teenage-knee-injury-4x-increase-in-last-decade-in-philadelphia.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="knee-injuries-on-the-rise-in-child-and-adolescent-athleteshttpmedicalxpresscomnews2011-10-knee-injuries-child-adolescent-athleteshtml">&lt;a href="http://medicalxpress.com/news/2011-10-knee-injuries-child-adolescent-athletes.html">Knee injuries on the rise in child and adolescent athletes&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clipped from Medical Express&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="knee-injuries-in-children-and-adolescents-has-there-been-an-increase-in-acl-and-meniscus-tears-in-recent-years">&amp;ldquo;Knee Injuries In Children and Adolescents: Has There Been An Increase In ACL and Meniscus Tears In Recent Years?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Academy of Pediatrics Oct 16, 2011 presentation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Researchers at the Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Philadelphia noted a more than 400 percent increase in these injuries at their institution over the last decade&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="suspect-slower-muscle-reaction-time-due-to-low-vitamin-d-levels">Suspect slower muscle reaction time due to low vitamin D levels&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d">Overview Sports and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Concussions (traumatic brain injury) getting big press coverage, vitamin D might be both a cause and a solution</title><link>/posts/concussions-traumatic-brain-injury-getting-big-press-coverage-vitamin-d-might-be--and-a-solution.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/concussions-traumatic-brain-injury-getting-big-press-coverage-vitamin-d-might-be--and-a-solution.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="reasons-to-associate-concussion-with-low-vitamind">Reasons to associate concussion with low vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Those people having concussions have lower vitamin D levels&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Increase in the number of concussions as vitamin D levels have dropped&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Giving vitamin D (and other supplements) shortens recovery time from concussions&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Giving vitamin D resulted in fewer concussions (football players)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="researchers-tie-gulf-war-illness-to-brain-damagehttpmusatodaycomarticlenewsnation1982817preferredarticleviewmodesingle-usa-today-march2013">&lt;a href="http://m.usatoday.com/article/news/nation/1982817?preferredArticleViewMode=single">Researchers tie Gulf War illness to brain damage&lt;/a> USA Today March 2013&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Using fMRI machines, the Georgetown University researchers could see anomalies in the bundle of nerve fibers that interpret pain signals in the brain in 31 Gulf War veterans. The research will be published Wednesday in PLOS ONE journal.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>CAUTION: The FMRI magnetic fields MAY substantially reduce the vitamin D levels - &lt;a href="/posts/update" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 4093">Update May 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Another outdoor sport produces more bone than indoor sport – vitamin D</title><link>/posts/another-outdoor-sport-produces-more-bone-than-indoor-sport-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/another-outdoor-sport-produces-more-bone-than-indoor-sport-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-badminton-and-ice-hockey-on-bone-mass-in-young-males-a-12-year-follow-up">Effects of badminton and ice hockey on bone mass in young males: a 12-year follow-up.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Bone. 2010 Sep;47(3):666-72. Epub 2010 Jun 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tervo T, Nordström P, Nordström A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Surgical and Perioperative Sciences, Sports Medicine, Umeå University, Umeå, Sweden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of the present study was to investigate the influence of different types of weight bearing physical activity on bone mineral density (BMD, g/cm(2)) and evaluate any residual benefits after the active sports career. Beginning at 17 years of age, BMD was measured 5 times, during 12 years, in 19 badminton players, 48 ice hockey players, and 25 controls. During the active career, badminton players gained significantly more BMD compared to ice hockey players at all sites: in their femoral neck (mean difference (Delta) 0.06 g/cm(2), p=0.04), humerus (Delta 0.06 g/cm(2), p=0.01), lumbar spine (Delta 0.08 g/cm(2), p=0.01), and their legs (Delta 0.05 g/cm(2), p=0.003), after adjusting for age at baseline, changes in weight, height, and active years. BMD gains in badminton players were higher also compared to in controls at all sites (Delta 0.06-0.17 g/cm(2), p&amp;lt;0.01 for all). Eleven badminton players and 37 ice hockey players stopped their active career a mean of 6 years before the final follow-up. Both these groups lost significantly more BMD at the femoral neck and lumbar spine compared to the control group (Delta 0.05-0.12 g/cm(2), p&amp;lt;0.05 for all).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basketball players low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/basketball-players-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/basketball-players-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-levels-of-vitamin-d-in-professional-basketball-players-after-wintertime-relationship-with-dietary-intake-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium">Low levels of vitamin D in professional basketball players after wintertime: relationship with dietary intake of vitamin D and calcium&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolor00fnote-pdf-is-attached---text-extracted-below-with-just-a-single-image-from-the-pdfspan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Note: PDF is attached - text extracted below with just a single image from the PDF&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d">Overview Sports and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/suggests-that-college-athletes-supplement-with-vitamin-d-in-winter" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 479">Suggests that college athletes supplement with vitamin D in winter - June 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/young-israeli-athletes-and-dancers-had-just-25-ng-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 903">Young Israeli athletes and dancers had just 25 ng of vitamin D – Sept 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Senior women more physically able if vitamin D higher than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/senior-women-more-physically-able-if-vitamin-d-higher-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/senior-women-more-physically-able-if-vitamin-d-higher-than-30-ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ballet Dancers with low D had 50 percent more injuries – pilot study</title><link>/posts/ballet-dancers-with-low-d-had-50-percent-more-injuries-pilot-study.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ballet-dancers-with-low-d-had-50-percent-more-injuries-pilot-study.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Book on Sports and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/book-on-sports-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/book-on-sports-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="athletes-edge-faster-quicker-stronger-with-vitamin-d">Athlete&amp;rsquo;s Edge: Faster, Quicker, Stronger With Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>by Dr. John Cannell, $23 including US shipping&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;685&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Athletes-Edge-Quicker-Stronger-Vitamin/dp/0977427293/ref=sr_1_2?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=Athlete%27s+Edge%3A+Faster%2C+Quicker%2C+Stronger&amp;amp;qid=1596585017&amp;amp;sr=8-2">Amazon&lt;/a> $4 used 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>320 page book is described on their &lt;a href="http://www.vitamindsportsbook.com/">website&lt;/a> which allow looking at 12 pages and has the following summary&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This book covers new ground. After extensive investigation and translation of numerous scientific reports into the English language,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>   author Dr. John Cannell reveals a long-held secret once known only to Eastern European athletic trainers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More muscle injuries in NFL players who were low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/more-muscle-injuries-in-nfl-players-who-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-muscle-injuries-in-nfl-players-who-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-lower-in-nfl-football-players-who-suffered-muscled-injuries-study-reports">Vitamin D Lower In NFL Football Players Who Suffered Muscled Injuries, Study Reports&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been known to cause an assortment of health problems, a recent study being presented at the American Orthopaedic Society for Sports Medicine’s (AOSSM) Annual Meeting in San Diego today, suggests that lack of the vitamin might also increase the chance of muscle injuries in athletes, specifically NFL football players.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="san-diego-ca-prweb-july-09-2011httpwwwprwebcomreleasesprwebaossm7prweb8619796htm20">&lt;a href="http://www.prweb.com/releases/prwebAOSSM/7/prweb8619796.htm%20">San Diego, CA (PRWEB) July 09, 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been known to cause an assortment of health problems, a recent study being presented at the American Orthopaedic Society for Sports Medicine’s (AOSSM) Annual Meeting in San Diego today, suggests that lack of the vitamin might also increase the chance of muscle injuries in athletes, specifically NFL football players.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4000 IU vitamin D and exercise for overweight – PhD 2010</title><link>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-and-exercise-for-overweight-phd-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-and-exercise-for-overweight-phd-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="does-vitamin-d-supplementation-augment-exercise-induced-changes-in-health-and-physical-performance">Does vitamin D supplementation augment exercise-induced changes in health and physical performance?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>by Carrillo, Andres Ernesto, Ph.D., PURDUE UNIVERSITY, 2010, 167 pages; 3444489&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this research was to examine the effects of vitamin D supplementation &lt;strong>(4000 IU/d)&lt;/strong> during an exercise training intervention on body composition, muscular strength and power, glucose tolerance, and inflammatory biomarkers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-three (26.1 ? 4.7 yrs) overweight-to-obese (BMI: 31.3 ? 3.2 kg/m2 ) adults were recruited during winter months (25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) 19.3 ? 7.2 ng/mL) and randomized into a vitamin D (VitD, n = 10) or placebo (PL, n = 13) group.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perhaps Stress fractures 2X less frequent if 4000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/perhaps-stress-fractures-2x-less-frequent-if-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/perhaps-stress-fractures-2x-less-frequent-if-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-is-associated-with-low-incidence-of-stress-fractures">High serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D is associated with low incidence of stress fractures.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2011 Jun 22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jbmr.451.">doi: 10.1002/jbmr.451.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burgi AA, Gorham ED, Garland CF, Mohr SB, Garland FC, Zeng K, Thompson K, Lappe JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Naval Health Research Center, San Diego, California.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations are associated with hip fractures, but the dose-response relationship of serum 25(OH)D with risk of stress fractures in young women is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oxygen uptake associated with higher vitamin D – up to 50 hours per week</title><link>/posts/oxygen-uptake-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-up-to-50-hours-per-week.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/oxygen-uptake-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-up-to-50-hours-per-week.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="relation-of-vitamin-d-level-to-maximal-oxygen-uptake-in-adults">Relation of vitamin D level to maximal oxygen uptake in adults.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Cardiol. 2011 Apr 15;107(8):1246-9. Epub 2011 Feb 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ardestani A, Parker B, Mathur S, Clarkson P, Pescatello LS, Hoffman HJ, Polk DM, Thompson PD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Cardiology, Hartford Hospital, Hartford, Connecticut, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low cardiorespiratory fitness and low serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels are associated with increased cardiovascular and all-cause mortality, but whether low 25(OH)D is independently associated with cardiorespiratory fitness in healthy adults is not known. We examined 25(OH)D levels and fitness in 200 healthy adults participating in a double-blind clinical trial investigating statins and muscle performance (STOMP study). Maximal aerobic exercise capacity (Vo?(max)) was measured using metabolic gas analysis during graded treadmill exercise to exhaustion. 25(OH)D was measured using an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. Daily physical activity was assessed using the Paffenbarger Physical Activity Questionnaire.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors with more than 20 ng of vitamin D were 14 percent stronger</title><link>/posts/seniors-with-more-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-were-14-percent-stronger.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-with-more-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-were-14-percent-stronger.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-nutritional-status-on-muscle-function-and-strength-in-healthy-women-aged-over-sixty-five-years">Effect of Vitamin D Nutritional Status on Muscle Function and Strength in Healthy Women Aged over Sixty-Five Years.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Nutr Health Aging. 2011;15(5):349-54.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mastaglia SR, Seijo M, Muzio D, Somoza J, Nuñez M, Oliveri B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S.R. Mastaglia, Av. Cordoba 2351(1120), Tel/Fax: 541159508972, Buenos Aires- Argentina, &lt;a href="mailto:Silvinamastaglia@hotmail.com">Silvinamastaglia@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D insufficiency is common in elderly adults, and leads to secondary hyperparathyroidism, bone loss, muscle weakness, and osteoporotic fractures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To evaluate the relation between vitamin D nutritional status and muscle function and muscle strength in women aged over 65 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>8500 IU average daily helped sports performance</title><link>/posts/8500-iu-average-daily-helped-sports-performance.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/8500-iu-average-daily-helped-sports-performance.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-cholecalciferol-and-calcium-supplementati-on-on-muscle-strength-and-energy-metabolism-in-vitamin-d-deficient-asian-indians-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Effect of cholecalciferol and calcium supplementati on on muscle strength and energy metabolism in vitamin D-deficient Asian Indians: a randomized, controlled trial.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2010 Oct;73(4):445-51. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2265.2010.03816.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2265.2010.03816.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gupta R, Sharma U, Gupta N, Kalaivani M, Singh U, Guleria R, Jagannathan NR, Goswami R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India. &lt;a href="mailto:gosravinder@hotmail.com">gosravinder@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CONTEXT:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is prevalent worldwide. Vitamin D supplementation has shown variable effect on skeletal muscle strength in the elderly with hypovitaminosis D. There is a paucity of similar data in young individuals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Injury-Prevention with Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/injury-prevention-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/injury-prevention-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://triathlon.competitor.com/2010/02/nutrition/vitamin-d-the-injury-prevention-vitamin_7118">Tralthlon competitor had the following&lt;/a> Feb 2010, Written by: Nathan Koch&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D: The Injury-Prevention Vitamin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New studies find that Vitamin D may be more important than previously thought when it comes to the health of endurance athletes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an avid cyclist and runner, I am always looking for ways to improve performance while avoiding forced time off due to injury or illness. While attending the American College of Sports Medicine meeting in Seattle last year, I heard a lecture from a well-known researcher on the benefits of vitamin D supplementation, which included increased athletic performance. I even learned about a study in which Russian and German athletes used ultraviolet sunlamps to improve performance. &lt;strong>Four Russian sprinters used UV light and another group didn’t. The two groups trained identically for the 100-meter sprint. The control group lowered its time by 1.7 percent and the UV group improved 7.4 percent.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces stress fractures – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-stress-fractures-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-stress-fractures-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="evaluating-the-relationship-of-calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-the-prevention-of-stress-fracture-injuries-in-the-young-athlete-a-review-of-the-literature">Evaluating the relationship of calcium and vitamin D in the prevention of stress fracture injuries in the young athlete: a review of the literature.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PM R. 2010 Oct;2(10):945-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tenforde AS, Sayres LC, Sainani KL, Fredericson M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calcium and vitamin D are recognized as 2 components of nutrition needed to achieve and maintain bone health. Calcium and vitamin D have been clearly shown to improve bone density and prevent fractures at all ages. However, the literature is conflicting as to the role of these nutrients in young athletes ages 18 to 35 years, both for bone development and for the prevention of bone overuse injuries. Differences in findings may relate to study design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Story – Prevent injuries and speed healing with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/story-prevent-injuries-and-speed-healing-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/story-prevent-injuries-and-speed-healing-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-iehealthhttpiehealthblogspotcom201001todays-post-thursday-1-21-2010-lasthtml20-jan-2010">From &lt;a href="http://iehealth.blogspot.com/2010/01/todays-post-thursday-1-21-2010-last.html%20">IEHealth&lt;/a> Jan 2010&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Last Saturday, I spoke to a woman who broke some of her ribs when she fell off of a bicycle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She saw a doctor close to where she works who is one of the pioneers in using vitamin D3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He dramatically, though for just 3 weeks, increased her vitamin D. The results may interest you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her pain stopped more than four times sooner than the doctors at the emergency room told her to expect. Then when she got an x-ray at the point when the doctors were checking to see if the progress they expected to see towards full healing, about 25% there, had happened, she was 100 % healed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Postmenopausal women with higher vitamin D exercised more</title><link>/posts/postmenopausal-women-with-higher-vitamin-d-exercised-more.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/postmenopausal-women-with-higher-vitamin-d-exercised-more.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="duration-of-physical-activity-and-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-of-postmenopausal-women">Duration of Physical Activity and Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D Status of Postmenopausal Women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ann Epidemiol. 2011 Mar 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kluczynski MA, Lamonte MJ, Mares JA, Wactawski-Wende J, Smith AW, Engelman CD, Andrews CA, Snetselaar LG, Sarto GE, Millen AE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Social and Preventive Medicine, School of Public Health and Health Professions, University at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY (M.A.K., A.E.M., M.J.L., J.W.); Department of Ophthalmology and Visual Sciences, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, Madison, WI (J.A.M.); Outcomes Research Branch, Applied Research Program, Cancer Control and Population Sciences, National Cancer Institute, 6130 Bethesda, MD (A.W.S.); Department of Population Health Sciences, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, Madison, WI (C.D.E.); Department of Biostatistics, School of Public Health and Health Professions, University at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY (C.A.A.); Departments of Community and Behavior Health and Epidemiology, College of Public Health, the University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA (L.G.S.); and Department of Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, Madison, WI (G.E.S.).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shin splints decrease with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/shin-splints-decrease-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shin-splints-decrease-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-may-both-prevent-and-treat-shin-splints">Vitamin D may both prevent and treat shin splints.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has been proven to prevent bone stress fractures and micro cracks.&lt;br>
Vitamin D appears to substantially prevent and treat shin splints, which is a closely related bone problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Google Search below&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Papers attached to the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="wikipedia-provided-alternate-terms-to-searchfor">Wikipedia provided alternate terms to search for&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The most common sources of shin splints are tendinitis, periostitis, stress fractures, and compartment syndrome.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D bed used 4 minutes daily by dark skin members of UK sports team</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-bed-used-4-minutes-daily-by-dark-skin-members-of-uk-sports-team.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-bed-used-4-minutes-daily-by-dark-skin-members-of-uk-sports-team.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="manchester-uniteds-ryan-giggs-and-rio-ferdinand-buy-into-cutting-edge-methods-at-carrington">Manchester United&amp;rsquo;s Ryan Giggs and Rio Ferdinand buy into cutting-edge methods at Carrington&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Manchester United’s attempt to &lt;strong>reclaim the Premier League title&lt;/strong> is being bolstered by cutting-edge technology which includes GPS tracking of the players, zero-gravity rehabilitation and vitamin D beds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/sport/football/teams/manchester-united/8275326/Manchester-Uniteds-Ryan-Giggs-and-Rio-Ferdinand-buy-into-cutting-edge-methods-at-Carrington.html">By Mark Ogden 21 Jan 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a revelatory access-all-areas documentary by MUTV, the club’s in-house television channel, Ryan &amp;amp; Rio — Carrington Revealed, sheds light on the behind-the-scenes operation at Manchester United’s 108-acre Carrington training centre.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less muscle and insulin resistance for children of vitamin D deficient mothers</title><link>/posts/less-muscle-and-insulin-resistance-for-children-of-vitamin-d-deficient-mothers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-muscle-and-insulin-resistance-for-children-of-vitamin-d-deficient-mothers.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-during-pregnancy-and-body-composition-and-cardiovascular-risk-markers-in-indian-children-the-mysore-parthenon-study">Maternal vitamin D status during pregnancy and body composition and cardiovascular risk markers in Indian children: the Mysore Parthenon Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>AM J CLIN NUTR () (2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ghattu V Krishnaveni, Sargoor R Veena, Nicola R Winder, Jacqueline C Hill, Kate Noonan, Barbara J Boucher, Samuel C Karat and Caroline Hd Fall&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiology Research Unit, CSI Holdsworth Memorial Hospital, Mysore, India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Metabolic consequences of vitamin D deficiency have become a recent research focus. Maternal vitamin D status is thought to influence musculoskeletal health in children, but its relation with offspring metabolic risk is not known.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Sports and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="should-an-athlete-supplement-with-vitamin-d---2018">Should an athlete supplement with Vitamin D - 2018&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D and the Athlete: Current Perspectives and NewChallenges&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/vitamin-d-and-the-athlete---current-perspectives-and-newchallenges.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/athletes-yes-no.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="high-intensity-athletes---professional-and-olympic">High Intensity Athletes - Professional and Olympic&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sprint internal training improves cognition &lt;a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/sms.14349?campaign=wolearlyview%20">March 2023&lt;/a>, &lt;del>!hs&lt;/del> &lt;a href="https://www.mdpi.com/1660-4601/19/1/613%20">Jan 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/olympic-athletes-and-vitamin-d-clippings-2009-10" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 349">Olympic Athletes and vitamin D - clippings 2009-10&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>UV used by Olympic athletes since the 1930&amp;rsquo;s, High UV in Mexico Olympics broke many records&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/professional-sports-team-takes-span-stylecolor00f5000-iuspan-vitamin-d-and-wins-championship" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 293">Professional sports team takes &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">5000 IU&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> vitamin D and wins championship&lt;/a> Hockey&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 intervention increased elderly muscle strength</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-intervention-increased-elderly-muscle-strength.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-intervention-increased-elderly-muscle-strength.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-randomized-controlled-trial-of-the-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-muscle-strength-and-mobility-in-older-women-with-vitamin-d-insufficiency">A Randomized Controlled Trial of the Effects of Vitamin D on Muscle Strength and Mobility in Older Women with Vitamin D Insufficiency&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kun Zhu PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Nicole Austin PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Amanda Devine PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>David Bruce MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Richard L. Prince MD&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Article first published online: 4 NOV 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03142.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2010, Copyright the Authors. Journal compilation © 2010, The American Geriatrics Society&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 58, Issue 11, pages 2063–2068, November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhu, K., Austin, N., Devine, A., Bruce, D. and Prince, R. L. (2010), A Randomized Controlled Trial of the Effects of Vitamin D on Muscle Strength and Mobility in Older Women with Vitamin D Insufficiency. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society, 58: 2063–2068. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03142.x">doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03142.x&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>