<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sports and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/sports-and-vitamin-d/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sports and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/sports-and-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Muscle Inflammation (idiopathic inflammatory myopathy) 3.2 X more likely if low Vitamin D – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/muscle-inflammation-idiopathic-inflammatory-myopathy-32-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/muscle-inflammation-idiopathic-inflammatory-myopathy-32-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-levels-in-idiopathic-inflammatory-myopathy-patients-a-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;Vitamin D levels in idiopathic inflammatory myopathy patients: a meta-analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Review Postgrad Med . 2024 Feb 29. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/00325481.2024.2325335&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1080/00325481.2024.2325335&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anji Xiong 1 2 3, Shifeng Zhou 1, Can Liu 1, Ziyi Hu 1, Chuanmei Xie 4, Xiaoli Zheng 5, Xiongyan Luo 6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Purpose: This meta-analysis aimed to explore correlations between vitamin D and idiopathic inflammatory myopathy (IIM).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Methods: A comprehensive database search was conducted on 13 October 2020. Mean differences (MDs) and aggregated risk ratios (RR) with 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were used to determine the correlation between vitamin D deficiency (VDD) and IIM. Statistical analysis was performed with RevMan 5.4 and Stata15, statistical significance was set at p &amp;lt; 0.05.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stronger rowers have higher levels of Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/stronger-rowers-have-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/stronger-rowers-have-higher-levels-of-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;association-of-cartilage-metabolism-biomarkers-and-25ohd-levels-with-muscle-biomechanical-functions-in-professional-rowers-and-canoeists&#34;&gt;Association of cartilage metabolism biomarkers and 25(OH)D levels with muscle biomechanical functions in professional rowers and canoeists&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sci Rep. 2024 Jan 11;14(1):1112. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-51272-8.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-51272-8.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Małgorzata Ogurkowska 1, Tomasz Podgórski 2, Alicja Nowak 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the study was to assess the association of cartilage metabolism biomarkers and vitamin D metabolite levels with muscle biomechanical functions in professional rowers and canoeists. The serum levels of aggrecan, cartilage oligomeric matrix protein (COMP), and 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) were determined in elite male sweep-oar rowers (n = 24) and canoeists (n = 15). This was followed by a biomechanical study consisting in isometric measurement of peak torque (PT) of muscles involved in the rowing cycle in the athletes. There were found significant correlations of COMP with the ratio of trunk PT flexor to extensor (p &amp;lt; 0.05) and 25(OH)D with trunk PT-left rotators (p &amp;lt; 0.05), knee joints PT-left and right flexor (p ≤ 0.01), ratio of knee joint PT-right flexor to knee joint PT-right extensor (p &amp;lt; 0.05) in rowers and aggreccan with elbow joint PT of the right flexor (p ≤ 0.01) and extensor (p = 0.05) in canoeists. The correlations of COMP and aggrecan levels with PT of the muscle groups studied in rowers and canoeists indicate the importance of stabilizing the muscular system in cartilage metabolism. The relationship between 25(OH)D status and biomechanical parameters confirm that vitamin D plays an important role in maintaining skeletal muscle health.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Longevity books compared in a video</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/16-longevity-books-compared-in-a-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/16-longevity-books-compared-in-a-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;peter-attias-longevity-book-outlive-the-best-or-worst-longevitybook&#34;&gt;Peter Attia&amp;rsquo;s Longevity Book Outlive: The BEST or WORST longevity book?&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VWeg3l3RBIM&amp;amp;ab_channel=PlantChompers&#34;&gt;YouTube 35 minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Outlive: The Science and Art of Longevity by Peter Attia&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Longevity Project: Surprising Discoveries for Health and Long Life from the Landmark Eight-Decade Study&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Longevity Diet by Valter Longo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Path to Longevity: The Secrets to Living a Long, Happy, Healthy Life by Luigi Fontana&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How Not to Age: The Scientific Approach to Getting Healthier as You Get Older by Michael Greger&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Individualized – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/individualized-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/individualized-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effects-of-an-individualized-vs-standardized-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-the-25ohd-level-in-athletes&#34;&gt;Effects of an Individualized vs. Standardized Vitamin D Supplementation on the 25(OH)D Level in Athletes&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2023, 15(22), 4747; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15224747&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15224747&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Chiara Tuma 1,2,*ORCID, Arne Schick 1,Nele Pommerening 1,Hans Braun 1,2 and Mario Thevis 1,3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Institute of Biochemistry/Center of Preventive Doping Research, German Sport University Cologne, 50933 Cologne, Germany&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 German Research Centre of Elite Sports (Momentum), German Sport University Cologne, 50933 Cologne, Germany&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 European Monitoring Center for Emerging Doping Agents, 50933 Cologne, Germany&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Omega-3 helps muscles - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/omega-3-helps-muscles-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/omega-3-helps-muscles-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effects-of-omega-3-fatty-acid-supplementation-on-skeletal-muscle-mass-and-strength-in-adults-a-systematic-review---oct-2023&#34;&gt;Effects of Omega-3 Fatty Acid Supplementation on Skeletal Muscle Mass and Strength in Adults: A Systematic Review - Oct 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clin Nutr Res. 2023 Oct 23;12(4):304-319. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7762/cnr.2023.12.4.304&#34;&gt;doi: 10.7762/cnr.2023.12.4.304&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gi Kyoung Moon 1, So Young Bu 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Previous studies have suggested that omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids, predominantly eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA) and docosahexaenoic acid (DHA), have several health benefits. However, their effect on changes in skeletal muscle mass and strength has not been established, owing to differences in study designs. This systematic review aimed to investigate the recent evidence regarding the role of dietary EPA and DHA in muscle mass changes and their association with muscle strength. Databases including PubMed and Google Scholar were searched for randomized controlled trials and single-arm interventions that investigated the effects of omega-3 fatty acids on skeletal muscle mass, strength, and body composition in adults aged 18 years and older.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skeletal Muscles regenerated with Vitamin D supplementation – review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/skeletal-muscles-regenerated-with-vitamin-d-supplementation-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/skeletal-muscles-regenerated-with-vitamin-d-supplementation-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-skeletal-muscle-repair-and-regeneration-in-animal-models-and-humans-a-systematic-review&#34;&gt;The Role of Vitamin D in Skeletal Muscle Repair and Regeneration in Animal Models and Humans: A Systematic Review&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients. 2023 Oct 16;15(20):4377. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15204377.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/nu15204377.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Miguel Agoncillo 1, Josephine Yu 1, Jenny E Gunton 1 2 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D deficiency, prevalent worldwide, is linked to muscle weakness, sarcopenia, and falls. Muscle regeneration is a vital process that allows for skeletal muscle tissue maintenance and repair after injury. PubMed and Web of Science were used to search for studies published prior to May 2023. We assessed eligible studies that discussed the relationship between vitamin D, muscle regeneration in this review. Overall, the literature reports strong associations between vitamin D and skeletal myocyte size, and muscle regeneration. In vitro studies in skeletal muscle cells derived from mice and humans showed vitamin D played a role in regulating myoblast growth, size, and gene expression. Animal studies, primarily in mice, demonstrate vitamin D&amp;rsquo;s positive effects on skeletal muscle function, such as improved grip strength and endurance. These studies encompass vitamin D diet research, genetically modified models, and disease-related mouse models. Relatively few studies looked at muscle function after injury, but these also support a role for vitamin D in muscle recovery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Athletes who had been COVID infected had lower Vitamin D levels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/athletes-who-had-been-covid-infected-had-lower-vitamin-d-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/athletes-who-had-been-covid-infected-had-lower-vitamin-d-levels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;blood-profiling-of-athletes-after-covid-19-differences-in-blood-profiles-of-post-covid-19-athletes-compared-to-uninfected-athletic-individuals-an-exploratory-analysis&#34;&gt;Blood Profiling of Athletes after COVID-19: Differences in Blood Profiles of Post-COVID-19 Athletes Compared to Uninfected Athletic Individuals-An Exploratory Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biomedicines . 2023 Jul 6;11(7):1911. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines11071911.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/biomedicines11071911.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shirin Vollrath 1, Lynn Matits 1 2, Achim Jerg 1, Jule Zorn 1, Lucas John 1, Jürgen Michael Steinacker 1, Daniel Alexander Bizjak 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Perhaps not outdoors as much while recovering&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blood profiling data in athletic populations and their respective responses to SARS-CoV-2 infection are lacking. Thus, this exploratory pilot study aimed to analyze and compare clinical blood markers in previously infected trained athletes (ATH; 30 m/29 f) and a not previously infected healthy athletic control group (HC; 12 m/19 f). The ATH group undertook a sports medical examination which included extended blood analyses. Blood profiles with a total of 74 variables were assessed (blood counts, pro-/inflammatory and immunological markers, and micronutrients), and the ATH group was compared to the age-matched, vaccinated HC group with comparable athletic back grounds, though without previous SARS-CoV-2-infections. The ATH group showed lower IgG, Troponin-T levels, and they had a lower complement/acute-phase protein activation. Furthermore, Vitamin D levels were lower and electrolyte/micronutrient concentrations were higher in ATH. Soluble transferrin receptor as a marker of erythrocyte turnover was decreased whereas PTT as a coagulation marker was increased. Subgroup analyses according to sex revealed more differences between the women of the ATH and HC groups (for 25 different variables) than between the men (for 5 different variables), especially for immunological and metabolic variables. In particular, the immune system and electrolyte/micronutrient status should be observed frequently and sex-specifically in this athletic cohort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some excess calories diverted to muscle growth if high level vitamin D (exercising mice) – preprint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-excess-calories-diverted-to-muscle-growth-if-high-level-vitamin-d-exercising-mice-preprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-excess-calories-diverted-to-muscle-growth-if-high-level-vitamin-d-exercising-mice-preprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;high-dose-dietary-vitamin-d-allocates-surplus-calories-to-muscle-and-growth-instead-of-fat-via-modulation-of-myostatin-and-leptin-signaling&#34;&gt;High dose dietary vitamin D allocates surplus calories to muscle and growth instead of fat via modulation of myostatin and leptin signaling.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Caela Long1t, Zahra Tara1t, Alex Casella1, Julian Mark1, and Jeffrey D. Roizen1*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;tCo-first Authors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1The Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia and The University of Pennsylvania Perelman School of Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obesity is the leading proportional cause for diabetes, heart disease and cancer. Obesity occurs because the body stores surplus calories as fat. Fat cells secrete a hormone, leptin, that modulates energy balance at the brain. Changes in fat mass are mirrored by changes in serum leptin. Increases in leptin cause the brain to decrease appetite and increase energy expenditure. However in obesity, leptin sensitivity is decreased which mutes leptin mediated changes in appetite and energy expenditure. We have limited understanding of what controls leptin production by fat or how sensitive the brain is to leptin. Muscle produces a hormone, myostatin, that plays an analogous role to the role that leptin plays in fat. Absent myostatin leads to increased muscle mass and strength. We also do not know what controls myostatin production or sensitivity. Although fat mass and muscle mass are closely linked, the interplay between leptin and myostatin remains unexplored. Vitamin D improves lean mass via what are thought to be primarily trophic effects at the muscle. Here we show that high dose dietary vitamin D preferentially allocates excess calories to muscle and growth instead of storage as fat by decreasing myostatin production and increasing leptin production and sensitivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low Vitamin D resulted in 1.8X increase in ACL knee tears in next 2 years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/low-vitamin-d-resulted-in-18x-increase-in-acl-knee-tears-in-next-2-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/low-vitamin-d-resulted-in-18x-increase-in-acl-knee-tears-in-next-2-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-diagnosis-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-increased-rates-of-anterior-cruciate-ligament-tears-and-reconstruction-failure&#34;&gt;A Diagnosis of Vitamin D Deficiency is Associated with Increased Rates of Anterior Cruciate Ligament Tears and Reconstruction Failure&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arthroscopy. 2023 Apr 29;S0749-8063(23)00375-4. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arthro.2023.04.011&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2023.04.011&lt;/a&gt;  PDF behind paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J Alex Albright 1, Kenny Chang 2, Rory A Byrne 3, Matthew Quinn 3, Ozair Meghani 3, Alan H Daniels 3, Brett D Owens 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Purpose: This study aims to characterize the association between a diagnosis of hypovitaminosis D and primary anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) tear, primary ACL reconstruction (ACLR), and revision ACLR in different sex and age cohorts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indoor athletes have 4.5 ng less Vitamin D (Asia in this case) – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/indoor-athletes-have-45-ng-less-vitamin-d-asia-in-this-case-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/indoor-athletes-have-45-ng-less-vitamin-d-asia-in-this-case-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;difference-in-levels-of-vitamin-d-between-indoor-and-outdoor-athletes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;Difference in Levels of Vitamin D between Indoor and Outdoor Athletes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Int J Mol Sci . 2023 Apr 20;24(8):7584. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms24087584&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/ijms24087584&lt;/a&gt; DOI: 10.3390/ijms24087584&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maria Bârsan 1, Vlad-Florin Chelaru 2, Armand-Gabriel Râjnoveanu 1, Ștefan Lucian Popa 3, Andreea-Iulia Socaciu 1, Andrei-Vlad Bădulescu 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D, its importance in different processes taking place in the human body, the effects of abnormal levels of this hormone, either too low or too high, and the need for supplementation have been extensively researched thus far. Variances in exposure to sunlight can cause vitamin D levels to fluctuate. Indoor activity can be a factor for these fluctuations and can lead to a decrease in vitamin D levels. We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis aiming to identify whether indoor compared to outdoor training has a significant influence on vitamin D levels; we also performed subgroup analyses and multivariate meta-regression. The type of training has an impact on vitamin D levels that is influenced by multiple cofounders. In a subgroup analysis not considering cofounders, the mean serum vitamin D was 3.73 ng/mL higher in outdoor athletes, a difference which barely fails to achieve significance (p = 0.052, a total sample size of 5150).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
