<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sports and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/sports-and-vitamin-d.html</link><description>Recent content in Sports and Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/sports-and-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D and bicarbonate perhaps synergistically reduce muscle loss</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-bicarbonate-perhaps-synergistically-reduce-muscle-loss.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-bicarbonate-perhaps-synergistically-reduce-muscle-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="could-vitamin-d-and-bicarbonate-supplementation-synergize-to-mitigate-age-related-loss-of-muscle">Could vitamin D and bicarbonate supplementation synergize to mitigate age-related loss of muscle?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocrine, DOI 10.1007/s12020-013-0011-2; EDITORIAL&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D. Travis Thomas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span>[This is an editorial on a rat experiment]&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In patients with kidney disease receiving hemodialysis, metabolic acidosis is closely tied to muscle pathology and is known to exacerbate age-related loss of muscle mass and function. To a lesser extent, the &amp;ldquo;Western&amp;rdquo; diet is thought to contribute to mild (sub-clinical) metabolic acidosis via the supply of acid precursors from foods &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>, but the clinical significance to chronic age-related muscle degeneration has received little attention. This may partly be due to equivocal data on the benefits of neutralizing diet-induced metabolic acidosis for improving muscle-related outcomes in patients without kidney disease &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>. Despite limited data, acidosis has been shown to stimulate muscle proteolysis and is associated with negative functional outcomes including reduced peak torque and lower gait speed &lt;sup>[3]&lt;/sup>. This is important to note because aged adults are less able to excrete excess H? ions and are more prone to develop mild, but slowly increasing metabolic acidosis that may be exacerbated by a &amp;ldquo;Western&amp;rdquo; diet &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. Furthermore, approximately one out of four adults older than 50 years of age have low serum bicarbonate levels to neutralize an acidogenic diet. Because of these factors, recommendations for future work include examining the effects of alkali therapy on functional outcomes, nitrogen balance, strength and other relevant measures of physical function, in aged healthy adults &lt;sup>[3]&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Muscles and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/muscles-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/muscles-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#max-strength-not-improved-by-resistance-training-plus-daily-8000-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-whey-protien--rct-oct-2024">Max strength not improved by resistance training plus daily 8,000 IU of vitamin D and whey protien – RCT Oct 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#surplus-calories-not-put-into-fat-if-good-level-of-vitamin-d-mice-may-2024">Surplus calories not put into fat if good level of Vitamin D (mice) May 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#do-fast-twitch-muscles-respond-more-quickly-if-there-is-a-higher-level-of-vitamin-d-in-the-blood">Do fast twitch muscles respond more quickly if there is a higher level of vitamin D in the blood?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-skeletal-muscle-repair-and-regeneration-in-animal-models-and-humans-a-systematic-review---oct-2023">The Role of Vitamin D in Skeletal Muscle Repair and Regeneration in Animal Models and Humans: A Systematic Review - Oct 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#muscle-health-and-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-sept-2021-not-help-much---ignored-dose-size">Muscle Health and Vitamin D - Meta-analysis Sept 2021 (not help much - ignored dose size)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-promotes-skeletal-muscle-regeneration-and-mitochondrial-health--april-2021">Vitamin D Promotes Skeletal Muscle Regeneration and Mitochondrial Health – April 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-helps-muscles-in-many-ways--sept-2021">Vitamin D helps muscles in many ways – Sept 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-roles-of-vitamin-d-in-skeletal-muscle-feb-2013">The Roles of Vitamin D in Skeletal Muscle Feb 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#small-vitamin-d-doses-given-for-a-few-months-do-not-improve-muscles---meta-analysis-oct-2023">Small Vitamin D doses given for a few months do not improve muscles - meta-analysis Oct 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#48000-iu-monthly-for-a-year-did-not-help-elderly-muscles--june-2019">48,000 IU monthly for a year did not help elderly muscles- June 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sarcopenia-33-x-higher-risk-if-low-bio-available-vitamin-d---august-2021">Sarcopenia: 3.3 X higher risk if low bio-available vitamin D - August 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-reduced-muscle-function-associated-with-many-vitamin-d-genes---review-sept-2021">Some reduced muscle function associated with many Vitamin D genes - Review Sept 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-a-hrefpostsmuscular-dystrophy-probably-treated-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-plus-muscle-rehab-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-muscular-dystrophy-probably-treated-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-plus-muscle-rehabmuscular-dystrophy-probably-treated-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-plus-muscle-rehaba">See also: &lt;a href="/posts/muscular-dystrophy-probably-treated-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-plus-muscle-rehab" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Muscular Dystrophy probably treated by high-dose Vitamin D plus muscle rehab">Muscular Dystrophy probably treated by high-dose Vitamin D plus muscle rehab&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#creatine-might-help-grow-senior-muscles-when-added-to-exercise">Creatine might help grow senior muscles when added to exercise&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="max-strength-not-improved-by-resistance-training-plus-daily-8000-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-whey-protien--rct-oct-2024">Max strength not improved by resistance training plus daily 8,000 IU of vitamin D and whey protien – RCT Oct 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D Supplementation Does Not Enhance Gains in Muscle Strength and Lean Body Mass or Influence Cardiorespiratory Fitness in Vitamin D-Insufficient Middle-Aged Men Engaged in Resistance Training&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Muscle improved by increasing vitamin D if previously less than 24 ng</title><link>/posts/muscle-improved-by-increasing-vitamin-d-if-previously-less-than-24-ng.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/muscle-improved-by-increasing-vitamin-d-if-previously-less-than-24-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-and-muscle-function-is-there-a-threshold-in-the-relation">Vitamin D and Muscle Function: Is There a Threshold in the Relation?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Journal of the American Medical Directors Association, Available online 27 June 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hennie C.J.P. Janssen, MDa, &lt;a href="mailto:hcjp.janssen@gmail.com">hcjp.janssen@gmail.com&lt;/a> , Marielle H. Emmelot-Vonk, MD, PhD a; Harald J.J. Verhaar, MD, PhD a; Yvonne T. van der Schouw, Profb&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Geriatrics, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Julius Center for Health Sciences and Primary Care, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some athletes would benefit from more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/some-athletes-would-benefit-from-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-athletes-would-benefit-from-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-and-the-athlete-risks-recommendations-and-benefits">Vitamin D and the Athlete: Risks, Recommendations, and Benefits&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5, 1856-1868; doi:10.3390/nu5061856&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dana Ogan * and Kelly Pritchett&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutrition, Exercise and Health Science, Central Washington University, 400 E. University Way, Ellensburg, WA 98926, USA; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:kkerr@cwu.edu">kkerr@cwu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Author to whom correspondence should be addressed; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:danastorlie@yahoo.com">danastorlie@yahoo.com&lt;/a>; Tel.: +1-425-345-0970; Fax: +1-509-963-1848.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Received: 2 April 2013; in revised form: 7 May 2013 / Accepted: 8 May 2013 / Published: 28 May 2013&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Vitamin D and Physical Performance</title><link>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-and-physical-performance.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-and-physical-performance.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-and-physical-performance">Vitamin D and Physical Performance&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Sports Medicine, May 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daniel S. Moran &lt;a href="mailto:dmoran@sheba.health.gov.il">dmoran@sheba.health.gov.il&lt;/a> (1) (2) (3)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James P. McClung (4)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tal Kohen (2)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harris R. Lieberman (4)&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education Program, United States Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, Natick, MA, 01760, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Heller Institute of Medical Research, Sheba Medical Center, Tel Hashomer, 52621, Israel&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ariel University, Ariel, Israel&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Military Nutrition Division, United States Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, Natick, MA, 01760, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traumatic brain injury treated by Vitamin D Progesterone Omega-3 and glutamine</title><link>/posts/traumatic-brain-injury-treated-by-vitamin-d-progesterone-omega-3-and-glutamine.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/traumatic-brain-injury-treated-by-vitamin-d-progesterone-omega-3-and-glutamine.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="combination-therapy-with-vitamin-d3-progesterone-omega-3-fatty-acids-and-glutamine-reverses-coma-and-improves-clinical-outcomes-in-patients-with-severe-traumatic-brain-injuries-a-case-series-of-three-patients">Combination therapy with vitamin D3, progesterone, omega-3 fatty acids, and glutamine reverses coma and improves clinical outcomes in patients with severe traumatic brain injuries: A case series of three patients&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>IJCRI - International Journal of Case Reports and Images, Vol. No. 2013. ISSN - &lt;span>[0976-3198]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Leslie R Matthews&lt;/strong> 1, Omar K Danner1, Y A Ahmed2, Diane M Dennis-Griggs1, Alexis Frederick1, Clarence Clark1, Ronald Moore1, Wilson DuMornay1, Ed W Childs1, Kenneth L Wilson1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fewer injuries and higher ballet jumps with 2,000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/fewer-injuries-and-higher-ballet-jumps-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fewer-injuries-and-higher-ballet-jumps-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-influence-of-winter-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-muscle-function-and-injury-occurrence-in-elite-ballet-dancers-a-controlled-study">The influence of winter vitamin D supplementation on muscle function and injury occurrence in elite ballet dancers: A controlled study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matthew A. Wyon a, b, c, &lt;a href="mailto:m.wyon@wlv.ac.uk">m.wyon@wlv.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yiannis Koutedakis a, d, e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roger Wolman c, f,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alan M. Nevill a,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nick Allen a, b, c&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Research Centre for Sport Exercise and Performance, University of Wolverhampton, Walsall, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Jerwood Centre for the Prevention and Treatment of Dance Injuries, Birmingham, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D provides faster recovery after muscle overuse</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-provides-faster-recovery-after-muscle-overuse.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-provides-faster-recovery-after-muscle-overuse.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="higher-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-associate-with-a-faster-recovery-of-skeletal-muscle-strength-after-muscular-injury">Higher Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentrations Associate with a Faster Recovery of Skeletal Muscle Strength after Muscular Injury&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(4), 1253-1275; doi:10.3390/nu5041253&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tyler Barker 1,tyler.barker@imail.org, Vanessa T. Henriksen 1 , Thomas B. Martins 2 , Harry R. Hill 2,3 , Carl R. Kjeldsberg 2,3 , Erik D. Schneider 4 , Brian M. Dixon 4 and Lindell K. Weaver 5,6,7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 The Orthopedic Specialty Hospital, Murray, UT 84107, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 ARUP Laboratories, Institute for Clinical and Experimental Pathology, Salt Lake City, UT 84108, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5,000 IU daily was just enough vitamin D for Irish athletes in the winter</title><link>/posts/5000-iu-daily-was-just-enough-vitamin-d-for-irish-athletes-in-the-winter.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5000-iu-daily-was-just-enough-vitamin-d-for-irish-athletes-in-the-winter.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-supplementation-in-elite-irish-athletes">Vitamin D Status and Supplementation in Elite Irish Athletes.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2013 Mar 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pamela J. Magee 1, L. Kirsty Pourshahidi 1, Julie M.W. Wallace 1, John Cleary 2, 3, Joe Conway 4, Edward Harney 5 and Sharon M. Madigan 2, 3&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1 Northern Ireland Centre for Food and Health, University of Ulster, Coleraine, Northern Ireland, 2 High Performance Unit, National Boxing Stadium, Dublin,Ireland,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>3 Irish Institute of Sport, Sports Campus Ireland, Abbottstown, Dublin Ireland,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Collegiate Swimmers getting 4000 IU of vitamin D had fewer injuries</title><link>/posts/collegiate-swimmers-getting-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-had-fewer-injuries.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/collegiate-swimmers-getting-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-had-fewer-injuries.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-effects-of-season-long-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-collegiate-swimmers-and-divers">The Effects of Season-Long Vitamin D Supplementation on Collegiate Swimmers and Divers.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2013 Mar 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lewis RM, Redzic M, Thomas DT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Clinical Nutrition, University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this 6-month randomized placebo controlled trial was to determine the effect of season-long (September-March) vitamin D supplementation on changes in vitamin D status (measured as 25(OH)D), body composition, inflammation, frequency of illness and injury. Forty-five male and female athletes were randomized to 4000IU vitamin D (n=23) or placebo (n=22). 25(OH)D, bone turnover markers (NTx and BSAP), and inflammatory cytokines (TNF-alpha, IL-6, and IL1-β) were measured at baseline, midpoint, and endpoint. Body composition was assessed by DXA and injury and illness data were collected.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Muscle fatigue reduced with 10,000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/muscle-fatigue-reduced-with-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/muscle-fatigue-reduced-with-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="improving-the-vitamin-d-status-of-vitamin-d-deficient-adults-is-associated-with-improved-mitochondrial-oxidative-function-in-skeletal-muscle">Improving the Vitamin D Status of Vitamin D Deficient Adults Is Associated With Improved Mitochondrial Oxidative Function in Skeletal Muscle&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism March 1, 2013 vol. 98 no. 3 E509-E513&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Akash Sinha, Kieren G. Hollingsworth, Steve Ball and Tim Cheetham &lt;a href="mailto:t.d.cheetham@ncl.ac.uk">t.d.cheetham@ncl.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Paediatric Endocrinology (A.S., T.C.), Great North Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, and Department of Endocrinology (S.B.), Royal Victoria Infirmary, NE1 4LP Newcastle-upon-Tyne, United Kingdom; Institute of Genetic Medicine (A.S., S.B., T.C.), Newcastle University, Newcastle-upon-Tyne NE1 7RU, United Kingdom; and Newcastle Magnetic Resonance Centre (K.G.H.), Institute of Cellular Medicine, Newcastle University, Newcastle-upon-Tyne NE4 5PL, United Kingdom&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Muscle inflammation 17X more probable if vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/muscle-inflammation-17x-more-probable-if-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/muscle-inflammation-17x-more-probable-if-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-serum-levels-of-vitamin-d-in-idiopathic-inflammatory-myopathies">Low serum levels of vitamin D in idiopathic inflammatory myopathies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Rheum Dis 2013;72:512-516 doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2012-201849; Editor&amp;rsquo;s Choice&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Payam Azali 1, &lt;a href="mailto:payam.azali@ds.se">payam.azali@ds.se&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sevim Barbasso Helmers2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ingrid Kockum3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomas Olsson3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lars Alfredsson2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter J Charles4,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karin Piehl Aulin1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ingrid E Lundberg5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Rheumatology Unit, Danderyd&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Unit of Cardiovascular Epidemiology, Institute of Environmental Medicine, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Neuroimmunology, Department of Clinical Neurosciences, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4Department of Translational Research, Kennedy Institute, London, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sport performance not improved after 5710 IU of vitamin D daily for 12 weeks</title><link>/posts/sport-performance-not-improved-after-5710-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-for-12-weeks.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sport-performance-not-improved-after-5710-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-for-12-weeks.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-effects-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation-on-serum-total-25spanohspand-concentration-and-physical-performance-a-randomised-doseresponse-study">The effects of vitamin D3 supplementation on serum total 25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D concentration and physical performance: a randomised dose–response study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Br J Sports Med doi:10.1136/bjsports-2012-091735&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Graeme L Close1, Jill Leckey1, Marcelle Patterson1, Warren Bradley1, Daniel J Owens1, William D Fraser2, James P Morton1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Research Institute for Sport and Exercise Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Norwich Medical School, University of East Anglia, Norwich, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ballet dancers in the winter had more injuries and only 15 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ballet-dancers-in-the-winter-had-more-injuries-and-only-15-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ballet-dancers-in-the-winter-had-more-injuries-and-only-15-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-in-professional-ballet-dancers-winter-vs-summer">Vitamin D status in professional ballet dancers: Winter vs. summer.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Sci Med Sport. 2013 Feb 1. pii: S1440-2440(12)01139-5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsams.2012.12.010.">doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2012.12.010.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wolman R, Wyon MA, Koutedakis Y, Nevill AM, Eastell R, Allen N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Rheumatology and Sport and Exercise Medicine, Royal National Orthopaedic Hospital, Stanmore, UK; National Institute of Dance Medicine and Science, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D is produced by the exposure of the skin to sunlight. Therefore athletes who train indoors, such as dancers, are vulnerable to vitamin D deficiency. The purpose of the study was to evaluate the serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status in UK professional dancers during periods of reduced and increased sunlight exposure (i.e., winter vs. summer), and to assess the impact on bone metabolism and risk of injury.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Physical performance of seniors increases with vitamin D up to 30 ng</title><link>/posts/physical-performance-of-seniors-increases-with-vitamin-d-up-to-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/physical-performance-of-seniors-increases-with-vitamin-d-up-to-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-is-associated-with-physical-performance-the-results-of-three-independent-cohorts">Vitamin D status is associated with physical performance: the results of three independent cohorts.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2013 Jan;24(1):187-96. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-012-2124-5.">doi: 10.1007/s00198-012-2124-5.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Sep 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sohl E, de Jongh RT, Heijboer AC, Swart KM, Brouwer-Brolsma EM, Enneman AW, de Groot CP, van der Velde N, Dhonukshe-Rutten RA, Lips P, van Schoor NM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study, on the association between vitamin D status and physical performance and its decline, shows that vitamin D status is associated with physical performance in several older age groups. However, vitamin D status does not predict a decline in physical performance in individuals aged 55-65 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top UK soccer coach installed vitamin D booths in his club</title><link>/posts/top-uk-soccer-coach-installed-vitamin-d-booths-in-his-club.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/top-uk-soccer-coach-installed-vitamin-d-booths-in-his-club.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="clipped-from-various-places-on-the-web-dec-20-2012">Clipped from various places on the web Dec 20, 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sir Alex Ferguson, manager of Manchester United soccer club, has revealed that United had a Vitamin D machine installed for compensate for Manchester&amp;rsquo;s lack of natural sunlight.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Used 3X per week by each of the soccer players&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Now Manchester United can combat lack of sun&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Manchester has a reputation as being one of the wettest places in the UK, so it&amp;rsquo;s little wonder Sir Alex Ferguson had a tanning booth installed so the players could top up their Vitamin D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Surgeon on a mission to promote vitamin D</title><link>/posts/surgeon-on-a-mission-to-promote-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/surgeon-on-a-mission-to-promote-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Strong bones need both physical activity and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/strong-bones-need-both-physical-activity-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/strong-bones-need-both-physical-activity-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-status-and-physical-activity-interact-to-improve-bone-mass-in-adolescents">Vitamin D status and physical activity interact to improve bone mass in adolescents.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="the-helena-study">The HELENA Study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Aug;23(8):2227-37. Epub 2012 Jan 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Valtueña J, Gracia-Marco L, Vicente-Rodríguez G, González-Gross M, Huybrechts I, Rey-López JP, Mouratidou T, Sioen I, Mesana MI, Martínez AE, Widhalm K, Moreno LA; HELENA Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Collaborators (230)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Health and Human Performance, Faculty of Physical Activity and Sport Sciences-INEF, Technical University of Madrid, C/ Martín Fierro 7, Madrid, Spain. &lt;a href="mailto:jara.valtuena@upm.es">jara.valtuena@upm.es&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Activity and being outdoors helps seniors – GPS and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/activity-and-being-outdoors-helps-seniors-gps-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/activity-and-being-outdoors-helps-seniors-gps-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-relationship-between-outdoor-activity-and-health-in-older-adults-using-gps">The Relationship between Outdoor Activity and Health in Older Adults Using GPS&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 2012, 9, 4615-4625; doi:10.3390/ijerph9124615&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jacqueline Kerr Simon Marshall , Suneeta Godbole , Suvi Neukam , Katie Crist , Kari Wasilenko , Shahrokh Golshan 3 and David Buchner 4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Family and Preventive Medicine, UCSD, 9500 Gilman Drive, La Jolla, CA 92093, USA; E-Mails: &lt;a href="mailto:sjmarshall@ucsd.edu">sjmarshall@ucsd.edu&lt;/a> (S.M); &lt;a href="mailto:sgodbole@ucsd.edu">sgodbole@ucsd.edu&lt;/a> (S.G.); &lt;a href="mailto:kcrist@ucsd.edu">kcrist@ucsd.edu&lt;/a> (K.C.); &lt;a href="mailto:kwasilenko@ucsd.edu">kwasilenko@ucsd.edu&lt;/a> (K.W.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 University of New England College of Osteopathic Medicine, 11 Hills Beach Rd, Biddeford, ME 04005, USA; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:sneukam@une.edu">sneukam@une.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 2 muscles, not all muscles, get benefit from Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-2-muscles-not-all-muscles-get-benefit-from-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-2-muscles-not-all-muscles-get-benefit-from-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Off Topic – Light exercise extend life by 4.5 years – perhaps more than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/off-topic-light-exercise-extend-life-by-45-years-perhaps-more-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-light-exercise-extend-life-by-45-years-perhaps-more-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="leisure-time-physical-activity-of-moderate-to-vigorous-intensity-and-mortality-a-large-pooled-cohort-analysis">Leisure Time Physical Activity of Moderate to Vigorous Intensity and Mortality: A Large Pooled Cohort Analysis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Steven C. Moore1*, Alpa V. Patel2, Charles E. Matthews1, Amy Berrington de Gonzalez1, Yikyung Park1, Hormuzd A. Katki1, Martha S. Linet1, Elisabete Weiderpass3,4,5,6, Kala Visvanathan7, Kathy J. Helzlsouer7, Michael Thun2, Susan M. Gapstur2, Patricia Hartge1, I-Min Lee8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Cancer Epidemiology and Genetics, National Cancer Institute, Bethesda, Maryland, United States of America, 2 Epidemiology Research Program, American Cancer Society, Atlanta, Georgia, United States of America, 3 Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institute, Stockholm, Sweden, 4 Cancer Registry of Norway, Oslo, Norway, 5 Department of Community Medicine, Tromso, Norway, 6 Samfundet Folkhalsan, Helsinki, Finland, 7 Department of Epidemiology, Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Baltimore, Maryland, United States of America, 8 Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, United States of America&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5,000 IU vitamin D helped UK professional athletes in the winter</title><link>/posts/5000-iu-vitamin-d-helped-uk-professional-athletes-in-the-winter.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5000-iu-vitamin-d-helped-uk-professional-athletes-in-the-winter.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="assessment-of-vitamin-d-concentration-in-non-supplemented-professional-athletes-and-healthy-adults-during-the-winter-months-in-the-uk-implications-for-skeletal-muscle-function">Assessment of vitamin D concentration in non-supplemented professional athletes and healthy adults during the winter months in the UK: implications for skeletal muscle function.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Sports Sci. 2012 Oct 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Close GL, Russell J, Cobley JN, Owens DJ, Wilson G, Gregson W, Fraser WD, Morton JP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Muscle Metabolism and Physiology Research group, Research Institute for Sport and Exercise Sciences , Liverpool John Moores University , Liverpool , UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract The current study implemented a two-part design to (1) assess the vitamin D concentration of a large cohort of non-vitamin D supplemented UK-based athletes and 30 age-matched healthy non-athletes and (2) to examine the effects of 5000 IU · day(-1) vitamin D(3) supplementation for 8-weeks on musculoskeletal performance in a placebo controlled trial. Vitamin D concentration was determined as severely deficient if serum 25(OH)D &amp;lt; 12.5 nmol · l(-1), deficient 12.5-30 nmol · l(-1) and inadequate 30-50 nmol · l(-1).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese helped with resistance training by 4000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/obese-helped-with-resistance-training-by-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-helped-with-resistance-training-by-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="impact-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-a-resistance-training-intervention-on-body-composition-muscle-function-and-glucose-tolerance-in-overweight-and-obese-adults-clinical-nutrition">Impact of vitamin D supplementation during a resistance training intervention on body composition, muscle function, and glucose tolerance in overweight and obese adults Clinical Nutrition&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Andres E. Carrillo a, Michael G. Flynn b, Catherine Pinkston c, Melissa M. Markofski a, Yan Jiang c, Shawn S. Donkin d, Dorothy Teegarden c, &lt;a href="mailto:teegarden@purdue.edu">teegarden@purdue.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Wastl Human Performance Laboratory, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Health and Human Performance, College of Charleston, Charleston, SC, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Muscle strength not increased by raising vitamin D to only 30 ng – RCT</title><link>/posts/muscle-strength-not-increased-by-raising-vitamin-d-to-only-30-ng-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/muscle-strength-not-increased-by-raising-vitamin-d-to-only-30-ng-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>During basic training white females decreased vitamin D but non-whites increased</title><link>/posts/during-basic-training-white-females-decreased-vitamin-d-but-non-whites-increased.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/during-basic-training-white-females-decreased-vitamin-d-but-non-whites-increased.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Concussion-Free Football Season: How one High School beat the odds</title><link>/posts/a-concussion-free-football-season-how-one-high-school-beat-the-odds.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-concussion-free-football-season-how-one-high-school-beat-the-odds.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-hrefpostshigh-school-in-atlanta-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-2378high-school-in-atlantaa-added-vitamin-d-in-2011-to-their-sports-teams">&lt;a href="/posts/high-school-in-atlanta" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2378">High School in Atlanta&lt;/a> added vitamin D in 2011 to their sports teams&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Martin Luther King Jr. High School in Lithonia, Georgia has reduced its concussions and sports injuries by almost 100%. What was their secret? In 2011, the school started a parent-led nutrition program that included a daily regimen of vitamin D. The program was instituted by Dr. L. Ray Matthews, one of the nation’s leading researchers in vitamin D and assistant professor of surgery and director of surgical care at Grady Memorial Hospital in Atlanta,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Female Athlete health problems may be due to lack of vitamin D and Iron</title><link>/posts/female-athlete-health-problems-may-be-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d-and-iron.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/female-athlete-health-problems-may-be-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d-and-iron.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Half as many fractures for girls with high vitamin D intake</title><link>/posts/half-as-many-fractures-for-girls-with-high-vitamin-d-intake.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-as-many-fractures-for-girls-with-high-vitamin-d-intake.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-calcium-and-dairy-intakes-and-stress-fractures-among-female-adolescents">Vitamin D, Calcium, and Dairy Intakes and Stress Fractures Among Female Adolescents&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Kendrin R. Sonneville, ScD, RD; Catherine M. Gordon, MD, MSc; Mininder S. Kocher, MD, MPH; Laura M. Pierce, BA; Arun Ramappa, MD; Alison E. Field, ScD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. Published online March 5, 2012. , doi:10.1001/archpediatrics.2012.5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective To identify whether calcium, vitamin D, and/or dairy intakes are prospectively associated with stress fracture risk among female adolescents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Design Prospective cohort study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Helps Atlanta High School Athletes</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-atlanta-high-school-athletes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-atlanta-high-school-athletes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d">Overview Sports and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-dark-skin-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1064">Overview Dark Skin and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/a-concussion-free-football-season-how-one-high-school-beat-the-odds">A Concussion-Free Football Season: How one High School beat the odds - July 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-and-sports-book-2011-at-vitamindwiki" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1907">Review of Vitamin D and Sports book - 2011 at VitaminDWiki&lt;/a> excellent on Athletics, covers vitamin D concerns well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-bone-fractures-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1344">Overview Bone Fractures and vitamin D&lt;/a> mainly seniors&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D improves athletic performance</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-improves-athletic-performance.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-improves-athletic-performance.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-athletic-performance-the-potential-role-of-muscle">Vitamin D and Athletic Performance: The Potential Role of Muscle&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Asian Journal of Sports Medicine; 2011;2(4) : 211-219&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce Hamilton (MBCHB, FACSP); ASPETAR, Qatar Orthopaedic and Sports Medicine Hospital, Doha, Qatar &lt;a href="mailto:bruce.hamilton@aspetar.com">bruce.hamilton@aspetar.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received:	May 27,2011; Accepted: 	July 7,2011; Available online:	December 5, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is a worldwide epidemic, with well known impacts on calcium metabolism and bone health, but increasingly recognized associations with chronic health problems such as bowel and colonic cancer, arthritis, diabetes and cardiovascular disease. In recent years in the Sports Medicine literature, there has been an increased focus on the potential impact that inadequate Vitamin D levels may have on athletic performance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>None of the female soccer players got the minimum vitamin D</title><link>/posts/none-of-the-female-soccer-players-got-the-minimum-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/none-of-the-female-soccer-players-got-the-minimum-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nutrition Status of Junior Elite Canadian Female Soccer Athletes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2011 Dec;21(6):507-514.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gibson JC, Stuart-Hill L, Martin S, Gaul C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Exercise Science, Physical and Health Education, University of Victoria, Victoria, British Columbia, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CONTEXT:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adolescent female team-sport athletes are faced with the challenge of meeting nutrition requirements for growth and development, as well as sport performance. There is a paucity of evidence describing the dietary adequacy of this population in respect to these physiological demands. Therefore, the aim of this study was to comprehensively evaluate the nutrition status of junior elite female soccer athletes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fitness is associated with vitamin D, even accounting for BMI</title><link>/posts/fitness-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-even-accounting-for-bmi.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fitness-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-even-accounting-for-bmi.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cardiorespiratory-fitness-adiposity-and-serum-25-dihydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-women">Cardiorespiratory Fitness, Adiposity, and Serum 25-Dihydroxyvitamin D Levels in Women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Stephen W Farrell and Benjamin L Willis J Womens Health (Larchmt) () (2011) PMID 21970522&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2011 Oct 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cooper Institute , Dallas Texas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose: We examined the cross-sectional associations among cardiorespiratory fitness (CRF), different measures of adiposity, and serum vitamin D levels in women.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: Between 2007 and 2010, 1320 women completed a health examination. Measures included body mass index (BMI), waist circumference (WC), waist/hip ratio, percent body fat, CRF based on a maximal treadmill exercise test, and measurement of serum vitamin D. Participants were classified by CRF as unfit (lowest 20%) and fit (remaining 80%) based on age, as well as by clinical cutoff points for adiposity measures, and by categories of serum vitamin D. We examined trends of CRF and adiposity exposures across serum vitamin D categories. We calculated odds ratios (OR) of serum vitamin D insufficiency or deficiency across levels of adiposity exposures before and after adjustment for CRF.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Teenage knee injury 4X increase in last decade in Philadelphia</title><link>/posts/teenage-knee-injury-4x-increase-in-last-decade-in-philadelphia.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/teenage-knee-injury-4x-increase-in-last-decade-in-philadelphia.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="knee-injuries-on-the-rise-in-child-and-adolescent-athleteshttpmedicalxpresscomnews2011-10-knee-injuries-child-adolescent-athleteshtml">&lt;a href="http://medicalxpress.com/news/2011-10-knee-injuries-child-adolescent-athletes.html">Knee injuries on the rise in child and adolescent athletes&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clipped from Medical Express&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="knee-injuries-in-children-and-adolescents-has-there-been-an-increase-in-acl-and-meniscus-tears-in-recent-years">&amp;ldquo;Knee Injuries In Children and Adolescents: Has There Been An Increase In ACL and Meniscus Tears In Recent Years?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Academy of Pediatrics Oct 16, 2011 presentation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Researchers at the Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Philadelphia noted a more than 400 percent increase in these injuries at their institution over the last decade&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="suspect-slower-muscle-reaction-time-due-to-low-vitamin-d-levels">Suspect slower muscle reaction time due to low vitamin D levels&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d">Overview Sports and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Concussions (traumatic brain injury) getting big press coverage, vitamin D might be both a cause and a solution</title><link>/posts/concussions-traumatic-brain-injury-getting-big-press-coverage-vitamin-d-might-be--and-a-solution.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/concussions-traumatic-brain-injury-getting-big-press-coverage-vitamin-d-might-be--and-a-solution.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="reasons-to-associate-concussion-with-low-vitamind">Reasons to associate concussion with low vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Those people having concussions have lower vitamin D levels&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Increase in the number of concussions as vitamin D levels have dropped&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Giving vitamin D (and other supplements) shortens recovery time from concussions&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Giving vitamin D resulted in fewer concussions (football players)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h4 id="researchers-tie-gulf-war-illness-to-brain-damagehttpmusatodaycomarticlenewsnation1982817preferredarticleviewmodesingle-usa-today-march2013">&lt;a href="http://m.usatoday.com/article/news/nation/1982817?preferredArticleViewMode=single">Researchers tie Gulf War illness to brain damage&lt;/a> USA Today March 2013&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Using fMRI machines, the Georgetown University researchers could see anomalies in the bundle of nerve fibers that interpret pain signals in the brain in 31 Gulf War veterans. The research will be published Wednesday in PLOS ONE journal.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>CAUTION: The FMRI magnetic fields MAY substantially reduce the vitamin D levels - &lt;a href="/posts/update" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 4093">Update May 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Another outdoor sport produces more bone than indoor sport – vitamin D</title><link>/posts/another-outdoor-sport-produces-more-bone-than-indoor-sport-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/another-outdoor-sport-produces-more-bone-than-indoor-sport-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-badminton-and-ice-hockey-on-bone-mass-in-young-males-a-12-year-follow-up">Effects of badminton and ice hockey on bone mass in young males: a 12-year follow-up.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Bone. 2010 Sep;47(3):666-72. Epub 2010 Jun 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tervo T, Nordström P, Nordström A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Surgical and Perioperative Sciences, Sports Medicine, Umeå University, Umeå, Sweden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of the present study was to investigate the influence of different types of weight bearing physical activity on bone mineral density (BMD, g/cm(2)) and evaluate any residual benefits after the active sports career. Beginning at 17 years of age, BMD was measured 5 times, during 12 years, in 19 badminton players, 48 ice hockey players, and 25 controls. During the active career, badminton players gained significantly more BMD compared to ice hockey players at all sites: in their femoral neck (mean difference (Delta) 0.06 g/cm(2), p=0.04), humerus (Delta 0.06 g/cm(2), p=0.01), lumbar spine (Delta 0.08 g/cm(2), p=0.01), and their legs (Delta 0.05 g/cm(2), p=0.003), after adjusting for age at baseline, changes in weight, height, and active years. BMD gains in badminton players were higher also compared to in controls at all sites (Delta 0.06-0.17 g/cm(2), p&amp;lt;0.01 for all). Eleven badminton players and 37 ice hockey players stopped their active career a mean of 6 years before the final follow-up. Both these groups lost significantly more BMD at the femoral neck and lumbar spine compared to the control group (Delta 0.05-0.12 g/cm(2), p&amp;lt;0.05 for all).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basketball players low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/basketball-players-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/basketball-players-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-levels-of-vitamin-d-in-professional-basketball-players-after-wintertime-relationship-with-dietary-intake-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium">Low levels of vitamin D in professional basketball players after wintertime: relationship with dietary intake of vitamin D and calcium&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolor00fnote-pdf-is-attached---text-extracted-below-with-just-a-single-image-from-the-pdfspan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Note: PDF is attached - text extracted below with just a single image from the PDF&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d">Overview Sports and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/suggests-that-college-athletes-supplement-with-vitamin-d-in-winter" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 479">Suggests that college athletes supplement with vitamin D in winter - June 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/young-israeli-athletes-and-dancers-had-just-25-ng-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 903">Young Israeli athletes and dancers had just 25 ng of vitamin D – Sept 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Senior women more physically able if vitamin D higher than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/senior-women-more-physically-able-if-vitamin-d-higher-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/senior-women-more-physically-able-if-vitamin-d-higher-than-30-ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ballet Dancers with low D had 50 percent more injuries – pilot study</title><link>/posts/ballet-dancers-with-low-d-had-50-percent-more-injuries-pilot-study.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ballet-dancers-with-low-d-had-50-percent-more-injuries-pilot-study.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Book on Sports and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/book-on-sports-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/book-on-sports-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="athletes-edge-faster-quicker-stronger-with-vitamin-d">Athlete&amp;rsquo;s Edge: Faster, Quicker, Stronger With Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>by Dr. John Cannell, $23 including US shipping&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;685&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Athletes-Edge-Quicker-Stronger-Vitamin/dp/0977427293/ref=sr_1_2?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=Athlete%27s+Edge%3A+Faster%2C+Quicker%2C+Stronger&amp;amp;qid=1596585017&amp;amp;sr=8-2">Amazon&lt;/a> $4 used 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>320 page book is described on their &lt;a href="http://www.vitamindsportsbook.com/">website&lt;/a> which allow looking at 12 pages and has the following summary&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This book covers new ground. After extensive investigation and translation of numerous scientific reports into the English language,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>   author Dr. John Cannell reveals a long-held secret once known only to Eastern European athletic trainers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More muscle injuries in NFL players who were low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/more-muscle-injuries-in-nfl-players-who-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-muscle-injuries-in-nfl-players-who-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-lower-in-nfl-football-players-who-suffered-muscled-injuries-study-reports">Vitamin D Lower In NFL Football Players Who Suffered Muscled Injuries, Study Reports&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been known to cause an assortment of health problems, a recent study being presented at the American Orthopaedic Society for Sports Medicine’s (AOSSM) Annual Meeting in San Diego today, suggests that lack of the vitamin might also increase the chance of muscle injuries in athletes, specifically NFL football players.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="san-diego-ca-prweb-july-09-2011httpwwwprwebcomreleasesprwebaossm7prweb8619796htm20">&lt;a href="http://www.prweb.com/releases/prwebAOSSM/7/prweb8619796.htm%20">San Diego, CA (PRWEB) July 09, 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been known to cause an assortment of health problems, a recent study being presented at the American Orthopaedic Society for Sports Medicine’s (AOSSM) Annual Meeting in San Diego today, suggests that lack of the vitamin might also increase the chance of muscle injuries in athletes, specifically NFL football players.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4000 IU vitamin D and exercise for overweight – PhD 2010</title><link>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-and-exercise-for-overweight-phd-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-and-exercise-for-overweight-phd-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="does-vitamin-d-supplementation-augment-exercise-induced-changes-in-health-and-physical-performance">Does vitamin D supplementation augment exercise-induced changes in health and physical performance?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>by Carrillo, Andres Ernesto, Ph.D., PURDUE UNIVERSITY, 2010, 167 pages; 3444489&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this research was to examine the effects of vitamin D supplementation &lt;strong>(4000 IU/d)&lt;/strong> during an exercise training intervention on body composition, muscular strength and power, glucose tolerance, and inflammatory biomarkers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-three (26.1 ? 4.7 yrs) overweight-to-obese (BMI: 31.3 ? 3.2 kg/m2 ) adults were recruited during winter months (25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) 19.3 ? 7.2 ng/mL) and randomized into a vitamin D (VitD, n = 10) or placebo (PL, n = 13) group.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perhaps Stress fractures 2X less frequent if 4000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/perhaps-stress-fractures-2x-less-frequent-if-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/perhaps-stress-fractures-2x-less-frequent-if-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-is-associated-with-low-incidence-of-stress-fractures">High serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D is associated with low incidence of stress fractures.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2011 Jun 22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jbmr.451.">doi: 10.1002/jbmr.451.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burgi AA, Gorham ED, Garland CF, Mohr SB, Garland FC, Zeng K, Thompson K, Lappe JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Naval Health Research Center, San Diego, California.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations are associated with hip fractures, but the dose-response relationship of serum 25(OH)D with risk of stress fractures in young women is unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oxygen uptake associated with higher vitamin D – up to 50 hours per week</title><link>/posts/oxygen-uptake-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-up-to-50-hours-per-week.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/oxygen-uptake-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d-up-to-50-hours-per-week.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="relation-of-vitamin-d-level-to-maximal-oxygen-uptake-in-adults">Relation of vitamin D level to maximal oxygen uptake in adults.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Cardiol. 2011 Apr 15;107(8):1246-9. Epub 2011 Feb 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ardestani A, Parker B, Mathur S, Clarkson P, Pescatello LS, Hoffman HJ, Polk DM, Thompson PD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Cardiology, Hartford Hospital, Hartford, Connecticut, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low cardiorespiratory fitness and low serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels are associated with increased cardiovascular and all-cause mortality, but whether low 25(OH)D is independently associated with cardiorespiratory fitness in healthy adults is not known. We examined 25(OH)D levels and fitness in 200 healthy adults participating in a double-blind clinical trial investigating statins and muscle performance (STOMP study). Maximal aerobic exercise capacity (Vo?(max)) was measured using metabolic gas analysis during graded treadmill exercise to exhaustion. 25(OH)D was measured using an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. Daily physical activity was assessed using the Paffenbarger Physical Activity Questionnaire.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors with more than 20 ng of vitamin D were 14 percent stronger</title><link>/posts/seniors-with-more-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-were-14-percent-stronger.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-with-more-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-were-14-percent-stronger.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-nutritional-status-on-muscle-function-and-strength-in-healthy-women-aged-over-sixty-five-years">Effect of Vitamin D Nutritional Status on Muscle Function and Strength in Healthy Women Aged over Sixty-Five Years.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Nutr Health Aging. 2011;15(5):349-54.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mastaglia SR, Seijo M, Muzio D, Somoza J, Nuñez M, Oliveri B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S.R. Mastaglia, Av. Cordoba 2351(1120), Tel/Fax: 541159508972, Buenos Aires- Argentina, &lt;a href="mailto:Silvinamastaglia@hotmail.com">Silvinamastaglia@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D insufficiency is common in elderly adults, and leads to secondary hyperparathyroidism, bone loss, muscle weakness, and osteoporotic fractures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To evaluate the relation between vitamin D nutritional status and muscle function and muscle strength in women aged over 65 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>8500 IU average daily helped sports performance</title><link>/posts/8500-iu-average-daily-helped-sports-performance.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/8500-iu-average-daily-helped-sports-performance.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-cholecalciferol-and-calcium-supplementati-on-on-muscle-strength-and-energy-metabolism-in-vitamin-d-deficient-asian-indians-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Effect of cholecalciferol and calcium supplementati on on muscle strength and energy metabolism in vitamin D-deficient Asian Indians: a randomized, controlled trial.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2010 Oct;73(4):445-51. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2265.2010.03816.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2265.2010.03816.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gupta R, Sharma U, Gupta N, Kalaivani M, Singh U, Guleria R, Jagannathan NR, Goswami R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India. &lt;a href="mailto:gosravinder@hotmail.com">gosravinder@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CONTEXT:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is prevalent worldwide. Vitamin D supplementation has shown variable effect on skeletal muscle strength in the elderly with hypovitaminosis D. There is a paucity of similar data in young individuals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Injury-Prevention with Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/injury-prevention-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/injury-prevention-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://triathlon.competitor.com/2010/02/nutrition/vitamin-d-the-injury-prevention-vitamin_7118">Tralthlon competitor had the following&lt;/a> Feb 2010, Written by: Nathan Koch&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D: The Injury-Prevention Vitamin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New studies find that Vitamin D may be more important than previously thought when it comes to the health of endurance athletes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an avid cyclist and runner, I am always looking for ways to improve performance while avoiding forced time off due to injury or illness. While attending the American College of Sports Medicine meeting in Seattle last year, I heard a lecture from a well-known researcher on the benefits of vitamin D supplementation, which included increased athletic performance. I even learned about a study in which Russian and German athletes used ultraviolet sunlamps to improve performance. &lt;strong>Four Russian sprinters used UV light and another group didn’t. The two groups trained identically for the 100-meter sprint. The control group lowered its time by 1.7 percent and the UV group improved 7.4 percent.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces stress fractures – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-stress-fractures-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-stress-fractures-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="evaluating-the-relationship-of-calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-the-prevention-of-stress-fracture-injuries-in-the-young-athlete-a-review-of-the-literature">Evaluating the relationship of calcium and vitamin D in the prevention of stress fracture injuries in the young athlete: a review of the literature.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PM R. 2010 Oct;2(10):945-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tenforde AS, Sayres LC, Sainani KL, Fredericson M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calcium and vitamin D are recognized as 2 components of nutrition needed to achieve and maintain bone health. Calcium and vitamin D have been clearly shown to improve bone density and prevent fractures at all ages. However, the literature is conflicting as to the role of these nutrients in young athletes ages 18 to 35 years, both for bone development and for the prevention of bone overuse injuries. Differences in findings may relate to study design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Story – Prevent injuries and speed healing with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/story-prevent-injuries-and-speed-healing-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/story-prevent-injuries-and-speed-healing-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-iehealthhttpiehealthblogspotcom201001todays-post-thursday-1-21-2010-lasthtml20-jan-2010">From &lt;a href="http://iehealth.blogspot.com/2010/01/todays-post-thursday-1-21-2010-last.html%20">IEHealth&lt;/a> Jan 2010&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Last Saturday, I spoke to a woman who broke some of her ribs when she fell off of a bicycle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She saw a doctor close to where she works who is one of the pioneers in using vitamin D3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He dramatically, though for just 3 weeks, increased her vitamin D. The results may interest you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her pain stopped more than four times sooner than the doctors at the emergency room told her to expect. Then when she got an x-ray at the point when the doctors were checking to see if the progress they expected to see towards full healing, about 25% there, had happened, she was 100 % healed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Postmenopausal women with higher vitamin D exercised more</title><link>/posts/postmenopausal-women-with-higher-vitamin-d-exercised-more.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/postmenopausal-women-with-higher-vitamin-d-exercised-more.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="duration-of-physical-activity-and-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-of-postmenopausal-women">Duration of Physical Activity and Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D Status of Postmenopausal Women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ann Epidemiol. 2011 Mar 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kluczynski MA, Lamonte MJ, Mares JA, Wactawski-Wende J, Smith AW, Engelman CD, Andrews CA, Snetselaar LG, Sarto GE, Millen AE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Social and Preventive Medicine, School of Public Health and Health Professions, University at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY (M.A.K., A.E.M., M.J.L., J.W.); Department of Ophthalmology and Visual Sciences, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, Madison, WI (J.A.M.); Outcomes Research Branch, Applied Research Program, Cancer Control and Population Sciences, National Cancer Institute, 6130 Bethesda, MD (A.W.S.); Department of Population Health Sciences, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, Madison, WI (C.D.E.); Department of Biostatistics, School of Public Health and Health Professions, University at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY (C.A.A.); Departments of Community and Behavior Health and Epidemiology, College of Public Health, the University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA (L.G.S.); and Department of Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, Madison, WI (G.E.S.).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shin splints decrease with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/shin-splints-decrease-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shin-splints-decrease-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-may-both-prevent-and-treat-shin-splints">Vitamin D may both prevent and treat shin splints.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has been proven to prevent bone stress fractures and micro cracks.&lt;br>
Vitamin D appears to substantially prevent and treat shin splints, which is a closely related bone problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Google Search below&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Papers attached to the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="wikipedia-provided-alternate-terms-to-searchfor">Wikipedia provided alternate terms to search for&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The most common sources of shin splints are tendinitis, periostitis, stress fractures, and compartment syndrome.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D bed used 4 minutes daily by dark skin members of UK sports team</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-bed-used-4-minutes-daily-by-dark-skin-members-of-uk-sports-team.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-bed-used-4-minutes-daily-by-dark-skin-members-of-uk-sports-team.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="manchester-uniteds-ryan-giggs-and-rio-ferdinand-buy-into-cutting-edge-methods-at-carrington">Manchester United&amp;rsquo;s Ryan Giggs and Rio Ferdinand buy into cutting-edge methods at Carrington&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Manchester United’s attempt to &lt;strong>reclaim the Premier League title&lt;/strong> is being bolstered by cutting-edge technology which includes GPS tracking of the players, zero-gravity rehabilitation and vitamin D beds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/sport/football/teams/manchester-united/8275326/Manchester-Uniteds-Ryan-Giggs-and-Rio-Ferdinand-buy-into-cutting-edge-methods-at-Carrington.html">By Mark Ogden 21 Jan 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a revelatory access-all-areas documentary by MUTV, the club’s in-house television channel, Ryan &amp;amp; Rio — Carrington Revealed, sheds light on the behind-the-scenes operation at Manchester United’s 108-acre Carrington training centre.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less muscle and insulin resistance for children of vitamin D deficient mothers</title><link>/posts/less-muscle-and-insulin-resistance-for-children-of-vitamin-d-deficient-mothers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-muscle-and-insulin-resistance-for-children-of-vitamin-d-deficient-mothers.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-during-pregnancy-and-body-composition-and-cardiovascular-risk-markers-in-indian-children-the-mysore-parthenon-study">Maternal vitamin D status during pregnancy and body composition and cardiovascular risk markers in Indian children: the Mysore Parthenon Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>AM J CLIN NUTR () (2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ghattu V Krishnaveni, Sargoor R Veena, Nicola R Winder, Jacqueline C Hill, Kate Noonan, Barbara J Boucher, Samuel C Karat and Caroline Hd Fall&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiology Research Unit, CSI Holdsworth Memorial Hospital, Mysore, India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Metabolic consequences of vitamin D deficiency have become a recent research focus. Maternal vitamin D status is thought to influence musculoskeletal health in children, but its relation with offspring metabolic risk is not known.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Sports and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-sports-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="should-an-athlete-supplement-with-vitamin-d---2018">Should an athlete supplement with Vitamin D - 2018&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D and the Athlete: Current Perspectives and NewChallenges&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/vitamin-d-and-the-athlete---current-perspectives-and-newchallenges.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/athletes-yes-no.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="high-intensity-athletes---professional-and-olympic">High Intensity Athletes - Professional and Olympic&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sprint internal training improves cognition &lt;a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/sms.14349?campaign=wolearlyview%20">March 2023&lt;/a>, &lt;del>!hs&lt;/del> &lt;a href="https://www.mdpi.com/1660-4601/19/1/613%20">Jan 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/olympic-athletes-and-vitamin-d-clippings-2009-10" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 349">Olympic Athletes and vitamin D - clippings 2009-10&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>UV used by Olympic athletes since the 1930&amp;rsquo;s, High UV in Mexico Olympics broke many records&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/professional-sports-team-takes-span-stylecolor00f5000-iuspan-vitamin-d-and-wins-championship" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 293">Professional sports team takes &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">5000 IU&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> vitamin D and wins championship&lt;/a> Hockey&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 intervention increased elderly muscle strength</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-intervention-increased-elderly-muscle-strength.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-intervention-increased-elderly-muscle-strength.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-randomized-controlled-trial-of-the-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-muscle-strength-and-mobility-in-older-women-with-vitamin-d-insufficiency">A Randomized Controlled Trial of the Effects of Vitamin D on Muscle Strength and Mobility in Older Women with Vitamin D Insufficiency&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kun Zhu PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Nicole Austin PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Amanda Devine PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>David Bruce MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Richard L. Prince MD&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Article first published online: 4 NOV 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03142.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2010, Copyright the Authors. Journal compilation © 2010, The American Geriatrics Society&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 58, Issue 11, pages 2063–2068, November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhu, K., Austin, N., Devine, A., Bruce, D. and Prince, R. L. (2010), A Randomized Controlled Trial of the Effects of Vitamin D on Muscle Strength and Mobility in Older Women with Vitamin D Insufficiency. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society, 58: 2063–2068. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03142.x">doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03142.x&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>