<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Obesity on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/obesity.html</link><description>Recent content in Obesity on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/obesity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Obese teens needed 4000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/obese-teens-needed-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-teens-needed-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="press-release-from-university-of-missourihttpmunewsmissouriedunews-releases20111101-obese-adolescents-benefit-from-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplements-nov-2011">&lt;a href="http://munews.missouri.edu/news-releases/2011/1101-obese-adolescents-benefit-from-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplements/">Press Release from University of Missouri&lt;/a> Nov 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="the-press-release-has-the-hyperlinks">The Press Release has the hyperlinks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Catherine Peterson, nutrition researcher at MU, found that a daily dose of 4,000 IUs of vitamin D3 is both safe and effective at improving vitamin D status in obese adolescents.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="obese-adolescents-benefit-from-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplements">Obese Adolescents Benefit from High-Dose Vitamin D Supplements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="high-doses-safely-combat-nutritional-deficiencies-mu-researchers-find">High doses safely combat nutritional deficiencies, MU researchers find&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>COLUMBIA, Mo. –Vitamin D deficiency is common in Americans, and especially in overweight and obese adolescents, according to the National Institutes of Health. University of Missouri researchers have found that providing obese adolescents with a high daily dose of vitamin D3 is safe and effective in improving their vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity and diabetes reduced when move to better neighborhood – or better UV</title><link>/posts/obesity-and-diabetes-reduced-when-move-to-better-neighborhood-or-better-uv.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-and-diabetes-reduced-when-move-to-better-neighborhood-or-better-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="neighborhoods-obesity-and-diabetes--a-randomized-social-experiment">Neighborhoods, Obesity, and Diabetes — A Randomized Social Experiment&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Jens Ludwig, Ph.D. &lt;a href="mailto:jludwig@uchicago.ed">jludwig@uchicago.ed&lt;/a>, Lisa Sanbonmatsu, Ph.D., Lisa Gennetian, Ph.D., Emma Adam, Ph.D., Greg J. Duncan, Ph.D., Lawrence F. Katz, Ph.D., Ronald C. Kessler, Ph.D., Jeffrey R. Kling, Ph.D., Stacy Tessler Lindau, M.D., Robert C. Whitaker, M.D., M.P.H., and Thomas W. McDade, Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med 2011; 365:1509-1519October 20, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND The question of whether neighborhood environment contributes directly to the development of obesity and diabetes remains unresolved. The study reported on here uses data from a social experiment to assess the association of randomly assigned variation in neighborhood conditions with obesity and diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Telomeres improved when obese blacks took 2000 IU of vitamin D daily</title><link>/posts/telomeres-improved-when-obese-blacks-took-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/telomeres-improved-when-obese-blacks-took-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Resveratrol reduce weight gain in rats</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-resveratrol-reduce-weight-gain-in-rats.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-resveratrol-reduce-weight-gain-in-rats.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="from-natural-newshttpwwwnaturalnewscom033614_resveratrol_vitamin_dhtml">from &lt;a href="http://www.naturalnews.com/033614_resveratrol_vitamin_D.html">Natural News&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Resveratrol and vitamin D synergistically team to boost metabolism and prevent obesity&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>September 19, 2011 by: John Phillip&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(NaturalNews) Resveratrol has been on the nutritional radar of researchers because of its proven ability to mimic some of the life-extending characteristics provided by calorie restriction as seen in animals and humans alike. Scientists publishing in the journal Molecular Nutrition and Food Research draw a solid link between resveratrol, vitamin D and other phytonutrients as agents that may lend a helping hand in the life-threatening battle against overweight and obesity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Weight loss and Vitamin D, Calcium, and Magnesium</title><link>/posts/weight-loss-and-vitamin-d-calcium-and-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/weight-loss-and-vitamin-d-calcium-and-magnesium.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="there-have-been-various-studies-which-have-found-weight-loss-when-increasing-one-or-more-of-the-following">There have been various studies which have found weight loss when increasing one or more of the following&lt;/h4>
&lt;h5 id="vitamin-d-nbsp-nbsp-magnesium-nbsp-nbsp-calcium">Vitamin D     Magnesium     Calcium&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>There is a lot of synergy/interaction between these nutrients in the body&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been a very large decrease in both Magnesium and Vitamin D in bodies during the past 40 years&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been a significant increase in obesity in the past 40 years&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wonder if there has been any weight loss trial using all three of the supplements&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many obesity measures far worse for senior women with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/many-obesity-measures-far-worse-for-senior-women-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-obesity-measures-far-worse-for-senior-women-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-relation-to-cardiometabolic-risk-factors-and-metabolic-syndrome-in-postmenopausal-women">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations in relation to cardiometabolic risk factors and metabolic syndrome in postmenopausal women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul;94(1):209-17. Epub 2011 May 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chacko SA, Song Y, Manson JE, Van Horn L, Eaton C, Martin LW, McTiernan A, Curb JD, Wylie-Rosett J, Phillips LS, Plodkowski RA, Liu S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and the Program on Genomics and Nutrition, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Low concentrations of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) may be associated with cardiometabolic disorders; however, little is known about their relation to intermediate metabolic and lipid markers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels increased when senior women lost weight</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-increased-when-senior-women-lost-weight.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-increased-when-senior-women-lost-weight.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-weight-loss-on-serum-vitamin-d-in-postmenopausal-women">Effects of weight loss on serum vitamin D in postmenopausal women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul;94(1):95-103. Epub 2011 May 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mason C, Xiao L, Imayama I, Duggan CR, Bain C, Foster-Schubert KE, Kong A, Campbell KL, Wang CY, Neuhouser ML, Li L, W Jeffery R, Robien K, Alfano CM, Blackburn GL, McTiernan A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center, Seattle, WA 98109, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Low concentrations of circulating vitamin D are common with obesity and may represent a potential mechanism explaining the elevated risk of certain cancers and cardiovascular outcomes observed in individuals who are overweight or obese.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black women lacking Calcium and Vitamin D weighed more</title><link>/posts/black-women-lacking-calcium-and-vitamin-d-weighed-more.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-women-lacking-calcium-and-vitamin-d-weighed-more.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="higher-amounts-of-body-fat-are-associated-with-inadequate-intakes-of-calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-african-american-women">Higher amounts of body fat are associated with inadequate intakes of calcium and vitamin D in African American women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrition Research; Volume 31, Issue 7, July 2011, Pages 527-536; doi:10.1016/j.nutres.2011.06.005&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diane K. Tidwell a, &lt;a href="mailto:ditdwell@fsnhp.msstate.edu">ditdwell@fsnhp.msstate.edu&lt;/a> and Melinda W. Valliant b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Food Science, Nutrition and Health Promotion, PO Box 9805, Mississippi State, MS 39762&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Nutrition and Hospitality Management, The University of Mississippi&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 11 October 2010; revised 22 June 2011; accepted 23 June 2011, online 12 August 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone lost during postmenopausal dieting not all recovered with weight re-gain</title><link>/posts/bone-lost-during-postmenopausal-dieting-not-all-recovered-with-weight-re-gain.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-lost-during-postmenopausal-dieting-not-all-recovered-with-weight-re-gain.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="postmenopausal-women-who-lose-weight-may-also-lose-bone-mass-that-might-not-returnhttparticleslatimescom2011aug19newsla-heb-osteoporosis-weight-loss-20110819">&lt;a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2011/aug/19/news/la-heb-osteoporosis-weight-loss-20110819">Postmenopausal women who lose weight may also lose bone mass that might not return&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>August 19, 2011 By Jeannine Stein, Los Angeles Times&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Postmenopausal women who lose weight can also lose bone mass. But a study finds that regaining that weight doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily replace the lost bone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The small, exploratory study included 23 overweight women who had been through menopause and were not taking any hormone therapy or drugs that might affect their bone metabolism. Women are at high risk for osteoporosis after menopause.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese men were 40 percent more likely to be vitamin D deficient than women</title><link>/posts/obese-men-were-40-percent-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-women.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-men-were-40-percent-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-women.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="impact-of-gender-on-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-morbidly-obese-patients-a-cross-sectional-study">Impact of gender on vitamin D deficiency in morbidly obese patients: a cross-sectional study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul 27. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2011.140.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2011.140.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johnson LK, Hofsø D, Aasheim ET, Tanbo T, Holven KB, Andersen LF, Røislien J, Hjelmesæth J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1] Department of Medicine, Morbid Obesity Centre, Vestfold Hospital Trust, Tønsberg, Norway &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup> Department of Gynaecology, Norwegian Resource Centre for Women&amp;rsquo;s Health, Oslo University Hospital Rikshospitalet, Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Objective: Obesity is associated with vitamin D deficiency (25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) &amp;lt;50?nmol/l). We aimed to examine the effect of gender on vitamin D status in severe obesity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4000 IU vitamin D was not enough to reduce obesity – PhD 2010</title><link>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-reduce-obesity-phd-2010.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-reduce-obesity-phd-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="does-vitamin-d-supplementation-augment-exercise-induced-changes-in-health-and-physical-performance">Does vitamin D supplementation augment exercise-induced changes in health and physical performance?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>by Carrillo, Andres Ernesto, Ph.D., PURDUE UNIVERSITY, 2010, 167 pages; 3444489&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this research was to examine the effects of vitamin D supplementation &lt;strong>(4000 IU/d)&lt;/strong> during an exercise training intervention on body composition, muscular strength and power, glucose tolerance, and inflammatory biomarkers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-three (26.1 ? 4.7 yrs) overweight-to-obese (BMI: 31.3 ? 3.2 kg/m2 ) adults were recruited during winter months (25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) 19.3 ? 7.2 ng/mL) and randomized into a vitamin D (VitD, n = 10) or placebo (PL, n = 13) group.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Adioponectin and low vitamin D both associated with Obesity</title><link>/posts/low-adioponectin-and-low-vitamin-d-both-associated-with-obesity.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-adioponectin-and-low-vitamin-d-both-associated-with-obesity.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-independent-association-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-adiponectin-and-its-relation-with-bmi-in-two-large-cohorts">The Independent Association Between 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Adiponectin and Its Relation With BMI in Two Large Cohorts:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The NHS and the HPFS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obesity (Silver Spring). 2011 Jul 14. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/oby.2011.210.">doi: 10.1038/oby.2011.210.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vaidya A, Williams JS, Forman JP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes, and Hypertension, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and adiponectin levels are both associated with obesity and cardiovascular disease. Cross-sectional studies have suggested that 25(OH)D concentrations are positively associated with adiponectin, and that this relation may strengthen with increasing BMI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Vitamin D Diet – book</title><link>/posts/the-vitamin-d-diet-book.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-vitamin-d-diet-book.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Older obese adults got one third the benefit from vitamin D</title><link>/posts/older-obese-adults-got-one-third-the-benefit-from-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/older-obese-adults-got-one-third-the-benefit-from-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-adiposity-on-vitamin-d-status-and-the-25-hydroxycholecalciferol-response-to">Effect of adiposity on vitamin D status and the 25-hydroxycholecalciferol response to&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>supplementation in healthy young and older Irish adults.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2011 Jun 28:1-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kirsty Forsythe L, Livingstone MB, Barnes MS, Horigan G, McSorley EM, Bonham MP, Magee PJ, Hill TR, Lucey AJ, Cashman KD, Kiely M, Strain JJ, Wallace JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Northern Ireland Centre for Food and Health, University of Ulster, Coleraine BT52 1SA, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is increasing epidemiological evidence linking sub-optimal vitamin D status with overweight and obesity. Although increasing BMI and adiposity have also been negatively associated with the change in vitamin D status following supplementation, results have been equivocal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Weight reduction review – Vitamin D and Calcium may help</title><link>/posts/weight-reduction-review-vitamin-d-and-calcium-may-help.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/weight-reduction-review-vitamin-d-and-calcium-may-help.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-for-obesity-a-review-of-randomized-controlled-trials">Calcium and vitamin D for obesity: a review of randomized controlled trials.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2011.106.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2011.106.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soares MJ, Chan She Ping-Delfos W, Ghanbari MH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Program of Nutrition, School of Public Health, Curtin Health Innovation Research Institute, Curtin University, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obesity often coexists with low calcium intake and vitamin D insufficiency. There is emerging evidence of a role for these nutrients in the regulation of body weight. However, it is unclear whether increasing intakes of calcium and/or vitamin D during energy restriction, is a better strategy for weight and fat loss. We searched the literature from 2000 to date for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) on weight loss that had increased calcium or vitamin D per se, or in combination. Primary and secondary studies were included for this analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D less than 10 ng for groups of 45 year olds</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-10-ng-for-groups-of-45-year-olds.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-10-ng-for-groups-of-45-year-olds.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and--pre-clinical-alterations-in-inflammatory-and-hemostatic-markers">25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Pre-Clinical Alterations in Inflammatory and Hemostatic Markers:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-cross-sectional-analysis-in-the--1958-british-birth-cohort">A Cross Sectional Analysis in the 1958 British Birth Cohort&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Elina Hypponen, Diane Berry, Mario Cortina-Borja, Chris Power&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical Research Council Centre for Epidemiology of Child Health and Centre for Paediatric Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University College London Institute of Child Health, London, United Kingdom&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency has been suggested as a cardiovascular risk factor, but little is known about underlying mechanisms or associations with inflammatory or hemostatic markers. Our aim was to investigate the association between&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamins To Speed Up Metabolism And Aid Weight Loss</title><link>/posts/vitamins-to-speed-up-metabolism-and-aid-weight-loss.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamins-to-speed-up-metabolism-and-aid-weight-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="by-jeff-anderson-on-29-may-2011httpuknewsreportercoukhealthvitamins-to-speed-up-metabolism-and-aid-weight-loss673588comment-283">By &lt;a href="http://uknewsreporter.co.uk/health/vitamins-to-speed-up-metabolism-and-aid-weight-loss/673588/#comment-283">Jeff Anderson on 29, May 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Henry James once wrote that the two sweetest words in the English language are ‘Summer Afternoon’- and he wasn’t talking about the effects of the sun’s essential vitamin on our abilities to speed up metabolism and fat loss. Indeed, there’s no end to the amount of happy times we can associate in the summer sun, either through playing outdoors as a kid, or playing outdoors as adults! Studies show that one Vitamin D, found in large amount through sunshine, is deficit in the industrialized world’ and pharmaceutical companies are trying to capitalize on this fundamental vitamin through fancy pills and potions. Believe it or not, this sun-sational vitamin, is also an essential part of our heart health and metabolism, as well!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skinned obese not helped much by weekly 50000 IU dose of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-obese-not-helped-much-by-weekly-50000-iu-dose-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-obese-not-helped-much-by-weekly-50000-iu-dose-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-status-among-obese-adolescents-prevalence-and-response-to-treatment">Low Vitamin D Status Among Obese Adolescents: Prevalence and Response to Treatment&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Adolescent Health, Volume 48, Issue 5 , Pages 448-452, May 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zeev Harel, M.D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patricia Flanagan, M.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michelle Forcier, M.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dalia Harel, M.Sc. Received 19 September 2010; accepted 20 January 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Adolescent Medicine, Hasbro Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Providence, Rhode Island&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Warren Alpert Medical School of Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corresponding Author InformationAddress correspondence to: Zeev Harel, M.D., Division of Adolescent Medicine, Hasbro Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, 593 Eddy Street, Providence, RI 02903&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The more vitamin D the lower the infant BMI</title><link>/posts/the-more-vitamin-d-the-lower-the-infant-bmi.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-more-vitamin-d-the-lower-the-infant-bmi.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Are microbs – probiotics – vitamin D – allergy – asthma – obesity related</title><link>/posts/are-microbs-probiotics-vitamin-d-allergy-asthma-obesity-related.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/are-microbs-probiotics-vitamin-d-allergy-asthma-obesity-related.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="gut-microbiota-probiotics-and-vitamin-d-interrelated-exposures-influencing-allergy-asthma-and-obesity">Gut microbiota, probiotics, and vitamin D: Interrelated exposures influencing allergy, asthma, and obesity?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology; Clinical reviews in allergy and immunology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2011.02.015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ngoc P. Ly MD, MPHa &lt;a href="mailto:lyn@peds.ucsf.edu">lyn@peds.ucsf.edu&lt;/a>, Augusto Litonjua MD, MPHb, Diane R. Gold MD, MPHb and Juan C. Celedón MD, DrPHc&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Division of Pediatric Pulmonary Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, University of California San Francisco, Calif&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Channing Laboratory, Brigham and Women’s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, Mass&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtually all Bariatric Surgery patients vitamin D deficient – should we routinely supplement</title><link>/posts/virtually-all-bariatric-surgery-patients-vitamin-d-deficient-should-we-routinely-supplement.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/virtually-all-bariatric-surgery-patients-vitamin-d-deficient-should-we-routinely-supplement.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-before-bariatric-surgery-should-supplement-intake-be-routinely-prescribed">Vitamin D Deficiency Before Bariatric Surgery: Should Supplement Intake Be Routinely Prescribed?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Obes Surg. 2011 Jan 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ducloux R, Nobécourt E, Chevallier JM, Ducloux H, Elian N, Altman JJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Service de Diabétologie-Endocrinologie-Nutrition, Hôpital Européen Georges Pompidou, Paris, France, &lt;a href="mailto:roxane.ducloux@egp.aphp.fr">roxane.ducloux@egp.aphp.fr&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Before bariatric surgery, we demonstrate a 96% rate of vitamin D deficiency in morbidly obese French patients: should supplement intake be routinely prescribed? We conducted a prospective observational study to demonstrate the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in morbidly obese patients awaiting bariatric surgery.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black obese children had low vitamin D and more fat under skin than whites</title><link>/posts/black-obese-children-had-low-vitamin-d-and-more-fat-under-skin-than-whites.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-obese-children-had-low-vitamin-d-and-more-fat-under-skin-than-whites.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-adiposity-and-lipids-in-black-american-and-caucasian-children">Vitamin D Status, Adiposity, and Lipids in Black American and Caucasian Children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Mar 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rajakumar K, de Las Heras J, Chen TC, Lee S, Holick MF, Arslanian SA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics (K.R.), Division of General Academic Pediatrics, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Department of Pediatrics (J.d.l.H., S.L., S.A.A.), Division of Weight Management and Wellness, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Division of Pediatric Endocrinology, Metabolism, and Diabetes Mellitus (S.A.A.), University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Department of Pediatrics and Endocrinology and Diabetes Research Group (J.d.l.H.), Cruces Hospital, 48903 Barakaldo, Vizcaya, Spain; and Department of Medicine (T.C.C., M.F.H.), Boston University School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts 02118.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Map of BMI increase</title><link>/posts/map-of-bmi-increase.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/map-of-bmi-increase.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-the-economisthttpwwweconomistcomblogsdailychart201102daily_chart_global_obesity">&lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/dailychart/2011/02/daily_chart_global_obesity">From the Economist&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="how-mens-waistlines-have-grown-since-1980">How mens&amp;rsquo; waistlines have grown since 1980&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>RISING levels of obesity are bad news for people and health-care budgets, but they also correlate with good things such as rising economic wealth. The three maps below, which are drawn from a new global study led by Professor Majid Ezzati of Imperial College, London, and published in the Lancet, show that, Polynesia aside, obesity was a rich-world phenomenon in 1980. By 2008 the rich world had itself expanded, bringing obesity to groups within countries that were previously considered poor, such as Brazil and South Africa. During that period, the prevalence rate of obesity among men doubled to nearly 10%. One country has stubbornly resisted this trend. For all its dynamism since India opened up its economy in 1990, its men have on average become even thinner. The study suggests that Congo is the thinnest country in the world, and Nauru the fattest. Imperial College&amp;rsquo;s own map is &lt;a href="http://www5.imperial.ac.uk/medicine/metabolic_risks/bmi/"> &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#390;">here&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> &lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Higher BMI need more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/higher-bmi-need-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/higher-bmi-need-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cross-sectional-and-longitudinal-relation-between-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-body-mass-index-the-tromsø-study">Cross-sectional and longitudinal relation between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and body mass index: the Tromsø study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Nutr. 2010 Oct;49(7):401-7. Epub 2010 Mar 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cross-sectional and longitudinal relation between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and body mass index: the Tromsø study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorde R, Sneve M, Emaus N, Figenschau Y, Grimnes G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, Tromsø, Norway. &lt;a href="mailto:rolf.jorde@unn.no">rolf.jorde@unn.no&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: The serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels are lower in obese than lean subjects. The present study examines the cross-sectional and longitudinal relations between body mass index (BMI) and serum 25(OH)D, and the serum 25(OH)D response to vitamin D supplementation in relation to BMI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D then Obesity then adenovirus-36</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-then-obesity-then-adenovirus-36.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-then-obesity-then-adenovirus-36.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Women can lose weight with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/women-can-lose-weight-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-can-lose-weight-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-vitamin-d-linked-to-80-less-belly-fat">High Vitamin D linked to 80% less belly fat&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="from-first-for-women-nov-2010">From First For Women Nov 2010&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;302&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;303&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="spantiki-download_filephpfileid1586span">&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1586]&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Note: had a hard time finding this magazine, and it was not available on-line&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-at-vitamindwiki-a-hrefpostsspan-stylecolor30foverview-of-obesityspan-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-710-span-stylecolor30foverview-of-obesityspan-a">See also at VitaminDWiki: &lt;a href="/posts/span-stylecolor30foverview-of-obesityspan" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 710"> &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#30F;">Overview of Obesity&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> &lt;/a>&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Middle-aged women gained weight if they did not drink fortified milk</title><link>/posts/middle-aged-women-gained-weight-if-they-did-not-drink-fortified-milk.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/middle-aged-women-gained-weight-if-they-did-not-drink-fortified-milk.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-calcium-milk-prevents-overweight-and-obesity-among-postmenopausal-women">High-calcium milk prevents overweight and obesity among postmenopausal women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Food Nutr Bull. 2010 Sep;31(3):381-90.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Angeles-Agdeppa I, Capanzana MV, Li-Yu J, Schollum LM, Kruger MC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Food and Nutrition Research Institute, Department of Science and Technology, Taguig City, Philippines. &lt;a href="mailto:imelda_agdeppa@yahoo.com">imelda_agdeppa@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The Sixth National Nutrition Survey 2003 revealed that the highest prevalence of overweight and obesity among Filipino female adults (30.8%) was found in the age group from 40 to 59 years. Obesity is associated with a number of chronic diseases, including cardiovascular disease, hypertension, and diabetes. Low calcium intake has been identified as a potential contributing factor to overweight and obesity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>600 mg dairy resulted in 12 pound loss in 2 years</title><link>/posts/600-mg-dairy-resulted-in-12-pound-loss-in-2-years.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/600-mg-dairy-resulted-in-12-pound-loss-in-2-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dairy-calcium-intake-serum-vitamin-d-and-successful-weight-loss">Dairy calcium intake, serum vitamin D, and successful weight loss.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2010 Nov;92(5):1017-22. Epub 2010 Sep 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shahar DR, Schwarzfuchs D, Fraser D, Vardi H, Thiery J, Fiedler GM, Blüher M, Stumvoll M, Stampfer MJ, Shai I; DIRECT Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S Daniel Abraham Center for Health and Nutrition and the Department of Epidemiology, Faculty of Health Sciences, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Beer-Sheva, Israel. &lt;a href="mailto:dshahar@bgu.ac.il">dshahar@bgu.ac.il&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The role of dairy calcium intake and serum vitamin D concentrations in weight loss is controversial.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>