<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Obesity on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/obesity.html</link><description>Recent content in Obesity on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/obesity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D roles in obesity: genetics and cell signaling</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-roles-in-obesity-genetics-and-cell-signaling.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-roles-in-obesity-genetics-and-cell-signaling.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-beneficial-role-of-vitamin-d-in-obesity-possible-genetic-and-cell-signaling-mechanisms">The beneficial role of vitamin D in obesity: possible genetic and cell signaling mechanisms.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr J. 2013 Jun 25;12(1):89.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vinh Qu C L Ng K, Nguy N LT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The prevalence rates of overweight and obesity are considered an important public issue in the United States, and both of these conditions are increasing among both children and adults. There is evidence of aberrations in the vitamin D-endocrine system in obese subjects. Vitamin D deficiency is highly prevalent in patients with obesity, and many studies have demonstrated the significant effect of calcitriol on adipocytes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Those low on vitamin D were 2.4X more likely to gain weight</title><link>/posts/those-low-on-vitamin-d-were-24x-more-likely-to-gain-weight.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/those-low-on-vitamin-d-were-24x-more-likely-to-gain-weight.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="hypovitaminosis-d-and-incidence-of-obesity-a-prospective-study-short-communication">Hypovitaminosis D and incidence of obesity: a prospective study, Short Communication&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Clinical Nutrition (2013) 67, 680–682; doi:10.1038/ejcn.2013.48;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I González-Molero1,2, G Rojo-Martínez1,2, S Morcillo1,2, C Gutierrez1,2, E Rubio1,2, V Pérez-Valero3, I Esteva1,2, M S Ruiz de Adana1,2, M C Almaraz1,2, N Colomo1,2, G Olveira1,2 and F Soriguer1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Servicio de Endocrinología y Nutrición, Hospital Regional Universitario Carlos Haya de Málaga, Málaga, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Ciber de Diabetes y Metabolismo (CIBERDEM), Barcelona, Spain&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Obesity causes vitamin D deficiency and type 2 diabetes - 2012</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-obesity-causes-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-type-2-diabetes-2012.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-obesity-causes-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-type-2-diabetes-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-a-new-risk-factor-for-type-2-diabetes">Vitamin D deficiency: a new risk factor for type 2 diabetes?.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ann Nutr Metab. 2012;61(4):337-48. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1159/000342771.">doi: 10.1159/000342771.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Dec 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mezza T, Muscogiuri G, Sorice GP, Prioletta A, Salomone E, Pontecorvi A, Giaccari A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinologia, Università Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Roma, Italia. &lt;a href="mailto:teresa.mezza@gmail.com">teresa.mezza@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent compelling evidence suggests a role of vitamin D deficiency in the pathogenesis of insulin resistance and insulin secretion derangements, with a consequent possible interference with type 2 diabetes mellitus. The mechanism of this link is incompletely understood. In fact, vitamin D deficiency is usually detected in obesity in which insulin resistance is also a common finding. The coexistence of insulin resistance and vitamin D deficiency has generated several hypotheses. Some cross-sectional and prospective studies have suggested that vitamin D deficiency may play a role in worsening insulin resistance; others have identified obesity as a risk factor predisposing individuals to exhibit both vitamin D deficiency and insulin resistance. The available data from intervention studies are largely confounded, and inadequate considerations of seasonal effects on 25(OH)D concentrations are also a common design flaw in many studies. On the contrary, there is strong evidence that obesity might cause both vitamin D deficiency and insulin resistance, leaving open the possibility that vitamin D and diabetes are not related at all. Although it might seem premature to draw firm conclusions on the role of vitamin D supplementation in reducing insulin resistance and preventing type 2 diabetes, this manuscript will review the circumstances leading to vitamin D deficiency and how such a deficiency can eventually independently affect insulin sensitivity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese have 50 percent less of two enzymes in fatty tissue to process vitamin D</title><link>/posts/obese-have-50-percent-less-of-two-enzymes-in-fatty-tissue-to-process-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-have-50-percent-less-of-two-enzymes-in-fatty-tissue-to-process-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="expression-of-vitamin-d-metabolizing-enzymes-in-human-adipose-tissue-the-effect-of-obesity-and-diet-induced-weight-loss">Expression of vitamin D-metabolizing enzymes in human adipose tissue-the effect of obesity and diet-induced weight loss.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Obes (Lond). 2013 May;37(5):651-7. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ijo.2012.112.">doi: 10.1038/ijo.2012.112.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jul 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wamberg L, Christiansen T, Paulsen SK, Fisker S, Rask P, Rejnmark L, Richelsen B, Pedersen SB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Internal Medicine MEA, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: Low vitamin D (VD) levels are common in obesity. We hypothesized that this may be due to metabolism of VD in &lt;strong>adipose tissue&lt;/strong> (AT). Thus, we studied (1) whether the VD-metabolizing enzymes were expressed differently in AT of lean and obese individuals and in visceral adipose tissue (VAT) and subcutaneous adipose tissue (SAT), and (2) whether their expression was influenced by weight loss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4,000 IU vitamin D did not change 25OHD to Vitamin D Binding Protein ratio for obese – RCT</title><link>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-change-25ohd-to-vitamin-d-binding-protein-ratio-for-obese-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-change-25ohd-to-vitamin-d-binding-protein-ratio-for-obese-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="high-dose-4000-iu-vitamin-d-supplementation-does-not-increase-circulating-concentrations-of-free-25-hydroxyvitamin-d">High-dose (4000 IU) Vitamin D Supplementation Does Not Increase Circulating Concentrations of Free 25-hydroxyvitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>(The FASEB Journal. 2013;27:859.4) Meeting Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anthony M Belenchia1, Aneesh Tosh2, Laura Hillman2 and Catherine A Peterson2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Nutrition and Exercise Physiology, University of Missouri, Columbia, MO&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 University of Missouri, Columbia, MO&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Free/bioavailable circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) makes up a small fraction of total 25OHD concentration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We demonstrated the efficacy of a daily 4000 IU vit D dosage in raising total 25OHD concentrations of obese adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Obesity: review concludes that D is just diluted by total weight</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-obesity-review-concludes-that-d-is-just-diluted-by-total-weight.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-obesity-review-concludes-that-d-is-just-diluted-by-total-weight.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-obesity">Vitamin D and Obesity&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(3), 949-956; doi:10.3390/nu5030949&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simon Vanlintemail&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Discipline of General Practice, School of Population Health, University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, SA 5005, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received: 16 February 2013; revised12 March / Accepted: 14 March / Published: 20 March&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>(This article belongs to the Special Issue Vitamin D and Human Health)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Obesity is a significant health problem world-wide, particularly in developed nations. Vitamin D deficiency is pandemic, and has been implicated in a wide variety of disease states. This paper seeks to examine the consistently reported relationship between obesity and low vitamin D concentrations, with reference to the possible underlying mechanisms. The possibility that vitamin D may assist in preventing or treating obesity is also examined, and recommendations for future research are made. There is a clear need for adequately-powered, prospective interventions which include baseline measurement of 25D concentrations and involve adequate doses of supplemental vitamin D. Until such studies have been reported, the role of vitamin D supplementation in obesity prevention remains uncertain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity not reduced with 7,000 IU vitamin D daily</title><link>/posts/obesity-not-reduced-with-7000-iu-vitamin-d-daily.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-not-reduced-with-7000-iu-vitamin-d-daily.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-body-fat-accumulation-inflammation-and-metabolic-risk-factors-in-obese-adults-with-low-vitamin-d-levels---results-from-a-randomized-trial">Effects of vitamin D supplementation on body fat accumulation, inflammation, and metabolic risk factors in obese adults with low vitamin D levels - Results from a randomized trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Intern Med. 2013 Apr 5. pii: S0953-6205(13)00089-7. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejim.2013.03.005.">doi: 10.1016/j.ejim.2013.03.005.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wamberg L, Kampmann U, Stødkilde-Jørgensen H, Rejnmark L, Pedersen SB, Richelsen B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dept. of Endocrinology and Internal Medicine MEA, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark; Institute of Clinical Medicine, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:louisewamberg@dadlnet.dk">louisewamberg@dadlnet.dk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Obesity – Review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-obesity-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-obesity-review.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(3), 949-956; doi:10.3390/nu5030949&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simon Vanlint&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Discipline of General Practice, School of Population Health, University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, SA 5005, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received: 16 February 2013; in revised form: 12 March 2013 / Accepted: 14 March 2013 / Published: 20 March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(This article belongs to the Special Issue Vitamin D and Human Health)&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="comments-on-study-by-vitamindwiki">Comments on study by VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>More weight needs more vitamin D, BMI is not an issue&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Muscle cells differentiate into fat cells if there is low vitamin D in petrie dish</title><link>/posts/muscle-cells-differentiate-into-fat-cells-if-there-is-low-vitamin-d-in-petrie-dish.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/muscle-cells-differentiate-into-fat-cells-if-there-is-low-vitamin-d-in-petrie-dish.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="dose-dependent-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-transdifferentiation-of-skeletal-muscle-cells-to-adipose-cells">Dose-dependent effects of vitamin D on transdifferentiation of skeletal muscle cells to adipose cells&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Endocrinol April 1, 2013 217 45-58&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kevin J P Ryan, Zoe C T R Daniel, Lucinda J L Craggs, Tim Parr and John M Brameld. &lt;a href="mailto:john.brameld@nottingham.ac.uk">john.brameld@nottingham.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nutritional Sciences, School of Biosciences, University of Nottingham, Loughborough, Leics LE12 5RD, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fat infiltration within muscle is one of a number of features of vitamin D deficiency, which leads to a decline in muscle functionality. The origin of this fat is unclear, but one possibility is that it forms from myogenic precursor cells present in the muscle, which transdifferentiate into mature adipocytes. The current study examined the effect of the active form of vitamin D3, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3), on the capacity of the C2C12 muscle cell line to differentiate towards the myogenic and adipogenic lineages. Cells were cultured in myogenic or adipogenic differentiation media containing increasing concentrations (0, 10−13, 10−11, 10−9, 10−7 or 10−5 M) of 1,25(OH)2D3 for up to 6 days and markers of muscle and fat development measured. Mature myofibres were formed in both adipogenic and myogenic media, but fat droplets were only observed in adipogenic media.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No apparent genetic association between vitamin D and obesity</title><link>/posts/no-apparent-genetic-association-between-vitamin-d-and-obesity.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-apparent-genetic-association-between-vitamin-d-and-obesity.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="genetic-association-analysis-of-vitamin-d-pathway-with-obesity-traits">Genetic association analysis of vitamin D pathway with obesity traits.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Int J Obes (Lond). 2013 Feb 5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ijo.2013.6.">doi: 10.1038/ijo.2013.6.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vimaleswaran KS, Cavadino A, Berry DJ; The Genetic Investigation of Anthropometric Traits (GIANT) Consortium, Whittaker JC, Power C, Järvelin MR, Hyppönen E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Paediatric Epidemiology and Biostatistics, MRC Centre of Epidemiology for Child Health, UCL Institute of Child Health, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective:Observational studies have examined the link between vitamin D deficiency and obesity traits. Some studies have reported associations between vitamin D pathway genes such as VDR, GC and CYP27B1 with body mass index (BMI) and waist circumference (WC); however, the findings have been inconsistent. Therefore, we investigated the involvement of vitamin D metabolic pathway genes in obesity-related traits in a large population-based study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D associated of where fat accumulates varies by race – 2012</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-associated-of-where-fat-accumulates-varies-by-race-2012.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-associated-of-where-fat-accumulates-varies-by-race-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ethnic-specific-differences-in-vitamin-d-status-is-associated-with-adiposity">Ethnic-specific differences in vitamin D status is associated with adiposity.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(8):e43159. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0043159.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0043159.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Aug 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sulistyoningrum DC, Green TJ, Lear SA, Devlin AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, University of British Columbia, Child and Family Research Institute, Vancouver, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Low circulating 25 hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations are common in obesity (BMI ≥30 kg/m(2)) and a negative relationship with body fat distribution has recently been reported. Ethnic-specific differences in body fat distribution have been described with South Asians are reported to have greater visceral adipose tissue (VAT), which could influence circulating 25(OH)D concentrations. The objective of this study is to investigate the relationship between plasma 25(OH)D, adiposity, and body fat distribution in Europeans and South Asians.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese mothers with adequate vitamin D gave birth to low D and fat infants</title><link>/posts/obese-mothers-with-adequate-vitamin-d-gave-birth-to-low-d-and-fat-infants.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-mothers-with-adequate-vitamin-d-gave-birth-to-low-d-and-fat-infants.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="maternal-obesity-and-vitamin-d-sufficiency-are-associated-with-cord-blood-vitamin-d-insufficiency">Maternal obesity and vitamin D sufficiency are associated with cord blood vitamin D insufficiency.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013 Jan;98(1):114-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2012-2882.">doi: 10.1210/jc.2012-2882.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Nov 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Josefson JL, Feinglass J, Rademaker AW, Metzger BE, Zeiss DM, Price HE, Langman CB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatric Endocrinology, Ann and Robert H. Lurie Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Chicago, Department of Pediatrics, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois 60611-2605, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:J-Josefson@northwestern.edu">J-Josefson@northwestern.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CONTEXT: An inverse relationship between total serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OH D) and increased adiposity has been established in children, adolescents, and adults. However, the relationship between neonatal adiposity and vitamin D status has not been reported. Both maternal obesity and vitamin D deficiency in pregnancy are common and are associated with adverse pregnancy outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese have a slow, decreased response to 700 IU of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/obese-have-a-slow-decreased-response-to-700-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-have-a-slow-decreased-response-to-700-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#body-size-and-serum-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-response-to-oral-supplements-in-healthy-older-adults---rct-2008">Body Size and Serum 25 Hydroxy Vitamin D Response to Oral Supplements in Healthy Older Adults - RCT 2008&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#obese-response-to-700-iu-vitamin-d-daily--calcium-is-approximately-12-months---feb-2025">Obese response to 700 IU Vitamin D daily + Calcium is approximately 12 months - Feb 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="body-size-and-serum-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-response-to-oral-supplements-in-healthy-older-adults---rct-2008">Body Size and Serum 25 Hydroxy Vitamin D Response to Oral Supplements in Healthy Older Adults - RCT 2008&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Miriam Blum, MD, Gerard E. Dallal, PhD, and Bess Dawson-Hughes, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone Metabolism Laboratory (M.B., B.D.H.) and Biostatistics Department (G.E.D.), Jean Mayer U. S. Department of Agriculture Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging at Tufts University, Boston, Massachusetts&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Higher weight and blood pressure in second generation from mother mouse who had low vitamin D – 2012</title><link>/posts/higher-weight-and-blood-pressure-in-second-generation-from-mother-mouse-who-had-low-vitamin-d-2012.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/higher-weight-and-blood-pressure-in-second-generation-from-mother-mouse-who-had-low-vitamin-d-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="maternal-vitamin-d-deficiency-delays-glomerular-maturity-in-f1-and-f2-offspring">Maternal vitamin D deficiency delays glomerular maturity in F1 and F2 offspring.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(8):e41740. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0041740.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0041740.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Aug 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nascimento FA, Ceciliano TC, Aguila MB, Mandarim-de-Lacerda CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laboratory of Morphometry, Metabolism and Cardiovascular Disease, Biomedical Center, Institute of Biology, State University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, RJ, Brazil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: There is a high prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency in women of reproductive age.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: This work studied the first two generations of offspring (F1 and F2) of Swiss mice from mothers fed one of two diets: SC (standard chow) or VitD- (vitamin D-deficient). Functional and developmental kidney measurements were taken.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Insulin sensitivity in obese adolescents greatly improved with 4000 IU of vitamin D - RCT</title><link>/posts/insulin-sensitivity-in-obese-adolescents-greatly-improved-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/insulin-sensitivity-in-obese-adolescents-greatly-improved-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="correcting-vitamin-d-insufficiency-improves-insulin-sensitivity-in-obese-adolescents-a-randomized-controlled-trial123">Correcting vitamin D insufficiency improves insulin sensitivity in obese adolescents: a randomized controlled trial1,2,3&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr April 2013 ajcn.050013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anthony M Belenchia,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aneesh K Tosh,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laura S Hillman, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Catherine A Peterson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1From the Department of Nutrition and Exercise Physiology (AMB and CAP), and the Department of Child Health, University of Missouri School of Medicine (AKT and LSH), University of Missouri, Columbia, MO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵2 Supported by a JR Albert Foundation grant (Naperville, IL).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes indicate that Obesity causes vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/genes-indicate-that-obesity-causes-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-indicate-that-obesity-causes-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="causal-relationship-between-obesity-and-vitamin-d-status-bi-directional-mendelian-randomization-analysis-of-multiple-cohorts">Causal Relationship between Obesity and Vitamin D Status: Bi-Directional Mendelian Randomization Analysis of Multiple Cohorts&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLOS One&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karani S. Vimaleswaran equal contributor, Diane J. Berry equal contributor, Chen Lu,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emmi Tikkanen, Stefan Pilz, Linda T. Hiraki, Jason D. Cooper, Zari Dastani,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rui Li, Denise K. Houston, Andrew R. Wood, Karl Michaëlsson, Liesbeth Vandenput, Elina Hyppönen equal contributor mail&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="background">Background&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Obesity is associated with vitamin D deficiency, and both are areas of active public health concern. We explored the causality and direction of the relationship between body mass index (BMI) and 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> using genetic markers as instrumental variables (IVs) in bi-directional Mendelian randomization (MR) analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omega-3 reduced vitamin D3 inflammation for obese – RCT</title><link>/posts/omega-3-reduced-vitamin-d3-inflammation-for-obese-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-reduced-vitamin-d3-inflammation-for-obese-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="treatment-with-n-3-polyunsaturated-fatty-acids-overcomes-the-inverse-association-of-vitamin-d3">Treatment with n-3 Polyunsaturated Fatty Acids Overcomes the Inverse Association of Vitamin D3&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>D Deficiency with Inflammation in Severely Obese Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PLOS ONE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bianca K. Itariu, Maximilian Zeyda, Lukas Leitner, Rodrig Marculescu, Thomas M. Stulnig &lt;a href="mailto:thomas.stulnig@meduniwien.ac.at">thomas.stulnig@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Internal Medicine III, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria, Christian Doppler Laboratory for Cardio-Metabolic Immunotherapy, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obesity affects the vitamin D status in humans. Vitamin D and long-chain n-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFA) provide benefit for the prevention of fractures and cardiovascular events, respectively, and both are involved in controlling inflammatory and immune responses. However, published epidemiological data suggest a potential interference of n-3 PUFA supplementation with vitamin D status. Therefore, we aimed to investigate in a randomized controlled clinical trial whether treatment with long chain n-3 PUFA affects vitamin D status in severely obese patients and potential interrelations of vitamin D and PUFA treatment with inflammatory parameters. Fifty-four severely obese (BMI≥40 kg/m2) non-diabetic patients were treated for eight weeks with either 3.36 g/d EPA and DHA or the same amount of butter fat as control. Changes in serum 25-hydroxy-vitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations, plasma fatty acid profiles and circulating inflammatory marker concentrations from baseline to end of treatment were assessed. At baseline 43/54 patients were vitamin D deficient (serum 25(OH)D concentration &amp;lt;50 nmol/l). Treatment with n-3 PUFA did not affect vitamin D status (P = 0.91). Serum 25(OH)D concentration correlated negatively with both IL-6 (P = 0.02) and hsCRP serum concentration (P = 0.03) at baseline. Strikingly, the negative correlations of 25(OH)D with IL-6 and hsCRP were lost after n-3 PUFA treatment. In conclusion, vitamin D status of severely obese patients remained unaffected by n-3 PUFA treatment. However, abrogation of the inverse association of 25(OH)D concentration with inflammatory markers indicated that n-3 PUFA treatment could compensate for some detrimental consequences of vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolic Syndrome 10% less likely for every 4 ng increase in Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-10-percent-less-likely-for-every-4-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-10-percent-less-likely-for-every-4-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-parathyroid-hormone-and-their-association-with-metabolic-syndrome-in-chinese">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D, parathyroid hormone, and their association with metabolic syndrome in Chinese.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocrine. 2013 Jan 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Li LH, Yin XY, Yao CY, Zhu XC, Wu XH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Dali University School of Clinical Medicine, Jiashibo Road 32, Dali, 671000, Yunnan, China, &lt;a href="mailto:lilihuayncn@gmail.com">lilihuayncn@gmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Increasing evidence suggests that 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> and parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels are associated with metabolic syndrome (MetS). In 2010, we explored the association of serum 25(OH)D and PTH levels with MetS in 1,390 Chinese participants, aged 20-83 years. Anthropometric phenotypes, blood pressure, and the incidence of MetS were evaluated. In addition, serum lipids, 25(OH)D, and PTH were measured. The median concentration of 25(OH)D and PTH were 55.3 nmol/l and 2.8 pmol/l, respectively. The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency (&amp;lt;50 nmol/l) was 39.9 %, with 34.5 % in men and 47.8 % in women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No association between diabetes level and vitamin D insufficiency in obese youth</title><link>/posts/no-association-between-diabetes-level-and-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-obese-youth.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-association-between-diabetes-level-and-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-obese-youth.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-obese-youth-across-the-spectrum-of-glucose-tolerance-from-normal-to-prediabetes-to-type-2-diabetes">25-Hydroxyvitamin D in Obese Youth Across the Spectrum of Glucose Tolerance From Normal to Prediabetes to Type 2 Diabetes.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care. 2013 Jan 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>de Las Heras J, Rajakumar K, Lee S, Bacha F, Holick MF, Arslanian SA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatric Metabolism, Hospital Universitario de Cruces, Barakaldo, Vizcaya, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE To 1) determine if plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) concentrations differ among obese youth with normal glucose tolerance (NGT) versus prediabetes versus type 2 diabetes, and 2) assess the relationships between 25(OH)D and in vivo insulin sensitivity and β-cell function in this cohort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>African-Americans at high risk of obesity and diabetes - 2011</title><link>/posts/african-americans-at-high-risk-of-obesity-and-diabetes-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/african-americans-at-high-risk-of-obesity-and-diabetes-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-type-2-diabetes-in-african-americans-the-common-denominators">Vitamin D Deficiency and Type 2 Diabetes in African Americans: The Common Denominators&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Shani V. Davis, MSN, ANP-BC, CDE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetic Spectrum&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>7000 IU vitamin D was not enough to reduce obese tissue – RCT</title><link>/posts/7000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-reduce-obese-tissue-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-reduce-obese-tissue-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#investigations-of-the-anti-inflammatory-effects-of-vitamin-d-in-adipose-tissue-results-from-an-in-vitro-study-and-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Investigations of the Anti-inflammatory Effects of Vitamin D in Adipose Tissue: Results from an In Vitro Study and a Randomized Controlled Trial.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="investigations-of-the-anti-inflammatory-effects-of-vitamin-d-in-adipose-tissue-results-from-an-in-vitro-study-and-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Investigations of the Anti-inflammatory Effects of Vitamin D in Adipose Tissue: Results from an In Vitro Study and a Randomized Controlled Trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Horm Metab Res. 2013 Jan 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wamberg L, Cullberg KB, Rejnmark L, Richelsen B, Pedersen SB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Internal Medicine MEA, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lost more weight on low calorie diet if add 600 mg Ca and just 150 IU vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/lost-more-weight-on-low-calorie-diet-if-add-600-mg-ca-and-just-150-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lost-more-weight-on-low-calorie-diet-if-add-600-mg-ca-and-just-150-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="calcium-plus-vitamin-d3-supplementation-facilitated-fat-loss-in-overweight-and-obese-college-students-with-very-low-calcium-consumption-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Calcium plus vitamin D3 supplementation facilitated Fat loss in overweight and obese college students with very-low calcium consumption: a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nutr J. 2013 Jan 8;12(1):8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhu W, Cai D, Wang Y, Lin N, Hu Q, Qi Y, Ma S, Amarasekara S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Recent evidence suggests that higher calcium and/or vitamin D intake may be associated with lower body weight and better metabolic health. Due to contradictory findings from intervention trials, we investigated the effect of calcium plus vitamin D3 (calcium+D) supplementation on anthropometric and metabolic profiles during energy restriction in healthy, overweight and obese adults with very-low calcium consumption.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Higher BMI associated with lower vitamin D</title><link>/posts/higher-bmi-associated-with-lower-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/higher-bmi-associated-with-lower-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-relationship-between-obesity-and-the-increase-in-serum-25ohd-levels-in-response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation">The relationship between obesity and the increase in serum 25(OH)D levels in response to vitamin D supplementation.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Sep 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saliba W, Barnett-Griness O, Rennert G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Community Medicine and Epidemiology, Carmel Medical Center, Clalit Health Services, and Bruce Rappaport Faculty of Medicine, Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, 7 Michal St, Haifa, 34362, Israel, &lt;a href="mailto:saliba_wa@clalit.org.il">saliba_wa@clalit.org.il&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study examines the relationship between obesity and the increase in serum 25(OH)D levels in response to vitamin D supplementation among adults with baseline serum 25(OH)D levels &amp;lt;50 nmol/L. This study revealed that the increase in serum 25(OH)D in response to vitamin D supplementation was higher in lean subjects as compared to obese subjects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heavier kids more vitamin D deficient, especially if dark skinned – Pediatrics</title><link>/posts/heavier-kids-more-vitamin-d-deficient-especially-if-dark-skinned-pediatrics.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heavier-kids-more-vitamin-d-deficient-especially-if-dark-skinned-pediatrics.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-among-overweight-and-obese-us-children">Prevalence of Vitamin D Deficiency Among Overweight and Obese US Children&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Pediatrics, December 24, 2012, (&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2012-1711">doi: 10.1542/peds.2012-1711)&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christy B. Turer, MD, MHSa,b, Hua Lin, PhDa, and Glenn Flores, MDa,b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Division of General Pediatrics, Department of Pediatrics, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas; and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Children’s Medical Center, Dallas, Texas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Adequate vitamin D is essential for skeletal health in developing children. Although excess body weight is associated with risk of vitamin D deficiency, the national prevalence of and risk factors associated with vitamin D deficiency in overweight and obese children are unknown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese need more Vitamin D: Volume dilution, IU per pound, or BMI – RCT</title><link>/posts/obese-need-more-vitamin-d-volume-dilution-iu-per-pound-or-bmi-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-need-more-vitamin-d-volume-dilution-iu-per-pound-or-bmi-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-serum-25ohd-in-thin-and-obese-women">The Effect Of Vitamin D Supplementation On Serum 25OHD In Thin And Obese Women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology,2012.12.003&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. Christopher Gallagher a &lt;a href="mailto:jcg@creighton.edu">jcg@creighton.edu&lt;/a>, Vinod Yalamanchili a , Lynette M. Smith b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Bone Metabolism Unit, Creighton University Medical Center, Omaha, Nebraska&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Public Health, University of Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha, Nebraska&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obese people are known to have lower serum 25OHD levels compared to non-obese people. It is not known whether it is due to storage of vitamin D in fat, inadequate input from sunlight, diet or other unknown factors. We examined the relationship at study baseline of serum 25OHD, PTH, 1,25(OH)2D with body composition measurements using Dual energy X-ray Absorptiometry. The results showed a significant inverse relation between total body fat mass and serum 25OHD (p &amp;lt; 0.0001) and serum 1,25(OH2)D (p = 034) and an independent positive correlation between serum PTH and total body fat mass (p &amp;lt; 0.0001). In a randomized controlled study of seven doses of vitamin D (400-4800IU/d) the increase in serum 25OHD levels was compared in women with a normal body mass index to obese women. The response to the low doses of vitamin D (400-800IU/d) was significantly less than that of the medium (1600-2400IU/d) and high doses groups (3200-4800IU) (p &amp;lt; 0.0001) in all BMI categories. The increase in serum 25OHD in the medium and high dose groups was not significantly different with increasing level of obesity. But thinner women with a normal BMI (&amp;lt; 25 kg/m2) showed a much higher response to vitamin D at any dose level compared to other BMI groups. There was no significant change in total body fat mass after treatment with vitamin D or calcitriol in our randomized trials. In summary, the response to vitamin D is dependent on body weight. Women with BMI &amp;lt;25 kg/m2 develop much higher levels of serum 25OHD after vitamin D supplementation compared to those with BMI of &amp;gt;25 kg/m2 .The differences in serum 25OHD levels between normal and obese women may be due to differences in volume dilution. After vitamin D supplementation, all obese women reach adequate levels of serum 25OHD but normal women (BMI &amp;lt; 25 kg/m2) reach much higher levels of 25OHD and in this group smaller doses of vitamin D used should be used.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less weight gain by senior women if vitamin D levels over 30 ng – Kaiser</title><link>/posts/less-weight-gain-by-senior-women-if-vitamin-d-levels-over-30-ng-kaiser.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-weight-gain-by-senior-women-if-vitamin-d-levels-over-30-ng-kaiser.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#associations-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-weight-gain-in-elderly-women">Associations between 25-hydroxyvitamin D and weight gain in elderly women.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="associations-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-weight-gain-in-elderly-women">Associations between 25-hydroxyvitamin D and weight gain in elderly women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2012 Oct;21(10):1066-73. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1089/jwh.2012.3506.">doi: 10.1089/jwh.2012.3506.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jun 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LeBlanc ES, Rizzo JH, Pedula KL, Ensrud KE, Cauley J, Hochberg M, Hillier TA; Study Of Osteoporotic Fractures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Health Research, Kaiser Permanente Northwest, Portland, OR 97227, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:erin.s.leblanc@kpchr.org">erin.s.leblanc@kpchr.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>25-Hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels are lower in obese individuals. Determining whether low vitamin D status can predispose weight gain requires a longitudinal study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>90 percent of Swiss men have less than 30 ng of vitamin D in the winter</title><link>/posts/90-percent-of-swiss-men-have-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-in-the-winter.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/90-percent-of-swiss-men-have-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-in-the-winter.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-levels-and-associated-factors-a-population-based-study-in-switzerland">Vitamin D levels and associated factors: a population-based study in Switzerland.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Swiss Med Wkly. 2012 Nov 26;142:0. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4414/smw.2012.13719.">doi: 10.4414/smw.2012.13719.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Guessous I, Dudler V, Glatz N, Theler JM, Zoller O, Paccaud F, Burnier M, Bochud M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Community Prevention Unit, Institute of Social and Preventive Medicine (IUMSP), Lausanne University Hospital, Lausanne, Switzerland; &lt;a href="mailto:idris.guessous@chuv.ch">idris.guessous@chuv.ch&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>QUESTIONS UNDER STUDY:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To update the prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency and to identify factors associated with vitamin D status in the Swiss adult population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU raised vitamin D levels of thin teens by 10 ng, obese teens by 6 ng</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-raised-vitamin-d-levels-of-thin-teens-by-10-ng-obese-teens-by-6-ng.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-raised-vitamin-d-levels-of-thin-teens-by-10-ng-obese-teens-by-6-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="response-to-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-obese-and-non-obese-caucasian-adolescents">Response to Vitamin D(3) Supplementation in Obese and Non-Obese Caucasian Adolescents.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Horm Res Paediatr. 2012 Oct 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aguirre Castaneda R, Nader N, Weaver A, Singh R, Kumar S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatric Endocrinology and Metabolism, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine, Rochester, Minn., USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aims: Vitamin D deficiency is highly prevalent in obese children, and obese children tend to respond poorly to vitamin D supplementation. The objective of the study was to compare the response to vitamin D(3) supplementation (2,000 IU once daily for 12 weeks) between obese and non-obese Caucasian adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5700 IU vitamin D improved various growth factors in overweight people</title><link>/posts/5700-iu-vitamin-d-improved-various-growth-factors-in-overweight-people.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5700-iu-vitamin-d-improved-various-growth-factors-in-overweight-people.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="insulin-like-growth-factor-i-growth-hormone-and-insulin-sensitivity-the-effects-of-a-one-year-cholecalciferol-supplementation-in-middle-aged-overweight-and-obese-subjects">Insulin-like growth factor I, growth hormone, and insulin sensitivity: the effects of a one-year cholecalciferol supplementation in middle-aged overweight and obese subjects.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocrine. 2012 Oct 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kamycheva E, Berg V, Jorde R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, University Hospital of North Norway, 9038, Tromsø, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:elena.kamycheva@unn.no">elena.kamycheva@unn.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both altered GH-IGF-I axis and low serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) are linked to measures of metabolic syndrome. Our hypothesis was that there is a relation between GH, IGF-I, and 25(OH)D; and that vitamin D supplementation may have an effect on the levels of GH, IGF-I, and IGF-I/IGFBP-3 ratio.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic – Proven again – artificial sweeteners actually make you GAIN weight</title><link>/posts/off-topic-proven-again-artificial-sweeteners-actually-make-you-gain-weight.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-proven-again-artificial-sweeteners-actually-make-you-gain-weight.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="green-medical-informationhttpwwwgreenmedinfocomblogartificial-sweeteners-found-more-weight-promoting-sugar">&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/artificial-sweeteners-found-more-weight-promoting-sugar">Green Medical Information&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="some-highlights-from-the-article">Some highlights from the article&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rats on same number of calorie diets were given sugar and artificial sweeteners&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The rats getting artificial sweeteners actually GAINED weight&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>‘’ chemicals (aspartame and saccharin), much like pesticides, may actually poison us into gaining weight’’&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>‘’ you will find peer-reviewed and published research on our site linking aspartame to over 40 adverse health effects, including fibromyalgia, brain cancer, kidney damage, urinary tract cancer, leukemia and many other serious conditions.’’&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Can turn obesity on and off in mice with a gene – but not if obese for too long</title><link>/posts/off-topic-can-turn-obesity-on-and-off-in-mice-with-a-gene-but-not-if-obese-for-too-long.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-can-turn-obesity-on-and-off-in-mice-with-a-gene-but-not-if-obese-for-too-long.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Obesity of girls in Emirates associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/obesity-of-girls-in-emirates-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-of-girls-in-emirates-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="relations-between-obesity-and-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-emirati-youth--poster--1426">Relations Between Obesity and 25-Hydroxyvitamin D in Emirati Youth – Poster # 1426&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arch Dis Child 2012;97:A406 doi:10.1136/archdischild-2012-302724.1426,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 4th Congress of the European Academy of Paediatric Societies, 5–9 October 2012. Istandul, Turkey,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SM Shah1, S Muhairi2, M Naqbi2, A Khouri2, A Mehairi2, F Al Maskari3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Family Medicine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Community Medicine, United Arab Emirates University, FMHS, Al Ain, United Arab Emirates&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives The aim of this study was to identify the correlation of obesity with 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in a population-based sample of schoolchildren Al Ain, United Arab Emirates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overweight women lost fat in 12 weeks with just 1000 IU vitamin D daily</title><link>/posts/overweight-women-lost-fat-in-12-weeks-with-just-1000-iu-vitamin-d-daily.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overweight-women-lost-fat-in-12-weeks-with-just-1000-iu-vitamin-d-daily.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Weight loss of at least 10 percent resulted in 5 ng increase in vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/weight-loss-of-at-least-10-percent-resulted-in-5-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/weight-loss-of-at-least-10-percent-resulted-in-5-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="increased-weight-loss-seen-in-women-who-took-a-vitamin-d-serum">Increased weight loss seen in women who took a vitamin D serum&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>SAN FRANCISCO, CA, September 7, 2012 — San Francisco, CA – A study led by Cheryl L. Rock of University of Alabama at Birmingham in Birmingham, AL has showed that weight loss in obese women boosts Vitamin D serum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The increased serum in women was 25-hydroxyvitamin D or 25(OH)D concentration in overweight or obese women. Earlier studies had linked it to low circulating levels of vitamin D and have been associated with increased risk of cancer and heart diseases among several other diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese helped with resistance training by 4000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/obese-helped-with-resistance-training-by-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-helped-with-resistance-training-by-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="impact-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-a-resistance-training-intervention-on-body-composition-muscle-function-and-glucose-tolerance-in-overweight-and-obese-adults-clinical-nutrition">Impact of vitamin D supplementation during a resistance training intervention on body composition, muscle function, and glucose tolerance in overweight and obese adults Clinical Nutrition&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Andres E. Carrillo a, Michael G. Flynn b, Catherine Pinkston c, Melissa M. Markofski a, Yan Jiang c, Shawn S. Donkin d, Dorothy Teegarden c, &lt;a href="mailto:teegarden@purdue.edu">teegarden@purdue.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Wastl Human Performance Laboratory, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Health and Human Performance, College of Charleston, Charleston, SC, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese children with celiac disease had lower levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/obese-children-with-celiac-disease-had-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-children-with-celiac-disease-had-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-vitamin-d-deficiency-a-feature-of-pediatric-celiac-disease">Is vitamin D deficiency a feature of pediatric celiac disease?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab. 2012;25(5-6):607-10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Villanueva J, Maranda L, Nwosu BU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Massachusetts Medical School, Worcester, 01655, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Celiac disease (CD) is an autoimmune enteropathy characterized by villus atrophy and malabsorption of essential nutrients. Vitamin D deficiency has been described in autoimmune diseases, but its status in prepubertal children with CD has not been adequately studied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine the vitamin D status of prepubertal children with CD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes 6X more likely for those abdominal obese who have insufficient vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetes-6x-more-likely-for-those-abdominal-obese-who-have-insufficient-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-6x-more-likely-for-those-abdominal-obese-who-have-insufficient-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.mdedge.com/endocrinology/article/236356/obesity/obesity-pegged-diabetes-cause-almost-half-us-cases?ecd=wnl_evn_210224_mdedge_8pm&amp;amp;uac=138704MX&amp;amp;utm_source=News_MDedge_eNL_022421_F&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=Loss+of+smell+lingers+post+COVID-19&amp;amp;sso=true">Obesity pegged as diabetes cause in almost half of U.S. cases&lt;/a> Feb 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Note it appears else where that the connection might be obesity==&amp;gt; reduced vitamin D ==&amp;gt; diabetes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D less than 20 ng associated with 73 pct chance becoming obese in 11 years</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-20-ng-associated-with-73-pct-chance-becoming-obese-in-11-years.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-20-ng-associated-with-73-pct-chance-becoming-obese-in-11-years.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>3X more abdominal obesity among Korean children having low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/3x-more-abdominal-obesity-among-korean-children-having-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-more-abdominal-obesity-among-korean-children-having-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-obesity-and-the-metabolic-syndrome-among-korean-children">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels, obesity and the metabolic syndrome among Korean children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2012 Jul 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee SH, Kim SM, Park HS, Choi KM, Cho GJ, Ko BJ, Kim JH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Family Medicine, College of Medicine, Korea University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND AIM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evidence of the relationship between serum vitamin D levels and cardiovascular risk factors in children is limited. We investigated the associations between serum vitamin D levels (25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>) and obesity and metabolic syndrome and its components in Korean children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Korean teens more likely to be obese if have less than 18 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/korean-teens-more-likely-to-be-obese-if-have-less-than-18-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/korean-teens-more-likely-to-be-obese-if-have-less-than-18-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="estimate-of-a-predictive-cut-off-value-for-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-reflecting-abdominal-obesity-in-korean-adolescents">Estimate of a predictive cut-off value for serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D reflecting abdominal obesity in Korean adolescents.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutr Res. 2012 Jun;32(6):395-402. Epub 2012 Jun 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nam GE, Kim do H, Cho KH, Park YG, Han KD, Choi YS, Kim SM, Ko BJ, Kim YH, Lee KS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Family Medicine, Korea University College of Medicine, Seoul, South Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is a serious global issue. Although the serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> test is generally the most accurate way to assess vitamin D levels, the optimal range of 25(OH)D has yet to be established. Moreover, the optimal level may vary according to race, region, and age. Suboptimal vitamin D status is associated with obesity and metabolic syndrome, which are the major risk factors for cardiovascular disorders; however, these relationships in children and adolescents have yet to be clearly determined. Therefore, we identified the best predictive cut-off value for reflecting abdominal obesity and, based on this value, we investigated the relationship between suboptimal 25(OH)D status and the risk for having abdominal obesity, being overweight or obese, and having metabolic syndrome in Korean adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bariatric surgery less than 30 ng of vitamin D – 82 pcnt teens, 100 pcnt of black teens</title><link>/posts/bariatric-surgery-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-82-pcnt-teens-100-pcnt-of-black-teens.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bariatric-surgery-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-82-pcnt-teens-100-pcnt-of-black-teens.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="check-vitamin-d-in-adolescents-before-bariatric-surgeryhttpwwwfamilypracticenewscomnewsmore-top-newssingle-viewcheck-vitamin-d-in-adolescents-before-bariatric-surgery9fe0deca25b9ee123ab565b28f2d1a9ehtml20-family-practice-news">&lt;a href="http://www.familypracticenews.com/news/more-top-news/single-view/check-vitamin-d-in-adolescents-before-bariatric-surgery/9fe0deca25b9ee123ab565b28f2d1a9e.html%20">Check Vitamin D in Adolescents Before Bariatric Surgery&lt;/a> Family Practice News&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>clips of paper presented by Dr. Marisa Censani at Endocrine Society. ENDO 2012&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Every kilogram increase in BMI correlated with a 0.2-ng decrease in 25OHD levels,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Roughly 80% of African American deficient , rest had insufficient levels. (100%)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Hispanics, nearly 60% deficient, close to 25% had insufficient levels (85%)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Obese need 2X as much vitamin D to get the same response</title><link>/posts/obese-need-2x-as-much-vitamin-d-to-get-the-same-response.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-need-2x-as-much-vitamin-d-to-get-the-same-response.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-effect-of-weight-on-vitamin-d-dose-response">The Effect of Weight on Vitamin D Dose Response&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Endocr Rev, Vol. 33 (03_MeetingAbstracts): OR38-3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2012 by The Endocrine Society ENDO 2012: June 23-26, 2012, Houston, Texas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andjela T Drincic, MD1, Eileen Van Diest, MD2, Laura AG Armas, MD2, Robert P Heaney, MD2 and Susan Dowell, PhD2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Internal Medicine/Endocrinology, Universiy of Nebraska Medical Center Omaha, NE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Internal Medicine/Endocrinology, Creighton University Omaha, NE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Obesity is associated with low 25(OH) vitamin D levels. Recent Endocrine Society Guidelines advise that obese adults need at least 6,000-10,000 IU/d of vitamin D3 to treat and prevent vitamin D deficiency. There are vitamin D dose response studies in normal to overweight populations (1), but none in the frankly obese.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Severely obese having more vitamin D were in better physical condition</title><link>/posts/severely-obese-having-more-vitamin-d-were-in-better-physical-condition.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/severely-obese-having-more-vitamin-d-were-in-better-physical-condition.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="association-between-vitamin-d-status-and-physical-function-in-the-severely-obese">Association between Vitamin D Status and Physical Function in the Severely Obese&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocr Rev, Vol. 33 (03_MeetingAbstracts): MON-358&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2012 by The Endocrine Society ENDO 2012: June 23-26, 2012, Houston, Texas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aftab Khattak, MBBS1,2, Tomas Ahern, MB, BCh, BAO1,2,4, Emer O&amp;rsquo;Malley, BSc1, Dunlevy Colin, BSc, PhD1, Kilbane Mark, BSc, PhD3, Donal O&amp;rsquo;Shea, MB, BCh, BAO, MD1,2,4 and McKenna Malachi, MB, BCh, BAO, MD3,4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Endocrinology, St Columcille&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Loughlinstown, Ireland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity reduction with Calcium and vitamin D – controversy</title><link>/posts/obesity-reduction-with-calcium-and-vitamin-d-controversy.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-reduction-with-calcium-and-vitamin-d-controversy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-obesity">Calcium and vitamin D in obesity&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr Res Rev. 2012 May 16:1-12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Song Q, Sergeev IN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Health and Nutritional Sciences, South Dakota State University, Brookings, SD 57007, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New and more effective nutritional measures are urgently needed for the prevention of obesity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of Ca and vitamin D in obesity has been recently implicated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low Ca intake and low vitamin D status have been linked with an increased risk of obesity in epidemiological studies; however, clinical intervention trials designed to test this association have produced &lt;strong>controversial results&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity related to osteocalcin but not vitamin D</title><link>/posts/obesity-related-to-osteocalcin-but-not-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-related-to-osteocalcin-but-not-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-osteocalcin-and-risk-for-adiposity-as-comorbidities-in-middle-school-children">Vitamin D, osteocalcin, and risk for adiposity as comorbidities in middle school children.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Boucher-Berry C, Speiser PW, Carey DE, Shelov SP, Accacha S, Fennoy I, Rapaport R, Espinal Y, Rosenbaum M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2012 Feb;27(2):283-93.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Division of Pediatric Endocrinology, Cohen Children&amp;rsquo;s Medical Center, New Hyde Park, NY 11040, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nonclassic actions of vitamin D include potential regulation of immune function and glucose homeostasis. The bone-metabolism loop has recently been expanded to include osteocalcin, which appears to play a more direct role in pancreatic beta cell function and energy metabolism. We hypothesized that both vitamin D and osteocalcin would correlate negatively with indices of adiposity-related comorbidity risk in periadolescents, varying by ethnic group. We analyzed anthropometric, metabolic, and inflammatory markers from a multiethnic population of 106 school children 11 to 14 years of age studied as part of the Reduce Obesity and Diabetes (ROAD) consortium.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D in womb linked to more weight at age 6</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-womb-linked-to-more-weight-at-age-6.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-womb-linked-to-more-weight-at-age-6.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="lack-of-maternal-vitamin-d-may-predispose-baby-to-gain-excess-body-fat-in-childhood">Lack of maternal vitamin D may predispose baby to gain excess body fat in childhood&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.cbc.ca/news/health/story/2012/05/23/vitamin-d-pregnancy-childhood-fat.html%20">CBC News&lt;/a> Posted: May 23, 2012 2:39 PM ET&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">(unfortunately, the abstract does not quantize the amount of weight)&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Children of women with low blood levels of vitamin D were leaner at birth, researchers found. But by the time they reached age six, those children had more body fat than those born to women with higher vitamin D status during pregnancy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity epidemic: a perfect storm of deficiency of vitamin D, Magnesium, Iodine, etc</title><link>/posts/obesity-epidemic-a-perfect-storm-of-deficiency-of-vitamin-d-magnesium-iodine-etc.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-epidemic-a-perfect-storm-of-deficiency-of-vitamin-d-magnesium-iodine-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-womb-linked-to-more-weight-at-age-6">Low vitamin D in womb linked to more weight at age 6 – May 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It appears that low vitamin D while in womb provides an epigenetic signal that the child should prepare for an environment with low nutrients, such as vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The body is thus programmed to seek out and store up as much nutrients/food as it can, which leads to health when food is rare, but obesity when food is plentiful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Calcium and Vitamin D does not consistently reduce obesity</title><link>/posts/adding-calcium-and-vitamin-d-does-not-consistently-reduce-obesity.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adding-calcium-and-vitamin-d-does-not-consistently-reduce-obesity.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-obesity">Calcium and vitamin D in obesity.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr Res Rev. 2012 May 16:1-12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Song Q, Sergeev IN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Health and Nutritional Sciences, South Dakota State University, Brookings, SD 57007, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New and more effective nutritional measures are urgently needed for the prevention of obesity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of Ca and vitamin D in obesity has been recently implicated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low Ca intake and low vitamin D status have been linked with an increased risk of obesity in epidemiological studies;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Teen obesity strongly associated with vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/teen-obesity-strongly-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/teen-obesity-strongly-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Less overweight if good outdoor environment (more vitamin D from sunshine)</title><link>/posts/less-overweight-if-good-outdoor-environment-more-vitamin-d-from-sunshine.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-overweight-if-good-outdoor-environment-more-vitamin-d-from-sunshine.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Half of the women who are fat do not have a high BMI</title><link>/posts/half-of-the-women-who-are-fat-do-not-have-a-high-bmi.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-of-the-women-who-are-fat-do-not-have-a-high-bmi.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="bmi-was-found-to-categorize-as-healthy-when-actually-have-high-amount-of-fat">BMI was found to categorize as healthy when actually have high amount of fat&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>25% of men&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>48% of women&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="background-on-body-mass-index-at-bmi--wikipediahttpenwikipediaorgwikibody_mass_index">Background on Body Mass Index at &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Body_mass_index">BMI – WikiPedia&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>BMI became a standard by 1850 – more 160 years ago&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Has been known for a long time that BMI is easy to calculate but serves only as a vague means of estimating adiposity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Additional indexes described in WikiPedia include:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Body volume index; Waist-hip ratio; Sagittal Abdominal Diameter (SAD); Body fat percentage&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How might Calcium and Vitamin D cause weight loss</title><link>/posts/how-might-calcium-and-vitamin-d-cause-weight-loss.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-might-calcium-and-vitamin-d-cause-weight-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mechanistic-roles-for-calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-the-regulation-of-body-weight">Mechanistic roles for calcium and vitamin D in the regulation of body weight&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Obes Rev. 2012 Mar 2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-789X.2012.00986.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1467-789X.2012.00986.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. J. Soares1 &lt;a href="mailto:m.soares@curtin.edu.au">m.soares@curtin.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>L. L. Murhadi1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. V. Kurpad2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W. L. Chan She Ping-Delfos1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>L. S. Piers3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Program of Nutrition, School of Public Health, Curtin Health Innovation Research Institute, Curtin University, Perth, Western Australia, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Physiology, St John&amp;rsquo;s National Academy of Health Sciences, Bangalore, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Centre for Health &amp;amp; Society, Melbourne School of Population Health, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1000 IU of Vitamin D daily drops 5 pounds in 12 weeks</title><link>/posts/1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-drops-5-pounds-in-12-weeks.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily-drops-5-pounds-in-12-weeks.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Adenovirus-36 association with obesity letter to editor – 2011</title><link>/posts/adenovirus-36-association-with-obesity-letter-to-editor-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adenovirus-36-association-with-obesity-letter-to-editor-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-infection-with-adenovirus-36-in-belgium-and-holland-and-association-with-obesity">Prevalence of Infection With Adenovirus-36 in Belgium and Holland and Association With Obesity&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Letters to the Editor &lt;a href="http://www.nature.com/oby/journal/v19/n1/full/oby2010107a.html">http://www.nature.com/oby/journal/v19/n1/full/oby2010107a.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obesity (2011) 19 1, 2. doi:10.1038/oby.2010.107&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Richard L. Atkinson Obetech Obesity Research Center, Richmond, Virginia, &lt;a href="mailto:ratkinson2@vcu.edu">ratkinson2@vcu.edu&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TO THE EDITOR: The article titled “Lack of Evidence for the Role of Human Adenovirus-36 in Obesity in a European Cohort” by Goossens et al. (1) reports a very low prevalence of human adenovirus-36 (Ad-36) and no evidence of association with obesity in 540 Dutch and Belgian individuals. There are several concerns with this article. First, the findings are in contrast to other papers in the literature from the United States, Italy, and Korea (2,3,4,5,6,7,8). We reported that 30% of obese and 11% of nonobese US adults had Ad-36 antibodies and a strong association with obesity (P &amp;lt; 0.001) (2). We found a 30% prevalence of Ad-36 antibodies in obese children in Korea and a strong association with obesity (P &amp;lt; 0.01) (3). Na et al. (4) found Ad-36 antibodies in 29% of obese and 14% of nonobese children in Korea. Trovato et al. (5,6) in two studies from Italy noted a prevalence of Ad-36 antibodies of &amp;gt;40% and an association with obesity. Broderick et al. (7) did not find an association of Ad-36 with obesity in military personnel in San Diego, California, but the prevalence of antibodies was 37%. Gabbert et al. (8) presented a study at the Annual Meeting of The Obesity Society in October 2009, showing a prevalence of 22% in obese children and 7% in lean children in San Diego with a strong association with BMI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity pandemic since 1975 - is it due to Vitamin D, Magnesium, Iodine, adenovirus, or what</title><link>/posts/obesity-pandemic-since-1975-is-it-due-to-vitamin-d-magnesium-iodine-adenovirus-or-what.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-pandemic-since-1975-is-it-due-to-vitamin-d-magnesium-iodine-adenovirus-or-what.html</guid><description>&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;1952&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#obesity-pandemic-may-become-a-very-big-thing">Obesity pandemic may become a very big thing&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#relative-overweight-and-obesity-change-around-the-world-bmi-25">Relative Overweight and Obesity Change around the world (BMI &amp;gt;25)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#what-changes-around-the-world-have-occurred-since-the-mid-1970s-which-might-have-contributed-to-the-obesity-pandemic">What changes around the world have occurred since the mid 1970&amp;rsquo;s which might have contributed to the obesity pandemic&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#global-deficiency-now-of-items-1-3">Global deficiency now of items 1-3&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#there-do-not-appear-to-be-global-changes-in-other-factors-often-associated-with-obesity">There do not appear to be GLOBAL changes in other factors often associated with obesity&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="obesity-pandemic-may-become-a-very-big-thing">Obesity pandemic may become a very big thing&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;1948&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="relative-overweight-and-obesity-change-around-the-world-bmi-25">Relative Overweight and Obesity Change around the world (BMI &amp;gt;25)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;1109&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D associated with obesity-related diseases for ethnic minorities</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-obesity-related-diseases-for-ethnic-minorities.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-obesity-related-diseases-for-ethnic-minorities.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-obesity-and-obesity-related-chronic-disease-among-ethnic-minorities-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D, obesity, and obesity-related chronic disease among ethnic minorities: a systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrition. 2011 Sep;27(9):868-79. Epub 2011 Jun 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renzaho AM, Halliday JA, Nowson C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WHO Collaborating Centre for Obesity Prevention, Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria, Australia. &lt;a href="mailto:andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au">andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="for-ethnic-minorities-this-study-has-found-that-span-stylecolor00flow-vitamin-d-diabetes-etcspan">For ethnic minorities this study has found that &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">low vitamin D==&amp;gt; diabetes etc&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="rather-than-the-conventional-hypothesis-span-stylecolor00flow-vitamin-d--obesity--diabetes-etcspan">rather than the conventional hypothesis: &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">low vitamin D ==&amp;gt; obesity ==&amp;gt; diabetes etc&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To assess the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) status and obesity, cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), the metabolic syndrome, and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in ethnic minorities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity (BMI and waist circumference) associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/obesity-bmi-and-waist-circumference-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-bmi-and-waist-circumference-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cross-sectional-and-prospective-cohort-study-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-and-obesity-in-adults-the-hunt-study">Cross-Sectional and Prospective Cohort Study of Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Level and Obesity in Adults: The HUNT Study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Epidemiol. 2012 Feb 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mai XM, Chen Y, Camargo CA Jr, Langhammer A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Experimental studies suggest that vitamin D modulates the activity of adipocytes. The authors examined baseline serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) level in relation to prevalent and cumulative incident obesity in Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A cohort of 25,616 adults aged 19-55 years participated in both the second and third surveys of the Nord-Trøndelag Health Study (HUNT 2 (1995-1997) and HUNT 3 (2006-2008)). Serum 25(OH)D levels measured at baseline and anthropometric measurements taken at both baseline and follow-up were available for a random sample of 2,460 subjects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>400 IU of Vitamin D is just diluted by weight, and not stored in fat</title><link>/posts/400-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-just-diluted-by-weight-and-not-stored-in-fat.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/400-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-just-diluted-by-weight-and-not-stored-in-fat.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="volumetric-dilution-rather-than-sequestration-best-explains-the-low-vitamin-d-status-of-obesity">Volumetric Dilution, Rather Than Sequestration Best Explains the Low Vitamin D Status of Obesity.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Obesity (Silver Spring). 2012 Jan 19. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/oby.2011.404.">doi: 10.1038/oby.2011.404.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drincic AT, Armas LA, Van Diest EE, Heaney RP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Creighton University, Omaha, Nebraska, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D status is known to be poor in obese individuals; there is no consensus as to the reason. Cross-sectional study of the relation between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentration and body size in the baseline data from unsupplemented adults entering two study cohorts in our research unit, N = 686.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reasons for low response to vitamin D</title><link>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reasons-for-low-response-to-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#detailed-reasons-for-poor-response">Detailed Reasons for poor response&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reasons-for-not-getting-benefits---span-stylecolorf00even-if-blood-tests-are-okspan">Reasons for not getting benefits - &lt;span style="color:#F00;">even if blood tests are OK&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsuv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual--2010big-differences-in-uvb-responsesa-20-to-36-ng-after-6-weeks">&lt;a href="/posts/uv-production-of-vitamin-d-varies-with-the-individual-2010" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: UV production of Vitamin D varies with the individual – 2010">Big differences in UVB responses&lt;/a>: 20 to 36 ng after 6 weeks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#alternate-sources-of-vitamin-d">Alternate sources of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="overview-of-poor-response">Overview of Poor Response&lt;/h4>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>~ 50% of all people have a low response to vitamin D3&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity lowers vitamin D which increases probability of diabetes in children</title><link>/posts/obesity-lowers-vitamin-d-which-increases-probability-of-diabetes-in-children.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-lowers-vitamin-d-which-increases-probability-of-diabetes-in-children.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-obese-children-and-its-relationship-to-glucose-homeostasis">Vitamin D Deficiency in Obese Children and Its Relationship to Glucose Homeostasis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Nov 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olson ML, Maalouf NM, Oden JD, White PC, Hutchison MR. &lt;a href="mailto:michele.hutchison@utsouthwestern.edu">michele.hutchison@utsouthwestern.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Pediatrics (M.L.O., J.D.O., P.C.W., M.R.H.) and Internal Medicine (N.M.M.), University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives:The aim of the study was to compare the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in obese and non-overweight children in North Texas, to examine relationships between dietary habits and 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> level in obese children, and to examine the relationship between 25(OH)D level and markers of abnormal glucose metabolism and blood pressure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese teens needed 4000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/obese-teens-needed-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-teens-needed-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="press-release-from-university-of-missourihttpmunewsmissouriedunews-releases20111101-obese-adolescents-benefit-from-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplements-nov-2011">&lt;a href="http://munews.missouri.edu/news-releases/2011/1101-obese-adolescents-benefit-from-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplements/">Press Release from University of Missouri&lt;/a> Nov 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="the-press-release-has-the-hyperlinks">The Press Release has the hyperlinks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Catherine Peterson, nutrition researcher at MU, found that a daily dose of 4,000 IUs of vitamin D3 is both safe and effective at improving vitamin D status in obese adolescents.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="obese-adolescents-benefit-from-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplements">Obese Adolescents Benefit from High-Dose Vitamin D Supplements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="high-doses-safely-combat-nutritional-deficiencies-mu-researchers-find">High doses safely combat nutritional deficiencies, MU researchers find&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>COLUMBIA, Mo. –Vitamin D deficiency is common in Americans, and especially in overweight and obese adolescents, according to the National Institutes of Health. University of Missouri researchers have found that providing obese adolescents with a high daily dose of vitamin D3 is safe and effective in improving their vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity and diabetes reduced when move to better neighborhood – or better UV</title><link>/posts/obesity-and-diabetes-reduced-when-move-to-better-neighborhood-or-better-uv.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-and-diabetes-reduced-when-move-to-better-neighborhood-or-better-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="neighborhoods-obesity-and-diabetes--a-randomized-social-experiment">Neighborhoods, Obesity, and Diabetes — A Randomized Social Experiment&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Jens Ludwig, Ph.D. &lt;a href="mailto:jludwig@uchicago.ed">jludwig@uchicago.ed&lt;/a>, Lisa Sanbonmatsu, Ph.D., Lisa Gennetian, Ph.D., Emma Adam, Ph.D., Greg J. Duncan, Ph.D., Lawrence F. Katz, Ph.D., Ronald C. Kessler, Ph.D., Jeffrey R. Kling, Ph.D., Stacy Tessler Lindau, M.D., Robert C. Whitaker, M.D., M.P.H., and Thomas W. McDade, Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med 2011; 365:1509-1519October 20, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND The question of whether neighborhood environment contributes directly to the development of obesity and diabetes remains unresolved. The study reported on here uses data from a social experiment to assess the association of randomly assigned variation in neighborhood conditions with obesity and diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Telomeres improved when obese blacks took 2000 IU of vitamin D daily</title><link>/posts/telomeres-improved-when-obese-blacks-took-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/telomeres-improved-when-obese-blacks-took-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Resveratrol reduce weight gain in rats</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-resveratrol-reduce-weight-gain-in-rats.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-resveratrol-reduce-weight-gain-in-rats.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="from-natural-newshttpwwwnaturalnewscom033614_resveratrol_vitamin_dhtml">from &lt;a href="http://www.naturalnews.com/033614_resveratrol_vitamin_D.html">Natural News&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Resveratrol and vitamin D synergistically team to boost metabolism and prevent obesity&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>September 19, 2011 by: John Phillip&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(NaturalNews) Resveratrol has been on the nutritional radar of researchers because of its proven ability to mimic some of the life-extending characteristics provided by calorie restriction as seen in animals and humans alike. Scientists publishing in the journal Molecular Nutrition and Food Research draw a solid link between resveratrol, vitamin D and other phytonutrients as agents that may lend a helping hand in the life-threatening battle against overweight and obesity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Weight loss and Vitamin D, Calcium, and Magnesium</title><link>/posts/weight-loss-and-vitamin-d-calcium-and-magnesium.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/weight-loss-and-vitamin-d-calcium-and-magnesium.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="there-have-been-various-studies-which-have-found-weight-loss-when-increasing-one-or-more-of-the-following">There have been various studies which have found weight loss when increasing one or more of the following&lt;/h4>
&lt;h5 id="vitamin-d-nbsp-nbsp-magnesium-nbsp-nbsp-calcium">Vitamin D     Magnesium     Calcium&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>There is a lot of synergy/interaction between these nutrients in the body&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been a very large decrease in both Magnesium and Vitamin D in bodies during the past 40 years&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been a significant increase in obesity in the past 40 years&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wonder if there has been any weight loss trial using all three of the supplements&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many obesity measures far worse for senior women with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/many-obesity-measures-far-worse-for-senior-women-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-obesity-measures-far-worse-for-senior-women-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-in-relation-to-cardiometabolic-risk-factors-and-metabolic-syndrome-in-postmenopausal-women">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations in relation to cardiometabolic risk factors and metabolic syndrome in postmenopausal women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul;94(1):209-17. Epub 2011 May 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chacko SA, Song Y, Manson JE, Van Horn L, Eaton C, Martin LW, McTiernan A, Curb JD, Wylie-Rosett J, Phillips LS, Plodkowski RA, Liu S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and the Program on Genomics and Nutrition, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Low concentrations of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) may be associated with cardiometabolic disorders; however, little is known about their relation to intermediate metabolic and lipid markers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels increased when senior women lost weight</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-increased-when-senior-women-lost-weight.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-increased-when-senior-women-lost-weight.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-weight-loss-on-serum-vitamin-d-in-postmenopausal-women">Effects of weight loss on serum vitamin D in postmenopausal women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul;94(1):95-103. Epub 2011 May 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mason C, Xiao L, Imayama I, Duggan CR, Bain C, Foster-Schubert KE, Kong A, Campbell KL, Wang CY, Neuhouser ML, Li L, W Jeffery R, Robien K, Alfano CM, Blackburn GL, McTiernan A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center, Seattle, WA 98109, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Low concentrations of circulating vitamin D are common with obesity and may represent a potential mechanism explaining the elevated risk of certain cancers and cardiovascular outcomes observed in individuals who are overweight or obese.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black women lacking Calcium and Vitamin D weighed more</title><link>/posts/black-women-lacking-calcium-and-vitamin-d-weighed-more.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-women-lacking-calcium-and-vitamin-d-weighed-more.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="higher-amounts-of-body-fat-are-associated-with-inadequate-intakes-of-calcium-and-vitamin-d-in-african-american-women">Higher amounts of body fat are associated with inadequate intakes of calcium and vitamin D in African American women&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrition Research; Volume 31, Issue 7, July 2011, Pages 527-536; doi:10.1016/j.nutres.2011.06.005&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diane K. Tidwell a, &lt;a href="mailto:ditdwell@fsnhp.msstate.edu">ditdwell@fsnhp.msstate.edu&lt;/a> and Melinda W. Valliant b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Food Science, Nutrition and Health Promotion, PO Box 9805, Mississippi State, MS 39762&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Nutrition and Hospitality Management, The University of Mississippi&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 11 October 2010; revised 22 June 2011; accepted 23 June 2011, online 12 August 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone lost during postmenopausal dieting not all recovered with weight re-gain</title><link>/posts/bone-lost-during-postmenopausal-dieting-not-all-recovered-with-weight-re-gain.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-lost-during-postmenopausal-dieting-not-all-recovered-with-weight-re-gain.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="postmenopausal-women-who-lose-weight-may-also-lose-bone-mass-that-might-not-returnhttparticleslatimescom2011aug19newsla-heb-osteoporosis-weight-loss-20110819">&lt;a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2011/aug/19/news/la-heb-osteoporosis-weight-loss-20110819">Postmenopausal women who lose weight may also lose bone mass that might not return&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>August 19, 2011 By Jeannine Stein, Los Angeles Times&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Postmenopausal women who lose weight can also lose bone mass. But a study finds that regaining that weight doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily replace the lost bone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The small, exploratory study included 23 overweight women who had been through menopause and were not taking any hormone therapy or drugs that might affect their bone metabolism. Women are at high risk for osteoporosis after menopause.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obese men were 40 percent more likely to be vitamin D deficient than women</title><link>/posts/obese-men-were-40-percent-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-women.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obese-men-were-40-percent-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient-than-women.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="impact-of-gender-on-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-morbidly-obese-patients-a-cross-sectional-study">Impact of gender on vitamin D deficiency in morbidly obese patients: a cross-sectional study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul 27. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2011.140.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2011.140.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johnson LK, Hofsø D, Aasheim ET, Tanbo T, Holven KB, Andersen LF, Røislien J, Hjelmesæth J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1] Department of Medicine, Morbid Obesity Centre, Vestfold Hospital Trust, Tønsberg, Norway &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup> Department of Gynaecology, Norwegian Resource Centre for Women&amp;rsquo;s Health, Oslo University Hospital Rikshospitalet, Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Objective: Obesity is associated with vitamin D deficiency (25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) &amp;lt;50?nmol/l). We aimed to examine the effect of gender on vitamin D status in severe obesity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4000 IU vitamin D was not enough to reduce obesity – PhD 2010</title><link>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-reduce-obesity-phd-2010.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-to-reduce-obesity-phd-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="does-vitamin-d-supplementation-augment-exercise-induced-changes-in-health-and-physical-performance">Does vitamin D supplementation augment exercise-induced changes in health and physical performance?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>by Carrillo, Andres Ernesto, Ph.D., PURDUE UNIVERSITY, 2010, 167 pages; 3444489&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this research was to examine the effects of vitamin D supplementation &lt;strong>(4000 IU/d)&lt;/strong> during an exercise training intervention on body composition, muscular strength and power, glucose tolerance, and inflammatory biomarkers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-three (26.1 ? 4.7 yrs) overweight-to-obese (BMI: 31.3 ? 3.2 kg/m2 ) adults were recruited during winter months (25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) 19.3 ? 7.2 ng/mL) and randomized into a vitamin D (VitD, n = 10) or placebo (PL, n = 13) group.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Adioponectin and low vitamin D both associated with Obesity</title><link>/posts/low-adioponectin-and-low-vitamin-d-both-associated-with-obesity.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-adioponectin-and-low-vitamin-d-both-associated-with-obesity.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-independent-association-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-adiponectin-and-its-relation-with-bmi-in-two-large-cohorts">The Independent Association Between 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Adiponectin and Its Relation With BMI in Two Large Cohorts:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The NHS and the HPFS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obesity (Silver Spring). 2011 Jul 14. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/oby.2011.210.">doi: 10.1038/oby.2011.210.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vaidya A, Williams JS, Forman JP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes, and Hypertension, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and adiponectin levels are both associated with obesity and cardiovascular disease. Cross-sectional studies have suggested that 25(OH)D concentrations are positively associated with adiponectin, and that this relation may strengthen with increasing BMI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Vitamin D Diet – book</title><link>/posts/the-vitamin-d-diet-book.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-vitamin-d-diet-book.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Older obese adults got one third the benefit from vitamin D</title><link>/posts/older-obese-adults-got-one-third-the-benefit-from-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/older-obese-adults-got-one-third-the-benefit-from-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-adiposity-on-vitamin-d-status-and-the-25-hydroxycholecalciferol-response-to">Effect of adiposity on vitamin D status and the 25-hydroxycholecalciferol response to&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>supplementation in healthy young and older Irish adults.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2011 Jun 28:1-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kirsty Forsythe L, Livingstone MB, Barnes MS, Horigan G, McSorley EM, Bonham MP, Magee PJ, Hill TR, Lucey AJ, Cashman KD, Kiely M, Strain JJ, Wallace JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Northern Ireland Centre for Food and Health, University of Ulster, Coleraine BT52 1SA, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is increasing epidemiological evidence linking sub-optimal vitamin D status with overweight and obesity. Although increasing BMI and adiposity have also been negatively associated with the change in vitamin D status following supplementation, results have been equivocal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Weight reduction review – Vitamin D and Calcium may help</title><link>/posts/weight-reduction-review-vitamin-d-and-calcium-may-help.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/weight-reduction-review-vitamin-d-and-calcium-may-help.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-for-obesity-a-review-of-randomized-controlled-trials">Calcium and vitamin D for obesity: a review of randomized controlled trials.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2011.106.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2011.106.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soares MJ, Chan She Ping-Delfos W, Ghanbari MH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Program of Nutrition, School of Public Health, Curtin Health Innovation Research Institute, Curtin University, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obesity often coexists with low calcium intake and vitamin D insufficiency. There is emerging evidence of a role for these nutrients in the regulation of body weight. However, it is unclear whether increasing intakes of calcium and/or vitamin D during energy restriction, is a better strategy for weight and fat loss. We searched the literature from 2000 to date for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) on weight loss that had increased calcium or vitamin D per se, or in combination. Primary and secondary studies were included for this analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D less than 10 ng for groups of 45 year olds</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-10-ng-for-groups-of-45-year-olds.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-10-ng-for-groups-of-45-year-olds.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and--pre-clinical-alterations-in-inflammatory-and-hemostatic-markers">25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Pre-Clinical Alterations in Inflammatory and Hemostatic Markers:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-cross-sectional-analysis-in-the--1958-british-birth-cohort">A Cross Sectional Analysis in the 1958 British Birth Cohort&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Elina Hypponen, Diane Berry, Mario Cortina-Borja, Chris Power&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical Research Council Centre for Epidemiology of Child Health and Centre for Paediatric Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University College London Institute of Child Health, London, United Kingdom&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency has been suggested as a cardiovascular risk factor, but little is known about underlying mechanisms or associations with inflammatory or hemostatic markers. Our aim was to investigate the association between&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamins To Speed Up Metabolism And Aid Weight Loss</title><link>/posts/vitamins-to-speed-up-metabolism-and-aid-weight-loss.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamins-to-speed-up-metabolism-and-aid-weight-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="by-jeff-anderson-on-29-may-2011httpuknewsreportercoukhealthvitamins-to-speed-up-metabolism-and-aid-weight-loss673588comment-283">By &lt;a href="http://uknewsreporter.co.uk/health/vitamins-to-speed-up-metabolism-and-aid-weight-loss/673588/#comment-283">Jeff Anderson on 29, May 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Henry James once wrote that the two sweetest words in the English language are ‘Summer Afternoon’- and he wasn’t talking about the effects of the sun’s essential vitamin on our abilities to speed up metabolism and fat loss. Indeed, there’s no end to the amount of happy times we can associate in the summer sun, either through playing outdoors as a kid, or playing outdoors as adults! Studies show that one Vitamin D, found in large amount through sunshine, is deficit in the industrialized world’ and pharmaceutical companies are trying to capitalize on this fundamental vitamin through fancy pills and potions. Believe it or not, this sun-sational vitamin, is also an essential part of our heart health and metabolism, as well!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dark skinned obese not helped much by weekly 50000 IU dose of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dark-skinned-obese-not-helped-much-by-weekly-50000-iu-dose-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dark-skinned-obese-not-helped-much-by-weekly-50000-iu-dose-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-status-among-obese-adolescents-prevalence-and-response-to-treatment">Low Vitamin D Status Among Obese Adolescents: Prevalence and Response to Treatment&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Adolescent Health, Volume 48, Issue 5 , Pages 448-452, May 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zeev Harel, M.D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patricia Flanagan, M.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michelle Forcier, M.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dalia Harel, M.Sc. Received 19 September 2010; accepted 20 January 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Adolescent Medicine, Hasbro Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Providence, Rhode Island&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Warren Alpert Medical School of Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corresponding Author InformationAddress correspondence to: Zeev Harel, M.D., Division of Adolescent Medicine, Hasbro Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, 593 Eddy Street, Providence, RI 02903&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The more vitamin D the lower the infant BMI</title><link>/posts/the-more-vitamin-d-the-lower-the-infant-bmi.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-more-vitamin-d-the-lower-the-infant-bmi.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Are microbs – probiotics – vitamin D – allergy – asthma – obesity related</title><link>/posts/are-microbs-probiotics-vitamin-d-allergy-asthma-obesity-related.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/are-microbs-probiotics-vitamin-d-allergy-asthma-obesity-related.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="gut-microbiota-probiotics-and-vitamin-d-interrelated-exposures-influencing-allergy-asthma-and-obesity">Gut microbiota, probiotics, and vitamin D: Interrelated exposures influencing allergy, asthma, and obesity?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology; Clinical reviews in allergy and immunology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2011.02.015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ngoc P. Ly MD, MPHa &lt;a href="mailto:lyn@peds.ucsf.edu">lyn@peds.ucsf.edu&lt;/a>, Augusto Litonjua MD, MPHb, Diane R. Gold MD, MPHb and Juan C. Celedón MD, DrPHc&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Division of Pediatric Pulmonary Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, University of California San Francisco, Calif&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Channing Laboratory, Brigham and Women’s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, Mass&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtually all Bariatric Surgery patients vitamin D deficient – should we routinely supplement</title><link>/posts/virtually-all-bariatric-surgery-patients-vitamin-d-deficient-should-we-routinely-supplement.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/virtually-all-bariatric-surgery-patients-vitamin-d-deficient-should-we-routinely-supplement.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-before-bariatric-surgery-should-supplement-intake-be-routinely-prescribed">Vitamin D Deficiency Before Bariatric Surgery: Should Supplement Intake Be Routinely Prescribed?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Obes Surg. 2011 Jan 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ducloux R, Nobécourt E, Chevallier JM, Ducloux H, Elian N, Altman JJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Service de Diabétologie-Endocrinologie-Nutrition, Hôpital Européen Georges Pompidou, Paris, France, &lt;a href="mailto:roxane.ducloux@egp.aphp.fr">roxane.ducloux@egp.aphp.fr&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Before bariatric surgery, we demonstrate a 96% rate of vitamin D deficiency in morbidly obese French patients: should supplement intake be routinely prescribed? We conducted a prospective observational study to demonstrate the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in morbidly obese patients awaiting bariatric surgery.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black obese children had low vitamin D and more fat under skin than whites</title><link>/posts/black-obese-children-had-low-vitamin-d-and-more-fat-under-skin-than-whites.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/black-obese-children-had-low-vitamin-d-and-more-fat-under-skin-than-whites.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-adiposity-and-lipids-in-black-american-and-caucasian-children">Vitamin D Status, Adiposity, and Lipids in Black American and Caucasian Children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Mar 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rajakumar K, de Las Heras J, Chen TC, Lee S, Holick MF, Arslanian SA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics (K.R.), Division of General Academic Pediatrics, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Department of Pediatrics (J.d.l.H., S.L., S.A.A.), Division of Weight Management and Wellness, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Division of Pediatric Endocrinology, Metabolism, and Diabetes Mellitus (S.A.A.), University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 15224; Department of Pediatrics and Endocrinology and Diabetes Research Group (J.d.l.H.), Cruces Hospital, 48903 Barakaldo, Vizcaya, Spain; and Department of Medicine (T.C.C., M.F.H.), Boston University School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts 02118.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Map of BMI increase</title><link>/posts/map-of-bmi-increase.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/map-of-bmi-increase.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-the-economisthttpwwweconomistcomblogsdailychart201102daily_chart_global_obesity">&lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/dailychart/2011/02/daily_chart_global_obesity">From the Economist&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="how-mens-waistlines-have-grown-since-1980">How mens&amp;rsquo; waistlines have grown since 1980&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>RISING levels of obesity are bad news for people and health-care budgets, but they also correlate with good things such as rising economic wealth. The three maps below, which are drawn from a new global study led by Professor Majid Ezzati of Imperial College, London, and published in the Lancet, show that, Polynesia aside, obesity was a rich-world phenomenon in 1980. By 2008 the rich world had itself expanded, bringing obesity to groups within countries that were previously considered poor, such as Brazil and South Africa. During that period, the prevalence rate of obesity among men doubled to nearly 10%. One country has stubbornly resisted this trend. For all its dynamism since India opened up its economy in 1990, its men have on average become even thinner. The study suggests that Congo is the thinnest country in the world, and Nauru the fattest. Imperial College&amp;rsquo;s own map is &lt;a href="http://www5.imperial.ac.uk/medicine/metabolic_risks/bmi/"> &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#390;">here&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> &lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Higher BMI need more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/higher-bmi-need-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/higher-bmi-need-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cross-sectional-and-longitudinal-relation-between-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-body-mass-index-the-tromsø-study">Cross-sectional and longitudinal relation between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and body mass index: the Tromsø study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Nutr. 2010 Oct;49(7):401-7. Epub 2010 Mar 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cross-sectional and longitudinal relation between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and body mass index: the Tromsø study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorde R, Sneve M, Emaus N, Figenschau Y, Grimnes G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, Tromsø, Norway. &lt;a href="mailto:rolf.jorde@unn.no">rolf.jorde@unn.no&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: The serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels are lower in obese than lean subjects. The present study examines the cross-sectional and longitudinal relations between body mass index (BMI) and serum 25(OH)D, and the serum 25(OH)D response to vitamin D supplementation in relation to BMI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D then Obesity then adenovirus-36</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-then-obesity-then-adenovirus-36.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-then-obesity-then-adenovirus-36.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Women can lose weight with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/women-can-lose-weight-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-can-lose-weight-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-vitamin-d-linked-to-80-less-belly-fat">High Vitamin D linked to 80% less belly fat&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="from-first-for-women-nov-2010">From First For Women Nov 2010&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;302&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;303&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="spantiki-download_filephpfileid1586span">&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1586]&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Note: had a hard time finding this magazine, and it was not available on-line&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-at-vitamindwiki-a-hrefpostsspan-stylecolor30foverview-of-obesityspan-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-710-span-stylecolor30foverview-of-obesityspan-a">See also at VitaminDWiki: &lt;a href="/posts/span-stylecolor30foverview-of-obesityspan" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 710"> &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#30F;">Overview of Obesity&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> &lt;/a>&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Middle-aged women gained weight if they did not drink fortified milk</title><link>/posts/middle-aged-women-gained-weight-if-they-did-not-drink-fortified-milk.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/middle-aged-women-gained-weight-if-they-did-not-drink-fortified-milk.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-calcium-milk-prevents-overweight-and-obesity-among-postmenopausal-women">High-calcium milk prevents overweight and obesity among postmenopausal women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Food Nutr Bull. 2010 Sep;31(3):381-90.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Angeles-Agdeppa I, Capanzana MV, Li-Yu J, Schollum LM, Kruger MC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Food and Nutrition Research Institute, Department of Science and Technology, Taguig City, Philippines. &lt;a href="mailto:imelda_agdeppa@yahoo.com">imelda_agdeppa@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The Sixth National Nutrition Survey 2003 revealed that the highest prevalence of overweight and obesity among Filipino female adults (30.8%) was found in the age group from 40 to 59 years. Obesity is associated with a number of chronic diseases, including cardiovascular disease, hypertension, and diabetes. Low calcium intake has been identified as a potential contributing factor to overweight and obesity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>600 mg dairy resulted in 12 pound loss in 2 years</title><link>/posts/600-mg-dairy-resulted-in-12-pound-loss-in-2-years.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/600-mg-dairy-resulted-in-12-pound-loss-in-2-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dairy-calcium-intake-serum-vitamin-d-and-successful-weight-loss">Dairy calcium intake, serum vitamin D, and successful weight loss.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2010 Nov;92(5):1017-22. Epub 2010 Sep 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shahar DR, Schwarzfuchs D, Fraser D, Vardi H, Thiery J, Fiedler GM, Blüher M, Stumvoll M, Stampfer MJ, Shai I; DIRECT Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S Daniel Abraham Center for Health and Nutrition and the Department of Epidemiology, Faculty of Health Sciences, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Beer-Sheva, Israel. &lt;a href="mailto:dshahar@bgu.ac.il">dshahar@bgu.ac.il&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The role of dairy calcium intake and serum vitamin D concentrations in weight loss is controversial.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>