<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Multiple Sclerosis on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/multiple-sclerosis.html</link><description>Recent content in Multiple Sclerosis on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/multiple-sclerosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis: number needed to treat with vitamin D may be as low as 1.3 – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-number-needed-to-treat-with-vitamin-d-may-be-as-low-as-13-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-number-needed-to-treat-with-vitamin-d-may-be-as-low-as-13-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-case-for-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-multiple-sclerosis">The case for vitamin D supplementation in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Multiple Sclerosis and Related Disorders, Volume 2, Issue 4, October 2013, Pages 281–306 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msard.2012.12.008">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msard.2012.12.008&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aravind Ganesh a, &lt;a href="mailto:aravindganeshy@yahoo.ca">aravindganeshy@yahoo.ca&lt;/a>; Sabrina Apel b, Luanne Metz c, Scott Patten d,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>a Resident, Clinical Neurosciences, University of Calgary, 1403 29 Street NW Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 2T9&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>b Undergraduate Medical Education, University of Calgary, 33 Discovery Rise SW Calgary, Alberta, Canada T3H 4N6&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>c Clinical Neurosciences, University of Calgary, 1403 29 Street NW Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 2T9&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Melatonin interacts with Vitamin D in Multiple Sclerosis patients</title><link>/posts/melatonin-interacts-with-vitamin-d-in-multiple-sclerosis-patients.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/melatonin-interacts-with-vitamin-d-in-multiple-sclerosis-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="latitude-vitamin-d-melatonin-and-gut-microbiota-act-in-concert-to-initiate-multiple-sclerosis">Latitude, Vitamin D, Melatonin, and Gut Microbiota Act in Concert to Initiate Multiple Sclerosis:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A New Mechanistic Pathway - 2018&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>See &lt;a href="/posts/a-multiple-sclerosis-hypothesis-supported-by-eae-data" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: A Multiple Sclerosis hypothesis supported by EAE data – Oct 2018">A Multiple Sclerosis hypothesis supported by EAE data – Oct 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="disruption-of-melatonin-circadian-rhythm-production-is-related-to-multiple-sclerosis-severity-a-preliminary-study---2015">Disruption of melatonin circadian rhythm production is related to multiple sclerosis severity: A preliminary study - 2015&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;In conclusion, disruption of melatonin circadian rhythm production is frequent among RRMS patients and seemingly related to higher disability and fatigue scores&amp;rdquo;     &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2015.03.040">doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2015.03.040&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and MS, ALS, Autism, Alzheimer’s and other nervous system diseases – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-ms-als-autism-alzheimers-and-other-nervous-system-diseases-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-ms-als-autism-alzheimers-and-other-nervous-system-diseases-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="review-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-nervous-system-health-and-disease">Review: The role of vitamin D in nervous system health and disease&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Neuropathology and Applied Neurobiology. Volume 39, Issue 5, pages 458–484, August 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G. C. DeLuca 1,gabriele.deluca@ndcn.ox.ac.uk&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. M. Kimball 3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. Kolasinski 1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. V. Ramagopalan 2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G. C. Ebers 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Nuffield Department of Clinical Neurosciences (Clinical Neurology), University of Oxford, Oxford&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Blizard Institute of Cell and Molecular Science, Queen Mary University of London, Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Full-on Multiple Sclerosis was 3.3X more likely in patients with the lowest vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/full-on-multiple-sclerosis-was-33x-more-likely-in-patients-with-the-lowest-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/full-on-multiple-sclerosis-was-33x-more-likely-in-patients-with-the-lowest-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-levels-and-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-patients-with-clinically-isolated-syndromes">Vitamin D levels and risk of multiple sclerosis in patients with clinically isolated syndromes.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Mult Scler. 2013 Jul 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martinelli V, Dalla Costa G, Colombo B, Dalla Libera D, Rubinacci A, Filippi M, Furlan R, Comi G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, San Raffaele Hospital, Milan, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Growing evidence suggests that vitamin D deficiency may be one of the most important environmental factors for the development of multiple sclerosis (MS).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: The objectives of this paper are to evaluate serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels in patients with clinically isolated syndromes (CIS) and to examine whether they are related to MS risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV decreases Multiple Sclerosis via cis-urocanic acid (and via vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/uv-decreases-multiple-sclerosis-via-cis-urocanic-acid-and-via-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-decreases-multiple-sclerosis-via-cis-urocanic-acid-and-via-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="modulation-of-multiple-sclerosis-by-sunlight-exposure-role-of-cis-urocanic-acid">Modulation of multiple sclerosis by sunlight exposure: Role of cis-urocanic acid&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Jorge Correale &lt;a href="mailto:jcorreale@fleni.org.ar">jcorreale@fleni.org.ar&lt;/a> , Mauricio F. Farez&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 16 March 2013; published online 24 June 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of cis-urocanic acid (UCA) as a UV-mediated immunomodulator in MS patients was investigated. Plasma levels of cis-UCA were significantly lower in MS patients compared to controls. Stimulation of MBP- and MOG-specific T cells in the presence of cis-UCA, significantly increased IL-10, and inhibited IFN-γ production. PBMCs cultured in the presence of cis-UCA increased CD4+CD25+FoxP3+ regulatory T cell percentages. Dendritic cells cultured in the presence of cis-UCA significantly reduced Ag presentation capacity. Finally, cis-UCA activated the 5-HT2A receptor, inducing the increase in phosphorylated forms of ERK 1/2 and JNK2. Thus, in addition to vitamin D, cis-UCA also appears to be an additional UV-mediated immunomodulator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased risk of multiple sclerosis risk in African Americans due to genes</title><link>/posts/increased-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-risk-in-african-americans-due-to-genes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-risk-in-african-americans-due-to-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="genetic-risk-variants-in-african-americans-with-multiple-sclerosis">Genetic risk variants in African Americans with multiple sclerosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Neurology 10.1212/WNL.0b013e31829bfe2f&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Noriko Isobe, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pierre-Antoine Gourraud, PhD, MPH,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hanne F. Harbo, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stacy J. Caillier, BS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adam Santaniello, BS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pouya Khankhanian, BA,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martin Maiers, MS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen Spellman, MBS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nezih Cereb, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SooYoung Yang, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marcelo J. Pando, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laura Piccio, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anne H. Cross, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Philip L. De Jager, MD, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce A.C. Cree, MD, PhD, MCR,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS flu-like symptoms resulting from interferon-beta were reduced with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ms-flu-like-symptoms-resulting-from-interferon-beta-were-reduced-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-flu-like-symptoms-resulting-from-interferon-beta-were-reduced-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-for-patients-with-multiple-sclerosis-treated-with-interferon-beta">Vitamin D supplementation for patients with multiple sclerosis treated with interferon-beta:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>a randomized controlled trial assessing the effect on flu-like symptoms and immunomodulatory properties&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Neurology 2013, 13:60 doi:10.1186/1471-2377-13-60; Published: 14 June 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daniel Golan, Basheer Halhal, Lea Glass-Marmor, Elsebeth Staun-Ram, Orit Rozenberg, Idit Lavi, Sara Dishon, Mira Barak, Sophia Ish-Shalom and Ariel Miller&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Flu-like symptoms (FLS) are common side effects of interferon beta (IFN-beta) treatment in patients with Multiple Sclerosis (PwMS) and are associated with post-injection cytokine surge.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>98 pcnt of genes that Vitamin D activates to reduce MS are also activated by Interferon</title><link>/posts/98-pcnt-of-genes-that-vitamin-d-activates-to-reduce-ms-are-also-activated-by-interferon.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/98-pcnt-of-genes-that-vitamin-d-activates-to-reduce-ms-are-also-activated-by-interferon.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-ms-activity-during-therapy-with-interferon-beta-1b">25-Hydroxyvitamin D and MS Activity During Therapy with Interferon Beta-1b&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cmscactrims.confex.com/cmscactrims/2013/webprogram/Paper1448.html%20">CMSC Conference, May 30, 2013 &lt;/a> Florida&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alberto Ascherio, MD , Harvard University, Boston, MA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kassandra Munger, ScD , Harvard University, Boston, MA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Claire Simon, ScD , Harvard University, Boston, MA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ludwig Kappos, MD , University Hospital, Basel Neurology, Basel, Switzerland, Basel, Switzerland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chris H Polman, MD , VU Medical Center, Amsterdam, Netherlands&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mark Freedman, MD , University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is important for the central nervous system and cognition</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-important-for-the-central-nervous-system-and-cognition.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-important-for-the-central-nervous-system-and-cognition.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-the-central-nervous-system">Vitamin D and the central nervous system&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Pharmacological Reports, 2013, 65, 271-278 ISSN 1734-1140&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matgorzata Wrzosek1, Jacek tukaszkiewicz2, Michat Wrzosek3, Andrzej Jakubczyk4, Halina Matsumoto4, Pawet Piatkiewicz3, Maria Radziwoh-Zaleska4, Marcin Wojnar4,5, Grazyna Nowicka1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>department of Pharmacogenomics, department of Biochemistry and Clinical Chemistry,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>department of Internal Medicine and Diabetology, department of Psychiatry, Medical University of Warsaw, Zwirki i Wigury 61, PL 02-091 Warszawa, Poland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>department of Psychiatry, University of Michigan, 4250 Plymouth Rd., Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA Correspondence: Grazyna Nowicka, e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:grazyna.nowicka@wum.edu.p">grazyna.nowicka@wum.edu.p&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No association between Multiple Sclerosis relapses and being treated with vitamin D–meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/no-association-between-multiple-sclerosis-relapses-and-being-treated-with-vitamin-dmeta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-association-between-multiple-sclerosis-relapses-and-being-treated-with-vitamin-dmeta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>This is most likely similar to many other meta-analysis which find no association when averaging the response by people getting no benefit from as little as 400 IU with those getting a lot of benefit from 10,000 IU&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-related-interventions-on-multiple-sclerosis-relapses-a-meta-analysis">The effect of vitamin D-related interventions on multiple sclerosis relapses: a meta-analysis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mult Scler May 22, 2013 1352458513489756&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eleanor James, Ruth Dobson, Jens Kuhle, David Baker, Gavin Giovannoni, Sreeram V Ramagopalan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Blizard Institute, Queen Mary University of London, Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Season of birth associated with Pneumonia (10 %) and Multiple Sclerosis (30 %)</title><link>/posts/season-of-birth-associated-with-pneumonia-10-percent-and-multiple-sclerosis-30-percent.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/season-of-birth-associated-with-pneumonia-10-percent-and-multiple-sclerosis-30-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#no-effect-of-season-of-birth-on-risk-of-type-1-diabetes-cancer-schizophrenia-and-ischemic-heart-disease-while-some-variations-may-be-seen-for-pneumonia-and-multiple-sclerosis">No effect of season of birth on risk of type 1 diabetes, cancer, schizophrenia and ischemic heart disease, while some variations may be seen for pneumonia and multiple sclerosis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="no-effect-of-season-of-birth-on-risk-of-type-1-diabetes-cancer-schizophrenia-and-ischemic-heart-disease-while-some-variations-may-be-seen-for-pneumonia-and-multiple-sclerosis">No effect of season of birth on risk of type 1 diabetes, cancer, schizophrenia and ischemic heart disease, while some variations may be seen for pneumonia and multiple sclerosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermato Endocrinology: Volume 5, Issue 2 April/May/June 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Susanna við Streym, Lars Rejnmark, Leif Mosekilde and Peter Vestergaard&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More hijab clothing may have resulted in 6X increase in Multiple Sclerosis in Tehran</title><link>/posts/more-hijab-clothing-may-have-resulted-in-6x-increase-in-multiple-sclerosis-in-tehran.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-hijab-clothing-may-have-resulted-in-6x-increase-in-multiple-sclerosis-in-tehran.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#what-is-causing-irans-spike-in-ms-cases">What is Causing Iran’s Spike in MS Cases?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="what-is-causing-irans-spike-in-ms-cases">What is Causing Iran’s Spike in MS Cases?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency from lack of sunlight could be an unexpected long-term consequence of the Iranian revolution &lt;/p>
&lt;p>By Libby Copeland, Smithsonian magazine, May 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scientists have long recognized a link between lack of sunlight and multiple sclerosis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiple sclerosis has skyrocketed in Tehran, increasing almost sevenfold between 1989 and 2005. In Iran’s central province of Isfahan, the incidence nearly tripled from 2005 to 2009. Now Oxford University researchers suggest, for the first time, that the 1979 Iranian Revolution may deserve some of the blame for the extraordinary jump. They say the revolutionary mandate for modest dress and head coverings for women may have inadvertently fueled the increase by limiting their exposure to sunlight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis: high incidence in black women than whites (perhaps vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-high-incidence-in-black-women-than-whites-perhaps-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-high-incidence-in-black-women-than-whites-perhaps-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="incidence-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-multiple-racial-and-ethnic-groups">Incidence of multiple sclerosis in multiple racial and ethnic groups.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Neurology. 2013 May 7;80(19):1734-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182918cc2.">doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182918cc2.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Langer-Gould A, Brara SM, Beaber BE, Zhang JL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Department of Research and Evaluation (A.L.-G., J.L.Z.), Kaiser Permanente, Southern California, Pasadena; and Neurology Department (A.L.-G., S.M.B., B.E.B.), Kaiser Permanente, Southern California Los Angeles Medical Center, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To determine whether the incidence of multiple sclerosis (MS) varies by race/ethnicity in a multiethnic, population-based cohort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and multiple sclerosis (technical, outline only)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis-technical-outline-only.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis-technical-outline-only.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Neuroscience; Available online 26 March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah Hewer a,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robyn Lucas b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ingrid van der Mei c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce V. Taylor c, &lt;a href="mailto:bruce.taylor@utas.edu.au">bruce.taylor@utas.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Royal Hobart Hospital, Department of Neurology, Hobart, Tasmania, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b National Centre for Epidemiology and Population Health, The Australian National University, Canberra, Australian Capital Territory, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c Menzies Research Institute Tasmania, University of Tasmania, Locked Bag 23, Hobart, Tasmania 7000, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of vitamin D supplementation in preventing multiple sclerosis (MS) and/or treating MS progression is an area of significant research interest. We detail the current status of the ongoing research in this field, and note the lack of class 1 evidence from well-conducted, large, double-blind, placebo-controlled studies of vitamin D supplementation in the prevention and/or treatment of MS. We have been able to &lt;strong>provide some guidelines for practitioners&lt;/strong> based on the substantial burden of supportive evidence for the use of vitamin D in MS as summarised here. These guidelines may provide some support to those clinicians who treat people with MS and their families.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Appears that Vitamin D can induce remission in recent Multiple Sclerosis</title><link>/posts/appears-that-vitamin-d-can-induce-remission-in-recent-multiple-sclerosis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/appears-that-vitamin-d-can-induce-remission-in-recent-multiple-sclerosis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostsdr-coimbra-in-brazil-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-3857dr-coimbra-in-brazila">&lt;a href="/posts/dr-coimbra-in-brazil" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 3857">Dr. Coimbra, in Brazil&lt;/a>,&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Has found that large doses of vitamin D: 20,000 to 150,000 IU/day results in remission of recent cases of Multiple Sclerosis.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Specifically: Recent lesions appeared partially repaired or disappeared on MRI scans after one and two years of treatment.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="biomarkers-in-multiple-sclerosis-an-up-to-date-overview-jan-2013">Biomarkers in Multiple Sclerosis: An Up-to-Date Overview Jan 2013&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Shows that MRI is one of many MS biomarkers&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prevention with vitamin D in Multiple Sclerosis is logical – editorial</title><link>/posts/prevention-with-vitamin-d-in-multiple-sclerosis-is-logical-editorial.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prevention-with-vitamin-d-in-multiple-sclerosis-is-logical-editorial.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis-timing-of-sampling-treatment-and-prevention">Vitamin D and multiple sclerosis: timing of sampling, treatment and prevention.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Biomark Med. 2013 Apr;7(2):193-5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2217/bmm.13.10.">doi: 10.2217/bmm.13.10.&lt;/a> PMID: 23547812&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sundström P, Salzer J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pharmacology &amp;amp; Clinical Neuroscience, Section of Neurology, Umeå University, 901 87 Umeå, Sweden. &lt;a href="mailto:peter.sundstrom@neuro.umu.se">peter.sundstrom@neuro.umu.se&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With today&amp;rsquo;s knowledge, it is the authors&amp;rsquo; view that enough scientific data exist to suggest that multiple sclerosis patients should be informed about the association between vitamin D levels and multiple sclerosis inflammatory disease activity&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple sclerosis associated with sun, not low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-associated-with-sun-not-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-associated-with-sun-not-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="interdependence-and-contributions-of-sun-exposure-and-vitamin-d-to-mri-measures-in-multiple-sclerosis">Interdependence and contributions of sun exposure and vitamin D to MRI measures in multiple sclerosis.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2013 Feb 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zivadinov R, Treu CN, Weinstock-Guttman B, Turner C, Bergsland N, O&amp;rsquo;Connor K, Dwyer MG, Carl E, Ramasamy DP, Qu J, Ramanathan M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Buffalo Neuroimaging Analysis Center, State University of New York, , Buffalo, New York, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: To assess the relationships of sun exposure history, supplementation and environmental factors to vitamin D levels in multiple sclerosis (MS) patients and to evaluate the associations between sun exposure and MRI measures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autoimmune disorder patients in Brazil helped by vitamin D – video and Facebook</title><link>/posts/autoimmune-disorder-patients-in-brazil-helped-by-vitamin-d-video-and-facebook.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/autoimmune-disorder-patients-in-brazil-helped-by-vitamin-d-video-and-facebook.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="neat-social-media-spreads-the-word-of-the-benefits-of-vitamin-d3-and-vitamin-k2">Neat: Social media spreads the word of the benefits of Vitamin D3 (and Vitamin K2)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Large doses: 20,000 to 150,000 IU/d&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dose sizes are far larger than what what others are using to prevent MS, but this size is being used to TREAT MS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="facebook-page-by-the-patientshttpswwwfacebookcomgroups528624870516079-in-portuguese">&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/528624870516079/">Facebook Page by the patients&lt;/a> in Portuguese&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>15,800 members as of Nov 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="youtube-interview-of-the-doctorhttpwwwyoutubecomwatchvciwiwim4hnm">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cIwIWim4hNM">YouTube interview of the doctor&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/brazil.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="youtube-videohttpwwwyoutubecomwatchveragu1xcy-u-in-portuguese-with-english-and-spanish-subtitles">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=erAgu1XcY-U">YouTube Video&lt;/a> In Portuguese with English and Spanish subtitles&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The documentary was made by Daniel Cunha, a Brazilian journalist.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Small increase in Vitamin A metabolites cut new multiple sclerosis lesions in half</title><link>/posts/small-increase-in-vitamin-a-metabolites-cut-new-multiple-sclerosis-lesions-in-half.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/small-increase-in-vitamin-a-metabolites-cut-new-multiple-sclerosis-lesions-in-half.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-a-yet-another-player-in-multiple-sclerosis-pathogenesis">Vitamin A: yet another player in multiple sclerosis pathogenesis?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Expert Review of Clinical Immunology February 2013, Vol. 9, No. 2, Pages 113-115 , DOI 10.1586/eci.12.105&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Massimo Filippi*, Paolo Preziosa and Maria A Rocca&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evaluation of: Løken-Amsrud KI, Myhr KM, Bakke SJ et al. Retinol levels are associated with magnetic resonance imaging outcomes in multiple sclerosis. Mult. Scler. doi:10.1177/1352458512457843 (2012) (Epub ahead of print).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A combination of genetic and environmental factors probably plays a role in determining an increased susceptibility to multiple sclerosis (MS). Among these factors, vitamin D and A metabolites are likely to play a role given their immunomodulatory properties. Decreased serum vitamin D levels have been associated with clinical and MRI activity of MS. Løken-Amsrud et al. evaluated the association of retinol concentration with clinical and MRI measures of disease activity in MS patients over a 2-year period. Serum retinol levels correlated with MRI metrics of disease activity, but not with clinical findings. Following IFN-β-1a treatment, the association with MRI metrics was lost. These results support a role of vitamin A metabolites in influencing disease activity in MS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D: one sided debate is published in Multiple Sclerosis Journal</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-one-sided-debate-is-published-in-multiple-sclerosis-journal.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-one-sided-debate-is-published-in-multiple-sclerosis-journal.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="if-i-had-a-clinically-isolated-syndrome-with-mri-diagnostic-of-ms-i-would-take-vitamin-d-10000-iu-daily-no">If I had a clinically isolated syndrome with MRI diagnostic of MS, I would take vitamin D 10,000 IU daily: No&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mult Scler February 2013 vol. 19 no. 2 140-142&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Caroline Papeix, Catherine Lubetzki&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Université Pierre et Marie Curie AP-HP, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Catherine Lubetzki, Department of Neurology, Pitié-Salpêtrière Hospital, 75013 Paris, France. Email: &lt;a href="mailto:catherine.lubetzki@psl.aphp.fr">catherine.lubetzki@psl.aphp.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="observation-by-vitamindwiki">Observation by VitaminDWiki&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We see MS professionals, with a lot a stake to keep the status quo (note the conflict of interest section) valiently state why vitamin D has not yet been absolutely proven, and can never be absolutely proven to help MS (people in the placebo group can get vitamin D from food and sun).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D associated with reduced T-cell attacks in Multiple Sclerosis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-associated-with-reduced-t-cell-attacks-in-multiple-sclerosis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-associated-with-reduced-t-cell-attacks-in-multiple-sclerosis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="regulatory-role-of-vitamin-d-in-t-cell-reactivity-against-myelin-peptides-in-relapsing-remitting-multiple-sclerosis-patients">Regulatory role of vitamin D in T-cell reactivity against myelin peptides in relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>MC Neurol. 2012 Sep 24;12:103. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2377-12-103.">doi: 10.1186/1471-2377-12-103.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grau-López L, Granada ML, Raïch-Regué D, Naranjo-Gómez M, Borràs-Serres FE, Martínez-Cáceres E, Ramo-Tello C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurosciences, Hospital Universitari Germans Trias i Pujol, Carretera del Canyet s/n, Badalona, Barcelona, 08916, Spain. &lt;a href="mailto:laiagrlo@gmail.com">laiagrlo@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Low levels of plasma 25-hydroxyvitaminD (25(OH)D) are associated with a higher incidence of multiple sclerosis (MS) due to the immune suppressive properties of vitamin D.The aim of this study was to determine the correlation between plasma 25(OH)D concentrations and clinical and immunological variables in a cohort of multiple sclerosis patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone health not correlated with Vitamin D level in multiple sclerosis – review</title><link>/posts/bone-health-not-correlated-with-vitamin-d-level-in-multiple-sclerosis-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-health-not-correlated-with-vitamin-d-level-in-multiple-sclerosis-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-health-in-multiple-sclerosis">Bone health in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Dec;22(12):2935-49. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-011-1644-8.">doi: 10.1007/s00198-011-1644-8.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 May 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gibson JC, Summers GD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Level 2, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Royal Derby Hospital, Uttoxeter Road, Derby, DE22 3NE, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:jeremy.gibson@nhs.net">jeremy.gibson@nhs.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People who are disabled with multiple sclerosis (MS) may be at increased risk of osteoporosis. This review discusses issues relevant to bone health in MS and makes practical recommendations regarding prevention and screening for osteoporosis and fracture risk in MS. A search of the literature up until 5 April 2011 was performed using key search terms, and articles pertinent to bone health in MS were analysed. Bone mineral density (BMD) is reduced at the lumbar spine, hip and total body in MS, with the degree of reduction being greatest at the hip. A strong relationship exists between the disability level, measured by the Expanded Disability Status Score, and BMD at the lumbar spine and femoral neck, particularly the latter. The rate of loss of BMD also correlates with the level of disability. Pulsed corticosteroids for acute episodes of MS, even with a high cumulative steroid dose, do not significantly affect BMD, but an effect on fracture risk is yet to be elucidated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Late-stage MS associated with protein in spinal cord which blocks vitamin D</title><link>/posts/late-stage-ms-associated-with-protein-in-spinal-cord-which-blocks-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/late-stage-ms-associated-with-protein-in-spinal-cord-which-blocks-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-binding-protein-in-cerebrospinal-fluid-is-associated-with-multiple-sclerosis-progression">Vitamin D-binding Protein in Cerebrospinal Fluid is Associated with Multiple Sclerosis Progression.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mol Neurobiol. 2013 Jan 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yang M, Qin Z, Zhu Y, Li Y, Qin Y, Jing Y, Liu S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, School of Medicine, Shandong University, 44 Wenhuaxi Road, Jinan, Shandong, 250012, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiple sclerosis is a neurological disorder that presents with symptoms including inflammation, neurodegeneration, and demyelination of the central nervous system (CNS).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D looks promising to deal with MS – review 2013</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-looks-promising-to-deal-with-ms-review-2013.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-looks-promising-to-deal-with-ms-review-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="can-we-prevent-or-treat-multiple-sclerosis-by-individualised-vitamin-d-supply">Can we prevent or treat multiple sclerosis by individualised vitamin D supply?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>EPMA Journal 2013, 4:4 doi:10.1186/1878-5085-4-4. Published: 29 January 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jan Dörr, Andrea Döring and Friedemann Paul&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract (provisional)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apart from its principal role in bone metabolism and calcium homeostasis, vitamin D has been attributed additional effects including an immunomodulatory, anti-inflammatory, and possibly even neuroprotective capacity which implicates a possible role of vitamin D in autoimmune diseases like multiple sclerosis (MS). Indeed, several lines of evidence including epidemiologic, preclinical, and clinical data suggest that reduced vitamin D levels and/or dysregulation of vitamin D homeostasis is a risk factor for the development of multiple sclerosis on the one hand, and that vitamin D serum levels are inversely associated with disease activity and progression on the other hand. However, these data are not undisputable, and many questions regarding the preventive and therapeutic capacity of vitamin D in MS remain to be answered. In particular, available clinical data derived from interventional trials using vitamin D supplementation as a therapeutic approach in MS are inconclusive and partly contradictory. In this review, we summarise and critically evaluate the existing data on the possible link between vitamin D and multiple sclerosis in light of the crucial question whether optimization of vitamin D status may impact the risk and/or the course of multiple sclerosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If low level of Vitamin A then 60 percent less likely to get MS (maybe Vitamin D not blocked)</title><link>/posts/if-low-level-of-vitamin-a-then-60-percent-less-likely-to-get-ms-maybe-vitamin-d-not-blocked.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-low-level-of-vitamin-a-then-60-percent-less-likely-to-get-ms-maybe-vitamin-d-not-blocked.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-a-and-systemic-inflammation-as-protective-factors-in-multiple-sclerosis">Vitamin A and systemic inflammation as protective factors in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mult Scler January 18, 2013 1352458512472752&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jonatan Salzer 1 ; Göran Hallmans 2; Maria Nyström 1; Hans Stenlund 2; Göran Wadell 3; Peter Sundström 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Pharmacology and Clinical Neuroscience, Section of Neurology at Umeå University, Sweden&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Public Health and Clinical Medicine, Umeå University, Sweden&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Clinical Microbiology, Umeå University, Sweden&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jonatan Salzer, Department of Pharmacology and Clinical Neuroscience, Section of Neurology at Umeå University, SE-90187 Umeå, Sweden. Email: &lt;a href="mailto:jonatan.salzer@neuro.umu.se">jonatan.salzer@neuro.umu.se&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D prevents multiple sclerosis through multiple mechanisms</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-prevents-multiple-sclerosis-through-multiple-mechanisms.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-prevents-multiple-sclerosis-through-multiple-mechanisms.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="contribution-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency-to-the-pathogenesis-of-multiple-sclerosis">Contribution of vitamin D insufficiency to the pathogenesis of multiple sclerosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Therapeutic Advances in Neurological Disorders January 23, 2013 1756285612473513&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charles Pierrot-Deseilligny &lt;a href="mailto:cp.deseilligny@psl.aphp.fr">cp.deseilligny@psl.aphp.fr&lt;/a>, Université Pierre et Marie Curie (Paris VI), Paris, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jean-Claude Souberbielle. Université René Descartes (Paris V), Paris, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The contribution of vitamin D insufficiency to the pathogenesis of multiple sclerosis (MS) is reviewed. Among the multiple recently discovered actions of vitamin D, an immunomodulatory role has been documented in experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis and in humans.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis more likely if mother had less than 25 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-more-likely-if-mother-had-less-than-25-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-more-likely-if-mother-had-less-than-25-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-as-a-protective-factor-in-multiple-sclerosis">Vitamin D as a protective factor in multiple sclerosis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Salzer J, Hallmans G, Nyström M, Stenlund H, Wadell G, Sundström P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neurology. 2012 Nov 20;79(21):2140-5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182752ea8.">doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182752ea8.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pharmacology and Clinical Neuroscience, Section of Neurology, Umeå University, Umeå, Sweden. &lt;a href="mailto:jonatan.salzer@neuro.umu.se">jonatan.salzer@neuro.umu.se&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To examine the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels and the risk of multiple sclerosis (MS) in blood samples collected prospectively and during gestation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: In this nested case-control study, 2 population-based biobanks with 291,500 samples from 164,000 persons collected since 1975 in the northern half of Sweden were used. We identified prospectively collected blood samples from MS cases (n = 192, controls matched 2:1) and gestational samples from pregnant mothers where the offspring had later developed MS (n = 37, control mothers matched 5:1). 25(OH)D levels were measured using an ELISA, and the risk of MS was analyzed using matched logistic regression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis and vitamin D – Systematic Review inconclusive</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-and-vitamin-d-systematic-review-inconclusive.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-and-vitamin-d-systematic-review-inconclusive.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-systematic-review-of-randomized-double-blind-placebo-controlled-trials-examining-the-clinical-efficacy-of-vitamin-d-in-multiple-sclerosis">A Systematic Review of Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Trials Examining the Clinical Efficacy of Vitamin D in Multiple Sclerosis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Neuro-epidemiology Vol. 40, No. 3, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beatriz Pozuelo-Moyanoa, c, Julián Benito-Leóna –c &lt;a href="mailto:jbenitol@meditex.es">jbenitol@meditex.es&lt;/a>, Alex J. Mitchelld, Jesús Hernández-Gallegoa, c&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Department of Neurology, University Hospital ‘12 de Octubre’,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Centro de Investigación Biomédica en Red sobre Enfermedades Neurodegenerativas, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Department of Medicine, Complutense University, Madrid, Spain;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D Department of Psycho-Oncology, Leicestershire Partnership Trust and University of Leicester, Leicester, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Risk of going from pre-MS to MS reduced 68 percent with 7100 IU vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/risk-of-going-from-pre-ms-to-ms-reduced-68-percent-with-7100-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/risk-of-going-from-pre-ms-to-ms-reduced-68-percent-with-7100-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#preventive-effect-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation-on-conversion-of-optic-neuritis-to-clinically-definite-multiple-sclerosis---a-double-blind-randomized-placebo-controlled-pilot-clinical-trial">Preventive effect of vitamin D3 supplementation on conversion of optic neuritis to clinically definite multiple sclerosis: - a double blind, randomized, placebo-controlled pilot clinical trial.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#strong-evidence--vitamin-d-prevents-ms-and-reduces-ms-symptoms">Strong evidence: Vitamin D PREVENTS MS and REDUCES MS symptoms&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#85-citations-of-this-study-as-of-june-2024">85 citations of this study as of June 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="preventive-effect-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation-on-conversion-of-optic-neuritis-to-clinically-definite-multiple-sclerosis---a-double-blind-randomized-placebo-controlled-pilot-clinical-trial">Preventive effect of vitamin D3 supplementation on conversion of optic neuritis to clinically definite multiple sclerosis: - a double blind, randomized, placebo-controlled pilot clinical trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Neurol Belg. 2012 Dec 19.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D less than 3000 IU insufficient to reduce MS relapse rate – 5 RCT</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-3000-iu-insufficient-to-reduce-ms-relapse-rate-5-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-3000-iu-insufficient-to-reduce-ms-relapse-rate-5-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-ms-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 691">Overview MS and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>often 5,000 IU to 10,000 IU&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D can both prevent and treat Multiple Sclerosis – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-can-both-prevent-and-treat-multiple-sclerosis-review.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-can-both-prevent-and-treat-multiple-sclerosis-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="role-of-vitamin-d-in-the-onset-progression-and-severity-of-multiple-sclerosis">Role of Vitamin D in the Onset, Progression and Severity of Multiple Sclerosis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2012 Nov 27:1-22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mesliniene S, Ramrattan L, Giddings S, Sheikh-Ali M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, University of Florida College of Medicine-Jacksonville, Jacksonville, Florida.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To review and assess the role of vitamin D on the onset, progression and relapse of multiple sclerosis (MS), based on evidence acquired from the analysis of preclinical, observational and interventional studies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis of Autoimmunity which includes Epstein-Barr Virus and Vitamin D Deficiency – 2012</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-of-autoimmunity-which-includes-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-of-autoimmunity-which-includes-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cd8-t-cell-deficiency-epstein-barr-virus-infection-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-steps-to-autoimmunity-a-unifying-hypothesis">CD8+ T-Cell Deficiency, Epstein-Barr Virus Infection, Vitamin D Deficiency, and Steps to Autoimmunity: A Unifying Hypothesis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmune Diseases, Volume 2012 (2012), Article ID 189096, 16 pages, Review Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael P. Pender 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Medicine, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD 4072, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Brisbane, QLD 4029, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 18 August 2011; Revised 3 October 2011; Accepted 16 October 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Academic Editor: Corrado Betterle&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Autoimmune diseases, solar radiation and vitamin D – Schwalfenberg 2012</title><link>/posts/review-of-autoimmune-diseases-solar-radiation-and-vitamin-d-schwalfenberg-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-autoimmune-diseases-solar-radiation-and-vitamin-d-schwalfenberg-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="solar-radiation-and-vitamin-d-mitigating-environmental-factors-in-autoimmune-disease">Solar Radiation and Vitamin D: Mitigating Environmental Factors in Autoimmune Disease&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Environmental and Public Health, Volume 2012 (2012), Article ID 619381, 9 pages, Review Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gerry K. Schwalfenberg&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Family Medicine, University of Alberta, Suite No. 301, 9509-156 Street, Edmonton, AB, Canada T6G 2M7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 3 July 2011; Revised 29 November 2011; Accepted 13 December 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This paper looks at the environmental role of vitamin D and solar radiation as risk reduction factors in autoimmune disease. Five diseases are considered: multiple sclerosis, type 1 diabetes, rheumatoid arthritis, autoimmune disease of the thyroid, and inflammatory bowel disease. Clinical relevant studies and factors that may indicate evidence that autoimmune disease is a vitamin D-sensitive disease are presented. Studies that have resulted in prevention or amelioration of some autoimmune disease are discussed. An example of the utility of supplementing vitamin D in an unusual autoimmune disease, idiopathic thrombocytic purpura, is presented.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Transgeneration vitamin D deficiency related to MS was found in mice</title><link>/posts/transgeneration-vitamin-d-deficiency-related-to-ms-was-found-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/transgeneration-vitamin-d-deficiency-related-to-ms-was-found-in-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prenatal-vitamin-d-deficiency-induces-an-early-and-more-severe-experimental-autoimmune-encephalomyelitis-in-the-second-generation">Prenatal Vitamin D Deficiency Induces an Early and More Severe Experimental Autoimmune Encephalomyelitis in the Second Generation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2012, 13(9), 10911-10919; doi:10.3390/ijms130910911&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diana Andrea Fernandes de Abreu 1 , Véréna Landel 1 , Adrian G. Barnett 2 , John McGrath 3,4 , Darryl Eyles 3,4 and Francois Feron 1,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Neurobiology of Cell Interactions and Neurophysiopathology, Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, UMR 7259, Aix Marseille Université, Marseille 13015, France&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epigenetics, vitamin D, and Multiple Sclerosis</title><link>/posts/epigenetics-vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/epigenetics-vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epigenetic-changes-in-patients-with-multiple-sclerosis---nov-2012">Epigenetic changes in patients with multiple sclerosis - Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epigenetics---is-it-real-new-york-times-review-of-plos-genetics-article---july-2016">Epigenetics - is it real: New York Times review of PLOS Genetics article - July 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="epigenetic-changes-in-patients-with-multiple-sclerosis---nov-2012">Epigenetic changes in patients with multiple sclerosis - Nov 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Neurol. 2012 Nov 20. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2012.226.">doi: 10.1038/nrneurol.2012.226.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Koch MW, Metz LM, Kovalchuk O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Calgary, Foothills Hospital, 1403-29th Street N. W., Calgary, AB T2N 2T9, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epigenetic changes influence gene expression without altering the DNA sequence. DNA methylation, histone modification and microRNA-associated post-transcriptional gene silencing are three key epigenetic mechanisms. Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a disease of the CNS with both inflammatory and neurodegenerative features. Although studies on epigenetic changes in MS only began in the past decade, a growing body of literature suggests that epigenetic changes may be involved in the development of MS, possibly by mediating the effects of environmental risk factors, such as&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ms-associations-with-autoimmune-33-uv-21-genetics-20-intervention-18-parkinson-15-high-dose-15-cognitive-14-pregnancy-11-receptor-10-lupus-9-ra-9-omega-9-virus-9-immunity-7-psoriasis-7-diabetes-6-gut-6-etc">MS associations with: Autoimmune 33; UV 21; Genetics 20; Intervention 18; Parkinson 15; High-Dose 15; Cognitive 14; Pregnancy 11; Receptor 10; Lupus 9; RA 9; Omega 9; Virus 9; Immunity 7; Psoriasis 7; Diabetes 6; Gut 6 etc.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="ms-associations-with-autoimmune-33-uv-21-genetics-20-intervention-18-parkinson-15-high-dose-15-cognitive-14-pregnancy-11-receptor-10-lupus-9-ra-9-omega-9-virus-9-immunity-7-psoriasis-7-diabetes-6-gut-6-etc">MS associations with: Autoimmune 33; UV 21; Genetics 20; Intervention 18; Parkinson 15; High-Dose 15; Cognitive 14; Pregnancy 11; Receptor 10; Lupus 9; RA 9; Omega 9; Virus 9; Immunity 7; Psoriasis 7; Diabetes 6; Gut 6 etc.&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis 23 percent more likely if born in April vs. Oct – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-23-percent-more-likely-if-born-in-april-vs-oct-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-23-percent-more-likely-if-born-in-april-vs-oct-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-month-of-birth-effect-in-multiple-sclerosis-systematic-review-meta-analysis-and-effect-of-latitude">The month of birth effect in multiple sclerosis: systematic review, meta-analysis and effect of latitude&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry doi:10.1136/jnnp-2012-303934&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ruth Dobson1, Gavin Giovannoni1, Sreeram Ramagopalan1,2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Queen Mary University of London, Blizard Institute, Barts and the London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Wellcome Trust Centre for Human Genetics, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Clinical Neurology, John Radcliffe Hospital, Oxford, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence to: Dr Ruth Dobson, Queen Mary University of London, Blizard Institute, Newark Street, London E1 2AT; &lt;a href="mailto:ruth.dobson@qmul.ac.uk">ruth.dobson@qmul.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Environmental risk factors for MS include latitude and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/environmental-risk-factors-for-ms-include-latitude-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/environmental-risk-factors-for-ms-include-latitude-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="environmental-risk-factors-for-multiple-sclerosis-a-review-with-a-focus-on-molecular-mechanisms">Environmental Risk Factors for Multiple Sclerosis: A Review with a Focus on Molecular Mechanisms&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Mol Sci. 2012; 13(9): 11718–11752.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cullen O’Gorman,1,* Robyn Lucas,2 and Bruce Taylor 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Medicine, Griffith University, Gold Coast, Queensland 4222, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 National Centre for Epidemiology and Population Health, the Australian National University, Canberra, Australian Capital Territory 0200, Australia; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:robyn.lucas@anu.edu.au">robyn.lucas@anu.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Menzies Research Institute Tasmania, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Tasmania 7000, Australia; E-Mail: &lt;a href="mailto:bruce.taylor@utas.edu.au">bruce.taylor@utas.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D enabled a woman with MS to walk long distances again</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-enabled-a-woman-with-ms-to-walk-long-distances-again.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-enabled-a-woman-with-ms-to-walk-long-distances-again.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effect-of-high-dose-vitamin-d3-intake-on-ambulation-muscular-pain-and-bone-mineral-density">Effect of High-Dose Vitamin D3 Intake on Ambulation, Muscular Pain and Bone Mineral Density&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="in-a-woman-with-multiple-sclerosis-a-10-year-longitudinal-case-report">in a Woman with Multiple Sclerosis: A 10-Year Longitudinal Case Report&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2012, 13(10), 13461-13483; doi:10.3390/ijms131013461&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara M. van Amerongen 1,2, &lt;a href="mailto:b.m.van.amerongen@inter.nl.net">b.m.van.amerongen@inter.nl.net&lt;/a> and François Feron 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Molecular Cell Biology and Immunology, VU University Medical Center,1017 MB Amsterdam, The Netherlands&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Cariology Endodontology Pedodontology, Academic Centre for Dentistry, 1081 LA Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less MS (MRI) decline after raising Vitamin D levels – clinical trial</title><link>/posts/less-ms-mri-decline-after-raising-vitamin-d-levels-clinical-trial.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-ms-mri-decline-after-raising-vitamin-d-levels-clinical-trial.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis-an-interview-with-ellen-mowryhttpwwwnews-medicalnetnews20121031vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis-an-interview-with-ellen-mowryaspx-news-medicalnet">&lt;a href="http://www.news-medical.net/news/20121031/Vitamin-D-and-multiple-sclerosis-an-interview-with-Ellen-Mowry.aspx">Vitamin D and multiple sclerosis: an interview with Ellen Mowry&lt;/a> news Medical.Net&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Excellent interview&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tracked 469 people with MS for 5 years&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Higher vitamin D was associated with fewer MS spots on MRI the next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-predicts-new-brain-magnetic-resonance-imaging-activity-in-multiple-sclerosis">Vitamin D status predicts new brain magnetic resonance imaging activity in multiple sclerosis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Neurol. 2012 Aug;72(2):234-40. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.23591.">doi: 10.1002/ana.23591.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mowry EM, Waubant E, McCulloch CE, Okuda DT, Evangelista AA, Lincoln RR, Gourraud PA, Brenneman D, Owen MC, Qualley P, Bucci M, Hauser SL, Pelletier D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unsaturated Fatty acids important for both MS and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/unsaturated-fatty-acids-important-for-both-ms-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/unsaturated-fatty-acids-important-for-both-ms-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis not helped with half a microgram of calcitriol – 2012</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-not-helped-with-half-a-microgram-of-calcitriol-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-not-helped-with-half-a-microgram-of-calcitriol-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-adjunct-low-dose-vitamin-d-on-relapsing-remitting-multiple-sclerosis-progression-preliminary-findings-of-a-randomized-placebo-controlled-trial">Effects of Adjunct Low-Dose Vitamin D on Relapsing-Remitting Multiple Sclerosis Progression: !!Preliminary Findings of a Randomized Placebo-Controlled Trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Multiple Sclerosis International, Volume 2012 (2012), Article ID 452541, 7 pages&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vahid Shaygannejad,1 Mohsen Janghorbani,2 Fereshteh Ashtari,1 and Hamed Dehghan1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Neurology, Isfahan Neurosciences Research Center, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan 8144503500, Iran&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan 8144503500, Iran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is the Iranian Revolution to Blame for the Increasing Incidence of Multiple Sclerosis in Iran</title><link>/posts/is-the-iranian-revolution-to-blame-for-the-increasing-incidence-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-iran.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-the-iranian-revolution-to-blame-for-the-increasing-incidence-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-iran.html</guid><description>&lt;p>There are two items on this page&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="multiple-sclerosis-and-the-iranian-revolution">MULTIPLE SCLEROSIS AND THE IRANIAN REVOLUTION&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2013;84:e2 doi:10.1136/jnnp-2013-306573.185&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Association of British Neurologists (ABN) joint meeting with the Royal College of Physicians (RCP), London, 23–24 October 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Julia Pakpoor⇓,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sreeram Ramagopalan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Oxford; Barts and the London School of Medicine and Dentistry&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiple Sclerosis (MS) is a complex neurological disorder most likely caused by gene–environment interactions. There is a latitudinal gradient of MS prevalence and vitamin D deficiency has been strongly implicated in MS aetiology. Iran is a country of high levels of sunshine which has previously been considered a low–risk MS region. However, Iran has recently observed an &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">8.3–fold rise in the incidence of MS between 1989–2006&lt;/span>.&lt;/strong> 1 Previous studies have indicated a genetic predisposition to MS in the Iranian population but genetic changes are unlikely to account for the substantial rise in MS over the last few decades. Thus, we aimed to develop a novel hypothesis to explain the identification of Iran as a high–risk MS region. We believe that the influence of decreased sunshine exposure and vitamin D levels on MS risk needs to be strongly considered in the context of Iran&amp;rsquo;s history. In 1979 the Iranian Revolution took place and a country previously under great Western influences became an Islamic republic. It became a government requirement for women to wear loose–fitting clothing and the veil in public; it has previously been shown that veiled women have lower vitamin D levels compared to unveiled women. This significant cultural shift would not only potentially explain the observed increase in MS but notably, it would account for the increasing female preponderance of MS in Iran. Given that the average age of MS onset is 30 years old and that MS incidence in Iran just over 30 years following the revolution is the highest so far recorded, an association with the Iranian revolution and reduced subsequent vitamin D levels in particularly pregnant women is likely. Lifestyle changes such as urbanization and use of sunscreen may to some extent have contributed to increased vitamin D deficiency, but these are unlikely to contribute to the particularly high increase in MS observed in Iran as these changes occurred across the developed world and there is no evidence to suggest that they were particularly great in Iran. &lt;strong>A similar high incidence of MS has been observed among Iranian immigrants in countries at high latitude such as Sweden&lt;/strong> where Iranian immigrants have a reported greater prevalence of MS compared to the general population, &lt;strong>despite wearing a veil not being a requirement.&lt;/strong> Instead it is well–known that UVB exposure is lower in countries at high latitude and thus, a similar effect of increased MS incidence due to vitamin D deficiency may be observed among those in Iran wearing the veil and those resident in countries at high latitude, even if they are not wearing the veil. Therefore, vitamin D repletion is a critical public health issue for Iranians both within and outside Iran, and could help prevent an emerging MS epidemic in this population. More generally, this region is highly interesting for MS research and highlights that regions of exception to the latitudinal gradient of MS prevalence are an under–appreciated and very useful resource in evaluating MS aetiology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS helped by average daily 2800 IU vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/ms-helped-by-average-daily-2800-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-helped-by-average-daily-2800-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Neurology J. had 4 items on Multiple Sclerosis and Vitamin D – review by MS Soc</title><link>/posts/neurology-j-had-4-items-on-multiple-sclerosis-and-vitamin-d-review-by-ms-soc.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/neurology-j-had-4-items-on-multiple-sclerosis-and-vitamin-d-review-by-ms-soc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>2900 IU of vitamin D (20000 weekly) kept levels above 20 ng during the winter</title><link>/posts/2900-iu-of-vitamin-d-20000-weekly-kept-levels-above-20-ng-during-the-winter.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2900-iu-of-vitamin-d-20000-weekly-kept-levels-above-20-ng-during-the-winter.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="what-is-needed-to-keep-persons-with-multiple-sclerosis-vitamin-d-sufficient-throughout-the-year">What is needed to keep persons with multiple sclerosis vitamin D-sufficient throughout the year?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Neurol. 2012 Aug 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Steffensen LH, Brustad M, Kampman MT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, University Hospital of North Norway, P.O. Box 33, 9038, Tromsø, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:linn.hofsoy.steffensen@unn.no">linn.hofsoy.steffensen@unn.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D sufficiency has been associated with lower risk of multiple sclerosis and may also have a favorable effect on the course of the disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this work was to identify predictors of serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels in persons with multiple sclerosis (MS) and to assess the effect of high-dose vitamin D(3) supplementation on vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X more vitamin D from the sun if take MS drug Interferon-β</title><link>/posts/3x-more-vitamin-d-from-the-sun-if-take-ms-drug-interferon.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-more-vitamin-d-from-the-sun-if-take-ms-drug-interferon.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis not affected by 2800 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-not-affected-by-2800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-not-affected-by-2800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces multiple sclerosis relapses, but not with interferon treatment</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-multiple-sclerosis-relapses-but-not-with-interferon-treatment.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-multiple-sclerosis-relapses-but-not-with-interferon-treatment.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="two-publications-on-this-page-by-similar-set-of-authors">Two publications on this page by similar set of authors&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-disease-activity-in-multiple-sclerosis-before-and-during-interferon--treatment">Vitamin D and disease activity in multiple sclerosis before and during interferon-? treatment&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Neurology June 12, 2012, 78 (24)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kristin I. Løken-Amsrud, MD, Trygve Holmøy, PhD, Søren J. Bakke, PhD, Antonie Giaever Beiske, PhD, Kristian S. Bjerve, PhD, Bård T. Bjørnarå, PhD, Harald Hovdal, MD, Finn Lilleås, PhD, Rune Midgard, PhD, Tom Pedersen, PhD, Jurate Šaltyt? Benth, PhD, Leiv Sandvik, PhD, Øivind Torkildsen, PhD, Stig Wergeland, MD and Kjell-Morten Myhr, PhD&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS clinical trial (EVIDIMS) to use 10,000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ms-clinical-trial-evidims-to-use-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-clinical-trial-evidims-to-use-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="efficacy-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-multiple-sclerosis-evidims-trial-study-protocol-for-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Efficacy of vitamin D supplementation in multiple sclerosis (EVIDIMS Trial): study protocol for a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Trials. 2012 Feb 8;13:15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dörr J, Ohlraun S, Skarabis H, Paul F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NeuroCure Clinical Research Center, Charité - Universitätsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany. &lt;a href="mailto:jan-markus.doerr@charite.de">jan-markus.doerr@charite.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Multiple sclerosis is the most common chronic inflammatory disease of the central nervous system in young adults. Despite the fact that numerous lines of evidence link both the risk of disease development and the disease course to the serum level of 25-hydroxyvitamin D it still remains elusive whether multiple sclerosis patients benefit from boosting the serum level of 25-hydroxyvitamin D, mainly because interventional clinical trials that directly address the therapeutic effects of vitamin D in multiple sclerosis are sparse. We here present the protocol of an interventional clinical phase II study to test the hypothesis, that high-dose vitamin D supplementation of multiple sclerosis patients is safe and superior to low-dose supplementation with respect to beneficial therapeutic effects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS relapse rate reduced 14 percent for each 4 ng increase in vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ms-relapse-rate-reduced-14-percent-for-each-4-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-relapse-rate-reduced-14-percent-for-each-4-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="relationship-between-25-oh-d-serum-level-and-relapse-rate-in-multiple-sclerosis-patients">Relationship between 25-OH-D serum level and relapse rate in multiple sclerosis patients&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="before-and-after-vitamin-d-supplementation">before and after vitamin D supplementation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Therapeutic Advances in Neurological Disorders May 17, 2012 1756285612447090&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charles Pierrot-Deseilligny &lt;a href="mailto:cp.deseilligny@psl.aphp.fr">cp.deseilligny@psl.aphp.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Service de Neurologie 1, Hôpital de la Salpêtrière, Assistance Publique-Hôpitaux de Paris, Université Pierre et Marie Curie (Paris VI), Paris, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sophie Rivaud-Péchoux: INSERM URMS 975, CNRS 7225, Université Pierre et Marie Curie (Paris VI), Paris, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pierre Clerson: Orgamétrie biostatistiques, Roubaix, France&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hispanics with MS had lower levels of vitamin D which did not vary seasonally</title><link>/posts/hispanics-with-ms-had-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d-which-did-not-vary-seasonally.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hispanics-with-ms-had-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d-which-did-not-vary-seasonally.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-levels-in-hispanics-with-multiple-sclerosis">Vitamin D levels in Hispanics with multiple sclerosis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Neurol. 2012 May 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amezcua L, Chung RH, Conti DV, Langer-Gould AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Keck School of Medicine, University of Southern California (USC), Los Angeles, CA, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:lamezcua@usc.edu">lamezcua@usc.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has been associated with multiple sclerosis (MS) and several markers of disease state in whites. There are limited reports of vitamin D&amp;rsquo;s influence in MS in ethnic groups, such as in Hispanics. In this study, we compared vitamin D levels in Hispanics and whites with MS and tried to determine whether season or increasing disability influence hypovitaminosis D in Hispanics with MS. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and clinical characteristics were compared in a cross-sectional sample of Hispanics (n = 80) and whites (n = 80) with MS recruited from the University of Southern California. Serum 25(OH)D levels were significantly lower in Hispanics than whites with MS (mean and standard deviation 25.1 ± 9.4 and 37.3 ± 19.8 ng/ml, respectively; p &amp;lt; 0.001). Hispanics were significantly more likely than whites to be vitamin D insufficient (?30 ng/ml; 70 vs. 41 %, respectively; p &amp;lt; 0.001) and deficient (?20 ng/ml; 40 vs. 14 %, respectively, p &amp;lt; 0.001). In Hispanics, serum 25(OH)D levels were not influenced by season (p = 0.8) or higher physical disability (EDSS ?6, p = 0.7). We found that the relationship between vitamin D and MS differs by Hispanic ethnicity. Hypovitaminosis D was significantly more common among Hispanics than among whites with MS, and the majority of Hispanics were vitamin D insufficient. Interestingly, there was no association between vitamin D levels and season or increasing disability in the Hispanics. Our findings imply that factors influencing vitamin D levels and possibly vitamin D requirements may vary by ethnicity in patients with MS. These results should be confirmed in larger, prospective multi-ethnic cohort studies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5000 to 10000 IU vitamin D helped MS in a pilot study</title><link>/posts/5000-to-10000-iu-vitamin-d-helped-ms-in-a-pilot-study.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5000-to-10000-iu-vitamin-d-helped-ms-in-a-pilot-study.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-pilot-study-of-the-immunological-effects-of-high-dose-vitamin-d-in-healthy-volunteers">A pilot study of the immunological effects of high-dose vitamin D in healthy volunteers.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Mult Scler. 2012 Mar 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Allen AC, Kelly S, Basdeo SA, Kinsella K, Mulready KJ, Mills KH, Tubridy N, Walsh C, Brady JJ, Hutchinson M, Fletcher JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Biochemistry and Immunology, Trinity Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although vitamin D deficiency is considered an environmental factor in multiple sclerosis (MS), the immunological and clinical effects of vitamin D supplementation remain unclear.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MRI detects 32% less of one type of MS lesion for every 10 ng increased vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mri-detects-32-percent-less-of-one-type-of-ms-lesion-for-every-10-ng-increased-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mri-detects-32-percent-less-of-one-type-of-ms-lesion-for-every-10-ng-increased-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-predicts-new-brain-mri-activity-in-multiple-sclerosis">Vitamin D status predicts new brain MRI activity in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ellen M. Mowry M.D., M.C.R1,†,‡, &lt;a href="mailto:emowry1@jhmi.edu">emowry1@jhmi.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emmanuelle Waubant M.D., Ph.D1,‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charles E. McCulloch Ph.D2,‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Darin T. Okuda M.D3,‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alan A. Evangelista1,‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robin R. Lincoln B.S1,‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pierre-Antoine Gourraud Ph.D1,‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don Brenneman B.A1,‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary C. Owen N.P1,‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pamela Qualley M.A1,‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Monica Bucci M.D4,5,‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen L. Hauser M.D1,‡,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daniel Pelletier M.D1,6,‡,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 MS Center, Department of Neurology, University of California, San Francisco, San Francisco, CA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS Factoids</title><link>/posts/ms-factoids.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-factoids.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="general-information-about-multiple-sclerosishttpwwwthemcfoxcommultiple-sclerosisms-factsmultiple-sclerosis-factshtm-from-the-mc-foxcom">&lt;a href="http://www.themcfox.com/multiple-sclerosis/ms-facts/multiple-sclerosis-facts.htm">General Information about Multiple Sclerosis&lt;/a> from the MC Fox.com&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="notelow-vitamin-d-increases-probability-of-ms-which-lowers-vitamin-d-levels-even-more--span-stylecolor00fvitamin-d-related-items-are-marked-in-bluespan-">(Note:low vitamin D increases probability of MS which lowers vitamin D levels even more. &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Vitamin D related items are marked in blue&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> )&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>First Diagnosed in 1849&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The earliest known description of a person with possible Multiple Sclerosis dates from 14th century Holland&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Multiple Sclerosis is the most common progressive and disabling neurological condition in young adults&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Approx 2.5 million people worldwide, have Multiple Sclerosis&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Will 10000 IU of vitamin D decrease MS - RCT</title><link>/posts/will-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-decrease-ms-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/will-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-decrease-ms-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>MS prevention by UV is 2X better than prevention by vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/ms-prevention-by-uv-is-2x-better-than-prevention-by-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-prevention-by-uv-is-2x-better-than-prevention-by-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sunlight-is-associated-with-decreased-multiple-sclerosis-risk-no-interaction-with-human-leukocyte-antigen-drb115">Sunlight is associated with decreased multiple sclerosis risk: no interaction with human leukocyte antigen-DRB1*15.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Neurol. 2012 Jan 31. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2011.03650.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1468-1331.2011.03650.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bäärnhielm M, Hedström AK, Kockum I, Sundqvist E, Gustafsson SA, Hillert J, Olsson T, Alfredsson L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Environmental Medicine, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm Department of Clinical Neuroscience and Center for Molecular Medicine, Karolinska Institutet at Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm Department of Molecular Medicine and Surgery, Karolinska Institutet at Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased vitamin D should increase MS quality of life</title><link>/posts/increased-vitamin-d-should-increase-ms-quality-of-life.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-vitamin-d-should-increase-ms-quality-of-life.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-in-multiple-sclerosis-are-there-any-correlations-with-the-health-related-quality-of-life">Vitamin D status in multiple sclerosis: Are there any correlations with the health related quality of life&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Neurology, Psychiatry and Brain Research&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 18, Issue 1, January 2012, Pages 8–14&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ayse Kutlua, &lt;a href="mailto:draysekutlu@yahoo.com">draysekutlu@yahoo.com&lt;/a> , Gözde D. Görürb, Hüsnü Efendia, Halil Ünalanc, Sezer ?ener Komsuo?lua&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Kocaeli University, Faculty of Medicine, Department of Neurology, Kocaeli, Turkey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Kocaeli University, Faculty of Medicine, Department of Nuclear Medicine, Kocaeli, Turkey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c Istanbul University, Faculty of Medicine, Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Istanbul, Turkey&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Infectious mononucleosis and lack of UV linearly linked to MS in England</title><link>/posts/infectious-mononucleosis-and-lack-of-uv-linearly-linked-to-ms-in-england.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/infectious-mononucleosis-and-lack-of-uv-linearly-linked-to-ms-in-england.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="relationship-of-uv-exposure-to-prevalence-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-england">Relationship of UV exposure to prevalence of multiple sclerosis in England&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Neurology. 2011 April 19; 76(16): 1410–1414. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e318216715e">doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e318216715e&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S.V. Ramagopalan, DPhil, A.E. Handel, BMBCh, G. Giovannoni, MD, S. Rutherford Siegel, PhD, G.C. Ebers, MD, FMedSci, &lt;a href="mailto:george.ebers@clneuro.ox.ac.uk">george.ebers@clneuro.ox.ac.uk&lt;/a> and G. Chaplin, MS &lt;a href="mailto:guc5@psu.edu">guc5@psu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Wellcome Trust Centre for Human Genetics (S.V.R., A.E.H., G.C.E.) and Department of Clinical Neurology (S.V.R., A.E.H., G.C.E.), University of Oxford, Oxford; Blizard Institute of Cell and Molecular Science (S.V.R., G.G.), Queen Mary University of London, Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London, UK; and Department of Anthropology (S.R.S., G.C.), The Pennsylvania State University, Philadelphia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mutation of Vitamin D gene (CYP27B1) is strongly tied to MS</title><link>/posts/mutation-of-vitamin-d-gene-cyp27b1-is-strongly-tied-to-ms.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mutation-of-vitamin-d-gene-cyp27b1-is-strongly-tied-to-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The researchers looked for the gene variant in more than 3,000 families of unaffected parents with a child with MS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and found 35 parents who carried one copy of this variant along with one normal copy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In every one of these 35 cases, their child with MS had inherited the mutated version of the gene.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The likelihood of this gene’s transmission being unconnected to the MS is billion to one against&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is hot in MS research</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-hot-in-ms-research.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-hot-in-ms-research.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis-correlation-causality-and-controversy">Vitamin d and multiple sclerosis: correlation, causality, and controversy.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Autoimmune Dis. 2010 Oct 5;2011:629538.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Smolders J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Clinical and Experimental Immunology, Department of Internal Medicine and School for Mental Health and Neuroscience, Maastricht University Medical Center, Universiteitssingel 50, P.O. Box 616, 6200 MD Maastricht, The Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last years, many studies reported associations between correlates of vitamin D exposure and several correlates of multiple sclerosis (MS) disease activity. This review discusses studies on vitamin D status, Expanded Disability Status Scale (EDSS) score, and relapse activity of MS. Furthermore, several considerations for intervention studies on vitamin D supplementation in MS are provided.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS worse with Vitamin D2</title><link>/posts/ms-worse-with-vitamin-d2.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-worse-with-vitamin-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="multiple-sclerosis-and-vitamin-dhttpwwwneurologyorgcontent7717e99short">&lt;a href="http://www.neurology.org/content/77/17/e99.short">Multiple sclerosis and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="random-controlled-trial-with-6000-iu-of-vitamin-d2">Random controlled trial with 6,000 IU of vitamin D2&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While the high-dose group did reach higher levels of vitamin D, there were no significant differences between the groups in regard to MRI changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The high-dose group actually had significantly more relapses and worse disability than the low-dose group at the end of the study&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PDF is attached to the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/chance-of-a-fall-decreased-with-vitamin-d3-but-increased-with-d2">Chance of a fall decreased with vitamin D3 but increased with D2 – Oct 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why has the MS latitude gradient disappeared</title><link>/posts/why-has-the-ms-latitude-gradient-disappeared.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-has-the-ms-latitude-gradient-disappeared.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="why-does-the-northsouth-gradient-of-incidence-of-multiple-sclerosis-seem-to-have-disappeared-on-the-northern-hemisphere">Why does the north–south gradient of incidence of multiple sclerosis seem to have disappeared on the Northern hemisphere?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of the Neurological Sciences, doi:10.1016/j.jns.2011.09.003&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nils Koch-Henriksen a, b, Per Soelberg Sorensen c, &lt;a href="mailto:pss@rh.dk">pss@rh.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a	Department of Neurology, Aarhus University Hospital in Aalborg, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b	The Danish Multiple Sclerosis Registry, Neuroscience Centre, Copenhagen University Hospital Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c	Danish Multiple Sclerosis Center, University of Copenhagen and Department of Neurology, Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CureTogether Vitamin D symptoms, treatments, and causes</title><link>/posts/curetogether-vitamin-d-symptoms-treatments-and-causes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/curetogether-vitamin-d-symptoms-treatments-and-causes.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="curetogetherhttpcuretogethercomvitamin-d-deficiencysymptoms-is-an-excellent-source-on-100s-of-diseases">&lt;a href="http://curetogether.com/vitamin-d-deficiency/symptoms/">CureTogether&lt;/a> is an excellent source on 100&amp;rsquo;s of diseases&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostsspan-stylecolorf00click-herespan-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-4933span-stylecolorf00click-herespana-for-update-dec-2013">&lt;a href="/posts/span-stylecolorf00click-herespan" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 4933">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">CLICK HERE&lt;/span>&lt;/a> for update Dec 2013&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="snapshot-on-vitamin-d-oct-2011">Snapshot on Vitamin D Oct 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;809&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">The darker the blue the more severe: minimal, mild, moderate, severe, extreme &lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gray = not rated&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;810&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="chart-is-sorted-by-improvement-top--best">Chart is sorted by improvement: top = best&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="color:#090;">Light Green = Moderate improvement&lt;/span>; &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#090;">Dark green = major improvement&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> ; Gray = No effect&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning about MS and vitamin D in offspring from mice</title><link>/posts/learning-about-ms-and-vitamin-d-in-offspring-from-mice.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/learning-about-ms-and-vitamin-d-in-offspring-from-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="seasonal-gestational-and-postnatal-influences-on-multiple-sclerosis-the-beneficial-role-of-a-vitamin-d-supplementation-during-early-life">Seasonal, gestational and postnatal influences on multiple sclerosis: The beneficial role of a vitamin D supplementation during early life.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Neurol Sci. 2011 Sep 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fernandes de Abreu DA, Landel V, Féron F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is now strong evidence linking vitamin D, the steroid hormone of sunlight, and Multiple Sclerosis (MS).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two of the most intriguing findings are the season of birth and childhood sun exposure effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They both suggest that a vitamin D deficiency during these critical imprinting periods is a risk factor for MS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis etc. strongly associated with Epstein-Barr virus (and vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-etc-strongly-associated-with-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-etc-strongly-associated-with-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-epstein-barr-virus-and-endogenous-retroviruses-in-multiple-sclerosis---facts-and-hypotheses---march-2021">Vitamin D, Epstein-Barr virus, and endogenous retroviruses in multiple sclerosis - facts and hypotheses - March 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#evidence-for-the-role-of-a-virus-in-ms-httpswwwnationalmssocietyorgwhat-is-mswhat-causes-msviruses-national-ms-org-2021">&lt;a href="https://www.nationalmssociety.org/What-is-MS/What-Causes-MS/Viruses">Evidence for the role of a virus in MS &lt;/a> National MS Org 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epsteinbarr-virus-in-multiple-sclerosis-theory-and-emerging-immunotherapies---march-2020">Epstein–Barr Virus in Multiple Sclerosis: Theory and Emerging Immunotherapies - March 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-role-of-epstein-barr-virus-in-multiple-sclerosis">The role of Epstein-Barr virus in multiple sclerosis:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#exploring-the-effect-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation-on-the-anti-ebv-antibody-response-in-relapsing-remitting-multiple-sclerosis---2018">Exploring the effect of vitamin D3 supplementation on the anti-EBV antibody response in relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis - 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epstein-barr-virus-and-mononucleosis">Epstein-Barr Virus and Mononucleosis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#other-diseases-associated-with-epstein-barr-virus">Other diseases associated with Epstein-Barr Virus&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-epstein-barr-virus-and-endogenous-retroviruses-in-multiple-sclerosis---facts-and-hypotheses---march-2021">Vitamin D, Epstein-Barr virus, and endogenous retroviruses in multiple sclerosis - facts and hypotheses - March 2021&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Integr Neurosci. 2021 Mar 30;20(1):233-238. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.31083/j.jin.2021.01.392.">doi: 10.31083/j.jin.2021.01.392.&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>There is more in UV than vitamin D which suppresses MS in mice</title><link>/posts/there-is-more-in-uv-than-vitamin-d-which-suppresses-ms-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/there-is-more-in-uv-than-vitamin-d-which-suppresses-ms-in-mice.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>UV produces more than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/uv-produces-more-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-produces-more-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="modulation-of-the-immune-system-by-uv-radiation-more-than-just-the-effects-of-vitamin-d">Modulation of the immune system by UV radiation: more than just the effects of vitamin D?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Immunol. 2011 Aug 19. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nri3045.">doi: 10.1038/nri3045.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hart PH, Gorman S, Finlay-Jones JJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telethon Institute for Child Health Research, Centre for Child Health Research, University of Western Australia, PO Box 855, Perth, Western Australia 6872, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Humans obtain most of their vitamin D through the exposure of skin to sunlight. The immunoregulatory properties of vitamin D have been demonstrated in studies showing that vitamin D deficiency is associated with poor immune function and increased disease susceptibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS associated with 29 new and 23 previously known gene variants</title><link>/posts/ms-associated-with-29-new-and-23-previously-known-gene-variants.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-associated-with-29-new-and-23-previously-known-gene-variants.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Following press release is translated from German, and is followed by abstract&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="multiple-sclerosis-is-a-disease-of-the-immune-system">Multiple sclerosis is a disease of the immune system&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://translate.google.com/translate?js=n&amp;amp;prev=_t&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;layout=2&amp;amp;eotf=1&amp;amp;sl=de&amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fidw-online.de%2Fen%2Fnews436197%20">Press Release&lt;/a> Master of Business Administration (FH) Caroline Bahnemann&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Office of Communications and Press&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Medicine of the Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz; 08/10/2011 19:00&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International consortium of researchers found 29 new MS gene variants - involved researchers from Mainz&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scientists have identified &lt;strong>29 new genetic variants associated with disease multiple sclerosis&lt;/strong> . Many of the genes that were identified in the study belong to the immune system - so this is crucial in the development of the disease. Today the work of the international research consortium led by the Universities of Cambridge and Oxford in the &lt;strong>journal Nature&lt;/strong> , was published. It is the largest ever genetic study of multiple sclerosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decreased winter sun speeded up subsequent MS development 2X – VA</title><link>/posts/decreased-winter-sun-speeded-up-subsequent-ms-development-2x-va.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/decreased-winter-sun-speeded-up-subsequent-ms-development-2x-va.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="sun-exposure-vitamin-d-intake-and-progression-to-disability-among-veterans-with-progressive-multiple-sclerosis">Sun Exposure, Vitamin D Intake and Progression to Disability among Veterans with Progressive Multiple Sclerosis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Neuroepidemiology. 2011 Aug 5;37(1):52-57.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>McDowell TY, Amr S, Culpepper WJ, Langenberg P, Royal W, Bever C, Bradham DD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MS Center of Excellence-East, Baltimore VAMC, Baltimore, Md., USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Early life events have been suggested to influence multiple sclerosis (MS) susceptibility, and to potentially modulate its clinical course. We assessed vitamin D-related exposures from childhood to disease onset and their associations with MS progression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High vitamin D in moms decreased MS incidence in daughters by 40%</title><link>/posts/high-vitamin-d-in-moms-decreased-ms-incidence-in-daughters-by-40-percent.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-vitamin-d-in-moms-decreased-ms-incidence-in-daughters-by-40-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="gestational-vitamin-d-and-the-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-offspring">Gestational vitamin D and the risk of multiple sclerosis in offspring.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Neurol. 2011 Jul;70(1):30-40. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.22456.">doi: 10.1002/ana.22456.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mirzaei F, Michels KB, Munger K, O&amp;rsquo;Reilly E, Chitnis T, Forman MR, Giovannucci E, Rosner B, Ascherio A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutrition, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, MA; Department of Epidemiology, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, MA. &lt;a href="mailto:fmirzaei@hsph.harvard.edu">fmirzaei@hsph.harvard.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:Vitamin D may have a protective role in the etiology of multiple sclerosis (MS), but the effect of gestational vitamin D on adult onset MS has not been studied.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS new cases increased 2.5X in 2 years in Isfahan Iran</title><link>/posts/ms-new-cases-increased-25x-in-2-years-in-isfahan-iran.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-new-cases-increased-25x-in-2-years-in-isfahan-iran.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="sharp-increase-in-the-incidence-and-prevalence-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-isfahan-iran">Sharp increase in the incidence and prevalence of multiple sclerosis in Isfahan, Iran&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Masoud Etemadifar1,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amir-Hadi Maghzi1,2? &lt;a href="mailto:Maghzi@edc.mui.ac.ir">Maghzi@edc.mui.ac.ir&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Medical School, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Blizard Institute of Cell and Molecular Science, Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Neurology, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amir-Hadi Maghzi, Isfahan Research Committee of Multiple Sclerosis (IRCOMS), Multiple Sclerosis Clinic, Al-Zahra Hospital, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Soffeh Street, Isfahan 81744, Iran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X less Multiple Sclerosis with enough vitamin D - Veterans Administration</title><link>/posts/3x-less-multiple-sclerosis-with-enough-vitamin-d-veterans-administration.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-less-multiple-sclerosis-with-enough-vitamin-d-veterans-administration.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="it-appears-that-after-a-hrefpostsmuch-study-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1242much-studya-that-the-us-veterans-admin-has-decided-that-vitamin-d-does-indeed-help-ms">It appears that after &lt;a href="/posts/much-study" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1242">much study&lt;/a> that the US Veterans Admin. has decided that Vitamin D does indeed help MS&lt;/h4>
&lt;h5 id="the-va-multiple-sclerosis-center-of-excellencehttpwwwvagovmsvideo_multiple_sclerosis_and_vitamin_dasp-has-a-video-on-the-web-july-2011">The VA &lt;a href="http://www.va.gov/MS/video_multiple_sclerosis_and_vitamin_D.asp">Multiple Sclerosis Center of Excellence&lt;/a> has a video on the web July 2011&lt;/h5>
&lt;h4 id="the-25-minute-video-is-just-people-talking-but-has-the-following-graph">The 2.5 minute video is just people talking, but has the following graph&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>from an unknown study - perhaps in 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;638&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The horizontal axis shows the amount of vitamin D in the blood BEFORE getting MS&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yet again - more than 10000 IU of vitamin D treats MS</title><link>/posts/yet-again-more-than-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-treats-ms.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yet-again-more-than-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-treats-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="sunshine-vitamin-sheds-light-on-ms">Sunshine Vitamin Sheds Light on MS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://sciencemedicine.org/content/3/90/90ec102.short%20">Science Translational Medicine Home &amp;gt; 6 July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol. 3, Issue 90, p. 90ec102&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rebecca S. Boxer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Case Western Reserve University, School of Medicine, Cleveland, OH 44106, USA. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:Rebecca.Boxer@UHhospitals.org">Rebecca.Boxer@UHhospitals.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mother’s advice to get out into the sunshine may be better advice then many realize. Vitamin D, the sunshine vitamin, which is produced in skin exposed to ultraviolet (UVB) light, may have important down-regulatory effects on the inflammatory response in patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS reduces vitamin D which then causes osteoporosis</title><link>/posts/ms-reduces-vitamin-d-which-then-causes-osteoporosis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-reduces-vitamin-d-which-then-causes-osteoporosis.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="multiple-sclerosis-a-cause-of-secondary-osteoporosis-what-is-the-evidence-and-what-are-the-clinical-implications">Multiple sclerosis, a cause of secondary osteoporosis? What is the evidence and what are the clinical implications?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Acta Neurol Scand Suppl. 2011;(191):44-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0404.2011.01543.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0404.2011.01543.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kampman MT, Eriksen EF, Holmøy T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Clinical Research and Education, University Hospital of North Norway, Tromsø, Norway Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, Tromsø, Norway Department of Clinical Endocrinology, Oslo University Hospital, Aker, Oslo, Norway Department of Neurology, Akershus University Hospital, Nordbyhagen, Norway Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D patent for treating immune system diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wo2008039409httpwwwwipointpatentscopesearchenwo2008039409-world-wide-patent---2008">&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/WO2008039409">(WO2008039409)&lt;/a> World-Wide patent - 2008&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="treatment-and-prevention-of-diseases-or-conditions-of-the--immune-system-or-infectious-diseases">TREATMENT AND PREVENTION OF DISEASES OR CONDITIONS OF THE &lt;strong>IMMUNE SYSTEM OR INFECTIOUS DISEASES&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>allergic rhinitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eczema,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>psoriasis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>food allergy,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>type-1 diabetes,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>ulcerative colitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>rheumatoid arthritis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>multiple sclerosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>lupus,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>tuberculosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>parasitic infection, etc,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D targets 4 MS genes</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-targets-4-ms-genes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-targets-4-ms-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="genetics-and-the-environment-converge-to-dysregulate-n-glycosylation-in-multiple-sclerosis">Genetics and the environment converge to dysregulate N-glycosylation in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nature Communications, Article number: 334, doi:10.1038/ncomms1333&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Haik Mkhikian, Ani Grigorian, Carey F. Li, Hung-Lin Chen, Barbara Newton, Raymond W. Zhou, Christine Beeton, Sevan Torossian, Gevork Grikor Tatarian, Sung-Uk Lee, Ken Lau, Erin Walker, Katherine A. Siminovitch, K. George Chandy, Zhaoxia Yu, James W. Dennis. &lt;strong>Michael Demetriou&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="mailto:mdemetri@uci.edu">mdemetri@uci.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received – 02 February 2011, Accepted – 04 May 2011, Published – 31 May 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300000 IU vitamin D monthly may treat MS</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly-may-treat-ms.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly-may-treat-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="therapeutic-effect-of-vitamin-d3-in-multiple-sclerosis-patients">Therapeutic Effect of Vitamin D3 in Multiple Sclerosis Patients.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Immunol Invest. 2011 May 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mosayebi G, Ghazavi A, Ghasami K, Jand Y, Kokhaei P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Molecular and Medicine Research Center, Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Arak University of Medical Sciences, Arak, I.R. Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiple sclerosis (MS) is an inflammatory disease in which the myelin sheaths around the axons of the central nervous system are damaged. The damage leads to demyelination and scarring as well as a broad spectrum of signs and symptoms. The epidemiological data suggest a possible influence of vitamin D as an immunomodulatory agent on multiple sclerosis susceptibility as well as on clinical course of the disease. We investigated the effects of short-term vitamin D3 therapy on Iranian patients with MS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reduced vitamin D and BMD and Neurological Conditions</title><link>/posts/reduced-vitamin-d-and-bmd-and-neurological-conditions.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reduced-vitamin-d-and-bmd-and-neurological-conditions.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-mineral-density-in-adults-disabled-through-acquired-neurological-conditions-a-review">Bone Mineral Density in Adults Disabled Through Acquired Neurological Conditions: A Review&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Densitometry&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 14, Issue 2 , Pages 85-94, April 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone Mineral Density in Adults Disabled Through Acquired Neurological Conditions: A Review&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Áine Carroll&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 10 June 2010; received in revised form 12 December 2010; accepted 13 December 2010. published online 07 April 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article is a review of the changes in bone mineral density (BMD), which occur in a number of acquired neurological conditions resulting in disability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS is related to latitude – conclusion from 321 studies</title><link>/posts/ms-is-related-to-latitude-conclusion-from-321-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-is-related-to-latitude-conclusion-from-321-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="ms-is-significantly-associated-with-the-prevalence-of-multiple-sclerosis-a-meta-analysis">MS is significantly associated with the prevalence of multiple sclerosis: a meta-analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011 Apr 8. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simpson S Jr, Blizzard L, Otahal P, Van der Mei I, Taylor B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Menzies Research Institute Tasmania, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background There is a striking latitudinal gradient in multiple sclerosis (MS) prevalence, but exceptions in Mediterranean Europe and northern Scandinavia, and some systematic reviews, have suggested that the gradient may be an artefact. The authors sought to evaluate the association between MS prevalence and latitude by meta-regression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is a T-cell modulator in multiple sclerosis – April 2011.</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-a-t-cell-modulator-in-multiple-sclerosis-april-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-a-t-cell-modulator-in-multiple-sclerosis-april-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-as-a-t-cell-modulator-in-multiple-sclerosis">Vitamin D as a T-cell modulator in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Vitam Horm. 2011;86:401-28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Smolders J, Damoiseaux J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School for Mental Health and Neuroscience, Maastricht University Medical Center, Maastricht, The Netherlands; Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Clinical and Experimental Immunology, Maastricht University Medical Center, Maastricht, The Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a potent immune modulator, keeping the T-cell compartment in a more tolerogenic state. Multiple sclerosis (MS), a disease in which an autoreactive T-cell response contributes to inflammation in the central nervous system, has been associated with vitamin D deficiency. The effects of vitamin D on the immune system are believed to be an important driver of this association. In this chapter, we elaborate on vitamin D as a modulator of the T-cell response. This discussion will be placed in the perspective of MS as a T-cell-mediated disease and in the perspective of the numerous association studies on vitamin D deficiency and multiple health outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2800 IU vitamin D daily did not decrease bone loss for those with MS</title><link>/posts/2800-iu-vitamin-d-daily-did-not-decrease-bone-loss-for-those-with-ms.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2800-iu-vitamin-d-daily-did-not-decrease-bone-loss-for-those-with-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="can-vitamin-d3-supplementation-prevent-bone-loss-in-persons-with-ms-a-placebo-controlled-trial">Can vitamin D(3) supplementation prevent bone loss in persons with MS? A placebo-controlled trial.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Neurol. 2011 Mar 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Steffensen LH, Jørgensen L, Straume B, Mellgren SI, Kampman MT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, University Hospital of North Norway, Tromsø, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:linn.hofsoy.steffensen@unn.no">linn.hofsoy.steffensen@unn.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a possible cause of secondary osteoporosis. In this phase II trial we assessed whether a weekly dose of 20,000 IU vitamin D(3) prevents bone loss in ambulatory persons with MS age 18-50 years. ClinicalTrials.gov ID NCT00785473. All patients managed at the University Hospital of North Norway who fulfilled the main inclusion criteria were invited to participate in this double-blinded trial. Participants were randomised to receive &lt;strong>20,000 IU vitamin D(3) or placebo once a week&lt;/strong> and 500 mg calcium daily for 96 weeks. The primary outcome was the effect of the intervention on percentage change in bone mineral density (BMD) at the hip, the spine, and the ultradistal radius over the study period. Of 71 participants randomised, 68 completed. Mean serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels in the intervention group increased from 55 nmol/L at baseline to 123 nmol/L at week 96. After 96 weeks, percentage change in BMD did not differ between groups at any site. BMD decreased at the hip, by 1.4% in the placebo group (95% CI -2.3 to -0.4, SD 2.7, p = 0.006) and by 0.7% in the treatment group (-1.6 to 0.2, 2.7, p = 0.118), difference 0.7% (-1.9 to 0.7, p = 0.332). Findings were not altered by adjustment for sex or serum 25(OH)D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of sun and lack of vitamin D are both MS risk factors</title><link>/posts/lack-of-sun-and-lack-of-vitamin-d-are-both-ms-risk-factors.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-sun-and-lack-of-vitamin-d-are-both-ms-risk-factors.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sun-exposure-and-vitamin-d-are-independent-risk-factors-for-cns-demyelination">Sun exposure and vitamin D are independent risk factors for CNS demyelination.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Neurology. 2011 Feb 8;76(6):540-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lucas RM, Ponsonby AL, Dear K, Valery PC, Pender MP, Taylor BV, Kilpatrick TJ, Dwyer T, Coulthard A, Chapman C, van der Mei I, Williams D, McMichael AJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>National Centre for Epidemiology and Population Health, The Australian National University, Canberra 0200, Australia. &lt;a href="mailto:Robyn.Lucas@anu.edu.au">Robyn.Lucas@anu.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: To examine whether past and recent sun exposure and vitamin D status (serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels) are associated with risk of first demyelinating events (FDEs) and to evaluate the contribution of these factors to the latitudinal gradient in FDE incidence in Australia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unable to find a gene linking vitamin D and MS</title><link>/posts/unable-to-find-a-gene-linking-vitamin-d-and-ms.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/unable-to-find-a-gene-linking-vitamin-d-and-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-metabolic-pathway-genes-and-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-canadians">Vitamin D metabolic pathway genes and risk of multiple sclerosis in Canadians.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Neurol Sci. 2011 Mar 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Orton SM, Ramagopalan SV, Para AE, Lincoln MR, Handunnetthi L, Chao MJ, Morahan J, Morrison KM, Sadovnick AD, Ebers GC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wellcome Trust Centre for Human Genetics and Department of Clinical Neurology, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Multiple sclerosis (MS) is determined by interactions between genes and environment and the influence of vitamin D adequacy has been proposed. Previous studies have shown that serum 25-hydroxyvitaminD (25(OH)D) levels are genetically influenced. Polymorphisms in vitamin D pathway genes are candidates for association with MS susceptibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased sun and vitamin D both reduced MS risk</title><link>/posts/increased-sun-and-vitamin-d-both-reduced-ms-risk.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-sun-and-vitamin-d-both-reduced-ms-risk.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="sun-exposure-and-vitamin-d-are-independent-risk-factors-for-cns-demyelination">Sun exposure and vitamin D are independent risk factors for CNS demyelination&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>R.M. Lucas, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A.-L. Ponsonby, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>K. Dear, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>P.C. Valery, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>M.P. Pender, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>B.V. Taylor, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>T.J. Kilpatrick, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>T. Dwyer, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A. Coulthard, FRANZCR,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>C. Chapman, FRACP,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I. van der Mei, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>D. Williams, PhD and&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A.J. McMichael, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From the National Centre for Epidemiology and Population Health (R.M.L., K.D., A.J.M.), The Australian National University, Canberra; Murdoch Childrens Research Institute (A.-L.P., T.D.), Melbourne; Queensland Institute of Medical Research (P.C.V.), Brisbane; The University of Queensland and Royal Brisbane and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital (M.P.P., A.C.), Brisbane; Menzies Research Institute (B.V.T., I.v.d.M.), Hobart; Centre for Neuroscience (T.J.K.), The University of Melbourne, Melbourne; Department of Neurology (C.C.), Barwon Health, Geelong; and Department of Neurophysiology (D.W.), John Hunter Hospital, Newcastle, Australia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and MS - Correlation - Causality – Controversy</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-ms-correlation-causality-controversy.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-ms-correlation-causality-controversy.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis-correlation-causality-and-controversy">Vitamin D and Multiple Sclerosis: Correlation, Causality, and Controversy&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Autoimmune Dis. 2011; 2011: 629538.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2010 October 5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4061/2011/629538.">doi: 10.4061/2011/629538.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2011 Joost Smolders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joost &lt;a href="mailto:Smoldersj.smolders@mumc.nl">Smoldersj.smolders@mumc.nl&lt;/a>, 2*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Clinical and Experimental Immunology, Department of Internal Medicine and School for Mental Health and Neuroscience, Maastricht University Medical Center, Universiteitssingel 50, P.O. Box 616, 6200 MD Maastricht, The Netherlands&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Academic MS Center Limburg, Orbis Medical Center, P.O. Box 5500, 6130 MB Sittard, The Netherlands&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More females have MS – perhaps due to vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/more-females-have-ms-perhaps-due-to-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-females-have-ms-perhaps-due-to-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-increasing-incidence-and-prevalence-of-female-multiple-sclerosis---a-critical-analysis-of-potential-environmental-factors">The increasing incidence and prevalence of female multiple sclerosis - a critical analysis of potential environmental factors.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Autoimmun Rev. 2011 Feb 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sellner J, Kraus J, Awad A, Milo R, Hemmer B, Stüve O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Klinikum rechts der Isar, Technische Universität München, München, Germany; Department of Neurology, Christian-Doppler Klinik, Paracelsus Medizinische Universität, Salzburg, Austria.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiple sclerosis (MS) is the most common acquired inflammatory demyelinating disorder of the central nervous system (CNS). Not unlike many inflammatory diseases with a presumed autoimmune pathogenesis, it has been established that there is a female preponderance in prevalence. While in the past it was shown that there are &lt;strong>two women for every man with a diagnosis of MS&lt;/strong> , recent serial cross-sectional assessments provide compelling evidence for an increase of the female to male sex ratio in patients with relapsing-remitting MS over the last decades. An understanding of this phenomenon might provide key insights into the pathogenesis of the disease but also may have implications for health-care strategies and further research efforts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20000 IU vitamin D and MS – less fatigue and relapse</title><link>/posts/20000-iu-vitamin-d-and-ms-less-fatigue-and-relapse.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/20000-iu-vitamin-d-and-ms-less-fatigue-and-relapse.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="safety-and-t-cell-modulating-effects-of-high-dose-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-multiple-sclerosis">Safety and T Cell Modulating Effects of High Dose Vitamin D3 Supplementation in Multiple Sclerosis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 5(12): e15235. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0015235, Clinicaltrials.gov NCT00940719&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joost Smolders1,2,3*, Evelyn Peelen1,2,3, Mariëlle Thewissen2, Jan Willem Cohen Tervaert1,2,5, Paul Menheere4, Raymond Hupperts1,3, Jan Damoiseaux2,5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School for Mental Health and Neuroscience, Maastricht University Medical Center, Maastricht, The Netherlands,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Division of Clinical and Experimental Immunology, Department of Internal Medicine, Maastricht University Medical Center, Maastricht, The Netherlands,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of sunshine associated with MS two years sooner – 2 VHA articles 2010</title><link>/posts/lack-of-sunshine-associated-with-ms-two-years-sooner-2-vha-articles-2010.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-sunshine-associated-with-ms-two-years-sooner-2-vha-articles-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="and--cod-liver-oil-associated-with-ms-4-years-later">And – Cod Liver oil associated with MS 4 years later&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="sun-exposure-vitamin-d-and-age-at-disease-onset-in-relapsing-multiple-sclerosis">Sun Exposure, Vitamin D and Age at Disease Onset in Relapsing Multiple Sclerosis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Vol. 36, No. 1, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tzu-Yun McDowella, b, Sania Amrb, William J. Culpeppera, d, Patricia Langenbergb, Walter Royala, c, Christopher Bevera, c, Douglas D. Bradhama, e&lt;/p>
&lt;p>aMS Center of Excellence-East, Baltimore VAMC &lt;a href="mailto:tycmcdowell@hotmail.com">tycmcdowell@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of&lt;/p>
&lt;p>bEpidemiology and Public Health and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>cNeurology, School of Medicine, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>dDepartment of Pharmaceutical Health Services Research, School of Pharmacy, University of Maryland, Baltimore, Md., and&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of UV 20X more associated with MS than any other variable</title><link>/posts/lack-of-uv-20x-more-associated-with-ms-than-any-other-variable.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-uv-20x-more-associated-with-ms-than-any-other-variable.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-quantitative-analysis-of-suspected-environmental-causes-of-ms">A Quantitative Analysis of Suspected Environmental Causes of MS.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Can J Neurol Sci 38(1):98-105 (2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scott Sloka, Claudia Silva, William Pryse-Phillips, Scott Patten, Luanne Metz and V Wee Yong&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Grand River Hospital, Kitchener, Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a disease with purported environmental causes. Consistent correlations have been found in various settings for &lt;strong>latitude, smoking exposure, sunlight, and vitamin D deficiency&lt;/strong> . We analysed the contribution of various environmental factors to the risk of developing MS from a population perspective.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS Trust in UK is concerned about lack of vitamin D product</title><link>/posts/ms-trust-in-uk-is-concerned-about-lack-of-vitamin-d-product.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-trust-in-uk-is-concerned-about-lack-of-vitamin-d-product.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-insufficiency---available-products">Vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency - available products&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>from &lt;a href="http://www.mstrust.org.uk/news/article.jsp?id=4331">http://www.mstrust.org.uk/news/article.jsp?id=4331&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>16 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are currently a number of supply issues surrounding vitamin D preparations, with the limited number of licensed preparations available being confined to high strength injections for treatment of adult deficiency and oral vitamin drops for paediatric insufficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A recent BMJ article highlighted the problem of vitamin D insufficiency in the UK population. The article cites a survey in which more than 50% of the adult population had insufficiency and 16% had severe insufficiency, and goes on to discuss a large body of observational evidence associating such insufficiency with an increased risk of mortality. The authors report that expert consensus suggests vitamin D status measured by 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) should be 75 nmol/L (30 ?g/L) or more, with deficiency represented by 25-OHD&amp;lt;25 nmol/L and insufficiency represented by 25-OHD of 25-50 nmol/L. We are aware that organisations have or are developing their own local guidance on vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>