<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multiple Sclerosis on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/multiple-sclerosis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Multiple Sclerosis on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/multiple-sclerosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Poor Vitamin D Receptor increases the risk of Multiple Sclerosis in people of European descent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor-vitamin-d-receptor-increases-the-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-people-of-european-descent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor-vitamin-d-receptor-increases-the-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-people-of-european-descent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;evidence-supports-a-causal-association-between-allele-specific-vitamin-d-receptor-binding-and-multiple-sclerosis-among-europeans&#34;&gt;Evidence supports a causal association between allele-specific vitamin D receptor binding and multiple sclerosis among Europeans&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PNAS 121 (8)  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2302259121&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2302259121&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cameron Adams, Ali Manouchehrinia, Hong L. Quach, +6, and Lisa F. Barcellos &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:lbarcellos@berkeley.edu&#34;&gt;lbarcellos@berkeley.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is evidence for a causal association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) serum levels and multiple sclerosis (MS), but the underlying mechanisms are unknown. We conducted a Mendelian Randomization study to estimate causal associations between vitamin D receptor (VDR) binding at a locus and MS susceptibility using genetic instrumental variables constructed from variants previously associated with allele-specific VDR-binding (VDR-binding variant; VDR-BV) and serum 25(OH)D. Two VDR-BV (rs2881514; rs2531804) were independently associated with MS and rs2881514 demonstrated significant interaction with 25(OH)D, providing evidence for a causal association between rs2881514 and MS. Our results demonstrate that genetic variation in individual VDR binding sites contributes to MS and are relevant to other autoimmune diseases for which a role for vitamin D has been implicated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People with Multiple Sclerosis have blunted responses to Vitamin D supplementation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/people-with-multiple-sclerosis-have-blunted-responses-to-vitamin-d-supplementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/people-with-multiple-sclerosis-have-blunted-responses-to-vitamin-d-supplementation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;transcriptomics-identifies-blunted-immunomodulatory-effects-of-vitamin-d-in-people-with-multiple-sclerosis&#34;&gt;Transcriptomics identifies blunted immunomodulatory effects of vitamin D in people with multiple sclerosis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scientific Reports Vol 14, Article number: 1436 (2024)  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-51779-0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-51779-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wei Z. Yeh, Rodney Lea, Jim Stankovich, Sandeep Sampangi, Louise Laverick, Anneke Van der Walt, Vilija Jokubaitis, Melissa Gresle &amp;amp; Helmut Butzkueven&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D deficiency is a risk factor for developing multiple sclerosis (MS). However, the immune effects of vitamin D in people with MS are not well understood. We analyzed transcriptomic datasets generated by RNA sequencing of immune cell subsets (CD4+, CD8+ T cells, B cells, monocytes) from 33 healthy controls and 33 untreated MS cases. We utilized a traditional bioinformatic pipeline and weighted gene co-expression network analysis (WGCNA) to determine genes and pathways correlated with endogenous vitamin D. In controls, CD4+ and CD8+ T cells had 1079 and 1188 genes, respectively, whose expressions were correlated with plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D level (P &amp;lt; 0.05). Functional enrichment analysis identified association with TNF-alpha and MAPK signaling. In CD4+ T cells of controls, vitamin D level was associated with expression levels of several genes proximal to multiple sclerosis risk loci (P = 0.01). Genes differentially associated with endogenous vitamin D by case–control status were enriched in TNF-alpha signaling via NF-κB. WGCNA suggested a blunted response to vitamin D in cases relative to controls. Collectively, our findings provide further evidence for the immune effects of vitamin D, and demonstrate a differential immune response to vitamin D in cases relative to controls, highlighting a possible mechanism contributing to MS pathophysiology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Sclerosis treatment not helped by small doses of vitamin D (yet again) – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-treatment-not-helped-by-small-doses-of-vitamin-d-yet-again-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-treatment-not-helped-by-small-doses-of-vitamin-d-yet-again-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d3-as-an-add-on-treatment-for-multiple-sclerosis-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials&#34;&gt;Vitamin D3 as an add-on treatment for multiple sclerosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mult Scler Relat Disord . 2024 Jan 6:82:105433. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msard.2024.105433&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.msard.2024.105433&lt;/a&gt; PDF I behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;João Vitor Mahler 1, Marina Solti 2, Samira Luísa Apóstolos-Pereira 3, Tarso Adoni 3, Guilherme Diogo Silva 3, Dagoberto Callegaro 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Vitamin D deficiency has been linked to a higher risk of multiple sclerosis (MS) and disease progression. However, the efficacy of vitamin D3 as an adjuvant therapy for MS remains a controversial topic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central Nervous System protection by Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-nervous-system-protection-by-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/central-nervous-system-protection-by-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;molecular-regulation-of-the-cns-by-vitamin-d&#34;&gt;Molecular Regulation of the CNS by Vitamin D&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Physiol Res 2023 Dec 17;72(S4):S339-S356.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;L Máčová 1, R Kancheva, M Bičíková&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;Factors that are up-regulated are marked in green&lt;/span&gt;%%%  &lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;factors that are down-regulated are in red&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D is a lipid-soluble vitamin that can be found in some foods. It is also produced endogenously (in the presence of ultraviolet light), transported through the blood to the targets organs and this is the reason to consider vitamin D as a hormone. It is known that vitamin D has genomic and non-genomic effects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blood–brain barrier dysfunction in multiple sclerosis (improved by vitamin D, etc.)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bloodbrain-barrier-dysfunction-in-multiple-sclerosis-improved-by-vitamin-d-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bloodbrain-barrier-dysfunction-in-multiple-sclerosis-improved-by-vitamin-d-etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;bloodbrain-barrier-dysfunction-in-multiple-sclerosis-causes-consequences-and-potential-effects-of-therapies&#34;&gt;Blood–brain barrier dysfunction in multiple sclerosis: causes, consequences, and potential effects of therapies&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lancet January, 2024DOI:https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(23)00377-0 PDF behind paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bettina Zierfuss, PhD, Catherine Larochelle, MD PhD, Prof Alexandre Prat, MD PhD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summary&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Established by brain endothelial cells, the  &lt;strong&gt;blood–brain barrier&lt;/strong&gt;  (BBB) regulates the trafficking of molecules, restricts immune cell entry into the CNS, and has an active role in neurovascular coupling (the regulation of cerebral blood flow to support neuronal activity). In the early stages of multiple sclerosis, around the time of symptom onset, inflammatory BBB damage is accompanied by pathogenic immune cell infiltration into the CNS. In the later stages of multiple sclerosis, dysregulation of neurovascular coupling is associated with grey matter atrophy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID infections or vaccinations may increase Multiple Sclerosis (if low D) - several studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-infections-or-vaccinations-may-increase-multiple-sclerosis-if-low-d-several-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-infections-or-vaccinations-may-increase-multiple-sclerosis-if-low-d-several-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-potential-role-of-sars-cov-2-infection-and-vaccines-in-multiple-sclerosis-onset-and-reactivation-a-case-series-and-literature-review---july-2023&#34;&gt;The Potential Role of SARS-CoV-2 Infection and Vaccines in Multiple Sclerosis Onset and Reactivation: A Case Series and Literature Review - July 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Viruses . 2023 Jul 18;15(7):1569. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/v15071569.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/v15071569.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eleonora Tavazzi 1, Anna Pichiecchio 1 2, Elena Colombo 1, Eleonora Rigoni 1, Carlo Asteggiano 1 2, Elisa Vegezzi 1, Francesco Masi 1 2, Giacomo Greco 1 2, Stefano Bastianello 2, Roberto Bergamaschi 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The recent SARS-CoV-2 pandemic and related vaccines have raised several issues. Among them, the potential role of the viral infection (COVID-19) or anti-SARS-CoV-2 vaccines as causal factors of dysimmune CNS disorders, as well as the safety and efficacy of vaccines in patients affected by such diseases and on immune-active treatments have been analyzed. The aim is to better understand the relationship between SARS-CoV-2 infection/vaccines with dysimmune CNS diseases by describing 12 cases of multiple sclerosis/myelitis onset or reactivation after exposure to SARS-CoV-2 infection/vaccines and reviewing all published case reports or case series in which MS onset or reactivation was temporally associated with either COVID-19 (8 case reports, 3 case series) or anti-SARS-CoV-2 vaccines (13 case reports, 6 case series). All the cases share a temporal association between viral/vaccine exposure and symptoms onset. This finding, together with direct or immune-based mechanisms described both during COVID-19 and MS, claims in favor of a role for SARS-CoV-2 infection/vaccines in unmasking dysimmune CNS disorders. The most common clinical presentations involve the optic nerve, brainstem and spinal cord. The preferential tropism of the virus together with the presence of some host-related genetic/immune factors might predispose to the involvement of specific CNS districts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Many Neurological Diseases fought by Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/many-neurological-diseases-fought-by-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/many-neurological-diseases-fought-by-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-in-neurological-diseases&#34;&gt;Vitamin D in Neurological Diseases&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2023, 24(1), 87; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms24010087&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms24010087&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Domenico Plantone 1,*ORCID,Guido Primiano 2,3ORCID,Carlo Manco 1,Sara Locci 1,Serenella Servidei 2,3ORCID andNicola De Stefano 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Centre for Precision and Translational Medicine, Department of Medicine, Surgery and Neuroscience, University of Siena, 53100 Siena, Italy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Fondazione Policlinico Universitario A. Gemelli IRCCS, 00168 Rome, Italy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 Dipartimento Universitario di Neuroscienze, Università Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, 00168 Rome, Italy&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autoimmune diseases caused in first day after COVID Vaccination</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/autoimmune-diseases-caused-in-first-day-after-covid-vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/autoimmune-diseases-caused-in-first-day-after-covid-vaccination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;covid-19-vaccines-immediate-onset-autoimmune-disease-adverse-events-in-vaers&#34;&gt;COVID-19 vaccines immediate onset Autoimmune Disease adverse events in VAERS&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://darrellricke.substack.com/p/covid-19-vaccines-immediate-onset?utm_source=cross-post&amp;amp;publication_id=735472&amp;amp;post_id=138024521&amp;amp;utm_campaign=583200&amp;amp;isFreemail=false&amp;amp;r=ofo3r&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&#34;&gt;Substack&lt;/a&gt;  Oct 16&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamindwiki-covid-infections-and-vaccinations-decrease-vitamin-d--many-studiespostscovid-infections-and-vaccinations-decrease-vitamin-d-many-studies&#34;&gt;VitaminDwiki &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-infections-and-vaccinations-decrease-vitamin-d-many-studies&#34;&gt;COVID infections and vaccinations decrease Vitamin D – many studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;266-vitamindwiki-pages-with-a-hrefpostsvaccination-pages-in-vitamindwikivaccin-booster-etc-in-the-title-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-vaccination-pages-in-vitamindwikivaccin-booster-etc-in-the-titlevaccination-pages-in-vitamindwikivaccin-booster-etc-in-the-titlea&#34;&gt;266+ VitaminDWiki pages with &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/vaccination-pages-in-vitamindwikivaccin-booster-etc-in-the-title&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Vaccination pages in VitaminDWiki|VACCIN, BOOSTER, etc in the title&#34;&gt;Vaccination pages in VitaminDWiki|VACCIN, BOOSTER, etc in the title&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{list max=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;VACCIN OR VAXX OR BOOSTER&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obese are 50% more likely to develop or have severe MS (Vitamin D not mentioned)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/obese-are-50-percent-more-likely-to-develop-or-have-severe-ms-vitamin-d-not-mentioned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/obese-are-50-percent-more-likely-to-develop-or-have-severe-ms-vitamin-d-not-mentioned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;obesity-linked-to-multiple-ills-in-ms-study&#34;&gt;Obesity linked to multiple ills in MS study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdedge.com/neurology/article/265902/multiple-sclerosis/obesity-linked-multiple-ills-ms-study?ecd=WNL_EVE_231014_mdedge&amp;amp;icd=login_success_email_match_norm&#34;&gt;MD Edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They seem unaware that&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obese people are more likely to have low vitamin D&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People with lower vitamin D are more likely to get MS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamindwiki--&#34;&gt;VitaminDWiki -&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {SQL(db=&gt;vitamind)}SELECT COUNT(*) FROM (SELECT catObjectId, COUNT(*) FROM `tiki_category_objects` WHERE categId = 18  OR categId = 19 GROUP BY catObjectId HAVING COUNT(*) &gt; 1) AS categs INNER JOIN tiki_objects ON tiki_objects.objectId = categs.catObjectId WHERE type = &#34;wiki page&#34;{SQL} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   studies in both categories Obesity and MS&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Sclerosis risk factors - Vitamin D was the only one you can easily change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-risk-factors-vitamin-d-was-the-only-one-you-can-easily-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-risk-factors-vitamin-d-was-the-only-one-you-can-easily-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;multi-criterial-model-for-weighting-biological-risk-factors-in-multiple-sclerosis-clinical-and-health-insurance-implications&#34;&gt;Multi-Criterial Model for Weighting Biological Risk Factors in Multiple Sclerosis: Clinical and Health Insurance Implications&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Healthcare (Basel) . 2023 Aug 29;11(17):2420. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare11172420.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/healthcare11172420.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Roberto De Masi 1 2, Stefania Orlando 2, Chiara Leo 3, Matteo Pasca 1, Luca Anzilli 3, Maria Carmela Costa 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The etiology of Multiple Sclerosis (MS) remains undetermined. Its pathogenic risk factors are thought to play a negligible role individually in the development of the disease, instead assuming a pathogenic role when they interact with each other. Unfortunately, the statistical weighting of this pathogenic role in predicting MS risk is currently elusive, preventing clinical and health insurance applications. Here, we aim to develop a population-based multi-criterial model for weighting biological risk factors in MS; also, to calculate the individual MS risk value useful for health insurance application. Accordingly, among 596 MS patients retrospectively assessed at the time of diagnosis,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doctor got MS and was later cured by high-dose Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/doctor-got-ms-and-was-later-cured-by-high-dose-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/doctor-got-ms-and-was-later-cured-by-high-dose-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;narrative-by-satya-l-nahu-md--from-grassrootshealthhttpswwwgrassrootshealthnetblogvitamin-d-changed-life-doctor-ms-journey-interviewutm_sourcenewsletter-mainutm_mediumemailutm_campaignnewsletters&#34;&gt;Narrative by Satya L. Nahu, MD ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.grassrootshealth.net/blog/vitamin-d-changed-life-doctor-ms-journey-interview/?utm_source=newsletter-main&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Newsletters&#34;&gt;from GrassrootsHealth&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.grassrootshealth.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/dr-nahu-1-e1691533792747-200x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My story with Vitamin D began in 2012, at the time of my Multiple Sclerosis diagnosis. I was 31, and already a doctor as I had just finished my second specialization (Cardiology) a few months prior. It was suddenly and without warning that I woke up with intense tingling in both hands, which spread up both arms in addition to the sensation of shocks in the spine when flexing the neck. Fatigue, days later, was associated with the condition. Around 30 days after symptoms began, the diagnosis was made, through the addition of magnetic resonance imaging of my entire central nervous system (brain and spinal cord), collection of cerebrospinal fluid and blood laboratory tests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epstein-Barr Virus may be a prerequisite for Multiple Sclerosis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/epstein-barr-virus-may-be-a-prerequisite-for-multiple-sclerosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/epstein-barr-virus-may-be-a-prerequisite-for-multiple-sclerosis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;risk-factors-for-multiple-sclerosis-in-the-context-of-epstein-barr-virus-infection&#34;&gt;Risk factors for multiple sclerosis in the context of Epstein-Barr virus infection&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front Immunol. 2023 Jul 24;14:1212676. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2023.1212676&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2023.1212676&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anna Karin Hedström 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Combined Risk Factors for MS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compelling evidence indicates that Epstein Barr virus (EBV) infection is a prerequisite for multiple sclerosis (MS). The disease may arise from a complex interplay between latent EBV infection, genetic predisposition, and various environmental and lifestyle factors that negatively affect immune control of the infection. Evidence of gene-environment interactions and epigenetic modifications triggered by environmental factors in genetically susceptible individuals supports this view. This review gives a short introduction to EBV and host immunity and discusses evidence indicating EBV as a prerequisite for MS. The role of genetic and environmental risk factors, and their interactions, in MS pathogenesis is reviewed and put in the context of EBV infection. Finally, possible preventive measures are discussed based on the findings presented.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Sclerosis prevention with high-dose vitamin D (in rats in this case)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-prevention-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-in-rats-in-this-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-prevention-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-in-rats-in-this-case/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-dan-effective-antioxidant-in-an-animal-model-of-progressive-multiple-sclerosis---july-2023&#34;&gt;Vitamin D—An Effective Antioxidant in an Animal Model of Progressive Multiple Sclerosis - July 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2023, 15(15), 3309; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15153309&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15153309&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Michaela Tanja Haindl 1ORCID,Muammer Üçal 2ORCID,Willibald Wonisch 3ORCID,Michaela Lang 1,4,Marta Nowakowska 2ORCID,Milena Z. Adzemovic 5,Michael Khalil 1ORCID,Christian Enzinger 1 and Sonja Hochmeister 1,*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Department of Neurology, Medical University of Graz, 8036 Graz, Austria&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Department of Neurosurgery, Medical University of Graz, 8036 Graz, Austria&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 Otto Loewi Research Center, Department of Physiological Medicine, Medical University of Graz, 8010 Graz, Austria&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global burden of brain disorders surpasses cardiovascular disease and cancer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/global-burden-of-brain-disorders-surpasses-cardiovascular-disease-and-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/global-burden-of-brain-disorders-surpasses-cardiovascular-disease-and-cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;from-mdedgehttpswwwmdedgecomneurologyarticle264086neurologyglobal-burden-brain-disorders-surpasses-cardiovascular-diseaseecdwnl_eve_230715_mdedge&#34;&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdedge.com/neurology/article/264086/neurology/global-burden-brain-disorders-surpasses-cardiovascular-disease?ecd=WNL_EVE_230715_mdedge&#34;&gt;MDEdge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brain disorders, including mental illness, neurologic conditions, and stroke, account for more than 15% of all health loss worldwide – more than either cardiovascular disease or cancer – at huge cost to health care systems and society, an analysis of data from the most recent Global Burden of Disease (GBD) study shows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“The burden of brain conditions will increase as populations continue to grow and age,” said study presenter Shayla Smith, MPH, an epidemiologist at the Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation, the University of Washington, Seattle, in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Multiple Sclerosis might be prevented by Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-multiple-sclerosis-might-be-prevented-by-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-multiple-sclerosis-might-be-prevented-by-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-neuroprotection-in-multiple-sclerosis-an-update&#34;&gt;The Role of Vitamin D in Neuroprotection in Multiple Sclerosis: An Update&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients. 2023 Jun 30;15(13):2978. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15132978.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/nu15132978.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amarpreet Sangha 1, Michaela Quon 1, Gerald Pfeffer 2 3, Sarah-Michelle Orton 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a complex neurological condition that involves both inflammatory demyelinating and neurodegenerative components. MS research and treatments have traditionally focused on immunomodulation, with less investigation of neuroprotection, and this holds true for the role of vitamin D in MS. Researchers have already established that vitamin D plays an anti-inflammatory role in modulating the immune system in MS. More recently, researchers have begun investigating the potential neuroprotective role of vitamin D in MS. The active form of vitamin D, 1,25(OH)2D3, has a range of neuroprotective properties, which may be important in remyelination and/or the prevention of demyelination. The most notable finding relevant to MS is that 1,25(OH)2D3 promotes stem cell proliferation and drives the differentiation of neural stem cells into oligodendrocytes, which carry out remyelination. In addition, 1,25(OH)2D3 counteracts neurodegeneration and oxidative stress by suppressing the activation of reactive astrocytes and M1 microglia. 1,25(OH)2D3 also promotes the expression of various neuroprotective factors, including neurotrophins and antioxidant enzymes. 1,25(OH)2D3 decreases blood-brain barrier permeability, reducing leukocyte recruitment into the central nervous system. These neuroprotective effects, stimulated by 1,25(OH)2D3, all enhance neuronal survival. This review summarizes and connects the current evidence supporting the vitamin D-mediated mechanisms of action for neuroprotection in MS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Sclerosis fatigue reduced by weekly Vitamin D (50,000 IU)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-fatigue-reduced-by-weekly-vitamin-d-50000-iu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-fatigue-reduced-by-weekly-vitamin-d-50000-iu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-fatigue-in-multiple-sclerosis-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation on Fatigue in Multiple Sclerosis: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients. 2023 Jun 24;15(13):2861. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15132861.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/nu15132861.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Purificación López-Muñoz 1 2, Ana Isabel Torres-Costoso 1 3, Rubén Fernández-Rodríguez 3, María José Guzmán-Pavón 1, Sergio Núñez de Arenas-Arroyo 3, Julián Ángel Basco-López 1 2, Sara Reina-Gutiérrez 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;With 1296 trials to select from, %%%they managed to include a trial that used an impossibly small 40 IU of Vitamin D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Sclerosis treated equally by UVB and weekly 50,000 IU of Vitamin D – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-treated-equally-by-uvb-and-weekly-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-treated-equally-by-uvb-and-weekly-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;efficacy-of-ultraviolet-b-radiation-versus-vitamin-d3-on-postural-control-and-cognitive-functions-in-relapsing-remitting-multiple-sclerosis-a-randomized-controlled-study&#34;&gt;Efficacy of ultraviolet B radiation versus vitamin D3 on postural control and cognitive functions in relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis: A randomized controlled study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2023 Jul;35:49-56. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbmt.2023.04.069&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.jbmt.2023.04.069&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shimaa Abdelalim Essa 1, Ahmed Elokda 2, Dalia Mosaad 3, Wael Shendy 4, Maged Abdel-Nasser 5, Asmaa Mohamed Ebraheim 6, Hadeel Mohammad 7, Alaa Elmazny 8, Eman Magdy 9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: The relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis (RRMS) is the most common type of MS with prevalence rate 20-60 patients/100.000 individuals in Egypt. Poor postural control and cognitive dysfunctions are well-established complications of RRMS without potent remedy yet. The latest evidence highlighted the potential and independent immune-modulating effects of vitamin D3 and ultraviolet radiation in the management of RRMS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Multiple Sclerosis while younger if have a poor CYP24A1 vitamin D gene</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/get-multiple-sclerosis-while-younger-if-have-a-poor-cyp24a1-vitamin-d-gene/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/get-multiple-sclerosis-while-younger-if-have-a-poor-cyp24a1-vitamin-d-gene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-cyp24a1-gene-variant-rs2762943-is-associated-with-low-serum-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-multiple-sclerosis-patients&#34;&gt;The CYP24A1 gene variant rs2762943 is associated with low serum 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D levels in multiple sclerosis patients&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eur J Neurol . 2023 May 14. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.15866&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1111/ene.15866&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sunny Malhotra # 1, Luciana Midaglia # 1, Omar Chuquisana 2, Nikolaos A Patsopoulos 3 4 5, Roser Ferrer 6, Marina Giralt 6, Nicolas Fissolo 1, Elia Gil-Varea 1, Juan Carlos Triviño 7, Jan D Lünemann 2, Xavier Montalban 1, Manuel Comabella 1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Sclerosis is again not fought by 5,000 IU vitamin D daily (need at least 10X more) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-is-again-not-fought-by-5000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-need-at-least-10x-more-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-is-again-not-fought-by-5000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-need-at-least-10x-more-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fighting MS with Vitamin D needs some combination of:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Larger Vitamin D doses: &amp;gt;50,000 IU if taken daily&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gut-friendly form of vitamin D&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magnesium - increases effective IU by 30%&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Take Vitamin D with evening meal - increases effective IU by 30%&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D Receptor activators: i.e. Resveratrol, Curcumin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Take Vitamin D non-daily - say weekly - gets past any Vitamin D Receptor limitation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;high-dose-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-relapsing-remitting-multiple-sclerosis-a-randomised-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;High-dose vitamin D3 supplementation in relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis: a randomised clinical trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EClinicalMedicine. 2023 Apr 13;59:101957. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.101957&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.101957&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Vitamin D fights Alzheimer’s, Parkinson’s, Multiple Sclerosis and Epilepsy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-vitamin-d-fights-alzheimers-parkinsons-multiple-sclerosis-and-epilepsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-vitamin-d-fights-alzheimers-parkinsons-multiple-sclerosis-and-epilepsy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;molecular-insights-into-the-pathogenic-impact-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-neurological-disorders&#34;&gt;Molecular insights into the pathogenic impact of vitamin D deficiency in neurological disorders&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biomed Pharmacother. 2023 Apr 19;162:114718. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2023.114718&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.biopha.2023.114718&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Md Jamir Anwar 1, Sattam Khulaif Alenezi 2, Ahmad Hamad Alhowail 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;charts-of-impact-of-vitamin-d&#34;&gt;Charts of impact of Vitamin D&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PDF Table of Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neurological disorders are the major cause of disability, leading to a decrease in quality of life by impairing cognitive, sensorimotor, and motor functioning. Several factors have been proposed in the pathogenesis of neurobehavioral changes, including nutritional, environmental, and genetic predisposition. Vitamin D (VD) is an environmental and nutritional factor that is widely distributed in the central nervous system&amp;rsquo;s subcortical grey matter, neurons of the substantia nigra, hippocampus, thalamus, and hypothalamus. It is implicated in the regulation of several brain functions by preserving neuronal structures. It is a hormone rather than a nutritional vitamin that exerts a regulatory role in the pathophysiology of several neurological disorders, including Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease, epilepsy, and multiple sclerosis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Vitamin D fights neurodegeneration (Multiple Sclerosis, Alzheimer’s, Dementia, etc)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-vitamin-d-fights-neurodegeneration-multiple-sclerosis-alzheimers-dementia-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-vitamin-d-fights-neurodegeneration-multiple-sclerosis-alzheimers-dementia-etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-and-neurodegenerative-diseases&#34;&gt;Vitamin D and neurodegenerative diseases&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Heliyon &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e12877&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e12877&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Weixia Wang 1 YijinLi 1 Xianfang Meng 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;700&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neurodegenerative diseases, featured by progressive loss of structure or function of neurons, are considered incurable at present. Movement disorders like tremor and postural instability, cognitive or behavioral disorders such as memory impairment are the most common symptoms of them and the growing patient population of neurodegenerative diseases poses a serious threat to public health and a burden on economic development. Hence, it is vital to prevent the occurrence of the diseases and delay their progress. Vitamin D can be transformed into a hormone in vivo with both genomic and non-genomic actions, exerting diverse physiological effects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
