<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Autoimmune on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/autoimmune.html</link><description>Recent content in Autoimmune on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/autoimmune/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D and Immune Function – Review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-immune-function-review.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-immune-function-review.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(7), 2502-2521; doi:10.3390/nu5072502 (doi registration under processing)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara Prietlemail, Gerlies Treiberemail, Thomas R. Pieberemail and Karin Amrein &lt;a href="mailto:karin.amrein@medunigraz.at">karin.amrein@medunigraz.at&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Internal Medicine, Medical University of Graz, Auenbruggerplatz 15, A 8036 Graz, Austria&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(This article belongs to the Special Issue Nutrients and Immune Function)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D metabolizing enzymes and vitamin D receptors are present in many cell types including various immune cells such as antigen-presenting-cells, T cells, B cells and monocytes. In vitro data show that, in addition to modulating innate immune cells, vitamin D also promotes a more tolerogenic immunological status. In vivo data from animals and from human vitamin D supplementation studies have shown beneficial effects of vitamin D on immune function, in particular in the context of autoimmunity. In this review, currently available data are summarized to give an overview of the effects of vitamin D on the immune system in general and on the regulation of inflammatory responses, as well as regulatory mechanisms connected to autoimmune diseases particularly in type 1 diabetes mellitus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Myasthenia gravis score improved 38 percent with just 800 IU of vitamin D daily</title><link>/posts/myasthenia-gravis-score-improved-38-percent-with-just-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/myasthenia-gravis-score-improved-38-percent-with-just-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-myasthenia-gravis-and-improvement-of-fatigue-after-supplementation-of-vitamin-d3-a-pilot-study">Vitamin D deficiency in patients with myasthenia gravis and improvement of fatigue after supplementation of vitamin D3: a pilot study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Neurol. 2012 Dec;19(12):1554-60. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2012.03773.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1468-1331.2012.03773.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Askmark H, Haggård L, Nygren I, Punga AR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Uppsala University Hospital, Institute of Neuroscience, Uppsala, Sweden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Myasthenia gravis (MG) is a chronic autoimmune neuromuscular disorder. Vitamin D has important roles both in the autoimmune response and in skeletal muscles. We determined the levels of 25-hydroxy vitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> in patients with MG and in healthy subjects to determine whether vitamin D deficiency is present in MG and whether vitamin D supplementation has beneficial effects on fatigue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects against many types of health problems – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-effects-on-musculoskeletal-health-immunity-autoimmunity-cardiovascular-disease-cancer-fertility-pregnancy-dementia-and-mortality-a-review-of-recent-evidence">Vitamin D effects on musculoskeletal health, immunity, autoimmunity, cardiovascular disease, cancer, fertility, pregnancy, dementia and mortality-A review of recent evidence.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmun Rev. 2013 Mar 28. pii: S1568-9972(13)00040-2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.">doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pawel Pludowski a &lt;a href="mailto:p.pludowski@czd.pl">p.pludowski@czd.pl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael F. Holick b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Pilzc, d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carol L. Wagner e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce W. Hollis e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant f,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yehuda Shoenfeld g,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elisabeth Lerchbaum c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David J. Llewellyn h,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katharina Kienreich c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maya Soni h&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Biochemistry, Radioimmunology and Experimental Medicine, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Health Institute, Warsaw, Poland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autoimmunity, T Cells and vitamin D: A chemical network analysis</title><link>/posts/autoimmunity-t-cells-and-vitamin-d-a-chemical-network-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/autoimmunity-t-cells-and-vitamin-d-a-chemical-network-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-sensitivity-to-the-immune-responses-and-autoimmunity-a-chemical-network-model-study">Vitamin D sensitivity to the immune responses and autoimmunity: A chemical network model study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Susmita Roy, Krishna Shrinivas and Biman Bagchi* SSCU, Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore 560012, India. (Email: &lt;a href="mailto:profbiman@gmail.com">profbiman@gmail.com&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although Vitamin D is believed to be involved in a large number of immune responses our understanding of these processes at cellular level remained at infancy. We develop and solve a coarse grained kinetic network model to quantify the effects of variation of vitamin D on human immunity. The system of equations accounts for known inter-relation between active and inactive vitamin D, antigen presenting cells, effector T cells, regulatory T cells and pathogen. Both time dependent and steady state solutions are obtained. The time dependent solution of the system of equations reveals that the immune response is rather strongly regulated in presence of vitamin D. We found quantitatively that lower than optimum levels of concentration of active vitamin D correspond to weak regulation where, once a pathogen/antigen enters the body, the nature of the immune response would be less regulatory and hence more aggressive, or inflammatory. The steady state solution of our model shows that vitamin D enhances the tolerance level of immune system, thereby increasing resistance to autoimmune diseases. Our model and accompanied numerical analyses reveal another important aspect of immunity: While extremely low levels of vitamin D could lead to increased risk of autoimmune responses, an overdose (toxic) level would give rise to too large a tolerant response, leading to the increased risk of tumors and cancerous cell growth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, Vitamin A, or Vitamin E association with allergies and asthma</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-vitamin-a-or-vitamin-e-association-with-allergies-and-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-vitamin-a-or-vitamin-e-association-with-allergies-and-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="fat-soluble-vitamins-and-atopic-disease-what-is-the-evidence">Fat-soluble vitamins and atopic disease: what is the evidence?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Proc Nutr Soc. 2012 Feb;71(1):67-74. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/S002966511100334X.">doi: 10.1017/S002966511100334X.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Nov 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Litonjua AA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Channing Laboratory and Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Harvard Medical School, 181 Longwood Avenue, Boston, MA 02115, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:augusto.litonjua@channing.harvard.edu">augusto.litonjua@channing.harvard.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The prevalence of asthma and other atopic disorders continues to increase worldwide. Examination of the epidemiologic patterns has revealed that this rise has occurred primarily in western, industrialised countries and countries transitioning to this lifestyle. While many changes have occurred in human populations over the years, it has been hypothesised that some of the relevant changes that have led to the rise in asthma and atopic disorders have been the changes from a traditional diet to a more western diet consisting of decreased intake of fruits and vegetables (sources of antioxidant vitamins and carotenoids) leading to decreased intakes of vitamins E and A, and a decrease in sun exposure (e.g. greater time spent indoors and heavy use of sunscreen) leading to decreased circulating levels of vitamin D. This review will examine the evidence for an effect of fat-soluble vitamins (vitamins A, D and E) on the development and severity of asthma and allergies. While observational studies suggest that these vitamins may play a salutary role in asthma and allergies, large, well-designed clinical trials are lacking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yet another meta-analysis ignores vitamin D dose and serum level – Autoimmune disease</title><link>/posts/yet-another-meta-analysis-ignores-vitamin-d-dose-and-serum-level-autoimmune-disease.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yet-another-meta-analysis-ignores-vitamin-d-dose-and-serum-level-autoimmune-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="can-supplementation-with-vitamin-d-reduce-the-risk-or-modify-the-course-of-autoimmune-diseases-a-systematic-review-of-the-literature">Can supplementation with vitamin D reduce the risk or modify the course of autoimmune diseases? A systematic review of the literature.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Autoimmun Rev. 2012 Dec;12(2):127-36. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2012.07.007.">doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2012.07.007.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jul 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antico A, Tampoia M, Tozzoli R, Bizzaro N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laboratorio di Patologia Clinica, Ospedale Civile, Cittadella, Italy. &lt;a href="mailto:antonioantico@virgilio.it">antonioantico@virgilio.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate whether vitamin D levels are related to the risk of developing autoimmune diseases and whether supplementation with vitamin D can modify the course of the diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sjögren’s syndrome (2nd most common rheumatic disease) and vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/sjogrens-syndrome-2nd-most-common-rheumatic-disease-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sjogrens-syndrome-2nd-most-common-rheumatic-disease-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-sjögrens-disease-revealing-the-connectionsa-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis---jan-2023">Vitamin D and Sjögren’s Disease: Revealing the Connections—A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis - Jan 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dry-eye-more-severe-with-lower-vitamin-d-in-sjögren-syndrome---dec-2019">Dry eye more severe with lower vitamin D in Sjögren Syndrome - Dec 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-sjögren-syndrome---review-april-2017">Vitamin D and Sjögren syndrome - Review April 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#novel-aspects-of-sjögrens-syndrome-in-2012">Novel aspects of Sjögren’s syndrome in 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sections-on-vitamin-d-clipped-from-the-pdf">Sections on vitamin D clipped from the PDF&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#novel-aspects-of-ss-the-role-of-infections-and-vitamin-d-infections-and-ss">Novel aspects of SS: the role of infections and vitamin D Infections and SS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-levels-of-vitamin-d-are-associated-with-neuropathy-and-lymphoma-among-patients-with-ss">Low levels of vitamin D are associated with neuropathy and lymphoma among patients with SS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-levels-of-vitamin-d-are-associated-with-neuropathy-and-lymphoma-among-patients-with-sjögrens-syndrome">Low levels of vitamin-D are associated with neuropathy and lymphoma among patients with Sjögren&amp;rsquo;s syndrome.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clips-from-wikipedia-april-2013">Clips from Wikipedia April 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mega-doses-of-vitamin-d-reduces-sjögrens-fatigue-for-one-person">Mega Doses Of Vitamin D reduces Sjögren’s fatigue for one person&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-and-sjögrens-disease-revealing-the-connectionsa-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis---jan-2023">Vitamin D and Sjögren’s Disease: Revealing the Connections—A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis - Jan 2023&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2023, 15(3), 497; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15030497">https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15030497&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Infectious burden linked to cognitive decline (both linked to low vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/infectious-burden-linked-to-cognitive-decline-both-linked-to-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/infectious-burden-linked-to-cognitive-decline-both-linked-to-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="infectious-burden-and-cognitive-function-the-northern-manhattan-study">Infectious burden and cognitive function, The Northern Manhattan Study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Neurology March 26, 2013 vol. 80 no. 13 1209-1215; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182896e79">doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182896e79&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mira Katan, MD, &lt;a href="mailto:mk3270@columbia.edu">mk3270@columbia.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeseon Park Moon, MS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Myunghee Cho Paik, PhD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ralph L. Sacco, MD, MS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinton B. Wright, MD and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mitchell S.V. Elkind, MD, MS&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology (M.K., Y.P.M., M.S.V.E.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Gertrude Sergievsky Center (M.S.V.E.), Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, New York;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Biostatistics (M.C.P.), Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University, New York, NY;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces inflammation (heat shock protein)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-inflammation-heat-shock-protein.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-inflammation-heat-shock-protein.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="regulatory-effects-of-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3-on-vascular-smooth-muscle-cells">Regulatory effects of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 on vascular smooth muscle cells.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Biochim Pol. 2012;59(3):395-400. Epub 2012 Aug 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tukaj S, Trzonkowski P, Tukaj C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Plant Physiology and Biotechnology, University of Gdańsk, Poland. &lt;a href="mailto:stefantukaj@gmail.com">stefantukaj@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inflammatory response has been recognized as a central feature in the development and progression of atherosclerosis, and VSMCs (Vascular Smooth Muscle Cells) - the main cellular component of media, play an important role in this process. Many reports indicate that the biologically active vitamin D metabolite - 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) (1,25(OH)(2)D(3) = calcitriol), besides its well established role in calcium homeostasis, plays an essential role in the regulation of the inflammation process. The aim of this study was to determine the regulatory effects of calcitriol, applied at two supra-physiological doses (10 nM and 100 nM), in VSMC culture. Secretion of the pro-inflammatory cytokines, IL-6 and TNF-α, was significantly attenuated in calcitriol-treated VSMC culture, but the level of anti-inflammatory TGF-β was generally unchanged. Since in advanced atherosclerosis lesions several cell types, including VSMCs, overproduce the HSP70 chaperone protein, we also checked the effects of calcitriol on its synthesis. The presence of 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) did not affect HSP70 synthesis under physiological conditions but the synthesis of HSP70 in VSMCs exposed to heat shock was significantly inhibited by calcitriol (=100 nM). We observed that 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) induced SOD 1 activity, stimulated the expression of IκB-α, and did not influence the level of NF-κB-p65 in VSMCs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>11X more non-immigrant children allergic to peanuts if vitamin D less than 20 ng</title><link>/posts/11x-more-non-immigrant-children-allergic-to-peanuts-if-vitamin-d-less-than-20-ng.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/11x-more-non-immigrant-children-allergic-to-peanuts-if-vitamin-d-less-than-20-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-is-associated-with-challenge-proven-food-allergy-in-infants">Vitamin D insufficiency is associated with challenge-proven food allergy in infants&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology. Available online 27 February 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katrina J. Allen, MBBS, BMedSc, FRACP, PhDa, b, c, &lt;a href="mailto:katie.allen@rch.org.au">katie.allen@rch.org.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jennifer J. Koplin, PhDa, b, ∗, Anne-Louise Ponsonby, MBBS, PhDa, b, Lyle C. Gurrin, PhDa, d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Melissa Wake, MD, FRACPa, b, e, Peter Vuillermin, MBBS, FRACP, PhDa, f, Pamela Martin, PhDa,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Melanie Matheson, PhDd, Adrian Lowe, PhDa, d, Marnie Robinson, MBBS, FRACPc,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autoimmune disorder patients in Brazil helped by vitamin D – video and Facebook</title><link>/posts/autoimmune-disorder-patients-in-brazil-helped-by-vitamin-d-video-and-facebook.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/autoimmune-disorder-patients-in-brazil-helped-by-vitamin-d-video-and-facebook.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="neat-social-media-spreads-the-word-of-the-benefits-of-vitamin-d3-and-vitamin-k2">Neat: Social media spreads the word of the benefits of Vitamin D3 (and Vitamin K2)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Large doses: 20,000 to 150,000 IU/d&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dose sizes are far larger than what what others are using to prevent MS, but this size is being used to TREAT MS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="facebook-page-by-the-patientshttpswwwfacebookcomgroups528624870516079-in-portuguese">&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/528624870516079/">Facebook Page by the patients&lt;/a> in Portuguese&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>15,800 members as of Nov 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="youtube-interview-of-the-doctorhttpwwwyoutubecomwatchvciwiwim4hnm">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cIwIWim4hNM">YouTube interview of the doctor&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/brazil.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="youtube-videohttpwwwyoutubecomwatchveragu1xcy-u-in-portuguese-with-english-and-spanish-subtitles">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=erAgu1XcY-U">YouTube Video&lt;/a> In Portuguese with English and Spanish subtitles&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The documentary was made by Daniel Cunha, a Brazilian journalist.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ankylosing spondylitis and low vitamin D – many studies</title><link>/posts/ankylosing-spondylitis-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ankylosing-spondylitis-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ankylosing-spondylitis--patients-should-increase-vitamin-d-levels---meta-analysis-nov-2022">Ankylosing Spondylitis patients should increase Vitamin D levels - meta-analysis Nov 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ankylosing-spondylitis-is-still-associated-with-low-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-sept-2022">Ankylosing Spondylitis is still associated with low Vitamin D - meta-analysis Sept 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#considering-testing-all-as-patients-for-low-vitamin-d----jan-2017">Considering testing all AS patients for low Vitamin D - Jan 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#patients-with-ankylosing-spondylitis-continue-to-have-low-vitamin-d---march-2021">Patients with Ankylosing Spondylitis continue to have low Vitamin D - March 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#males-with-ankylosing-spondylitis-having-10ng-of-vitamin-d-had-a-22-x-higher-risk-of-dying---may-2020">Males with Ankylosing Spondylitis having &amp;lt;10ng of vitamin D had a 2.2 X higher risk of dying - May 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#as-related-to-low-vitamin-d---sept-2018">AS related to low Vitamin D - Sept 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#higher-vitamin-d-associated-with-less-risk-of-as---span-stylecolorf00review--meta-analysisspan-sept-2014">Higher Vitamin D associated with less risk of AS - &lt;span style="color:#F00;">review &amp;amp; meta-analysis&lt;/span> Sept 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sponsdyloarthritis-is-21-x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficiency---nov-2017">Sponsdyloarthritis is 2.1 X more likely if Vitamin D Deficiency - Nov 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#decreased-plasma-vitamin-d-levels-in-patients-with-undifferentiated-spondyloarthritis-and-ankylosing-spondylitis---2013">Decreased plasma vitamin d levels in patients with undifferentiated spondyloarthritis and ankylosing spondylitis - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#systematic-review-of-association-between-vitamin-d-levels-and-susceptibility-and-disease-activity-of-ankylosing-spondylitis---2014">Systematic review of association between vitamin D levels and susceptibility and disease activity of ankylosing spondylitis - 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#4-out-of-7-studies-found-as-associated-with-low-vitamin-d---july-2014">4 out of 7 studies found AS associated with low vitamin D - July 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="ankylosing-spondylitis--patients-should-increase-vitamin-d-levels---meta-analysis-nov-2022">Ankylosing Spondylitis patients should increase Vitamin D levels - meta-analysis Nov 2022&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Ankylosing spondylitis disease activity and serum vitamin D levels: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autoimmunity and vitamin D – review</title><link>/posts/autoimmunity-and-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/autoimmunity-and-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-implication-of-vitamin-d-and-autoimmunity-a-comprehensive-review">The Implication of Vitamin D and Autoimmunity: a Comprehensive Review.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2013 Jan 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yang CY, Leung PS, Adamopoulos IE, Gershwin ME.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Rheumatology, Allergy and Clinical Immunology, University of California at Davis School of Medicine, 451 Health Sciences Drive, Suite 6510, Davis, CA, 95616, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Historically, vitamin D has been associated with the regulation of bone metabolism. However, increasing evidence demonstrates a strong association between vitamin D signaling and many biological processes that regulate immune responses. The discovery of the vitamin D receptor in multiple immune cell lineages, such as monocytes, dendritic cells, and activated T cells credits vitamin D with a novel role in modulating immunological functions and its subsequent role in the development or prevention of autoimmune diseases. In this review we, discuss five major areas in vitamin D biology of high immunological significance:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30 to 40 ng of vitamin D associated with the least peanut allergy</title><link>/posts/30-to-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-the-least-peanut-allergy.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/30-to-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-the-least-peanut-allergy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="neonatal-vitamin-d-status-and-childhood-peanut-allergy-a-pilot-study">Neonatal vitamin D status and childhood peanut allergy: a pilot study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2012 Nov;109(5):324-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.anai.2012.07.009.">doi: 10.1016/j.anai.2012.07.009.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mullins RJ, Clark S, Wiley V, Eyles D, Camargo CA Jr.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John James Medical Centre, Deakin, Australia, Medical School, Canberra, Australia. &lt;a href="mailto:rmullins@allergycapital.com.au">rmullins@allergycapital.com.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Although a number of factors have been proposed to explain the increase in food allergy during the last decade, the possibility that vitamin D status may play a pathogenic role has received recent attention.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High level of maternal vitamin D and infant food allergy – controversy</title><link>/posts/high-level-of-maternal-vitamin-d-and-infant-food-allergy-controversy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-level-of-maternal-vitamin-d-and-infant-food-allergy-controversy.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="maternal-and-newborn-vitamin-d-status-and-its-impact-on-food-allergy-development-in-the-german-lina-cohort-study">Maternal and newborn vitamin D status and its impact on food allergy development in the German LINA cohort study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Allergy 2012; 68:220–228; DOI: 10.1111/all.12081.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K. Weisse 1, S. Winkler 1,2, F. Hirche 2, G. Herberth 1, D. Hinz 1, M. Bauer 1, S. Röder 3, U. Rolle-Kampczyk 4, M. von Bergen 4, S. Olek 5, U. Sack 6, T. Richter 7, U. Diez 7, M. Borte 7, G. I. Stangl 2, I. Lehmann 1,3, &lt;a href="mailto:irina.lehmann@ufz.de">irina.lehmann@ufz.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis of Autoimmunity which includes Epstein-Barr Virus and Vitamin D Deficiency – 2012</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-of-autoimmunity-which-includes-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-of-autoimmunity-which-includes-epstein-barr-virus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="cd8-t-cell-deficiency-epstein-barr-virus-infection-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-steps-to-autoimmunity-a-unifying-hypothesis">CD8+ T-Cell Deficiency, Epstein-Barr Virus Infection, Vitamin D Deficiency, and Steps to Autoimmunity: A Unifying Hypothesis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmune Diseases, Volume 2012 (2012), Article ID 189096, 16 pages, Review Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael P. Pender 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Medicine, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD 4072, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Brisbane, QLD 4029, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 18 August 2011; Revised 3 October 2011; Accepted 16 October 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Academic Editor: Corrado Betterle&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Autoimmune diseases, solar radiation and vitamin D – Schwalfenberg 2012</title><link>/posts/review-of-autoimmune-diseases-solar-radiation-and-vitamin-d-schwalfenberg-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-autoimmune-diseases-solar-radiation-and-vitamin-d-schwalfenberg-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="solar-radiation-and-vitamin-d-mitigating-environmental-factors-in-autoimmune-disease">Solar Radiation and Vitamin D: Mitigating Environmental Factors in Autoimmune Disease&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Environmental and Public Health, Volume 2012 (2012), Article ID 619381, 9 pages, Review Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gerry K. Schwalfenberg&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Family Medicine, University of Alberta, Suite No. 301, 9509-156 Street, Edmonton, AB, Canada T6G 2M7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 3 July 2011; Revised 29 November 2011; Accepted 13 December 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This paper looks at the environmental role of vitamin D and solar radiation as risk reduction factors in autoimmune disease. Five diseases are considered: multiple sclerosis, type 1 diabetes, rheumatoid arthritis, autoimmune disease of the thyroid, and inflammatory bowel disease. Clinical relevant studies and factors that may indicate evidence that autoimmune disease is a vitamin D-sensitive disease are presented. Studies that have resulted in prevention or amelioration of some autoimmune disease are discussed. An example of the utility of supplementing vitamin D in an unusual autoimmune disease, idiopathic thrombocytic purpura, is presented.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>6X as many people with allergic rhinitis were severely vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/6x-as-many-people-with-allergic-rhinitis-were-severely-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/6x-as-many-people-with-allergic-rhinitis-were-severely-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-serum-levels-in-allergic-rhinitis-any-difference-from-normal-population">Vitamin D serum levels in allergic rhinitis: any difference from normal population?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Asia Pac Allergy. 2012 Jan;2(1):45-8. Epub 2012 Jan 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arshi S, Ghalehbaghi B, Kamrava SK, Aminlou M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Asthma, Allergy and Clinical Immunology, Hazrat Rasoul Akram Hospital, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran 1445613131, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Recently it has been suggested that, the worldwide increase in allergic diseases such as asthma, allergic rhinitis and food allergy is associated with low vitamin D intake.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Youths with autoimmunity disorders were 2.3 X more likely to be vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/youths-with-autoimmunity-disorders-were-23-x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/youths-with-autoimmunity-disorders-were-23-x-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-children-with-rheumatologic-disorders-and-controls">25-hydroxyvitamin D levels and vitamin D deficiency in children with rheumatologic disorders and controls.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Rheumatol. 2011 Sep;38(9):2000-4. Epub 2011 Jul 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pelajo CF, Lopez-Benitez JM, Miller LC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatric Rheumatology, Floating Hospital for Children at Tufts Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:cpelajo@tuftsmedicalcenter.org">cpelajo@tuftsmedicalcenter.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To evaluate the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency, as well as factors associated with serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels, in children attending a pediatric rheumatology clinic, and to determine whether there was a difference in serum 25(OH)D levels and in vitamin D deficiency between children with autoimmune disorders and nonautoimmune conditions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, Allergy, and genetics</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-allergy-and-genetics.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-allergy-and-genetics.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="evidence-for-a-genetic-interaction-in-allergy-related-responsiveness-to-vitamin-d-deficiency">Evidence for a genetic interaction in allergy-related responsiveness to vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Allergy. 2012 Jun 12. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1398-9995.2012.02856.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1398-9995.2012.02856.x.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vimaleswaran KS, Cavadino A, Hyppönen E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Paediatric Epidemiology and Biostatistics and MRC Centre for the Epidemiology of Child Health, UCL Institute of Child Health, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The hormonal form of vitamin D affects both adaptive and innate immune functions involved in the development of allergies. Certain genotypes have been seen to alter the association between vitamin D deficiency (VDD) and the risk of food sensitization in children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is Vitamin D Supplementation Responsible for the Allergy Pandemic</title><link>/posts/is-vitamin-d-supplementation-responsible-for-the-allergy-pandemic.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-vitamin-d-supplementation-responsible-for-the-allergy-pandemic.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Matthias Wjst&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Posted: 05/22/2012; Curr Opin Allergy Clin Immunol. 2012;12(3):257-262. © 2012 Lippincott Williams &amp;amp; Wilkins&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matthias Wjst, Molecular Genetics of Lung Diseases, Comprehensive Pneumology Center (CPC), Institute of Lung Biology and Disease (iLBD), Helmholtz Zentrum München, German Research Center for Environmental Health, Ingolstädter Landstr. 1, D-85764 Neuherberg, Germany. E-mail: wjst@helmholtz-muenchen. &lt;a href="mailto:de/wjst@tum.de">de/wjst@tum.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>(Impression after a very quick read by VitaminDWiki: Author speculates that low vitamin D during pregnancy sets up an expectation in the infant body for low vitamin D environment – which is upset by getting vitamin D. This would not occur if there were enough vitamin D during pregnancy)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Allergic Disease: Sunlight at the End of the Tunnel</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-allergic-disease-sunlight-at-the-end-of-the-tunnel.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-allergic-disease-sunlight-at-the-end-of-the-tunnel.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Solar, vitamin D, and autoimmunity</title><link>/posts/solar-vitamin-d-and-autoimmunity.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/solar-vitamin-d-and-autoimmunity.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Still unsure of association between vitamin D and asthma and allergies – review</title><link>/posts/still-unsure-of-association-between-vitamin-d-and-asthma-and-allergies-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/still-unsure-of-association-between-vitamin-d-and-asthma-and-allergies-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-risk-factor-for-childhood-allergic-disease-and-asthma">Vitamin D deficiency as a risk factor for childhood allergic disease and asthma.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Allergy Clin Immunol. 2012 Apr;12(2):179-85.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Litonjua AA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Channing Laboratory and Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusettes, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE OF REVIEW: Over the past 2 years, the number of studies relating vitamin D deficiency and asthma and allergies has increased significantly. The purpose of this review is to update the last review in this journal and examine the evidence of the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and childhood asthma and allergies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Being told you have allergies is associated with less than 10 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/being-told-you-have-allergies-is-associated-with-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/being-told-you-have-allergies-is-associated-with-less-than-10-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-risk-factor-for-allergic-disorders-and-immune-mechanisms">Vitamin D deficiency as a risk factor for allergic disorders and immune mechanisms.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Allergy Asthma Proc. 2011 Nov;32(6):438-44.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frieri M, Valluri A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Allergy Immunology, Department of Medicine, Nassau University Medical Center, East Meadow, New York, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency (VDD) has been reported in very high rates in the U.S. population. Deficiency has been implicated in various diseases such as diabetes, high blood pressure, cardiovascular disease, and many cancers. It has also been implicated in several allergic disorders and immune system dysregulation. The National Health and Nutrition examination survey (NHANES) in 2005-2006 was a cross-sectional survey performed in the noninstitutionalized population of the United States by the Center for Disease Control and Prevention and National Center for Health Statistics. It consists of an extensive interview performed at home and an examination performed at a mobile center. An allergy questionnaire was provided as interview data on self-reported allergic diseases including allergic rhinitis, allergies, and atopic dermatitis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Allergic diseases in the elderly</title><link>/posts/allergic-diseases-in-the-elderly.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/allergic-diseases-in-the-elderly.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Victoria Cardona 1,2*, Mar Guilarte 1,2, Olga Luengo 1,2, Moises Labrador-Horrillo 1,2, Anna Sala-Cunill 1,2 and Teresa Garriga 1&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Corresponding author: Victoria Cardona &lt;a href="mailto:vcardona@comb.cat">vcardona@comb.cat&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>1 Allergy Section, Department of Internal Medicine, Hospital Universitari Vall d&amp;rsquo;Hebron, Barcelona, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Allergy Research Unit, Institut de Recerca Vall d&amp;rsquo;Hebron, Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical and Translational Allergy 2011, 1:11 doi:10.1186/2045-7022-1-11&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received:	22 August 2011; Accepted:	17 October 2011; Published:	17 October 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-page">PDF is attached at bottom of page&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Demographic distribution of the population is progressively changing with the proportion of elderly persons increasing in most societies. This entails that there is a need to evaluate the impact of common diseases, such as asthma and other allergic conditions, in this age segment. Frailty, comorbidities and polymedication are some of the factors that condition management in geriatric patients. The objective of this review is to highlight the characteristics of allergic diseases in older age groups, from the influence of immunosenescence, to particular clinical implications and management issues, such as drug interactions or age-related side effects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increase food sensitization by 80 percent if vitamin D deficient with specific genotypes</title><link>/posts/increase-food-sensitization-by-80-percent-if-vitamin-d-deficient-with-specific-genotypes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increase-food-sensitization-by-80-percent-if-vitamin-d-deficient-with-specific-genotypes.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="genevitamin-d-interactions-on-food-sensitization-a-prospective-birth-cohort-study">Gene–vitamin D interactions on food sensitization: a prospective birth cohort study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Liu X, &lt;a href="mailto:xnliu@childrensmemorial.org">xnliu@childrensmemorial.org&lt;/a> ;Wang G, Hong X, Wang D, Tsai H-J, Zhang S, Arguelles L, Kumar R, Wang H, Liu R, Zhou Y, Pearson C, Ortiz K, Schleimer R, Holt P, Pongracic J, Price HE, Langman C, Wang X.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Allergy 2011; DOI: 10.1111/j.1398-9995.2011.02681.x; Article first published online: 5 AUG 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:? It has been hypothesized that vitamin D deficiency (VDD) contributes to the development of &lt;strong>food sensitization (FS)&lt;/strong> and then food allergy. However, the epidemiological evidence is conflicting. We aim to examine whether cord blood VDD is associated with FS and whether such association can be modified by genetic variants in a prospective birth cohort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Huge increase in food allergies in Australia may be due to low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/huge-increase-in-food-allergies-in-australia-may-be-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/huge-increase-in-food-allergies-in-australia-may-be-due-to-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostshypothesis-adolescent-allergies-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1604hypothesis-adolescent-allergies-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levelsa">&lt;a href="/posts/hypothesis-adolescent-allergies-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1604">Hypothesis: adolescent allergies associated with low vitamin D levels&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="allergy-statistics-for-many-countrieshttpbarbfeickcomvaccinationsallergy403-statisticshtm-not-just-australia">&lt;a href="http://barbfeick.com/vaccinations/allergy/403-statistics.htm">Allergy statistics for many countries&lt;/a>, not just Australia&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5X&lt;/strong> increase in hospital admissions due to food allergies in children 1994-2005&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eczema and hay fever up &lt;strong>3X&lt;/strong> in past 30 years&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="overview-asthma-and-vitamin-dpostsoverview-asthma-and-vitamin-d">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-asthma-and-vitamin-d">Overview Asthma and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There appears to be strong evidence that increasing vitamin D decreases asthma&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Australia had a huge increase in Asthma in the 90’s (perhaps also due to low levels of vitamin D)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Narcolepsy with Cataplexy was 5X higher if low Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/narcolepsy-with-cataplexy-was-5x-higher-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/narcolepsy-with-cataplexy-was-5x-higher-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-vitamin-d-in-narcolepsy-with-cataplexy">Low Vitamin D in Narcolepsy with Cataplexy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bertrand Carlander1, Anne Marie Puech-Cathala2, Isabelle Jaussent3, Sabine Scholz1, Sophie Bayard1,3, Valérie Cochen1, Yves Dauvilliers1,3*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 National Reference Network for Narcolepsy, Department of Neurology, Hôpital Gui-de-Chauliac, CHU Montpellier, Montpellier, France, 2 Laboratoire d&amp;rsquo;Hormonologie, Hôpital Lapeyronie, CHU Montpellier, Montpellier, France, 3 Inserm U1061, University of Montpellier 1, Montpellier, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Narcolepsy with cataplexy (NC) is currently thought to be an autoimmune-mediated disorder in which environmental risk factors make a significant contribution to its development. It was proposed that &lt;strong>vitamin D deficiency plays a role in autoimmune diseases&lt;/strong> . Here we investigated whether NC can be associated with 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) level deficiency in patients with NC compared with gender- and age-matched normal controls.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus 8X more likely to not even have 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/lupus-8x-more-likely-to-not-even-have-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-8x-more-likely-to-not-even-have-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-an-increased-autoimmune-response-in-healthy-individuals-and-in-patients-with-systemic-lupus-erythematosus">Vitamin D deficiency is associated with an increased autoimmune response in healthy individuals and in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ann Rheum Dis. 2011 May 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ritterhouse LL, Crowe SR, Niewold TB, Kamen DL, Macwana SR, Roberts VC, Dedeke AB, Harley JB, Scofield RH, Guthridge JM, James JA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Arthritis and Clinical Immunology, Oklahoma Medical Research Foundation, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is widespread and has been associated with many chronic diseases, including autoimmune disorders. A study was undertaken to explore the impact of low vitamin D levels on autoantibody production in healthy individuals, as well as B cell hyperactivity and interferon ? (IFN?) activity in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Allergy - Overview</title><link>/posts/allergy-overview.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/allergy-overview.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="might-peanut-allergy-be-associated-with-low-vitamin-d--asked-perplexity-ai-july-2024">Might peanut allergy be associated with low vitamin D? asked Perplexity AI July 2024&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There is evidence suggesting a potential association between peanut allergy and low vitamin D levels. Several studies have explored this relationship, indicating that vitamin D deficiency might play a role in the development of food allergies, including peanut allergy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Evidence Supporting the Association&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Australian Study&lt;/strong> :&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>An Australian study found that infants with low vitamin D levels were more likely to have egg or peanut allergies and multiple allergies compared to those with normal vitamin D levels. This suggests that vitamin D might have a protective role against the development of food allergies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces hair loss - many studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-hair-loss-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-hair-loss-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> Vitamins, such as vitamin D, are needed to reduce hair loss&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> Chemotherapy reduces vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>OBSERVATION:&lt;/strong> Vitamin D reduces hair loss due to chemotherapy: reasons include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D can reduce the amount of chemo needed, so less hair is killed off&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fewer chemo results in less reduction in Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D can keep the hair healthy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/#hl=en&amp;amp;pwst=1&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=bv-VTe3EBsfiiAL744T0CA&amp;amp;ved=0CBgQvwUoAQ&amp;amp;q=%22hair%20loss%22%20chemotherapy%20%22vitamin%20d%22&amp;amp;spell=1&amp;amp;fp=cc8e06da34e9bc37">Google search &amp;ldquo;hair loss&amp;rdquo; chemotherapy &amp;ldquo;vitamin d&amp;rdquo; &lt;/a> 3,60,000 hits Nov2019&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#89700-hair-and-vitamin-d-results-in-google-scholar---feb-2025">89,700 Hair and Vitamin D results in Google Scholar - Feb 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#evaluation-of-the-safety-and-effectiveness-of-nutritional-supplements-for-treating-hair-loss---nov2022">Evaluation of the Safety and Effectiveness of Nutritional Supplements for Treating Hair Loss - Nov 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#role-of-vitamin-d-in-hair-loss-a-short-review-2021">Role of vitamin D in hair loss: A short review – 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hair-and-the-founder-of-vitamindwiki">Hair and the founder of VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#noticed-more-hair-growth-after-added-gluathione-protein-and-weekly-omega-3--may-2025">Noticed more hair growth after added Gluathione, Protein, and weekly Omega-3 May 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#great-hair-regrowth-june-2012-henry-lahore-admin-ofvitamindwiki">Great hair regrowth June 2012: Henry Lahore, admin of VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#observation--vitamin-d3--cofactors--massage--has-worked-extremely-well-forme">Observation: &lt;strong>Vitamin D3 + cofactors + massage&lt;/strong> has worked extremely well for me.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#my-beard-growth-perhaps-aided-by-vitamin-d-andzinc">My beard growth, perhaps aided by Vitamin D and Zinc&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-level-laser-therapy-helps-hairgrowth---2019-note-lllt-known-to-increase-vitamin-dlevels">Low-Level Laser Therapy helps hair growth - 2019 (note LLLT known to increase Vitamin D levels)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#great-hair-regrowth-june-2012-henry-lahore-admin-ofvitamindwiki-1">Great hair regrowth June 2012: Henry Lahore, admin of VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#observation--vitamin-d3--cofactors--massage--has-worked-extremely-well-forme-1">Observation: &lt;strong>Vitamin D3 + cofactors + massage&lt;/strong> has worked extremely well for me.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-hair-cycle-and-vitamin-d-receptor--2011">The Hair Cycle and Vitamin D Receptor - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#female-hair">Female hair&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#female-pattern-hair-loss-treatment-augmented-by-vitamin-d--jan2022">Female pattern hair loss treatment augmented by Vitamin D – Jan 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#serum-ferritin-and-vitamin-d-in-female-hair-loss-do-they-play-a-role--2013">Serum ferritin and vitamin D in female hair loss: do they play a role? - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#serum-vitamin-d-in-patients-with-alopecia-areata-sept2016">Serum Vitamin D in Patients with alopecia areata Sept 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#female-pattern-hair-loss-treatment-augmented-by-vitamin-d--jan2022-1">Female pattern hair loss treatment augmented by Vitamin D – Jan 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#google-scholar-18000-hits-for-alopecia-and-vitamin-d-as-of-march2022">Google Scholar 18,000 hits for alopecia and &amp;ldquo;Vitamin D&amp;rdquo; as of March 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsovitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsoweb">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web---graying-hair-is-related-to-several-vitamin-d-deficientdiseases">See also web - graying hair is related to several vitamin D deficient diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dr-greger-low-zinc-too-much-mercury-or-smoking-causes-hairloss">Dr. Greger: Low Zinc, too much Mercury, or smoking causes hair loss&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-helps-minoxidil-rogaine-re-growhair">Vitamin D helps minoxidil (rogaine) re-grow hair&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#role-of-vitamin-d-in-hair-loss-a-short-review-2021-1">Role of vitamin D in hair loss: A short review – 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#feb-2010-meta-analysishttpdermatologycdliborg1602reviewsvitamindrashidhtml-of-vitamin-d-and-hairloss">&lt;a href="http://dermatology.cdlib.org/1602/reviews/vitamind/rashid.html">Feb 2010 Meta-analysis&lt;/a> of Vitamin D and Hair Loss&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-hair-cycle-and-vitamin-d-receptor--2011-1">The Hair Cycle and Vitamin D Receptor - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#serum-ferritin-and-vitamin-d-in-female-hair-loss-do-they-play-a-rolehttpwwwncbinlmnihgovpubmedterm23428658--2013">&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=23428658">Serum ferritin and vitamin d in female hair loss: do they play a role?&lt;/a> - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#serum-vitamin-d-in-patients-with-alopecia-areata-sept2016-1">Serum Vitamin D in Patients with alopecia areata Sept 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#female-pattern-hair-loss-vitd-135-ng-vs-controlsno-fp-hair-loss-172-ng-2016">Female pattern hair loss VitD: 13.5 ng vs controls(no FP hair loss): 17.2 ng -2016&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsovitamindwiki-1">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#google-scholar-18000-hits-for-alopecia-and-vitamin-d-as-of-march2022-1">Google Scholar 18,000 hits for alopecia and &amp;ldquo;Vitamin D&amp;rdquo; as of March 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsoweb-1">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web---graying-hair-is-related-to-several-vitamin-d-deficientdiseases-1">See also web - graying hair is related to several vitamin D deficient diseases&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-level-laser-therapy-helps-hairgrowth">Low-Level Laser Therapy helps hair growth&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#my-beard-growth-perhaps-aided-by-vitamin-d-andzinc-1">My beard growth, perhaps aided by Vitamin D and Zinc&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dr-greger-low-zinc-too-much-mercury-or-smoking-causes-hairloss-1">Dr. Greger: Low Zinc, too much Mercury, or smoking causes hair loss&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-helps-minoxidil-rogaine-re-growhair-1">Vitamin D helps minoxidil (rogaine) re-grow hair&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="89700-hair-and-vitamin-d-results-in-google-scholar---feb-2025">89,700 Hair and Vitamin D results in Google Scholar - Feb 2025&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?q=hair%20%22vitamin%20d%22&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0,48">Google Scholar here are some of them&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D less than 15 ng associated with some allergies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-15-ng-associated-with-some-allergies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-15-ng-associated-with-some-allergies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Vitamin D levels and food and environmental allergies in the United States: Results from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2005-2006.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2011 Feb 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sharief S, Jariwala S, Kumar J, Muntner P, Melamed ML.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Rush University Medical Center, Chicago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Previous research supports a possible link between low vitamin D levels and atopic disease. However, the association between low vitamin D levels and total and allergen-specific IgE levels has not been studied.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X more allergy to peanuts if child born with low UV</title><link>/posts/3x-more-allergy-to-peanuts-if-child-born-with-low-uv.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-more-allergy-to-peanuts-if-child-born-with-low-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="season-of-birth-and-childhood-food-allergy-in-australia">Season of birth and childhood food allergy in Australia.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2011 Feb 22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01151.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01151.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mullins RJ, Clark S, Katelaris C, Smith V, Solley G, Camargo Jr CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John James Medical Centre, Deakin, ACT, Australia Medical School, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT, Australia Clinical Immunology,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Faculty of Health, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia Division of General Internal Medicine,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Professor, Department of Medicine, University of Western Sydney, Sydney, Australia Rose Cottage Medical Centre, Launceston,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More childhood allergies when vitamin D is less than 15 ng</title><link>/posts/more-childhood-allergies-when-vitamin-d-is-less-than-15-ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-childhood-allergies-when-vitamin-d-is-less-than-15-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-levels-and-food-and-environmental-allergies-in-the-united-states-results-from-the-national-health-and-nutrition-examination-survey-2005-2006">Vitamin D levels and food and environmental allergies in the United States: Results from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2005-2006&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2011.01.017 | How to Cite or Link Using DOI&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shimi Sharief MDa, Sunit Jariwala MDb, Juhi Kumar MD, MPHc, Paul Muntner PhDd and Michal L. Melamed MD, MHSe, &lt;a href="mailto:michal.melamed@einstein.yu.edu">michal.melamed@einstein.yu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Medicine, Rush University Medical Center, Chicago&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Allergy and Immunology, Montefiore Medical Center, Bronx, NY&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>