<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Breathing on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/breathing.html</link><description>Recent content in Breathing on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/breathing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Less COPD if vitamin D more than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/less-copd-if-vitamin-d-more-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-copd-if-vitamin-d-more-than-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-levels-do-not-increase-the-risk-of-chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-diseasehttpwwweurekalertorgpub_releases2011-11ats-lvd110111php20-press-release">&lt;a href="http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2011-11/ats-lvd110111.php%20">Low vitamin D levels do not increase the risk of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease&lt;/a> press release&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Vitamin D levels are not related to acute exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (AECOPD) in patients with severe COPD, according to a large prospective cohort study involving 973 North American patients. The findings were published online ahead of the print edition of the American Thoracic Society&amp;rsquo;s American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children with low vitamin D were 4.8X more likely to get asthma</title><link>/posts/children-with-low-vitamin-d-were-48x-more-likely-to-get-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-with-low-vitamin-d-were-48x-more-likely-to-get-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="note-many-asthmatics-were-also-low-on-span-stylecolorf00magnesiumspan">Note: many asthmatics were also low on &lt;span style="color:#F00;">Magnesium&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-strong-predictor-of-asthma-in-children">Vitamin D Deficiency as a Strong Predictor of Asthma in Children.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int Arch Allergy Immunol. 2011 Oct 6;157(2):168-175.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bener A, Ehlayel MS, Tulic MK, Hamid Q.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medical Statistics and Epidemiology, Hamad Medical Corporation, Department of Public Health, Weill Cornell Medical College, Doha, Qatar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Epidemiological studies suggest a link between vitamin D deficiency in early life and development of asthma in later life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Asthma worse with low Vitamin D only at age 4 - cohort study</title><link>/posts/asthma-worse-with-low-vitamin-d-only-at-age-4-cohort-study.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/asthma-worse-with-low-vitamin-d-only-at-age-4-cohort-study.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-micronutrient-concentrations-and-childhood-asthma-the-piama-birth-cohort-study">Serum micronutrient concentrations and childhood asthma: the PIAMA birth cohort study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2011 Sep 19. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01190.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01190.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van Oeffelen AA, Bekkers MB, Smit HA, Kerkhof M, Koppelman GH, Haveman-Nies A, van der A DL, Jansen EH, Wijga AH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Human Nutrition, Wageningen University, Wageningen, The Netherlands Institute for Risk Assessment Sciences, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands Center for Prevention and Health Services Research, National Institute for Public Health and the Environment (RIVM), Bilthoven, The Netherlands Julius Center for Health Sciences and Primary Care, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands Department of Epidemiology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, The Netherlands Department of Pulmonology and Pediatric Allergology, Beatrix Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, The Netherlands Center for Nutrition and Health, National Institute for Public Health and the Environment (RIVM), Bilthoven, The Netherlands Laboratory for Health Protection Research, National Institute for Public Health and the Environment (RIVM), Bilthoven, The Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epigenetics and Vitamin D – many studies</title><link>/posts/epigenetics-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/epigenetics-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#restoring-vitamin-d-reduces-epigenetic-aging---may-2024">Restoring Vitamin D reduces epigenetic Aging - May 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#evidence-in-support-of-the-strong-epigenetic-theory-of-aging---oct2020">Evidence in support of the Strong Epigenetic Theory of Aging - Oct 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-copd-and-epigenetics--aug2011">Vitamin D, COPD, and Epigenetics – Aug 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#noteable-epigenetics-and-vitamin-d-studies-by-perplexity-ai-april2024httpswwwperplexityaisearchplease-provide-a-kzo7nlw3tgm5ajrxvrnzq">Noteable Epigenetics and Vitamin D studies &lt;a href="https://www.perplexity.ai/search/Please-provide-a-kzO7NLw3Tgm5AjRxVrN.zQ">by Perplexity AI April 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epigenetics-can-change-vdr-activation-without-changing-the-dna">Epigenetics can change VDR activation without changing the DNA&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="restoring-vitamin-d-reduces-epigenetic-aging---may-2024">Restoring Vitamin D reduces epigenetic Aging - May 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.naturalhealthresearch.org/the-association-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-with-the-rate-of-epigenetic-aging/%20">The Association of Vitamin D Supplementation with the Rate of Epigenetic Aging&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crescendo of papers on Asthma, Allergy, and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/crescendo-of-papers-on-asthma-allergy-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/crescendo-of-papers-on-asthma-allergy-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="asthma-allergy-and-respiratory-infections-the-vitamin-d-hypothesis">Asthma, allergy and respiratory infections: the vitamin D hypothesis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>S. Bozzetto1, S. Carraro1, G. Giordano1, A. Boner2, E. Baraldi1 &lt;a href="mailto:baraldi@pediatria.unipd.it">baraldi@pediatria.unipd.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Allergy Unit and Respiratory Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, University of Padova, Padova&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Pediatrics, University Hospital, Verona, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Allergy &amp;amp; Clinical Immunology , 21 SEP 2011, DOI: 10.1111/j.1398-9995.2011.02711.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The recent discovery that every tissue in the human body has vitamin D receptors and that vitamin D has pleiotropic effects has prompted an increased interest in this hormone. Vitamin D deficiency is widespread and on the increase. There is no consensus on the serum vitamin D levels to consider appropriate for global health, the cutoffs for its deficiency, or the doses to use for its supplementation. Vitamin D seems to correlate closely with host reactions against various respiratory infections. Epidemiological studies have shown that low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels are associated with a higher risk of upper and lower respiratory infections in children and a shortage of vitamin D may contribute to asthmatic patients’ symptoms and morbidity rates. There are studies highlighting associations between childhood asthma, fetal lung and/or immune development, and maternal vitamin D intake. An insufficiency of this vitamin also seems to be implicated in the onset of childhood atopy and food allergies. The hypothesis is that vitamin D could have a central role in these pathological situations and that it may represent a novel preventive and/or therapeutic strategy. This article reviews and discusses published data on the relationship between vitamin D and asthma and allergy, emphasizing the need for controlled, prospective studies on vitamin D supplementation to clarify whether it has a role in the prevention of and treatment for asthma and allergic conditions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Severe asthma strongly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/severe-asthma-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/severe-asthma-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chronic Bronchitis 2.6 percent less likely for every extra ng of vitamin D – CDC</title><link>/posts/chronic-bronchitis-26-percent-less-likely-for-every-extra-ng-of-vitamin-d-cdc.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-bronchitis-26-percent-less-likely-for-every-extra-ng-of-vitamin-d-cdc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Allergies and bone health may be connected by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/allergies-and-bone-health-may-be-connected-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/allergies-and-bone-health-may-be-connected-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="allergy-and-the-bone-unexpected-relationships">Allergy and the bone: unexpected relationships.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2011 Sep;107(3):202-6. Epub 2011 May 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gatti D, Senna G, Viapiana O, Rossini M, Passalacqua G, Adami S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatologic Department, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To examine the relationships between allergy and bone metabolism as represented by the effects of antihistamines and leukotriene modifiers on bone resorption and formation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DATA SOURCES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The major databases MEDLINE and Scopus were searched using the keywords bone metabolism, bone resorption, bone formation, antihistamines, h1 antagonist, leukotriene antagonist, and leukotriene modifier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smoking while pregnant lowers vitamin D and increases child asthma by 3.6 X</title><link>/posts/smoking-while-pregnant-lowers-vitamin-d-and-increases-child-asthma-by-36-x.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/smoking-while-pregnant-lowers-vitamin-d-and-increases-child-asthma-by-36-x.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The title of this page is the conclusion of a &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Sept 2011&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> study – bullet point summary are below&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FACT: Being Pregnant greatly increases the need for vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FACT: Smoking reduces vitamin D in the body&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FACT: Children born of women with lots of vitamin D are 5X less likely to get asthma&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VitaminDWiki interpretation of the study: Smoking ==&amp;gt; Reduce vitamin D ==&amp;gt; Increase chance of asthma in child&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV produces more than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/uv-produces-more-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-produces-more-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="modulation-of-the-immune-system-by-uv-radiation-more-than-just-the-effects-of-vitamin-d">Modulation of the immune system by UV radiation: more than just the effects of vitamin D?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Immunol. 2011 Aug 19. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nri3045.">doi: 10.1038/nri3045.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hart PH, Gorman S, Finlay-Jones JJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telethon Institute for Child Health Research, Centre for Child Health Research, University of Western Australia, PO Box 855, Perth, Western Australia 6872, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Humans obtain most of their vitamin D through the exposure of skin to sunlight. The immunoregulatory properties of vitamin D have been demonstrated in studies showing that vitamin D deficiency is associated with poor immune function and increased disease susceptibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and wheeze – especially in seniors</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-wheeze-especially-in-seniors.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-wheeze-especially-in-seniors.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="low-vitamin-d-levels-are-associated-with-increased-risk-of-wheeze-especially-in-older-adults">Low vitamin D levels are associated with increased risk of wheeze, especially in older adults&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="published-online-august-1-2011httpwwwaaaaiorggloballatest-research-summariescurrent-jaci-researchlow-vitamin-d-levels-are-associated-with-increasedaspx">&lt;a href="http://www.aaaai.org/global/latest-research-summaries/Current-JACI-Research/low-vitamin-D-levels-are-associated-with-increased.aspx">Published Online: August 1, 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Although recent guidelines from the Institute of Medicine recommend supplementation with vitamin D only for prevention of bone-related diseases, there is accumulating evidence that vitamin D deficiency is implicated in respiratory disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a recent issue of The Journal of Allergy and Clinical and Immunology (JACI), Keet et al. assessed the relationship between serum vitamin D levels and self-reported wheeze and asthma in a large nationally representative survey (the National Health and Nutrition Examination Study 2005-2006).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis - vitamin D supplements caused allergy pandemic – 2009</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-supplements-caused-allergy-pandemic-2009.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-supplements-caused-allergy-pandemic-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="introduction-of-oral-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-the-rise-of-the-allergy-pandemic">Introduction of oral vitamin D supplementation and the rise of the allergy pandemic.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Allergy Asthma Clin Immunol. 2009 Nov 19;5(1):8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wjst M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Genetic Medicine, EURAC research, Drususallee 1, I-39100 Bozen, Italy. &lt;a href="mailto:wjst@helmholtz-muenchen.de">wjst@helmholtz-muenchen.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The history of the allergy pandemic is well documented, enabling us to put the vitamin D hypothesis into its historical context. The purpose of this study is to compare the prevalence of rickets, vitamin D supply, and allergy prevalence at 50-year intervals by means of a retrospective analysis of the literature since 1880. English cities in 1880 were characterized by an extremely high rickets prevalence, the beginning of commercial cod liver oil production, and the near absence of any allergic diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D supplements increased probability of allergic rhinitis by 66 percent - 2004</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-supplements-increased-probability-of-allergic-rhinitis-by-66-percent-2004.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-supplements-increased-probability-of-allergic-rhinitis-by-66-percent-2004.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="infant-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-allergic-conditions-in-adulthood-northern-finland-birth-cohort-1966">Infant vitamin d supplementation and allergic conditions in adulthood: northern Finland birth cohort 1966.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2004 Dec;1037:84-95.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hyppönen E, Sovio U, Wjst M, Patel S, Pekkanen J, Hartikainen AL, Järvelinb MR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Paediatric Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Institute of Child Health, 30 Guilford Street, London WC1N 1EH, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:e.hypponen@ich.ucl.ac.uk">e.hypponen@ich.ucl.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Allergen-induced secretion of Th2-type cytokines and IgE production have recently been reported to be increased in mice treated with 1,25(OH)(2)D, the active form of vitamin D. Our objective was to investigate whether vitamin D supplementation in infancy is associated with the risk of atopy, allergic rhinitis, and asthma. The Northern Finland Birth Cohort consists of all individuals in the two most northern provinces of Finland who were due to be born in 1966. Data on vitamin D supplementation during the first year of life was obtained in 1967.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sepsis is both prevented and treated by Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/sepsis-is-both-prevented-and-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sepsis-is-both-prevented-and-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary-of-sepsis-and-vitamin-d">Summary of Sepsis and Vitamin D&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki-recommendations-for-vitamin-d-treatment-of-sepsis-in-icu">VitaminDWiki recommendations for Vitamin D treatment of sepsis in ICU&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#people-with-sepis-have-poor-guts-vitamin-d-less-bio-available---perplexity-ai-june-2024">People with Sepis have poor guts (Vitamin D less bio-available) - Perplexity AI June 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#69100-hits-for-sepsis-vitamin-d---feb-2025-google-scholar">69,100 hits for sepsis &amp;ldquo;vitamin d&amp;rdquo; - Feb 2025 (Google Scholar)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#is-sepsis-treated-by-vitamin-d---asked-httpssearchsciphiai-jan-2024">Is sepsis treated by &amp;ldquo;Vitamin d&amp;rdquo;? - asked &lt;a href="https://search.sciphi.ai/">https://search.sciphi.ai/&lt;/a> Jan 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-in-icu-43-less-likely-to-die-in-30-days-if-happened-to-have-been-taking-vitamin-d--jan-2025">Sepsis in ICU: 43% less likely to die in 30 days if happened to have been taking vitamin D – Jan 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#no-consensus-on-sepsis-and-vitamin-d-type-amount-when-how-often---july-2023">No Consensus on Sepsis and Vitamin D: Type, Amount, When, How Often - July 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-an-underestimated-factor-in-sepsis--feb-2023">Vitamin D Deficiency: An Underestimated Factor in Sepsis? – Feb 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-strongly-associated-with-both-low-vitamin-d-and-poor-vitamin-d-receptors---jan2022">Sepsis strongly associated with both low vitamin D and poor Vitamin D Receptors - Jan 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#micronutrients-in-sepsis-and-covid-19-mostly-vitamin-d--april2021">Micronutrients in Sepsis and COVID-19 (mostly Vitamin D)- April 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-death-19-x-higher-risk-if-10-ng-of-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-march2020">Sepsis death 1.9 X higher risk if &amp;lt;10 ng of Vitamin D - meta-analysis March 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#200000-and-400000-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-septic-shock-length-of-stay---rct-june2015">200,000 and 400,000 IU of vitamin D reduced septic shock, length of stay - RCT June 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#12-x-more-likely-to-recover-from-septic-shock-in-24-hours-if-you-have-a-higher-level-of-vitamin-d--10-ng--2017">12 X more likely to recover from Septic Shock in 24 hours if you have a higher level of vitamin D (&amp;gt; 10 ng?) - 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-injection-of-300000-iu-of-vitamin-d-helped-in-a-small-rct---feb2017">Sepsis injection of 300,000 IU of vitamin D helped in a small RCT - Feb 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#two-meta-analyses-of-icu-and-vitamin-d---april-and-may2017">Two Meta-analyses of ICU and Vitamin D - April and May 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#high-dose--maint-dose-vitamin-d-reduce-mortality--large-rct2014">High dose + maint. dose Vitamin D reduce mortality – large RCT 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-only-people-who-died-of-sepsis-in-the-hospital-were-vitamin-d-deficient--april2017">The only people who died of sepsis in the hospital were vitamin D deficient – April 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-death-in-women-18x-more-likely-if-very-low-vitamin-d-nov2018">Sepsis death in women 1.8X more likely if very low vitamin D Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#review-of-vitamin-monotherapy-for-sepsis-vitamin-c-or-vitamin-d---july2021">Review of vitamin monotherapy for Sepsis: Vitamin C or Vitamin D - July 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#meta-analysis-concludes-sepsis-18-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---june2015">Meta-analysis concludes: Sepsis 1.8 X more likely if low vitamin D - June 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d---a-new-hope-for-septic-shock---july2013">Vitamin D - a new hope for septic shock - July 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-and-vitamin-d-inchildren">Sepsis and Vitamin D in children&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki">VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#role-of-vitamin-d-and-parathyroid-hormone-levels-in-prediction-of-late-onset-sepsis-among-preterm-infants---june-2024">Role of Vitamin D and Parathyroid Hormone Levels In Prediction of Late Onset Sepsis among Preterm Infants - June 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#neonatal-sepsis-47-x-more-likely-if-mother-was-vitamin-d-insufficient---feb2020">Neonatal Sepsis 4.7 X more likely if mother was Vitamin D insufficient - Feb 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#most-sepsis-children-also-have-a-chronic-disease-both-low-vitamin-d--aug2018">Most Sepsis children also have a chronic disease (both low vitamin D) – Aug 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-in-infants-8x-higher-if-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-india--june2021">Sepsis in infants 8X higher if less than 30 ng of vitamin D (India) – June 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-small-amount-of-vitamin-d-helped-children-with-sepsis---may-2020rct">A small amount of vitamin D helped children with Sepsis - May 2020 RCT&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-72-or-more-hours-after-birth-17-x-higher-risk-if-low-vitamin-d---nov2018">Sepsis 72 or more hours after birth: 1.7 X higher risk if low Vitamin D - Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#infants-with-sepsis-have-very-low-vitamin-d-levels--aug2014">Infants with sepsis have very low Vitamin D levels – Aug 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#neonatal-sepsis-48-x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor--june2018">Neonatal Sepsis 4.8 X more likely if poor Vitamin D receptor – June 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#neonates-are-17-x-more-likely-to-get-sepsis-if-they-low-vitamin-d-mothers-had-low-levels-as-well---july2018">Neonates are 1.7 X more likely to get Sepsis if they low vitamin D, mothers had low levels as well - July 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-in-general">Sepsis in general&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#is-sepsis-responsible-for-20-of-deaths-worldwide-asked-chat-gpt-jan-2-2024">Is Sepsis Responsible for 20% of Deaths Worldwide?: Asked Chat-GPT Jan 2, 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-overlaps-with-systemic-inflammatory-responsesyndrome">Sepsis overlaps with Systemic Inflammatory Response Syndrome&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-incidence-and-mortality-are-higher-than-many-other-healthproblems">Sepsis incidence and mortality are higher than many other health problems&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#severe-sepsis-increased-35x-in-adecade">Severe sepsis increased 3.5X in a decade.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#subtile-signs-of-sepsis---pintrest-2018httpswwwpinterestcompin544794886167487408">&lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/544794886167487408/">Subtile Signs of Sepsis - Pintrest -2018&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-myths-andfactshttpswwwpinnaclehealthorgwellness-libraryblog-and-staywellblog-homepostsepsis-the-silent-killer">&lt;a href="https://www.pinnaclehealth.org/wellness-library/blog-and-staywell/blog-home/post/sepsis-the-silent-killer">Sepsis Myths and Facts&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#i-nearly-died-from-sepsis--and-ignorance-of-this-condition-is-killing-millionshttpstheconversationcomi-nearly-died-from-sepsis-and-ignorance-of-this-condition-is-killing-millions-99051__-july2018">&lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/i-nearly-died-from-sepsis-and-ignorance-of-this-condition-is-killing-millions-99051#_=_">I nearly died from sepsis – and ignorance of this condition is killing millions&lt;/a>. July 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-treatment-other-than-vitamin-d">Sepsis treatment other than Vitamin D&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#flccc-sepsis-at-home-melatonin-vit-c-zinc-quercetin-curcumin-pre--probiotics---sept-2023">FLCCC: Sepsis at home: Melatonin, Vit. C, Zinc, Quercetin, Curcumin, Pre &amp;amp; Probiotics: - Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-c-perhaps-reducessepsis">Vitamin C perhaps reduces Sepsis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#update-on-vitamin-cocktail-without-vitamin-d---may2018">Update on Vitamin cocktail (without Vitamin D) - May 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-best-treated-by-thiamine-b1---vitamin-d-selenium-etc-also-considered---literature-review-july2018">Sepsis best treated by Thiamine (B1) - Vitamin D, Selenium, etc. also considered - literature review July 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="summary-of-sepsis-and-vitamin-d">Summary of Sepsis and Vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sepsis is more likely in those with poor immune systems&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Infants, the elderly, the sick, and those with low vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Additional 4 ng of vitamin D reduced chance of infection by 7 percent</title><link>/posts/additional-4-ng-of-vitamin-d-reduced-chance-of-infection-by-7-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/additional-4-ng-of-vitamin-d-reduced-chance-of-infection-by-7-percent.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D patent for treating immune system diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wo2008039409httpwwwwipointpatentscopesearchenwo2008039409-world-wide-patent---2008">&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/WO2008039409">(WO2008039409)&lt;/a> World-Wide patent - 2008&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="treatment-and-prevention-of-diseases-or-conditions-of-the--immune-system-or-infectious-diseases">TREATMENT AND PREVENTION OF DISEASES OR CONDITIONS OF THE &lt;strong>IMMUNE SYSTEM OR INFECTIOUS DISEASES&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>allergic rhinitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eczema,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>psoriasis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>food allergy,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>type-1 diabetes,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>ulcerative colitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>rheumatoid arthritis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>multiple sclerosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>lupus,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>tuberculosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>parasitic infection, etc,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Pulsed UV decreased peanut allergen by as much as 90 percent</title><link>/posts/pulsed-uv-decreased-peanut-allergen-by-as-much-as-90-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pulsed-uv-decreased-peanut-allergen-by-as-much-as-90-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="uf-researcher-reduces-allergens-in-peanuts-using-pulsed-lighthttpwwwphysorgcomnews2011-06-uf-allergens-peanuts-pulsedhtml">&lt;a href="http://www.physorg.com/news/2011-06-uf-allergens-peanuts-pulsed.html">UF researcher reduces allergens in peanuts using pulsed light&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="medical-xpress-june-9-2011-by-robert-h-wells">Medical Xpress, June 9, 2011 by Robert H. Wells&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A University of Florida researcher has developed a new technique to make peanuts safer for people with peanut allergies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wade Yang, an assistant professor in UF’s food science and human nutrition department, used pulsed ultraviolet light, or PUV, to reduce the allergenic potential of peanuts by &lt;strong>up to 90 percent.&lt;/strong> The study was published this week by the journal Food and Bioprocess Technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>100000 IU vitamin D monthly helps COPD patients – 3 RCT</title><link>/posts/100000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly-helps-copd-patients-3-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/100000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly-helps-copd-patients-3-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-improves-exercise-outcomes-in-patients-with-copd">Vitamin D Improves Exercise Outcomes In Patients With COPD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#copd-helped-by-100000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly---rct">COPD helped by 100,000 IU vitamin D monthly - RCT&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#100000-iu-monthly-helped-copd---rct-jan-2015">100,000 IU monthly helped COPD - RCT Jan 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#100000-iu-monthly-works-out-to-an-average-of-just-3300-iu-daily">100,000 IU monthly works out to an average of just 3,300 IU daily&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#100000-iu-monthly-helped-copd-rct-2012">100,000 IU monthly helped COPD RCT 2012&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#discussion-which-was-extracted-from-pdf-attached-to-the-bottom-of-this-page">Discussion which was extracted from PDF attached to the bottom of this page&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#based-on-published-research-listed-on-this-page-and-elsewhere-on-vitamindwiki">Based on published research listed on this page and elsewhere on VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-improves-exercise-outcomes-in-patients-with-copd">Vitamin D Improves Exercise Outcomes In Patients With COPD&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Medical News Today, 16 May 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sun exposure protects children from asthma</title><link>/posts/sun-exposure-protects-children-from-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sun-exposure-protects-children-from-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sunny-hours-and-variations-in-the-prevalence-of-asthma-in-schoolchildren-according-to-the-international-study-of-asthma-and-allergies-isaac-phase-iii-in-spain">Sunny hours and variations in the prevalence of asthma in schoolchildren according to the International Study of Asthma and Allergies (ISAAC) Phase III in Spain.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int J Biometeorol. 2011 May;55(3):423-34. Epub 2010 Aug 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arnedo-Pena A, García-Marcos L, Fernández-Espinar JF, Bercedo-Sanz A, Aguinaga-Ontoso I, González-Díaz C, Carvajal-Urueña I, Busquet-Monge R, Suárez-Varela MM, de Andoin NG, Batlles-Garrido J, Blanco-Quirós A, Varela AL, García-Hernández G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiology Division, Centre of Public Health, C/ L&amp;rsquo;Olivera 5, 2-C, 12005, Castellón, Spain, &lt;a href="mailto:arnedo_alb@gva.es">arnedo_alb@gva.es&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D for 6 year old boys predicted asthma at age 14</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-for-6-year-old-boys-predicted-asthma-at-age-14.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-for-6-year-old-boys-predicted-asthma-at-age-14.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-atopy-and-asthma-phenotypes-in-children-a-longitudinal-cohort-study">Vitamin d and atopy and asthma phenotypes in children: a longitudinal cohort study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eur Respir J. 2011 May 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hollams EM, Hart PH, Holt BJ, Serralha M, Parsons F, de Klerk NH, Zhang G, Sly PD, Holt PG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and Centre for Child Health Research, The University of Western Australia Perth Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has been linked in some studies with atopy- and asthma-associated phenotypes in children with established disease, but its role in disease inception at community level is less clear. To investigate associations between vitamin D status and biological signatures indicative of allergy and asthma development in children aged 6 and 14 years in Perth, Western Australia (32°S). Serum vitamin D was assayed in 989 6-year-olds and 1380 14-year-olds from an unselected community birth cohort; 689 were assessed at both ages. Vitamin D levels were assessed as a risk modifier for respiratory and allergic outcomes at both ages, utilising previously ascertained phenotypic data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Allergy - Overview</title><link>/posts/allergy-overview.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/allergy-overview.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="might-peanut-allergy-be-associated-with-low-vitamin-d--asked-perplexity-ai-july-2024">Might peanut allergy be associated with low vitamin D? asked Perplexity AI July 2024&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There is evidence suggesting a potential association between peanut allergy and low vitamin D levels. Several studies have explored this relationship, indicating that vitamin D deficiency might play a role in the development of food allergies, including peanut allergy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Evidence Supporting the Association&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Australian Study&lt;/strong> :&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>An Australian study found that infants with low vitamin D levels were more likely to have egg or peanut allergies and multiple allergies compared to those with normal vitamin D levels. This suggests that vitamin D might have a protective role against the development of food allergies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COPD and vitamin D in a vicious circle</title><link>/posts/copd-and-vitamin-d-in-a-vicious-circle.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/copd-and-vitamin-d-in-a-vicious-circle.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-disease-a-vicious-circle">Vitamin d deficiency and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease a vicious circle.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vitam Horm. 2011;86:379-99.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Janssens W, Mathieu C, Boonen S, Decramer M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Respiratory Division, University of Leuven, Herestraat 49, Leuven, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D and vitamin D deficiency strongly interact with different pathogenic mechanisms in COPD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prevalence of vitamin D deficiency is&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>particularly high in COPD patients,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>increases with the severity of COPD, and is&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>closely associated with osteoporosis prevalence.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Adequate calcium and vitamin D supplementation in COPD patients with documented deficiencies reduces the risk for falling and osteoporotic fractures, may indirectly reduce morbidity, and may potentially prevent the further deterioration of pulmonary function.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D less than 15 ng associated with some allergies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-15-ng-associated-with-some-allergies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-15-ng-associated-with-some-allergies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Vitamin D levels and food and environmental allergies in the United States: Results from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2005-2006.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2011 Feb 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sharief S, Jariwala S, Kumar J, Muntner P, Melamed ML.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Rush University Medical Center, Chicago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Previous research supports a possible link between low vitamin D levels and atopic disease. However, the association between low vitamin D levels and total and allergen-specific IgE levels has not been studied.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Are microbs – probiotics – vitamin D – allergy – asthma – obesity related</title><link>/posts/are-microbs-probiotics-vitamin-d-allergy-asthma-obesity-related.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/are-microbs-probiotics-vitamin-d-allergy-asthma-obesity-related.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="gut-microbiota-probiotics-and-vitamin-d-interrelated-exposures-influencing-allergy-asthma-and-obesity">Gut microbiota, probiotics, and vitamin D: Interrelated exposures influencing allergy, asthma, and obesity?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology; Clinical reviews in allergy and immunology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2011.02.015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ngoc P. Ly MD, MPHa &lt;a href="mailto:lyn@peds.ucsf.edu">lyn@peds.ucsf.edu&lt;/a>, Augusto Litonjua MD, MPHb, Diane R. Gold MD, MPHb and Juan C. Celedón MD, DrPHc&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Division of Pediatric Pulmonary Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, University of California San Francisco, Calif&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Channing Laboratory, Brigham and Women’s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, Mass&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COPD – Bone Metabolism – Osteoporosis – Vitamin D appear related</title><link>/posts/copd-bone-metabolism-osteoporosis-vitamin-d-appear-related.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/copd-bone-metabolism-osteoporosis-vitamin-d-appear-related.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="copd-bone-metabolism-and-osteoporosis">COPD, Bone Metabolism, and Osteoporosis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Chest. 2011 Mar;139(3):648-57.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lehouck A, Boonen S, Decramer M, Janssens W.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Respiratory Division, University Hospital Gasthuisberg, KUL, Herestraat 49, 3000 Leuven, Belgium. &lt;a href="mailto:wim.janssens@uz.kuleuven.be">wim.janssens@uz.kuleuven.be&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>COPD and osteoporosis are strongly associated because of common risk factors such as age, smoking, and inactivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, COPD-related systemic inflammation, &lt;strong>vitamin D deficiency&lt;/strong> , and the use of systemic corticosteroids enhance ongoing bone destruction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis, in turn, may cause fragility fractures, which further impair mobility and increase morbidity and mortality. Vertebral compression fractures and rib cage fractures in patients with COPD may also reduce pulmonary function or enhance exacerbations. Early prevention and treatment of osteoporosis in COPD is, therefore, important and should be based on integrated risk assessment tools such as FRAX, which take bone mineral density, history of fragility fractures, and population-specific clinical factors into account. As long as intervention studies focusing on the bone in COPD are lacking, a more rigorous application of existing treatment guidelines of osteoporosis in general is mandatory. PMID: 21362651&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Asthma and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-asthma-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-asthma-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-is-cost-effective-to-give-to-asthmatic-children-in-columbia---feb-2023">Vitamin D is cost-effective to give to asthmatic children in Columbia - Feb 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D supplementation for children with mild to moderate asthma: an economic evaluation&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Asthma . 2023 Feb 8;1-13. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/02770903.2023.2178007">doi: 10.1080/02770903.2023.2178007&lt;/a> PUBLISHER wants $62 for the PDF&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jefferson Antonio Buendía 1, Diana Guerrero Patiño 1, Erika Fernanda Lindarte 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction A large proportion of asthma patients remain uncontrolled despite using inhaled corticosteroids. Some add-on therapies such as vitamin D supplements have been recommended for this subgroup of patients. The purpose of this study was to assess the cost-utility of vitamin D supplementation in children with mild to moderate persistent asthma in Colombia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of Vitamin D reduces lung volume</title><link>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-reduces-lung-volume.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-reduces-lung-volume.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-causes-deficits-in-lung-function-and-alters-lung-structure">Vitamin D Deficiency Causes Deficits in Lung Function and Alters Lung Structure.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2011 Feb 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zosky GR, Berry LJ, Elliot JG, James AL, Gorman S, Hart PH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telethon Institute for Child Health Research, Subiaco, Western Australia, Australia; Centre for Child Health Research, University of Western Australia, Crawley, Western Australia, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RATIONALE: The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency is increasing and has been linked to obstructive lung diseases including &lt;strong>asthma and COPD&lt;/strong> . Recent studies suggest that vitamin D deficiency is associated with reduced lung function. The relationship between vitamin D deficiency and lung function is confounded by the association between physical activity levels and vitamin D status. Thus, causal data confirming a relationship between vitamin D and lung function are lacking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sleep Apnea and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/sleep-apnea-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sleep-apnea-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hypothesis-by-dr-gominak-in-texas-sleep-problems-and-sleep-apnea-are-due-to-a-lack-of-vitamins-d3-and-b12">Hypothesis by Dr. Gominak in Texas: Sleep problems and Sleep Apnea are due to a lack of vitamins D3 and B12&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="update-by-dr-gominak-nov-2011-poor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d---nov-2011postspoor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d">Update by Dr, Gominak Nov 2011 &lt;a href="/posts/poor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d">Poor sleep and lack of vitamin D - Nov 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h3 id="she-recommends-a-vitamin-d-level-of--70-85-ngml-with-daily-dose-of-10000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-not-work-as-well">She recommends a vitamin D level of 70-85 ng/ml, with daily dose of 10,000 IU vitamin D (weekly not work as well)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Here are links to her video, a few of the slides, and the PDF&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pneumonia and low vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/pneumonia-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pneumonia-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pneumonia Risk, intensity, and mortality are all associated with low vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#6-of-85-pneumonia-and-vitamin-d-publications-pubmed--april-2025httpspubmedncbinlmnihgovterm28pneumonia5btitle5d29and2822vitamind225btitle5d29sortrelevance">6 of 85 Pneumonia and Vitamin D publications &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%28Pneumonia%5BTitle%5D%29+AND+%28%22vitamin+d%22%5BTitle%5D%29&amp;amp;sort=relevance">PubMed- April 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#future-childhood-pneumonia-cut-in-half-by-300000-iu-of-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-oct-2020">Future childhood pneumonia cut in half by 300,000 IU of Vitamin D - meta-analysis Oct 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pneumonia-elderly-death-12x-more-likely-when-vitamin-d-less-than-12-ng--2011">Pneumonia elderly death 12X more likely when vitamin D less than 12 ng – 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-bacteria-pneumonia-causality-ignores-the-vitamin-d-receptor---march-2021">Vitamin D and bacteria pneumonia causality (ignores the Vitamin D Receptor) - March 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#type-of-pneumonia-viral-bacterial-fungal">Type of Pneumonia: viral, bacterial, fungal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#high-dose-vitamin-d-reduces-recurrent-pneumonia-by-half---meta-analysis-oct-2020">High-dose Vitamin D reduces recurrent pneumonia by half - meta-analysis Oct 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pneumonia-problems-in-china-might-by-treated-by-vitamin-a---dr-campbell-videos">Pneumonia problems in China might by treated by Vitamin A - Dr. Campbell Videos&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="6-of-85-pneumonia-and-vitamin-d-publications-pubmed--april-2025httpspubmedncbinlmnihgovterm28pneumonia5btitle5d29and2822vitamind225btitle5d29sortrelevance">6 of 85 Pneumonia and Vitamin D publications &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%28Pneumonia%5BTitle%5D%29+AND+%28%22vitamin+d%22%5BTitle%5D%29&amp;amp;sort=relevance">PubMed- April 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cost-effectiveness of high-dose vitamin D supplementation to reduce the occurrence of repeat episodes of pneumonia in children Nov 2024 &lt;a href="https://10.1186/s12962-024-00589-2">FREE PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many possible associations of increased asthma in black children</title><link>/posts/many-possible-associations-of-increased-asthma-in-black-children.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-possible-associations-of-increased-asthma-in-black-children.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="racial-disparities-in-pediatric-asthma-a-review-of-the-literature">Racial Disparities in Pediatric Asthma: A Review of the Literature.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Allergy Asthma Rep. 2010 Nov 24. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hill TD, Graham LM, Divgi V.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Georgia Pediatric Pulmonology Associates, 1100 Lake Hearn Drive, Suite 450, Atlanta, GA, 30342, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:tdhill@gppa.net">tdhill@gppa.net&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The burden of asthma disproportionately affects children living in economically disadvantaged urban communities. The relationships between ethnicity, genetic differences, lower socioeconomic status, poor medication adherence, greater exposure to environmental triggers, and absence of regular asthma care all contribute to this disparity. This review aims to identify and discuss recent studies on additional factors that may also impact to pediatric asthma disparity. The body of work examined in this review suggests that these disparities are the result of&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No association between low level of vitamin D and severity of Asthma</title><link>/posts/no-association-between-low-level-of-vitamin-d-and-severity-of-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-association-between-low-level-of-vitamin-d-and-severity-of-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="p14-does-vitamin-d-axis-have-an-effect-on-the-severity-of-asthma">P14 Does Vitamin D Axis have an effect on the severity of Asthma?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Thorax 2010;65:A82-A83 doi:10.1136/thx.2010.150961.14&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>R Sathyamurthy, 2. S Manney, 3. A Wood, 4. G Perkins, 5. C Webster, 6. MT Krishna, 7. AH Mansur; Heart of England NHS Trust, Birmingham, UK&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Background Vitamin D (VD) has been suggested to play a role in the development of asthma and frequency of asthma exacerbation1. Vitamin D Binding Protein (VDBP) is thought to influence the development of COPD through its immunomodulatory effect2. This study explores the role of vitamin D axis in relation to asthma severity.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>