<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Breathing on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/breathing.html</link><description>Recent content in Breathing on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/breathing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>More lung capacity (bronchial asthma, FEV1) associated with higher vitamin D</title><link>/posts/more-lung-capacity-bronchial-asthma-fev1-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-lung-capacity-bronchial-asthma-fev1-associated-with-higher-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-phenotypes-of-bronchial-asthma">Vitamin D and phenotypes of bronchial asthma&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Egyptian Journal of Chest Diseases and Tuberculosis. Available online 5 July 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R. Eman Shebl a, &lt;a href="mailto:emanshebl3000@yahoo.com">emanshebl3000@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Samah M. Shehata a,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maha Elgabry a,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Salah A.I. Ali b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hanaa H. Elsaid b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Chest Diseases, Faculty of Medicine, Zagazig University, Egypt&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Clinical Pathology, Faculty of Medicine, Zagazig University, Egypt&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many studies have suggested the role of vitamin D deficiency in both T-helper1 and T-helper2 diseases. The existence of associations of vitamin D with asthma and allergy remains uncertain. While some suggest that vitamin D may be protective, others suggest that vitamin D supplementation may increase the risk of allergy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Single dose of 200,000 IU of vitamin D during pregnancy did not reduce wheezing 3 years later</title><link>/posts/single-dose-of-200000-iu-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-did-not-reduce-wheezing-3-years-later.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/single-dose-of-200000-iu-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-did-not-reduce-wheezing-3-years-later.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="prenatal-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-child-respiratory-health-a-randomised-controlled-trial">Prenatal Vitamin D Supplementation and Child Respiratory Health: A Randomised Controlled Trial&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(6): e66627. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0066627&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen T. Goldring, Chris J. Griffiths, Adrian R. Martineau, Stephen Robinson, Christina Yu,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sheree Poulton, Jane C. Kirkby, Janet Stocks, Richard Hooper, Seif O. Shaheen, John O. Warner, Robert J. Boyle&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Observational studies suggest high prenatal vitamin D intake may be associated with reduced childhood wheezing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We examined the effect of prenatal vitamin D on childhood wheezing in an interventional study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and respiratory tract infections - Wikipedia</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-respiratory-tract-infections-wikipedia.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-respiratory-tract-infections-wikipedia.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 class="firstHeading" id="firstHeading" lang="en">
&lt;p>&lt;span>Vitamin D and respiratory tract infections&lt;/span>&lt;/h1>&lt;/p>
&lt;div id="siteSub">
&lt;p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="mw-jump" id="jump-to-nav">
&lt;p>Jump to: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vitamin_D_and_respiratory_tract_infections#mw-navigation">navigation&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vitamin_D_and_respiratory_tract_infections#p-search">search&lt;/a>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;table class="metadata plainlinks ambox ambox-content">&lt;tbody>&lt;tr>&lt;td class="mbox-image">
&lt;div style="width:52px;">
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="" height="40" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/f/f4/Ambox_content.png" width="40" />&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="mbox-text">
&lt;p>&lt;span class="mbox-text-span">This article &lt;b>needs more &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Identifying_reliable_sources_%28medicine%29" title="Wikipedia:Identifying reliable sources (medicine)">medical references&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Verifiability" title="Wikipedia:Verifiability">verification&lt;/a> or relies too heavily on primary sources&lt;/b>. &lt;span class="hide-when-compact">Please review the contents of the article and &lt;a class="external text" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Vitamin_D_and_respiratory_tract_infections&amp;amp;action=edit">add the appropriate references&lt;/a> if you can. Unsourced or poorly sourced material may be &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Verifiability#Burden_of_evidence" title="Wikipedia:Verifiability">removed&lt;/a>.&lt;/span> &lt;small>&lt;i>(October 2012)&lt;/i>&lt;/small> &lt;/span>&lt;/td>&lt;/p>
&lt;td class="mbox-imageright">
&lt;div style="width:52px;">
&lt;p>&lt;a class="image" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Rod_of_asclepius.png">&lt;img alt="Rod of asclepius.png" height="40" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/3d/Rod_of_asclepius.png/15px-Rod_of_asclepius.png" width="15" />&lt;/a>&lt;/div>&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>&lt;/tbody>&lt;/table>&lt;p>
&lt;p>A link between &lt;b>vitamin D and respiratory tract infections&lt;/b> has been hypothesised. According to the hypothesis, vitamin D deficiency may predispose to infection. Evidence supporting the hypothesis derives from some scientific studies and the observation that outbreaks of respiratory infections occur predominantly during months associated with lower exposure to the sun. Evidence against the hypothesis has also been reported. The &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Institute_of_Medicine" title="Institute of Medicine">Institute of Medicine&lt;/a> concluded in a 2011 report that the existing data were &amp;ldquo;not consistently supportive of a causal role&amp;rdquo; for the vitamin in reducing the risk of infection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children with pneumonia in Ethiopia were 22X more likely to have rickets – 1997</title><link>/posts/children-with-pneumonia-in-ethiopia-were-22x-more-likely-to-have-rickets-1997.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-with-pneumonia-in-ethiopia-were-22x-more-likely-to-have-rickets-1997.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="case-control-study-of-the-role-of-nutritional-rickets-in-the-risk-of-developing-pneumonia-in-ethiopian-children">Case-control study of the role of nutritional rickets in the risk of developing pneumonia in Ethiopian children.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Lancet. 1997 Jun 21;349(9068):1801-4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Muhe L, Lulseged S, Mason KE, Simoes EA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics and Child Health, Faculty of Medicine, Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Pneumonia is the most important cause of morbidity and mortality in children aged under 5 years worldwide. Studies in developing countries have suggested an association between nutritional rickets and pneumonia. Since both nutritional rickets and pneumonia are common in Ethiopia, we did a case-control study to determine the role of nutritional rickets in the development of pneumonia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Largest cause of infant deaths is respiratory infections, which is associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/largest-cause-of-infant-deaths-is-respiratory-infections-which-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/largest-cause-of-infant-deaths-is-respiratory-infections-which-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-to-improve-treatment-outcomes-among-children-diagnosed-with-respiratory-infections">Vitamin D supplementation to improve treatment outcomes among children diagnosed with respiratory infections&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.who.int/elena/titles/bbc/vitamind_pneumonia_children/en/index.html%20">e-Library of Evidence for Nutrition Actions (eLENA) &lt;/a>April 2011&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Acute lower respiratory infections, predominantly pneumonia, kill more children under the age of five in every region of the world 1 than any other cause. In 2007, of the estimated nine million child deaths that occurred globally, close to 20% or 1.8 million were attributable to pneumonia. Undernutrition has been shown to both increase the severity and overall prevalence of acute lower respiratory infections and is an important factor in determining the mortality rates from severe forms of respiratory infections1–4.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets in 80 percent of infants with severe pneumonia</title><link>/posts/rickets-in-80-percent-of-infants-with-severe-pneumonia.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-in-80-percent-of-infants-with-severe-pneumonia.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="frequency-of-nutritional-rickets-in-children-admitted-with-severe-pneumonia">Frequency of nutritional rickets in children admitted with severe pneumonia.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Pak Med Assoc. 2010 Sep;60(9):729-32.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Haider N, Nagi AG, Khan KM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Paediatric Medicine, National Institute of Child Health, Karachi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To determine the frequency of nutritional rickets in children hospitalized with severe pneumonia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHOD: This study was carried out at the department of paediatric medicine at National Institute of Child Health Karachi. It is a case series done over a period of six months from 15th November 2008 to 15th may 2009. Patients admitted (n=137) with severe pneumonia were included in the study and were investigated for presence of rickets with serum calcium, phosphorus and alkaline phosphatase. Those having low to normal calcium low phosphorus and raised alkaline phosphatase were labeled as having rickets. All data collected were entered on Performa. Children with familial, vitamin D dependent/resistant rickets, secondary rickets, and cerebral palsy or on anti convulsant therapy were excluded from this study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Respiratory Tract Infections – meta-analysis with charts</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-respiratory-tract-infections-meta-analysis-with-charts.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-respiratory-tract-infections-meta-analysis-with-charts.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-respiratory-tract-infections-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials">Vitamin D and Respiratory Tract Infections: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(6): e65835. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0065835&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter Bergman, Åsa U. Lindh, Linda Björkhem-Bergman, Jonatan D. Lindh&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Low levels of 25-OH vitamin D are associated with respiratory tract infection (RTI). However, results from randomized controlled trials are inconclusive. Therefore, we performed a systematic review and meta-analysis to assess the preventive effect of vitamin D supplementation on RTI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Season of birth associated with Pneumonia (10 %) and Multiple Sclerosis (30 %)</title><link>/posts/season-of-birth-associated-with-pneumonia-10-percent-and-multiple-sclerosis-30-percent.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/season-of-birth-associated-with-pneumonia-10-percent-and-multiple-sclerosis-30-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#no-effect-of-season-of-birth-on-risk-of-type-1-diabetes-cancer-schizophrenia-and-ischemic-heart-disease-while-some-variations-may-be-seen-for-pneumonia-and-multiple-sclerosis">No effect of season of birth on risk of type 1 diabetes, cancer, schizophrenia and ischemic heart disease, while some variations may be seen for pneumonia and multiple sclerosis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="no-effect-of-season-of-birth-on-risk-of-type-1-diabetes-cancer-schizophrenia-and-ischemic-heart-disease-while-some-variations-may-be-seen-for-pneumonia-and-multiple-sclerosis">No effect of season of birth on risk of type 1 diabetes, cancer, schizophrenia and ischemic heart disease, while some variations may be seen for pneumonia and multiple sclerosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermato Endocrinology: Volume 5, Issue 2 April/May/June 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Susanna við Streym, Lars Rejnmark, Leif Mosekilde and Peter Vestergaard&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COPD and Osteoporosis are related – vitamin D is one possible connection – 2013</title><link>/posts/copd-and-osteoporosis-are-related-vitamin-d-is-one-possible-connection-2013.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/copd-and-osteoporosis-are-related-vitamin-d-is-one-possible-connection-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="european-respiratory-monograph-59-copd-and-comorbidityhttpbooksgooglecombookshlenlrlang_enidt_tnga_8pnqcoifndpgpa26dq22vitamind22otszgr8mu7zgjsigkkcq8an4c0_bizpa5uhscgnbj30vonepageq22vitamin20d22ffalse">&lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=lang_en&amp;amp;id=T_tNgA_8pnQC&amp;amp;oi=fnd&amp;amp;pg=PA26&amp;amp;dq=%22vitamin+d%22&amp;amp;ots=zgr8mu7ZGj&amp;amp;sig=KKCq8aN4C0_BizPA5UHscgNBj30#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%22vitamin%20d%22&amp;amp;f=false">European Respiratory Monograph 59: COPD and Comorbidity&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>By Klaus F. Rabe, Jadwiga A. Wedzicha and Emiel F.M. Wouters&lt;/p>
&lt;p>can per read via Google – 87 references&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="chapter-7-osteoporosis-in-copd---4-pages">Chapter 7. Osteoporosis in COPD – 4 pages?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Elisabeth A.P.M. Romme*,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frank W.J.M. Smeenk*,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emiel F.M. Wouters# and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Erica P.A. Rutten&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dept of Respiratory Medicine, Catharina Hospital, Eindhoven, #Dept of Respiratory Medicine, Maastricht University Medical Centre, Maastricht University, Maastricht, and&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Program Development Centre, Centre of Expertise for Chronic Organ failure (CIRO+), Horn, The Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Non-TB lung disease (NTM) 4X more likely if less than 10 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/non-tb-lung-disease-ntm-4x-more-likely-if-less-than-10-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/non-tb-lung-disease-ntm-4x-more-likely-if-less-than-10-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="severe-vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-nontuberculous-mycobacterial-lung-disease-a-case-control-study">Severe vitamin D deficiency is associated with nontuberculous mycobacterial lung disease: a case-control study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Respirology, Vol. 18 Issue 4, DOI: 10.1111/resp.12109&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kyeongman Jeon1,†,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Su-Young Kim1,†,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Byeong-Ho Jeong1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boksoon Chang1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sung Jae Shin2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Won-Jung Koh1, &lt;a href="mailto:wjkoh@skku.edu">wjkoh@skku.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Samsung Medical Center, Sungkyunkwan University School of Medicine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Microbiology, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and objective: Previous studies have found evidence of an association between tuberculosis and vitamin D deficiency (VDD). However, the association between VDD and infection caused by nontuberculous mycobacteria (NTM) has never been studied. This study evaluated the prevalence and severity of VDD in NTM lung disease, and attempted to identify predictive factors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D, Vitamin A, or Vitamin E association with allergies and asthma</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-vitamin-a-or-vitamin-e-association-with-allergies-and-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-vitamin-a-or-vitamin-e-association-with-allergies-and-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="fat-soluble-vitamins-and-atopic-disease-what-is-the-evidence">Fat-soluble vitamins and atopic disease: what is the evidence?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Proc Nutr Soc. 2012 Feb;71(1):67-74. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/S002966511100334X.">doi: 10.1017/S002966511100334X.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Nov 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Litonjua AA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Channing Laboratory and Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Harvard Medical School, 181 Longwood Avenue, Boston, MA 02115, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:augusto.litonjua@channing.harvard.edu">augusto.litonjua@channing.harvard.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The prevalence of asthma and other atopic disorders continues to increase worldwide. Examination of the epidemiologic patterns has revealed that this rise has occurred primarily in western, industrialised countries and countries transitioning to this lifestyle. While many changes have occurred in human populations over the years, it has been hypothesised that some of the relevant changes that have led to the rise in asthma and atopic disorders have been the changes from a traditional diet to a more western diet consisting of decreased intake of fruits and vegetables (sources of antioxidant vitamins and carotenoids) leading to decreased intakes of vitamins E and A, and a decrease in sun exposure (e.g. greater time spent indoors and heavy use of sunscreen) leading to decreased circulating levels of vitamin D. This review will examine the evidence for an effect of fat-soluble vitamins (vitamins A, D and E) on the development and severity of asthma and allergies. While observational studies suggest that these vitamins may play a salutary role in asthma and allergies, large, well-designed clinical trials are lacking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pneumonia 2.6X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pneumonia-26x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pneumonia-26x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-and-the-risk-of-pneumonia-in-an-ageing-general-population">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 and the risk of pneumonia in an ageing general population&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Epidemiol Community Health doi:10.1136/jech-2012-202027&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alex Aregbesola, &lt;a href="mailto:alex.aregbesola@uef.fi">alex.aregbesola@uef.fi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sari Voutilainen,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tarja Nurmi,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jyrki K Virtanen,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kimmo Ronkainen,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomi-Pekka Tuomainen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Public Health and Clinical Nutrition, University of Eastern Finland, Kuopio, North Savo, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 5 October 2012; Revised 15 February 2013; Accepted 21 March 2013; Published Online First 17 April 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background Vitamin D has been suggested to have a role in infection defence and on the immune system. We therefore investigated the effect of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25(OH)D3) on the risk of incident hospitalised pneumonia in an ageing general population in eastern Finland.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Synergy between Vitamin D and corticosteroids in asthma – editorial</title><link>/posts/synergy-between-vitamin-d-and-corticosteroids-in-asthma-editorial.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/synergy-between-vitamin-d-and-corticosteroids-in-asthma-editorial.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-corticosteroids-in-asthma-synergy-interaction-and-potential-therapeutic-effects">Vitamin D and corticosteroids in asthma: synergy, interaction and potential therapeutic effects.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Expert Rev Respir Med. 2013 Apr;7(2):101-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1586/ers.12.85.">doi: 10.1586/ers.12.85.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Litonjua AA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Channing Division of Network Medicine and Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:augusto.litonjua@channing.harvard.edu">augusto.litonjua@channing.harvard.edu&lt;/a> .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why deficiencies in vitamin D and magnesium are linked to asthma</title><link>/posts/why-deficiencies-in-vitamin-d-and-magnesium-are-linked-to-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-deficiencies-in-vitamin-d-and-magnesium-are-linked-to-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;p>This article for VitaminDWiki comes from a phone interview and follow ups with a primary care physician who tested the 25-OH Vitamin D level in each of his asthmatic patients, using a desired target range of 50-100ng/ml (typically 80 +/- 10 ng/ml was attained). He employs vitamin D in conjunction with enhanced magnesium intake (oral +/- transdermal) and oral vitamin C (ascorbate). Serum calcium levels were always paired with the Vitamin D assays.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Severity of adult asthma associated with less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/severity-of-adult-asthma-associated-with-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/severity-of-adult-asthma-associated-with-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="severe-and-uncontrolled-adult-asthma-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-insufficiency-and-deficiency">Severe and uncontrolled adult asthma is associated with vitamin D insufficiency and deficiency&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Respiratory Research 2013, 14:25 doi:10.1186/1465-9921-14-25; Published: 22 February 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephanie Korn, Marisa Hübner, Matthias Jung, Maria Blettner and Roland Buhl&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has effects on the innate and adaptive immune system. In asthmatic children low vitamin D levels are associated with poor asthma control, reduced lung function, increased medication intake, and exacerbations. Little is known about vitamin D in adult asthma patients or its association with asthma severity and control.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Vitamin D reduces asthma – 2011</title><link>/posts/how-vitamin-d-reduces-asthma-2011.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-vitamin-d-reduces-asthma-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-mechanism-of-action-of-vitamin-d-in-the-asthmatic-lung">The Mechanism of Action of Vitamin D in the Asthmatic Lung&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Investig Med. Author manuscript; available in PMC 2012 December 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published in final edited form as: J Investig Med. 2011 December; 59(8): 1200–1202.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.231/JIM.0b013e31823279f0">doi: 10.231/JIM.0b013e31823279f0&lt;/a>, NIHMSID: NIHMS324409, PMCID: PMC3238450&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sabah F Iqbal, MDcorresponding author1,2,3 and Robert J Freishtat, MD, MPH1,2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D, or 1,25-di-hydroxy-vitamin D (1,25(OH)D) in its activated form, has long been recognized as a critical mediator in bone health. New research has identified 1,25(OH)D as also vital for respiratory health. Due to its intrinsic anti-inflammatory properties, 1,25(OH)D may be very important in people with asthma. This review article seeks to evaluate the current literature to delineate the potential mechanisms of action by which 1,25(OH)D impacts asthma. We summarize the evidence that 1,25(OH)D has receptors in multiple lung cell types and acts to abrogate asthma by several mechanisms: by promoting lung immunity, by decreasing inflammation, by slowing cell cycling, by reducing hyperplasia, and by enhancing the effects of exogenous steroids. Put together, there is compelling evidence for the role of vitamin D in asthma.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces asthma</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-asthma">Vitamin D and Asthma&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2012 January 15; 185(2): 124–132.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2012 January 15. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1164/rccm.201108-1502CI">doi: 10.1164/rccm.201108-1502CI&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3297088&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grace Paul,1 John M. Brehm,1 John F. Alcorn,1 Fernando Holguín,1 Shean J. Aujla,1 and Juan C. Celedóncorresponding author1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency and asthma are common conditions that share risk factors such as African American ethnicity, inner-city residence, and obesity. This review provides a critical examination of current experimental and epidemiologic evidence of a causal association between vitamin D status and asthma or asthma morbidity, including potential protective mechanisms such as antiviral effects and enhanced steroid responsiveness. Because most published epidemiologic studies of vitamin D and asthma or asthma morbidity are observational, a recommendation for or against vitamin D supplementation as preventive or secondary treatment for asthma is not advisable and must await results of ongoing clinical trials. Should these trials confirm a beneficial effect of vitamin D, others will be needed to assess the role of vitamin D supplementation to prevent or treat asthma in different groups such as infants, children of school age, and ethnic minorities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bronchiectasis strongly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/bronchiectasis-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bronchiectasis-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-chronic-bacterial-colonisation-and-disease-severity-in-bronchiectasis">Vitamin-D Deficiency Is Associated With Chronic Bacterial Colonisation and Disease Severity in Bronchiectasis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Thorax. 2013;68(1):39-47.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James D Chalmers, Brian J McHugh, Catherine Docherty, John R W Govan, Adam T Hill&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction Vitamin-D deficiency has been linked to an increased risk of respiratory infections. The objective of this study was to determine the frequency and clinical importance of vitamin-D deficiency in patients with bronchiectasis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods 25-hydroxyvitamin-D was measured by immunoassay in 402 stable patients with bronchiectasis. Patients were classified as vitamin-D deficient (serum 25-hydroxyvitamin-D &amp;lt;25 nmol/l), insufficient (25 nmol/l–74 nmol/l) or sufficient (≥75 nmol/l). Disease severity was assessed, including exacerbation frequency, measurement of airway inflammatory markers, sputum bacteriology and lung function over 3 years follow-up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU of vitamin D for just 5 days did not treat severe pneumonia – RCT</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-just-5-days-did-not-treat-severe-pneumonia-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-just-5-days-did-not-treat-severe-pneumonia-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-for-severe-pneumonia--a-randomized-controlled-trial">Vitamin D supplementation for severe pneumonia&amp;ndash;a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Indian Pediatr. 2012 Jun;49(6):449-54. Epub 2011 Aug 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choudhary N, Gupta P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, University College of Medical Sciences and Guru Teg Bahadur Hospital, Dilshad Garden, Delhi, India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Patients who remain critically ill for prolonged periods and require tracheotomy, defined as chronic critical illness (CCI), display elevated levels of bone resorption. The measurement of bone turnover markers reveals that osteoclastic bone resorption is not only enhanced but also uncoupled from osteoblastic bone formation. We examine the effect of ibandronate on bone turnover in patients with CCI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Respiratory infections reduced by 63 percent with 4000 IU vitamin D daily - RCT</title><link>/posts/respiratory-infections-reduced-by-63-percent-with-4000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/respiratory-infections-reduced-by-63-percent-with-4000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="highlights-of-report-in-swedishhttpwwwdagensmedicinsenyhetervitamin-d-bromsade-luftvagsinfektioner-translated-bygoogle">Highlights of &lt;a href="http://www.dagensmedicin.se/nyheter/vitamin-d-bromsade-luftvagsinfektioner/">Report in Swedish&lt;/a> translated by Google&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Peter Bergman and his colleagues are fortunate to have 140 patients in daily treatment for one year with either vitamin D (4000 IU) or a placebo.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The study was double-blind: neither the patients - all of which were susceptible to infections - nor caregivers knew who belonged to which group before the trial was over.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The results show that vitamin D reduced patient discomfort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces respiratory tract infections by 40 percent– meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-respiratory-tract-infections-by-40-percent-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-respiratory-tract-infections-by-40-percent-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Acute respiratory infection treated by vitamin D in 6 of 12 clinical trials – review</title><link>/posts/acute-respiratory-infection-treated-by-vitamin-d-in-6-of-12-clinical-trials-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/acute-respiratory-infection-treated-by-vitamin-d-in-6-of-12-clinical-trials-review.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Severity of difficult asthma not proportional to vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/severity-of-difficult-asthma-not-proportional-to-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/severity-of-difficult-asthma-not-proportional-to-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-the-difficult-asthma-population-findings-from-a-difficult-asthma-clinic">Vitamin D Deficiency in the Difficult Asthma Population; Findings from a Difficult Asthma Clinic&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Thorax 2012;67:A67, Poster session P8, Treating asthma&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VB Joshi1, B Dyke1, T Rahman1, C Townshend2, V Patil2, R Kurukullaratchy1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Respiratory Medicine, Mailpoint 52, Room CG-89, G-Level West Wing, Southampton General Hospital, Southampton, SO16 6YD, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 The David Hide Asthma and Allergy Research Centre, St Mary’s Hospital, Isle of Wight, PO30 5TG, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 X increased chance of death if have asthma – study of 200,000 people over 10 years</title><link>/posts/3-x-increased-chance-of-death-if-have-asthma-study-of-200000-people-over-10-years.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-x-increased-chance-of-death-if-have-asthma-study-of-200000-people-over-10-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="adult-asthma-and-risk-of-coronary-heart-disease-cerebrovascular-disease-and-heart-failure-a-prospective-study-of-2-matched-cohorts">Adult Asthma and Risk of Coronary Heart Disease, Cerebrovascular Disease, and Heart Failure: A Prospective Study of 2 Matched Cohorts&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Epidemiology, (2012), &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/aje/kws181">doi: 10.1093/aje/kws181&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carlos Iribarren*, Irina V. Tolstykh, Mary K. Miller, Erica Sobel and Mark D. Eisner&lt;/p>
&lt;p>?*Correspondence to Dr. Carlos Iribarren, Division of Research, Kaiser Permanente Medical Care Program, 2000 Broadway, Oakland, CA 94612 (e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:cgi@dor.kaiser.org">cgi@dor.kaiser.org&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abbreviations: CHD, coronary heart disease; CVD, cardiovascular disease; ICD-9, International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision; KPNC, Kaiser Permanente Northern California.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Deficiency is a Strong Predictor (4X) of Asthma in Children</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-is-a-strong-predictor-4x-of-asthma-in-children.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-is-a-strong-predictor-4x-of-asthma-in-children.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dial D for danger – absurd editorial in Thorax</title><link>/posts/dial-d-for-danger-absurd-editorial-in-thorax.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dial-d-for-danger-absurd-editorial-in-thorax.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dial-d-for-danger">Dial D for danger?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Andrew Bush, Ian Pavord, Editors&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thorax 2012;67:i doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2012-202790&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of us are following the vitamin D papers with the same apprehension as we contemplate our erratic teenage sons—huge potential for future good, but how much damage may be done to the family home and the parental psyche in the meantime? In this issue of Thorax, we feature two contributions to the unfolding Vitamin D story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Basic Science for the Chest Physician, &lt;a href="http://thorax.bmj.com/content/67/11/1018.abstract?sid=54537522-3561-499c-b812-522e657dc10d%20">Pfeffer and Hawrylowicz&lt;/a> steer the non-immunologists through the complexities of the actions of 1,25(OH)D3, which is now known to be generated in far more organs than just the kidney, the nuclear Vitamin D receptor, and the end-results on the expression of genes concerned in the adaptive and immune responses (see page 1017).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The lower the vitamin D level the more severe the rare bronchiectasis</title><link>/posts/the-lower-the-vitamin-d-level-the-more-severe-the-rare-bronchiectasis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-lower-the-vitamin-d-level-the-more-severe-the-rare-bronchiectasis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-chronic-bacterial-colonisation-and-disease-severity-in-bronchiectasis">Vitamin-D deficiency is associated with chronic bacterial colonisation and disease severity in bronchiectasis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Thorax doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2012-202125&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James D Chalmers1, Brian J McHugh1, Catherine Docherty2, John R W Govan2, Adam T Hill1,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 The University of Edinburgh/MRC Centre for Research Inflammation, The Queen&amp;rsquo;s Medical Research Institute, Edinburgh, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Cystic Fibrosis Group, University of Edinburgh, School of Medicine and Veterinary Medicine, Edinburgh, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Respiratory Medicine, Royal Infirmary of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors on mechanical ventilation having very low vitamin D died sooner</title><link>/posts/seniors-on-mechanical-ventilation-having-very-low-vitamin-d-died-sooner.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-on-mechanical-ventilation-having-very-low-vitamin-d-died-sooner.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-poor-outcomes-and-increased-mortality-in-severely-ill-patients">Vitamin D deficiency is associated with poor outcomes and increased mortality in severely ill patients.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>QJM. 2012 Jul;105(7):633-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/qjmed/hcs014.">doi: 10.1093/qjmed/hcs014.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Feb 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arnson Y, Gringauz I, Itzhaky D, Amital H. &lt;a href="mailto:hamital@netvision.net.il">hamital@netvision.net.il&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine B, Sheba Medical Center, Tel-Hashomer 52621, Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D plays a seminal role in many homeostatic mechanisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this study, we assessed the correlation between circulating vitamin D levels and mortality rates in critically ill patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Just 300 IU daily of vitamin D reduced respiratory infections by 50% – RCT</title><link>/posts/just-300-iu-daily-of-vitamin-d-reduced-respiratory-infections-by-50-percent-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/just-300-iu-daily-of-vitamin-d-reduced-respiratory-infections-by-50-percent-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Respiratory problems will decrease with increased vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-respiratory-problems-will-decrease-with-increased-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-respiratory-problems-will-decrease-with-increased-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Asthmatic corticosteroid treatment – get the least improvement if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/asthmatic-corticosteroid-treatment-get-the-least-improvement-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/asthmatic-corticosteroid-treatment-get-the-least-improvement-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-and-inhaled-corticosteroid-treatment-on-lung-function-in-children">The Effect of Vitamin D and Inhaled Corticosteroid Treatment on Lung Function in Children.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2012 Jul 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wu AC, Tantisira K, Li L, Fuhlbrigge AL, Weiss ST, Litonjua A; for the Childhood Asthma Management Program Research Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harvard Medical School and Harvard Pilgrim Health Care, Department of Population Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts, United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RATIONALE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low vitamin D levels are associated with asthma and decreased airway responsiveness. Treatment with inhaled corticosteroids improves airway responsiveness and asthma control.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COPD reduce 2X if severely deficient and treated with 3,300 IU daily average of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/copd-reduce-2x-if-severely-deficient-and-treated-with-3300-iu-daily-average-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/copd-reduce-2x-if-severely-deficient-and-treated-with-3300-iu-daily-average-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="span-stylecolor00fnote-there-are-2-studies-on-this-pagespan">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Note: There are 2 studies on this page&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="high-doses-of-vitamin-d-to-reduce-exacerbations-in-chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-disease-a-randomized-trial">High doses of vitamin D to reduce exacerbations in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a randomized trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ann Intern Med. 2012 Jan 17;156(2):105-14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lehouck A, Mathieu C, Carremans C, Baeke F, Verhaegen J, Van Eldere J, Decallonne B, Bouillon R, Decramer M, Janssens W.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University Hospitals Leuven, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels have been associated with lower FEV(1), impaired immunologic control, and increased airway inflammation. Because many patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) have vitamin D deficiency, effects of vitamin D supplementation may extend beyond preventing osteoporosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Acute lower respiratory infection 5X more frequent with low vitamin D intake</title><link>/posts/acute-lower-respiratory-infection-5x-more-frequent-with-low-vitamin-d-intake.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/acute-lower-respiratory-infection-5x-more-frequent-with-low-vitamin-d-intake.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Quarterly vitamin D3 is too infrequent – it increases the occurrence of pneumonia</title><link>/posts/quarterly-vitamin-d3-is-too-infrequent-it-increases-the-occurrence-of-pneumonia.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/quarterly-vitamin-d3-is-too-infrequent-it-increases-the-occurrence-of-pneumonia.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="is-quarterly-bolus-vitamin-d3-supplementation-adequate-to-prevent-childhood-pneumonia">Is quarterly bolus vitamin D3 supplementation adequate to prevent childhood pneumonia?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>?Transl Pediatr 2012 Jun 11. DOI: 10.3978/j.issn.2224-4336.2012.06.01&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ursula Thiem1, Enikö Kállay2, Kyra Borchhardt1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Medicine III, Division of Nephrology and Dialysis, Medical University of Vienna, Spitalgasse 23, Vienna, Austria;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Pathophysiology and Allergy Research, Medical University of Vienna, Spitalgasse 23, Vienna, Austria&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corresponding to: Priv.-Doz. Dr. Kyra Borchhardt, Department of Medicine III, Division of Nephrology and Dialysis, Medical University of Vienna, Spitalgasse 23, 1090 Vienna, Austria. Email: &lt;a href="mailto:kyra.borchhardt@meduniwien.ac.at">kyra.borchhardt@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COPD patients 4X more likely to have low Vitamin D – 2 articles in 2012</title><link>/posts/copd-patients-4x-more-likely-to-have-low-vitamin-d-2-articles-in-2012.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/copd-patients-4x-more-likely-to-have-low-vitamin-d-2-articles-in-2012.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and asthma – Review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-asthma-review.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-asthma-review.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Recurrence of child pneumonia delayed by 100000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/recurrence-of-child-pneumonia-delayed-by-100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/recurrence-of-child-pneumonia-delayed-by-100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-to-children-diagnosed-with-pneumonia-in-kabul-a-randomised-controlled-trial">Effects of vitamin D supplementation to children diagnosed with pneumonia in Kabul: a randomised controlled trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trop Med Int Health. 2010 Oct;15(10):1148-55. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-3156.2010.02578.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-3156.2010.02578.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2010 Aug 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manaseki-Holland S, Qader G, Isaq Masher M, Bruce J, Zulf Mughal M, Chandramohan D, Walraven G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kabul Medical University, Kabul, Afghanistan. Aga Khan Health Services, Kabul, Afghanistan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine whether (i) supplementation of oral 100,000 iu of vitamin D(3) (cholecalciferol) along with antibiotics will reduce the duration of illness in children with pneumonia; (ii) supplementation will reduce the risk of repeat episodes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One third of lung disease patients in China had less than 4ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/one-third-of-lung-disease-patients-in-china-had-less-than-4ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/one-third-of-lung-disease-patients-in-china-had-less-than-4ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="lung-cancer-and-benign-lung-diseases-in-patients-with-serious-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-eastern-china">Lung cancer and benign lung diseases in patients with serious vitamin D deficiency in eastern China.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology, 2012 ASCO Annual Meeting Proceedings (Post-Meeting Edition).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol 30, No 15_suppl (May 20 Supplement), 2012: e12010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2012 American Society of Clinical Oncology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rong Li, Jing Wu, Liwen Xiong and Baohui Han&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Pulmonary Medicine of Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai, China; The Biochemical Laboratory of Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai, China; Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai, China&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and the Lung – professional book 2012</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-lung-professional-book-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-lung-professional-book-2012.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Asthma strongly associated with modification in vitamin D genes</title><link>/posts/asthma-strongly-associated-with-modification-in-vitamin-d-genes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/asthma-strongly-associated-with-modification-in-vitamin-d-genes.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>100 percent of Acute Respiratory Failure patients had low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/100-percent-of-acute-respiratory-failure-patients-had-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/100-percent-of-acute-respiratory-failure-patients-had-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="abstract-pdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-this-page">Abstract PDF is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/h4></description></item><item><title>95 percent of astmatics low on vitamin D -esp high BMI</title><link>/posts/95-percent-of-astmatics-low-on-vitamin-d-esp-high-bmi.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/95-percent-of-astmatics-low-on-vitamin-d-esp-high-bmi.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolor00fpdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-this-pagespan">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-of-asthma-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1433">Overview of Asthma and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Low Vitamin D Associated With Decreased Vital Capacity Of Lung</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-decreased-vital-capacity-of-lung.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-decreased-vital-capacity-of-lung.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolor00fabstract-pdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-this-pagespan">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Abstract PDF is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Severe adult asthma strongly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/severe-adult-asthma-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/severe-adult-asthma-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolor00fabstract-pdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-this-pagespan">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Abstract PDF is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-asthma-and-vitamin-d">Overview Asthma and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Binding Protein, And Airflow In COPD</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-binding-protein-and-airflow-in-copd.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-binding-protein-and-airflow-in-copd.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D Genes associated with Childhood Asthma And Lung Function</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-genes-associated-with-childhood-asthma-and-lung-function.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-genes-associated-with-childhood-asthma-and-lung-function.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolor00fabstract-pdf-is-attached-at-bottom-of-this-pagespan">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Abstract PDF is attached at bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-asthma-and-vitamin-d">Overview Asthma and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>ICU patients with pneumonia stay 7 days longer if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/icu-patients-with-pneumonia-stay-7-days-longer-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/icu-patients-with-pneumonia-stay-7-days-longer-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Acetaminophen (Tylenol) increases asthma</title><link>/posts/acetaminophen-tylenol-increases-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/acetaminophen-tylenol-increases-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="hypothesis-acetaminophen-reduces-vitamin-d-which-increases-asthma">Hypothesis: Acetaminophen reduces vitamin D, which increases asthma&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update: Acetaminophen Linked to Autism and Other Neurological Disorders in Children; Oct 2022&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://greenmedinfo.com/blog/acetaminophen-linked-autism-and-other-neurological-disorders-children">GreenMed info&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Citing new studies linking the analgesic drug acetaminophen (a chemical also known as paracetamol or by brand names Tylenol and Panadol) to the development of neurological conditions such as autism, attention-deficit disorder and hyperactivity in their children, women in the United States have filed 87 lawsuits in seven states against several pharmacies . . . &amp;quot;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lung disease, vitamin D, and epigenetics</title><link>/posts/lung-disease-vitamin-d-and-epigenetics.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lung-disease-vitamin-d-and-epigenetics.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-susceptibility-of-chronic-lung-diseases-role-of-epigenetics">Vitamin D and susceptibility of chronic lung diseases: role of epigenetics.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Front Pharmacol. 2011;2:50. Epub 2011 Aug 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sundar IK, Rahman I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lung Biology and Disease Program, Department of Environmental Medicine, University of Rochester Medical Center Rochester, NY, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is linked to accelerated decline in lung function, increased inflammation, and reduced immunity in chronic lung diseases. Epidemiological studies have suggested that vitamin D insufficiency is associated with low lung function in susceptible subjects who are exposed to higher levels of environmental agents (airborne particulates). Recent studies have highlighted the role of vitamin D and vitamin D receptor (VDR) in regulation of several genes that are involved in inflammation, immunity, cellular proliferation, differentiation, and apoptosis. Vitamin D has also been implicated in reversal of steroid resistance and airway remodeling, which are the hallmarks of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and severe asthma. VDR protein level is decreased in lungs of patients with COPD. VDR deficient mice develop an abnormal lung phenotype with characteristics of COPD, such as airspace enlargement and decline in lung function associated with increased lung inflammatory cellular influx, and immune-lymphoid aggregates formation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of infectious diseases vitamin D trials</title><link>/posts/review-of-infectious-diseases-vitamin-d-trials.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-infectious-diseases-vitamin-d-trials.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pulmonary disease and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pulmonary-disease-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pulmonary-disease-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-pulmonary-disease-copd-asthma-infection-and-cancer">The role of vitamin D in Pulmonary disease: COPD, asthma, infection, and cancer&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Christian Herr 3,1, Timm Greulich 1, Rembert A Koczulla 1, Silke Meyer 2, Tetyana Zakharkina 3,1, Meret Branscheidt 1, Rebecca Eschmann 1 and Robert Bals 3,1*&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Corresponding author: Robert Bals &lt;a href="mailto:robert.bals@uks.eu">robert.bals@uks.eu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>1 Department of Internal Medicine, Division for Pulmonary Diseases, Philipps-Universtät Marburg, 35043 Marburg, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology &amp;amp; Diabetology, Department of Internal Medicine, University Hospital Marburg, 35043 Marburg, Germany&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lung and Vitamin D – Special Issue</title><link>/posts/lung-and-vitamin-d-special-issue.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lung-and-vitamin-d-special-issue.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breathing by seniors harder when have low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/breathing-by-seniors-harder-when-have-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breathing-by-seniors-harder-when-have-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-pulmonary-function-in-older-disabled-community-dwelling-women">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Pulmonary Function in Older Disabled Community-Dwelling Women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2011 Dec 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Semba RD, Chang SS, Sun K, Cappola AR, Ferrucci L, Fried LP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Smith Building, M015, 400 North Broadway, Baltimore, MD 21287. &lt;a href="mailto:rdsemba@jhmi.edu">rdsemba@jhmi.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent studies have expanded the functions of vitamin D to a possible role in pulmonary function.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our objective was to examine the relationship between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D), serum parathyroid hormone, and pulmonary function in older women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D in asthma and allergy – editorial</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-in-asthma-and-allergy-editorial.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-in-asthma-and-allergy-editorial.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-in-asthma-and-allergy-what-next">Vitamin D in asthma and allergy: what next?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>European Respiratory Journal December 1, 2011 vol. 38 no. 6 1255-1257&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S.T. Weiss and A.A. Litonjua&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Channing Laboratory, Brigham and Women’s Hospital, Boston, MA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S.T. Weiss, Channing Laboratory, Harvard School of Medicine, 181 Longwood Ave, Boston, MA 02115, USA. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:scott.weiss@channing.harvard.edu">scott.weiss@channing.harvard.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="click-herehttpwwwersjorgukcontent3861255full20-for-online-version-with-hyperlinks">&lt;a href="http://www.ersj.org.uk/content/38/6/1255.full%20">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for online version with hyperlinks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Much of the original work on vitamin D and asthma incidence focused on birth cohort studies. These studies examined the effect of maternal intake of vitamin D during pregnancy and its impact on asthma/wheeze in the first few years of life &lt;span>[1–3]&lt;/span>. In all three of these methodologically well-performed birth cohort studies, higher maternal intake of vitamin D was associated with a lower incidence of asthma and wheeze in the child. However, one cohort study with very a small sample size and high loss to follow-up may have obtained spurious negative results as a consequence of these significant methodological flaws &lt;sup>[4]&lt;/sup>. Another relevant concern is that the positive studies did not measure vitamin D directly but simply looked at maternal vitamin D intake, mostly from supplements, as a proxy for vitamin D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High maternal vitamin D resulted in 30 percent less infant problems with breathing</title><link>/posts/high-maternal-vitamin-d-resulted-in-30-percent-less-infant-problems-with-breathing.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-maternal-vitamin-d-resulted-in-30-percent-less-infant-problems-with-breathing.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-in-pregnancy-and-risk-of-lower-respiratory-tract-infections-wheezing-and-asthma-in-offspring">Maternal Vitamin D Status in Pregnancy and Risk of Lower Respiratory Tract Infections, Wheezing, and Asthma in Offspring.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Epidemiology. 2011 Nov 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morales E, Romieu I, Guerra S, Ballester F, Rebagliato M, Vioque J, Tardón A, Rodriguez Delhi C, Arranz L, Torrent M, Espada M, Basterrechea M, Sunyer J; on behalf of the INMA Project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the a Center for Research in Environmental Epidemiology (CREAL), Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain; b Hospital del Mar Research Institute (IMIM), Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain; c CIBER Epidemiología y Salud Pública (CIBERESP), Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain; d National Institute of Public Health, Cuernavaca, Mexico; eCenter for Public Health Research (CSISP), Valencia, Spain; fUniversity of Valencia, Valencia, Spain; gRey Juan Carlos University, Madrid, Spain; hDepartmento de Salud Pública, Hospital San Agustín, Servicio de Salud del Principado de Asturias (SESPA), Avilés, Asturias, Spain; iOviedo University, Asturias, Spain; jHospital San Agustin, Servicio de Salud del Principado de Asturias (SESPA), Avilés, Asturias, Spain; kServicio de Pediatría, Hospital Universitario Donostia, Servicio Vasco de Salud, Osakidetza, Euskadi, Spain; lDepartamento de Pediatría, Facultad de Medicina y Odontología, Universidad del País Vasco (UPV/EHU), Euskadi, Spain; mArea de Salud de Menorca, IB-SALUT, Menorca, Spain; nClinical Chemistry Unity, Public Health Laboratory of Bilbao, Euskadi, Spain; and oSubdirección de Salud Pública de Gipuzkoa, Departamento de Sanidad del Gobierno Vasco, Euskadi, Spain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less COPD if vitamin D more than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/less-copd-if-vitamin-d-more-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-copd-if-vitamin-d-more-than-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-levels-do-not-increase-the-risk-of-chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-diseasehttpwwweurekalertorgpub_releases2011-11ats-lvd110111php20-press-release">&lt;a href="http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2011-11/ats-lvd110111.php%20">Low vitamin D levels do not increase the risk of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease&lt;/a> press release&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Vitamin D levels are not related to acute exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (AECOPD) in patients with severe COPD, according to a large prospective cohort study involving 973 North American patients. The findings were published online ahead of the print edition of the American Thoracic Society&amp;rsquo;s American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children with low vitamin D were 4.8X more likely to get asthma</title><link>/posts/children-with-low-vitamin-d-were-48x-more-likely-to-get-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-with-low-vitamin-d-were-48x-more-likely-to-get-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="note-many-asthmatics-were-also-low-on-span-stylecolorf00magnesiumspan">Note: many asthmatics were also low on &lt;span style="color:#F00;">Magnesium&lt;/span>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-strong-predictor-of-asthma-in-children">Vitamin D Deficiency as a Strong Predictor of Asthma in Children.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int Arch Allergy Immunol. 2011 Oct 6;157(2):168-175.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bener A, Ehlayel MS, Tulic MK, Hamid Q.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medical Statistics and Epidemiology, Hamad Medical Corporation, Department of Public Health, Weill Cornell Medical College, Doha, Qatar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Epidemiological studies suggest a link between vitamin D deficiency in early life and development of asthma in later life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Asthma worse with low Vitamin D only at age 4 - cohort study</title><link>/posts/asthma-worse-with-low-vitamin-d-only-at-age-4-cohort-study.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/asthma-worse-with-low-vitamin-d-only-at-age-4-cohort-study.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-micronutrient-concentrations-and-childhood-asthma-the-piama-birth-cohort-study">Serum micronutrient concentrations and childhood asthma: the PIAMA birth cohort study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2011 Sep 19. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01190.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01190.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van Oeffelen AA, Bekkers MB, Smit HA, Kerkhof M, Koppelman GH, Haveman-Nies A, van der A DL, Jansen EH, Wijga AH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Human Nutrition, Wageningen University, Wageningen, The Netherlands Institute for Risk Assessment Sciences, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands Center for Prevention and Health Services Research, National Institute for Public Health and the Environment (RIVM), Bilthoven, The Netherlands Julius Center for Health Sciences and Primary Care, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands Department of Epidemiology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, The Netherlands Department of Pulmonology and Pediatric Allergology, Beatrix Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, The Netherlands Center for Nutrition and Health, National Institute for Public Health and the Environment (RIVM), Bilthoven, The Netherlands Laboratory for Health Protection Research, National Institute for Public Health and the Environment (RIVM), Bilthoven, The Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epigenetics and Vitamin D – many studies</title><link>/posts/epigenetics-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/epigenetics-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#restoring-vitamin-d-reduces-epigenetic-aging---may-2024">Restoring Vitamin D reduces epigenetic Aging - May 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#evidence-in-support-of-the-strong-epigenetic-theory-of-aging---oct2020">Evidence in support of the Strong Epigenetic Theory of Aging - Oct 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-copd-and-epigenetics--aug2011">Vitamin D, COPD, and Epigenetics – Aug 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#noteable-epigenetics-and-vitamin-d-studies-by-perplexity-ai-april2024httpswwwperplexityaisearchplease-provide-a-kzo7nlw3tgm5ajrxvrnzq">Noteable Epigenetics and Vitamin D studies &lt;a href="https://www.perplexity.ai/search/Please-provide-a-kzO7NLw3Tgm5AjRxVrN.zQ">by Perplexity AI April 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epigenetics-can-change-vdr-activation-without-changing-the-dna">Epigenetics can change VDR activation without changing the DNA&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="restoring-vitamin-d-reduces-epigenetic-aging---may-2024">Restoring Vitamin D reduces epigenetic Aging - May 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.naturalhealthresearch.org/the-association-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-with-the-rate-of-epigenetic-aging/%20">The Association of Vitamin D Supplementation with the Rate of Epigenetic Aging&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crescendo of papers on Asthma, Allergy, and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/crescendo-of-papers-on-asthma-allergy-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/crescendo-of-papers-on-asthma-allergy-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="asthma-allergy-and-respiratory-infections-the-vitamin-d-hypothesis">Asthma, allergy and respiratory infections: the vitamin D hypothesis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>S. Bozzetto1, S. Carraro1, G. Giordano1, A. Boner2, E. Baraldi1 &lt;a href="mailto:baraldi@pediatria.unipd.it">baraldi@pediatria.unipd.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Allergy Unit and Respiratory Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, University of Padova, Padova&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Pediatrics, University Hospital, Verona, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Allergy &amp;amp; Clinical Immunology , 21 SEP 2011, DOI: 10.1111/j.1398-9995.2011.02711.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The recent discovery that every tissue in the human body has vitamin D receptors and that vitamin D has pleiotropic effects has prompted an increased interest in this hormone. Vitamin D deficiency is widespread and on the increase. There is no consensus on the serum vitamin D levels to consider appropriate for global health, the cutoffs for its deficiency, or the doses to use for its supplementation. Vitamin D seems to correlate closely with host reactions against various respiratory infections. Epidemiological studies have shown that low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels are associated with a higher risk of upper and lower respiratory infections in children and a shortage of vitamin D may contribute to asthmatic patients’ symptoms and morbidity rates. There are studies highlighting associations between childhood asthma, fetal lung and/or immune development, and maternal vitamin D intake. An insufficiency of this vitamin also seems to be implicated in the onset of childhood atopy and food allergies. The hypothesis is that vitamin D could have a central role in these pathological situations and that it may represent a novel preventive and/or therapeutic strategy. This article reviews and discusses published data on the relationship between vitamin D and asthma and allergy, emphasizing the need for controlled, prospective studies on vitamin D supplementation to clarify whether it has a role in the prevention of and treatment for asthma and allergic conditions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Severe asthma strongly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/severe-asthma-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/severe-asthma-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chronic Bronchitis 2.6 percent less likely for every extra ng of vitamin D – CDC</title><link>/posts/chronic-bronchitis-26-percent-less-likely-for-every-extra-ng-of-vitamin-d-cdc.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-bronchitis-26-percent-less-likely-for-every-extra-ng-of-vitamin-d-cdc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Allergies and bone health may be connected by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/allergies-and-bone-health-may-be-connected-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/allergies-and-bone-health-may-be-connected-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="allergy-and-the-bone-unexpected-relationships">Allergy and the bone: unexpected relationships.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2011 Sep;107(3):202-6. Epub 2011 May 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gatti D, Senna G, Viapiana O, Rossini M, Passalacqua G, Adami S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatologic Department, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To examine the relationships between allergy and bone metabolism as represented by the effects of antihistamines and leukotriene modifiers on bone resorption and formation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DATA SOURCES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The major databases MEDLINE and Scopus were searched using the keywords bone metabolism, bone resorption, bone formation, antihistamines, h1 antagonist, leukotriene antagonist, and leukotriene modifier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smoking while pregnant lowers vitamin D and increases child asthma by 3.6 X</title><link>/posts/smoking-while-pregnant-lowers-vitamin-d-and-increases-child-asthma-by-36-x.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/smoking-while-pregnant-lowers-vitamin-d-and-increases-child-asthma-by-36-x.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The title of this page is the conclusion of a &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Sept 2011&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> study – bullet point summary are below&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FACT: Being Pregnant greatly increases the need for vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FACT: Smoking reduces vitamin D in the body&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FACT: Children born of women with lots of vitamin D are 5X less likely to get asthma&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VitaminDWiki interpretation of the study: Smoking ==&amp;gt; Reduce vitamin D ==&amp;gt; Increase chance of asthma in child&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV produces more than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/uv-produces-more-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-produces-more-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="modulation-of-the-immune-system-by-uv-radiation-more-than-just-the-effects-of-vitamin-d">Modulation of the immune system by UV radiation: more than just the effects of vitamin D?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Immunol. 2011 Aug 19. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nri3045.">doi: 10.1038/nri3045.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hart PH, Gorman S, Finlay-Jones JJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telethon Institute for Child Health Research, Centre for Child Health Research, University of Western Australia, PO Box 855, Perth, Western Australia 6872, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Humans obtain most of their vitamin D through the exposure of skin to sunlight. The immunoregulatory properties of vitamin D have been demonstrated in studies showing that vitamin D deficiency is associated with poor immune function and increased disease susceptibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and wheeze – especially in seniors</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-wheeze-especially-in-seniors.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-wheeze-especially-in-seniors.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="low-vitamin-d-levels-are-associated-with-increased-risk-of-wheeze-especially-in-older-adults">Low vitamin D levels are associated with increased risk of wheeze, especially in older adults&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="published-online-august-1-2011httpwwwaaaaiorggloballatest-research-summariescurrent-jaci-researchlow-vitamin-d-levels-are-associated-with-increasedaspx">&lt;a href="http://www.aaaai.org/global/latest-research-summaries/Current-JACI-Research/low-vitamin-D-levels-are-associated-with-increased.aspx">Published Online: August 1, 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Although recent guidelines from the Institute of Medicine recommend supplementation with vitamin D only for prevention of bone-related diseases, there is accumulating evidence that vitamin D deficiency is implicated in respiratory disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a recent issue of The Journal of Allergy and Clinical and Immunology (JACI), Keet et al. assessed the relationship between serum vitamin D levels and self-reported wheeze and asthma in a large nationally representative survey (the National Health and Nutrition Examination Study 2005-2006).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis - vitamin D supplements caused allergy pandemic – 2009</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-supplements-caused-allergy-pandemic-2009.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-supplements-caused-allergy-pandemic-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="introduction-of-oral-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-the-rise-of-the-allergy-pandemic">Introduction of oral vitamin D supplementation and the rise of the allergy pandemic.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Allergy Asthma Clin Immunol. 2009 Nov 19;5(1):8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wjst M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Genetic Medicine, EURAC research, Drususallee 1, I-39100 Bozen, Italy. &lt;a href="mailto:wjst@helmholtz-muenchen.de">wjst@helmholtz-muenchen.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The history of the allergy pandemic is well documented, enabling us to put the vitamin D hypothesis into its historical context. The purpose of this study is to compare the prevalence of rickets, vitamin D supply, and allergy prevalence at 50-year intervals by means of a retrospective analysis of the literature since 1880. English cities in 1880 were characterized by an extremely high rickets prevalence, the beginning of commercial cod liver oil production, and the near absence of any allergic diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D supplements increased probability of allergic rhinitis by 66 percent - 2004</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-supplements-increased-probability-of-allergic-rhinitis-by-66-percent-2004.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-supplements-increased-probability-of-allergic-rhinitis-by-66-percent-2004.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="infant-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-allergic-conditions-in-adulthood-northern-finland-birth-cohort-1966">Infant vitamin d supplementation and allergic conditions in adulthood: northern Finland birth cohort 1966.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2004 Dec;1037:84-95.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hyppönen E, Sovio U, Wjst M, Patel S, Pekkanen J, Hartikainen AL, Järvelinb MR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre for Paediatric Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Institute of Child Health, 30 Guilford Street, London WC1N 1EH, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:e.hypponen@ich.ucl.ac.uk">e.hypponen@ich.ucl.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Allergen-induced secretion of Th2-type cytokines and IgE production have recently been reported to be increased in mice treated with 1,25(OH)(2)D, the active form of vitamin D. Our objective was to investigate whether vitamin D supplementation in infancy is associated with the risk of atopy, allergic rhinitis, and asthma. The Northern Finland Birth Cohort consists of all individuals in the two most northern provinces of Finland who were due to be born in 1966. Data on vitamin D supplementation during the first year of life was obtained in 1967.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sepsis is both prevented and treated by Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/sepsis-is-both-prevented-and-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sepsis-is-both-prevented-and-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary-of-sepsis-and-vitamin-d">Summary of Sepsis and Vitamin D&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki-recommendations-for-vitamin-d-treatment-of-sepsis-in-icu">VitaminDWiki recommendations for Vitamin D treatment of sepsis in ICU&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#people-with-sepis-have-poor-guts-vitamin-d-less-bio-available---perplexity-ai-june-2024">People with Sepis have poor guts (Vitamin D less bio-available) - Perplexity AI June 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#69100-hits-for-sepsis-vitamin-d---feb-2025-google-scholar">69,100 hits for sepsis &amp;ldquo;vitamin d&amp;rdquo; - Feb 2025 (Google Scholar)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#is-sepsis-treated-by-vitamin-d---asked-httpssearchsciphiai-jan-2024">Is sepsis treated by &amp;ldquo;Vitamin d&amp;rdquo;? - asked &lt;a href="https://search.sciphi.ai/">https://search.sciphi.ai/&lt;/a> Jan 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-in-icu-43-less-likely-to-die-in-30-days-if-happened-to-have-been-taking-vitamin-d--jan-2025">Sepsis in ICU: 43% less likely to die in 30 days if happened to have been taking vitamin D – Jan 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#no-consensus-on-sepsis-and-vitamin-d-type-amount-when-how-often---july-2023">No Consensus on Sepsis and Vitamin D: Type, Amount, When, How Often - July 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-an-underestimated-factor-in-sepsis--feb-2023">Vitamin D Deficiency: An Underestimated Factor in Sepsis? – Feb 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-strongly-associated-with-both-low-vitamin-d-and-poor-vitamin-d-receptors---jan2022">Sepsis strongly associated with both low vitamin D and poor Vitamin D Receptors - Jan 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#micronutrients-in-sepsis-and-covid-19-mostly-vitamin-d--april2021">Micronutrients in Sepsis and COVID-19 (mostly Vitamin D)- April 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-death-19-x-higher-risk-if-10-ng-of-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-march2020">Sepsis death 1.9 X higher risk if &amp;lt;10 ng of Vitamin D - meta-analysis March 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#200000-and-400000-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-septic-shock-length-of-stay---rct-june2015">200,000 and 400,000 IU of vitamin D reduced septic shock, length of stay - RCT June 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#12-x-more-likely-to-recover-from-septic-shock-in-24-hours-if-you-have-a-higher-level-of-vitamin-d--10-ng--2017">12 X more likely to recover from Septic Shock in 24 hours if you have a higher level of vitamin D (&amp;gt; 10 ng?) - 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-injection-of-300000-iu-of-vitamin-d-helped-in-a-small-rct---feb2017">Sepsis injection of 300,000 IU of vitamin D helped in a small RCT - Feb 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#two-meta-analyses-of-icu-and-vitamin-d---april-and-may2017">Two Meta-analyses of ICU and Vitamin D - April and May 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#high-dose--maint-dose-vitamin-d-reduce-mortality--large-rct2014">High dose + maint. dose Vitamin D reduce mortality – large RCT 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-only-people-who-died-of-sepsis-in-the-hospital-were-vitamin-d-deficient--april2017">The only people who died of sepsis in the hospital were vitamin D deficient – April 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-death-in-women-18x-more-likely-if-very-low-vitamin-d-nov2018">Sepsis death in women 1.8X more likely if very low vitamin D Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#review-of-vitamin-monotherapy-for-sepsis-vitamin-c-or-vitamin-d---july2021">Review of vitamin monotherapy for Sepsis: Vitamin C or Vitamin D - July 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#meta-analysis-concludes-sepsis-18-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---june2015">Meta-analysis concludes: Sepsis 1.8 X more likely if low vitamin D - June 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d---a-new-hope-for-septic-shock---july2013">Vitamin D - a new hope for septic shock - July 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-and-vitamin-d-inchildren">Sepsis and Vitamin D in children&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki">VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#role-of-vitamin-d-and-parathyroid-hormone-levels-in-prediction-of-late-onset-sepsis-among-preterm-infants---june-2024">Role of Vitamin D and Parathyroid Hormone Levels In Prediction of Late Onset Sepsis among Preterm Infants - June 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#neonatal-sepsis-47-x-more-likely-if-mother-was-vitamin-d-insufficient---feb2020">Neonatal Sepsis 4.7 X more likely if mother was Vitamin D insufficient - Feb 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#most-sepsis-children-also-have-a-chronic-disease-both-low-vitamin-d--aug2018">Most Sepsis children also have a chronic disease (both low vitamin D) – Aug 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-in-infants-8x-higher-if-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-india--june2021">Sepsis in infants 8X higher if less than 30 ng of vitamin D (India) – June 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-small-amount-of-vitamin-d-helped-children-with-sepsis---may-2020rct">A small amount of vitamin D helped children with Sepsis - May 2020 RCT&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-72-or-more-hours-after-birth-17-x-higher-risk-if-low-vitamin-d---nov2018">Sepsis 72 or more hours after birth: 1.7 X higher risk if low Vitamin D - Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#infants-with-sepsis-have-very-low-vitamin-d-levels--aug2014">Infants with sepsis have very low Vitamin D levels – Aug 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#neonatal-sepsis-48-x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor--june2018">Neonatal Sepsis 4.8 X more likely if poor Vitamin D receptor – June 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#neonates-are-17-x-more-likely-to-get-sepsis-if-they-low-vitamin-d-mothers-had-low-levels-as-well---july2018">Neonates are 1.7 X more likely to get Sepsis if they low vitamin D, mothers had low levels as well - July 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-in-general">Sepsis in general&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#is-sepsis-responsible-for-20-of-deaths-worldwide-asked-chat-gpt-jan-2-2024">Is Sepsis Responsible for 20% of Deaths Worldwide?: Asked Chat-GPT Jan 2, 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-overlaps-with-systemic-inflammatory-responsesyndrome">Sepsis overlaps with Systemic Inflammatory Response Syndrome&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-incidence-and-mortality-are-higher-than-many-other-healthproblems">Sepsis incidence and mortality are higher than many other health problems&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#severe-sepsis-increased-35x-in-adecade">Severe sepsis increased 3.5X in a decade.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#subtile-signs-of-sepsis---pintrest-2018httpswwwpinterestcompin544794886167487408">&lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/544794886167487408/">Subtile Signs of Sepsis - Pintrest -2018&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-myths-andfactshttpswwwpinnaclehealthorgwellness-libraryblog-and-staywellblog-homepostsepsis-the-silent-killer">&lt;a href="https://www.pinnaclehealth.org/wellness-library/blog-and-staywell/blog-home/post/sepsis-the-silent-killer">Sepsis Myths and Facts&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#i-nearly-died-from-sepsis--and-ignorance-of-this-condition-is-killing-millionshttpstheconversationcomi-nearly-died-from-sepsis-and-ignorance-of-this-condition-is-killing-millions-99051__-july2018">&lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/i-nearly-died-from-sepsis-and-ignorance-of-this-condition-is-killing-millions-99051#_=_">I nearly died from sepsis – and ignorance of this condition is killing millions&lt;/a>. July 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-treatment-other-than-vitamin-d">Sepsis treatment other than Vitamin D&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#flccc-sepsis-at-home-melatonin-vit-c-zinc-quercetin-curcumin-pre--probiotics---sept-2023">FLCCC: Sepsis at home: Melatonin, Vit. C, Zinc, Quercetin, Curcumin, Pre &amp;amp; Probiotics: - Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-c-perhaps-reducessepsis">Vitamin C perhaps reduces Sepsis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#update-on-vitamin-cocktail-without-vitamin-d---may2018">Update on Vitamin cocktail (without Vitamin D) - May 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sepsis-best-treated-by-thiamine-b1---vitamin-d-selenium-etc-also-considered---literature-review-july2018">Sepsis best treated by Thiamine (B1) - Vitamin D, Selenium, etc. also considered - literature review July 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="summary-of-sepsis-and-vitamin-d">Summary of Sepsis and Vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;!-- ~tc~ start ~/tc~ -->
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sepsis is more likely in those with poor immune systems&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Infants, the elderly, the sick, and those with low vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Additional 4 ng of vitamin D reduced chance of infection by 7 percent</title><link>/posts/additional-4-ng-of-vitamin-d-reduced-chance-of-infection-by-7-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/additional-4-ng-of-vitamin-d-reduced-chance-of-infection-by-7-percent.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D patent for treating immune system diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wo2008039409httpwwwwipointpatentscopesearchenwo2008039409-world-wide-patent---2008">&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/WO2008039409">(WO2008039409)&lt;/a> World-Wide patent - 2008&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="treatment-and-prevention-of-diseases-or-conditions-of-the--immune-system-or-infectious-diseases">TREATMENT AND PREVENTION OF DISEASES OR CONDITIONS OF THE &lt;strong>IMMUNE SYSTEM OR INFECTIOUS DISEASES&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>allergic rhinitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eczema,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>psoriasis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>food allergy,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>type-1 diabetes,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>ulcerative colitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>rheumatoid arthritis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>multiple sclerosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>lupus,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>tuberculosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>parasitic infection, etc,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Pulsed UV decreased peanut allergen by as much as 90 percent</title><link>/posts/pulsed-uv-decreased-peanut-allergen-by-as-much-as-90-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pulsed-uv-decreased-peanut-allergen-by-as-much-as-90-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="uf-researcher-reduces-allergens-in-peanuts-using-pulsed-lighthttpwwwphysorgcomnews2011-06-uf-allergens-peanuts-pulsedhtml">&lt;a href="http://www.physorg.com/news/2011-06-uf-allergens-peanuts-pulsed.html">UF researcher reduces allergens in peanuts using pulsed light&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="medical-xpress-june-9-2011-by-robert-h-wells">Medical Xpress, June 9, 2011 by Robert H. Wells&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A University of Florida researcher has developed a new technique to make peanuts safer for people with peanut allergies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wade Yang, an assistant professor in UF’s food science and human nutrition department, used pulsed ultraviolet light, or PUV, to reduce the allergenic potential of peanuts by &lt;strong>up to 90 percent.&lt;/strong> The study was published this week by the journal Food and Bioprocess Technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>100000 IU vitamin D monthly helps COPD patients – 3 RCT</title><link>/posts/100000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly-helps-copd-patients-3-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/100000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly-helps-copd-patients-3-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-improves-exercise-outcomes-in-patients-with-copd">Vitamin D Improves Exercise Outcomes In Patients With COPD&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#copd-helped-by-100000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly---rct">COPD helped by 100,000 IU vitamin D monthly - RCT&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#100000-iu-monthly-helped-copd---rct-jan-2015">100,000 IU monthly helped COPD - RCT Jan 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#100000-iu-monthly-works-out-to-an-average-of-just-3300-iu-daily">100,000 IU monthly works out to an average of just 3,300 IU daily&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#100000-iu-monthly-helped-copd-rct-2012">100,000 IU monthly helped COPD RCT 2012&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#discussion-which-was-extracted-from-pdf-attached-to-the-bottom-of-this-page">Discussion which was extracted from PDF attached to the bottom of this page&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#based-on-published-research-listed-on-this-page-and-elsewhere-on-vitamindwiki">Based on published research listed on this page and elsewhere on VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-improves-exercise-outcomes-in-patients-with-copd">Vitamin D Improves Exercise Outcomes In Patients With COPD&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Medical News Today, 16 May 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sun exposure protects children from asthma</title><link>/posts/sun-exposure-protects-children-from-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sun-exposure-protects-children-from-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sunny-hours-and-variations-in-the-prevalence-of-asthma-in-schoolchildren-according-to-the-international-study-of-asthma-and-allergies-isaac-phase-iii-in-spain">Sunny hours and variations in the prevalence of asthma in schoolchildren according to the International Study of Asthma and Allergies (ISAAC) Phase III in Spain.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int J Biometeorol. 2011 May;55(3):423-34. Epub 2010 Aug 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arnedo-Pena A, García-Marcos L, Fernández-Espinar JF, Bercedo-Sanz A, Aguinaga-Ontoso I, González-Díaz C, Carvajal-Urueña I, Busquet-Monge R, Suárez-Varela MM, de Andoin NG, Batlles-Garrido J, Blanco-Quirós A, Varela AL, García-Hernández G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiology Division, Centre of Public Health, C/ L&amp;rsquo;Olivera 5, 2-C, 12005, Castellón, Spain, &lt;a href="mailto:arnedo_alb@gva.es">arnedo_alb@gva.es&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D for 6 year old boys predicted asthma at age 14</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-for-6-year-old-boys-predicted-asthma-at-age-14.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-for-6-year-old-boys-predicted-asthma-at-age-14.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-atopy-and-asthma-phenotypes-in-children-a-longitudinal-cohort-study">Vitamin d and atopy and asthma phenotypes in children: a longitudinal cohort study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eur Respir J. 2011 May 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hollams EM, Hart PH, Holt BJ, Serralha M, Parsons F, de Klerk NH, Zhang G, Sly PD, Holt PG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and Centre for Child Health Research, The University of Western Australia Perth Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has been linked in some studies with atopy- and asthma-associated phenotypes in children with established disease, but its role in disease inception at community level is less clear. To investigate associations between vitamin D status and biological signatures indicative of allergy and asthma development in children aged 6 and 14 years in Perth, Western Australia (32°S). Serum vitamin D was assayed in 989 6-year-olds and 1380 14-year-olds from an unselected community birth cohort; 689 were assessed at both ages. Vitamin D levels were assessed as a risk modifier for respiratory and allergic outcomes at both ages, utilising previously ascertained phenotypic data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Allergy - Overview</title><link>/posts/allergy-overview.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/allergy-overview.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="might-peanut-allergy-be-associated-with-low-vitamin-d--asked-perplexity-ai-july-2024">Might peanut allergy be associated with low vitamin D? asked Perplexity AI July 2024&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There is evidence suggesting a potential association between peanut allergy and low vitamin D levels. Several studies have explored this relationship, indicating that vitamin D deficiency might play a role in the development of food allergies, including peanut allergy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Evidence Supporting the Association&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Australian Study&lt;/strong> :&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>An Australian study found that infants with low vitamin D levels were more likely to have egg or peanut allergies and multiple allergies compared to those with normal vitamin D levels. This suggests that vitamin D might have a protective role against the development of food allergies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COPD and vitamin D in a vicious circle</title><link>/posts/copd-and-vitamin-d-in-a-vicious-circle.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/copd-and-vitamin-d-in-a-vicious-circle.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-disease-a-vicious-circle">Vitamin d deficiency and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease a vicious circle.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vitam Horm. 2011;86:379-99.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Janssens W, Mathieu C, Boonen S, Decramer M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Respiratory Division, University of Leuven, Herestraat 49, Leuven, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D and vitamin D deficiency strongly interact with different pathogenic mechanisms in COPD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prevalence of vitamin D deficiency is&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>particularly high in COPD patients,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>increases with the severity of COPD, and is&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>closely associated with osteoporosis prevalence.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Adequate calcium and vitamin D supplementation in COPD patients with documented deficiencies reduces the risk for falling and osteoporotic fractures, may indirectly reduce morbidity, and may potentially prevent the further deterioration of pulmonary function.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D less than 15 ng associated with some allergies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-15-ng-associated-with-some-allergies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-less-than-15-ng-associated-with-some-allergies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Vitamin D levels and food and environmental allergies in the United States: Results from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2005-2006.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2011 Feb 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sharief S, Jariwala S, Kumar J, Muntner P, Melamed ML.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Rush University Medical Center, Chicago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Previous research supports a possible link between low vitamin D levels and atopic disease. However, the association between low vitamin D levels and total and allergen-specific IgE levels has not been studied.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Are microbs – probiotics – vitamin D – allergy – asthma – obesity related</title><link>/posts/are-microbs-probiotics-vitamin-d-allergy-asthma-obesity-related.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/are-microbs-probiotics-vitamin-d-allergy-asthma-obesity-related.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="gut-microbiota-probiotics-and-vitamin-d-interrelated-exposures-influencing-allergy-asthma-and-obesity">Gut microbiota, probiotics, and vitamin D: Interrelated exposures influencing allergy, asthma, and obesity?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology; Clinical reviews in allergy and immunology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2011.02.015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ngoc P. Ly MD, MPHa &lt;a href="mailto:lyn@peds.ucsf.edu">lyn@peds.ucsf.edu&lt;/a>, Augusto Litonjua MD, MPHb, Diane R. Gold MD, MPHb and Juan C. Celedón MD, DrPHc&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Division of Pediatric Pulmonary Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, University of California San Francisco, Calif&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Channing Laboratory, Brigham and Women’s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, Mass&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COPD – Bone Metabolism – Osteoporosis – Vitamin D appear related</title><link>/posts/copd-bone-metabolism-osteoporosis-vitamin-d-appear-related.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/copd-bone-metabolism-osteoporosis-vitamin-d-appear-related.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="copd-bone-metabolism-and-osteoporosis">COPD, Bone Metabolism, and Osteoporosis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Chest. 2011 Mar;139(3):648-57.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lehouck A, Boonen S, Decramer M, Janssens W.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Respiratory Division, University Hospital Gasthuisberg, KUL, Herestraat 49, 3000 Leuven, Belgium. &lt;a href="mailto:wim.janssens@uz.kuleuven.be">wim.janssens@uz.kuleuven.be&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>COPD and osteoporosis are strongly associated because of common risk factors such as age, smoking, and inactivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, COPD-related systemic inflammation, &lt;strong>vitamin D deficiency&lt;/strong> , and the use of systemic corticosteroids enhance ongoing bone destruction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis, in turn, may cause fragility fractures, which further impair mobility and increase morbidity and mortality. Vertebral compression fractures and rib cage fractures in patients with COPD may also reduce pulmonary function or enhance exacerbations. Early prevention and treatment of osteoporosis in COPD is, therefore, important and should be based on integrated risk assessment tools such as FRAX, which take bone mineral density, history of fragility fractures, and population-specific clinical factors into account. As long as intervention studies focusing on the bone in COPD are lacking, a more rigorous application of existing treatment guidelines of osteoporosis in general is mandatory. PMID: 21362651&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Asthma and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-asthma-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-asthma-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-is-cost-effective-to-give-to-asthmatic-children-in-columbia---feb-2023">Vitamin D is cost-effective to give to asthmatic children in Columbia - Feb 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D supplementation for children with mild to moderate asthma: an economic evaluation&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Asthma . 2023 Feb 8;1-13. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/02770903.2023.2178007">doi: 10.1080/02770903.2023.2178007&lt;/a> PUBLISHER wants $62 for the PDF&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jefferson Antonio Buendía 1, Diana Guerrero Patiño 1, Erika Fernanda Lindarte 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction A large proportion of asthma patients remain uncontrolled despite using inhaled corticosteroids. Some add-on therapies such as vitamin D supplements have been recommended for this subgroup of patients. The purpose of this study was to assess the cost-utility of vitamin D supplementation in children with mild to moderate persistent asthma in Colombia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of Vitamin D reduces lung volume</title><link>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-reduces-lung-volume.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-reduces-lung-volume.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-causes-deficits-in-lung-function-and-alters-lung-structure">Vitamin D Deficiency Causes Deficits in Lung Function and Alters Lung Structure.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2011 Feb 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zosky GR, Berry LJ, Elliot JG, James AL, Gorman S, Hart PH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telethon Institute for Child Health Research, Subiaco, Western Australia, Australia; Centre for Child Health Research, University of Western Australia, Crawley, Western Australia, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RATIONALE: The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency is increasing and has been linked to obstructive lung diseases including &lt;strong>asthma and COPD&lt;/strong> . Recent studies suggest that vitamin D deficiency is associated with reduced lung function. The relationship between vitamin D deficiency and lung function is confounded by the association between physical activity levels and vitamin D status. Thus, causal data confirming a relationship between vitamin D and lung function are lacking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sleep Apnea and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/sleep-apnea-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sleep-apnea-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hypothesis-by-dr-gominak-in-texas-sleep-problems-and-sleep-apnea-are-due-to-a-lack-of-vitamins-d3-and-b12">Hypothesis by Dr. Gominak in Texas: Sleep problems and Sleep Apnea are due to a lack of vitamins D3 and B12&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="update-by-dr-gominak-nov-2011-poor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d---nov-2011postspoor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d">Update by Dr, Gominak Nov 2011 &lt;a href="/posts/poor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d">Poor sleep and lack of vitamin D - Nov 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h3 id="she-recommends-a-vitamin-d-level-of--70-85-ngml-with-daily-dose-of-10000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-not-work-as-well">She recommends a vitamin D level of 70-85 ng/ml, with daily dose of 10,000 IU vitamin D (weekly not work as well)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Here are links to her video, a few of the slides, and the PDF&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pneumonia and low vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/pneumonia-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pneumonia-and-low-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pneumonia Risk, intensity, and mortality are all associated with low vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#6-of-85-pneumonia-and-vitamin-d-publications-pubmed--april-2025httpspubmedncbinlmnihgovterm28pneumonia5btitle5d29and2822vitamind225btitle5d29sortrelevance">6 of 85 Pneumonia and Vitamin D publications &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%28Pneumonia%5BTitle%5D%29+AND+%28%22vitamin+d%22%5BTitle%5D%29&amp;amp;sort=relevance">PubMed- April 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#future-childhood-pneumonia-cut-in-half-by-300000-iu-of-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-oct-2020">Future childhood pneumonia cut in half by 300,000 IU of Vitamin D - meta-analysis Oct 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pneumonia-elderly-death-12x-more-likely-when-vitamin-d-less-than-12-ng--2011">Pneumonia elderly death 12X more likely when vitamin D less than 12 ng – 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-bacteria-pneumonia-causality-ignores-the-vitamin-d-receptor---march-2021">Vitamin D and bacteria pneumonia causality (ignores the Vitamin D Receptor) - March 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#type-of-pneumonia-viral-bacterial-fungal">Type of Pneumonia: viral, bacterial, fungal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#high-dose-vitamin-d-reduces-recurrent-pneumonia-by-half---meta-analysis-oct-2020">High-dose Vitamin D reduces recurrent pneumonia by half - meta-analysis Oct 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pneumonia-problems-in-china-might-by-treated-by-vitamin-a---dr-campbell-videos">Pneumonia problems in China might by treated by Vitamin A - Dr. Campbell Videos&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="6-of-85-pneumonia-and-vitamin-d-publications-pubmed--april-2025httpspubmedncbinlmnihgovterm28pneumonia5btitle5d29and2822vitamind225btitle5d29sortrelevance">6 of 85 Pneumonia and Vitamin D publications &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%28Pneumonia%5BTitle%5D%29+AND+%28%22vitamin+d%22%5BTitle%5D%29&amp;amp;sort=relevance">PubMed- April 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cost-effectiveness of high-dose vitamin D supplementation to reduce the occurrence of repeat episodes of pneumonia in children Nov 2024 &lt;a href="https://10.1186/s12962-024-00589-2">FREE PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many possible associations of increased asthma in black children</title><link>/posts/many-possible-associations-of-increased-asthma-in-black-children.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-possible-associations-of-increased-asthma-in-black-children.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="racial-disparities-in-pediatric-asthma-a-review-of-the-literature">Racial Disparities in Pediatric Asthma: A Review of the Literature.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Allergy Asthma Rep. 2010 Nov 24. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hill TD, Graham LM, Divgi V.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Georgia Pediatric Pulmonology Associates, 1100 Lake Hearn Drive, Suite 450, Atlanta, GA, 30342, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:tdhill@gppa.net">tdhill@gppa.net&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The burden of asthma disproportionately affects children living in economically disadvantaged urban communities. The relationships between ethnicity, genetic differences, lower socioeconomic status, poor medication adherence, greater exposure to environmental triggers, and absence of regular asthma care all contribute to this disparity. This review aims to identify and discuss recent studies on additional factors that may also impact to pediatric asthma disparity. The body of work examined in this review suggests that these disparities are the result of&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No association between low level of vitamin D and severity of Asthma</title><link>/posts/no-association-between-low-level-of-vitamin-d-and-severity-of-asthma.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-association-between-low-level-of-vitamin-d-and-severity-of-asthma.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="p14-does-vitamin-d-axis-have-an-effect-on-the-severity-of-asthma">P14 Does Vitamin D Axis have an effect on the severity of Asthma?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Thorax 2010;65:A82-A83 doi:10.1136/thx.2010.150961.14&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>R Sathyamurthy, 2. S Manney, 3. A Wood, 4. G Perkins, 5. C Webster, 6. MT Krishna, 7. AH Mansur; Heart of England NHS Trust, Birmingham, UK&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Background Vitamin D (VD) has been suggested to play a role in the development of asthma and frequency of asthma exacerbation1. Vitamin D Binding Protein (VDBP) is thought to influence the development of COPD through its immunomodulatory effect2. This study explores the role of vitamin D axis in relation to asthma severity.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>