<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meta-Analysis of Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/meta-analysis-of-vitamin-d.html</link><description>Recent content in Meta-Analysis of Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/meta-analysis-of-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis: number needed to treat with vitamin D may be as low as 1.3 – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-number-needed-to-treat-with-vitamin-d-may-be-as-low-as-13-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-number-needed-to-treat-with-vitamin-d-may-be-as-low-as-13-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-case-for-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-multiple-sclerosis">The case for vitamin D supplementation in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Multiple Sclerosis and Related Disorders, Volume 2, Issue 4, October 2013, Pages 281–306 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msard.2012.12.008">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msard.2012.12.008&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aravind Ganesh a, &lt;a href="mailto:aravindganeshy@yahoo.ca">aravindganeshy@yahoo.ca&lt;/a>; Sabrina Apel b, Luanne Metz c, Scott Patten d,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>a Resident, Clinical Neurosciences, University of Calgary, 1403 29 Street NW Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 2T9&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>b Undergraduate Medical Education, University of Calgary, 33 Discovery Rise SW Calgary, Alberta, Canada T3H 4N6&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>c Clinical Neurosciences, University of Calgary, 1403 29 Street NW Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 2T9&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Pancreatitis associated with painful bones (vitamin D) – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/chronic-pancreatitis-associated-with-painful-bones-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-pancreatitis-associated-with-painful-bones-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="high-prevalence-of-osteoporosis-in-patients-with-chronic-pancreatitis-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">High Prevalence of Osteoporosis in Patients with Chronic Pancreatitis: a Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clinical Gastroenterology and Hepatology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sinead N. Duggan &lt;a href="mailto:siduggan@tcd.ie">siduggan@tcd.ie&lt;/a>, Niamh D. Smyth. Anne Murphy. David MacNaughton , Stephen JD. O’Keefe , Kevin C. Conlon&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 21 March 2013; received in revised form 19 June 2013; accepted 19 June 2013. published online 15 July 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background &amp;amp; Aims: Patients with chronic pancreatitis may be at high risk for osteoporosis and osteopenia. We performed a systematic review and meta-analysis to determine the prevalence of osteoporosis and osteopenia in patients with chronic pancreatitis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer post menopause down 12 percent for every 5 ng of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-post-menopause-down-12-percent-for-every-5-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-post-menopause-down-12-percent-for-every-5-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="plasma-vitamin-d-levels-menopause-and-risk-of-breast-cancer-dose-response-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Plasma vitamin D levels, menopause, and risk of breast cancer: dose-response meta-analysis of prospective studies.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Medicine (Baltimore). 2013 May;92(3):123-31. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0b013e3182943bc2.">doi: 10.1097/MD.0b013e3182943bc2.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bauer SR, Hankinson SE, Bertone-Johnson ER, Ding EL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Channing Laboratory, Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous evidence suggests that higher circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels are variably associated with lower breast cancer risk; however, prospective studies and clinical trials have been inconsistent, particularly between older and younger women of differing menopausal status. We conducted a quantitative nonlinear dose-response meta-analysis of prospective studies evaluating the association between circulating 25(OH)D and breast cancer risk, stratified by menopause. A systematic search of MEDLINE and EMBASE included studies published through May 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brain (Alzheimer’s) worked better with Vitamin D intervention – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/brain-alzheimers-worked-better-with-vitamin-d-intervention-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/brain-alzheimers-worked-better-with-vitamin-d-intervention-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="meta-analysis-of-memory-and-executive-dysfunctions-in-relation-to-vitamin-d">Meta-Analysis of Memory and Executive Dysfunctions in Relation to Vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Disease, Online Date	Wednesday, July 03, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cedric Annweiler 1, 2, 3, Manuel Montero-Odasso2, David J. Llewellyn4, Stéphane Richard-Devantoy5, Gustavo Duque, Olivier Beauchet1&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1 Department of Neuroscience, Division of Geriatric Medicine and Memory Clinic, UPRES EA, UNAM, Angers University Hospital, Angers, France&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>2 Department of Medicine, Division of Geriatric Medicine, Parkwood Hospital, St. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s Health Care London; Gait and Brain Lab, Lawson Health Research Institute, the University of Western Ontario, London, ON, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Meta-analysis of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-meta-analysis-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-meta-analysis-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>3.2 percent less Breast Cancer for 2.4 ng more vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/32-percent-less-breast-cancer-for-24-ng-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/32-percent-less-breast-cancer-for-24-ng-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-breast-cancer-risk-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and breast cancer risk: a meta-analysis of prospective studies.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Tumour Biol. 2013 Jun 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wang D, Vélez de-la-Paz OI, Zhai JX, Liu DW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Hebei Medical University, No. 361 Zhongshan East Road, Shijiazhuang, Hebei Province, 050017, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were some case-control studies, nested case-control studies, and cohort studies with controversial results on the association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> and breast cancer risk. Case-control studies are prone to selection bias, which limit the strength and quality of the evidence. To overcome the shortcoming of the case-control studies, the meta-analysis of prospective studies including nested case-control studies and cohort studies was conducted. PubMed, Embase, and Web of Science databases were searched, and the last retrieval date was March 24, 2013. For the highest versus the lowest level of serum 25(OH)D, the relative risks (RRs) and its 95 % confidence intervals (CIs) from each study were used to estimate summary RR and its 95 % CI. Subgroup analyses by geographic region, menopausal status, and adjusted status of RR were also performed, respectively. A dose-response association between serum 25(OH)D concentration and breast cancer risk was assessed. Fourteen articles with 9,110 breast cancer cases and 16,244 controls were included in the meta-analysis. Overall, serum 25(OH)D levels were inversely significantly associated with breast cancer risk (RR = 0.845, 95 % CI = 0.750-0.951). Inversely statistically significant associations were observed in North American studies, postmenopausal women, and studies with adjusted and unadjusted RR, respectively. No statistically significant associations were observed in European studies and premenopausal women, respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Respiratory Tract Infections – meta-analysis with charts</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-respiratory-tract-infections-meta-analysis-with-charts.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-respiratory-tract-infections-meta-analysis-with-charts.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-respiratory-tract-infections-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials">Vitamin D and Respiratory Tract Infections: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(6): e65835. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0065835&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter Bergman, Åsa U. Lindh, Linda Björkhem-Bergman, Jonatan D. Lindh&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Low levels of 25-OH vitamin D are associated with respiratory tract infection (RTI). However, results from randomized controlled trials are inconclusive. Therefore, we performed a systematic review and meta-analysis to assess the preventive effect of vitamin D supplementation on RTI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer survival 2X more likely if vitamin D sufficient – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-survival-2x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-sufficient-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-survival-2x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-sufficient-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-relationship-between-serum-vitamin-d-levels-and-breast-cancer-prognosis-a-meta-analysis">The relationship between serum vitamin D levels and breast cancer prognosis: A meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology, 2013 ASCO Annual Meeting Proceedings (Post-Meeting Edition).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol 31, No 15_suppl (May 20 Supplement), 2013: 1521&lt;/p>
&lt;p>April Ann Nicole Rose, Christine Elser and Pamela Jean Goodwin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Faculty of Medicine, McGill University, Montreal, QC, Canada; Princess Margaret Hospital, Toronto, ON, Canada; Samuel Lunenfeld Research Institute, Mount Sinai Hospital, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 2 diabetes 1.5X more likely if low vs high vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/type-2-diabetes-15x-more-likely-if-low-vs-high-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-2-diabetes-15x-more-likely-if-low-vs-high-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="low-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-risk-of-type-2-diabetes-a-prospective-cohort-study-and-metaanalysis">Low 25-hydroxyvitamin D and risk of type 2 diabetes: a prospective cohort study and metaanalysis.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clin Chem. 2013 Feb;59(2):381-91. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1373/clinchem.2012.193003.">doi: 10.1373/clinchem.2012.193003.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Afzal S, Bojesen SE, Nordestgaard BG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Herlev Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital, Copenhagen, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D deficiency has been implicated in decreased insulin secretion and increased insulin resistance, hallmarks of type 2 diabetes mellitus. We tested the hypothesis that low plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> is associated with increased risk of type 2 diabetes in the general population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No association between Multiple Sclerosis relapses and being treated with vitamin D–meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/no-association-between-multiple-sclerosis-relapses-and-being-treated-with-vitamin-dmeta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-association-between-multiple-sclerosis-relapses-and-being-treated-with-vitamin-dmeta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>This is most likely similar to many other meta-analysis which find no association when averaging the response by people getting no benefit from as little as 400 IU with those getting a lot of benefit from 10,000 IU&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-related-interventions-on-multiple-sclerosis-relapses-a-meta-analysis">The effect of vitamin D-related interventions on multiple sclerosis relapses: a meta-analysis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mult Scler May 22, 2013 1352458513489756&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eleanor James, Ruth Dobson, Jens Kuhle, David Baker, Gavin Giovannoni, Sreeram V Ramagopalan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Blizard Institute, Queen Mary University of London, Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s diseases associated with low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-levels-in-alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-a-meta-analysis">Vitamin D levels in Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s diseases: A meta-analysis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-levels-in-alzheimers-and-parkinsons-diseases-a-meta-analysis">Vitamin D levels in Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s diseases: A meta-analysis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nutrition, Volume 29, Issue 6 , Pages 828-832, June 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yan Zhao, B.Sc., Yan Sun, B.Sc., Hong-Fang Ji, Ph.D. &lt;a href="mailto:jhf@sdut.edu.cn">jhf@sdut.edu.cn&lt;/a>, Liang Shen, Ph.D.email address&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shandong Provincial Research Center for Bioinformatic Engineering and Technique, Shandong University of Technology, Zibo, P. R. China&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 6 July 2012; accepted 25 November 2012. published online 15 February 2013.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4 percent less type 2 diabetes for every 4 ng more vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/4-percent-less-type-2-diabetes-for-every-4-ng-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4-percent-less-type-2-diabetes-for-every-4-ng-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="blood-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-levels-and-incident-type-2-diabetes-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Blood 25-Hydroxy Vitamin D Levels and Incident Type 2 Diabetes: A meta-analysis of prospective studies.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care. 2013 May;36(5):1422-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2337/dc12-0962.">doi: 10.2337/dc12-0962.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Song Y, Wang L, Pittas AG, Del Gobbo LC, Zhang C, Manson JE, Hu FB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corresponding author: Yiqing Song, &lt;a href="mailto:ysong3@rics.bwh.harvard.edu">ysong3@rics.bwh.harvard.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE To quantitatively assess the strength and shape of the association between blood 25-hydroxy vitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and incident risk of type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS A systematic search of the MEDLINE and Embase databases and a hand search of references from original reports were conducted up to 31 October 2012. Prospective observational studies that assessed the association between blood levels of 25(OH)D and risk of incident type 2 diabetes were included for meta-analysis. DerSimonian and Laird&amp;rsquo;s random-effects model was used. A quadratic spline regression analysis was used to examine the shape of the association with a generalized least-squares trend test performed for the dose-response relation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Standard and artificial vitamin D both help Chronic Kidney Disease – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/standard-and-artificial-vitamin-d-both-help-chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/standard-and-artificial-vitamin-d-both-help-chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="impact-of-vitamin-d-on-chronic-kidney-diseases-in-non-dialysis-patients">Impact of Vitamin D on Chronic Kidney Diseases in Non-Dialysis Patients:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(4): e61387. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0061387&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lijuan Xu, Xuesi Wan, Zhimin Huang, Fangfang Zeng, Guohong Wei, Donghong Fang, Wanping Deng, Yanbing Li mail&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and Objectives: Recent studies have supported a role for both newer and more established vitamin D compounds in improving proteinuria, although systematic evaluation is lacking. Furthermore, concerns remain regarding the influence of vitamin D on the progression of renal function. We analyzed the efficacy and safety of vitamin D in non-dialysis patients and compared the use of newer versus established vitamin D compounds by performing a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yet another meta-analysis ignores vitamin D dose and serum level – Autoimmune disease</title><link>/posts/yet-another-meta-analysis-ignores-vitamin-d-dose-and-serum-level-autoimmune-disease.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yet-another-meta-analysis-ignores-vitamin-d-dose-and-serum-level-autoimmune-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="can-supplementation-with-vitamin-d-reduce-the-risk-or-modify-the-course-of-autoimmune-diseases-a-systematic-review-of-the-literature">Can supplementation with vitamin D reduce the risk or modify the course of autoimmune diseases? A systematic review of the literature.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Autoimmun Rev. 2012 Dec;12(2):127-36. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2012.07.007.">doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2012.07.007.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jul 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antico A, Tampoia M, Tozzoli R, Bizzaro N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laboratorio di Patologia Clinica, Ospedale Civile, Cittadella, Italy. &lt;a href="mailto:antonioantico@virgilio.it">antonioantico@virgilio.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate whether vitamin D levels are related to the risk of developing autoimmune diseases and whether supplementation with vitamin D can modify the course of the diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D and depression - Study and meta-analysis,</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-depression-study-and-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-depression-study-and-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-association-between-low-vitamin-d-and-depressive-disorders">The association between low vitamin D and depressive disorders&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#8-less-likely-to-be-depressed-for-10ng-higher-level-of-vitamin-d---meta-analysis">8% less likely to be depressed for 10ng higher level of vitamin D - Meta-analysis&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="the-association-between-low-vitamin-d-and-depressive-disorders">The association between low vitamin D and depressive disorders&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Molecular Psychiatry , (9 April 2013) | doi:10.1038/mp.2013.36&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Y Milaneschi, W Hoogendijk, P Lips, A C Heijboer, R Schoevers, A M van Hemert, A T F Beekman, J H Smit and B W J H Penninx&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X more preeclampsia when vitamin D less than 30 ng, etc. - meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/2x-more-preeclampsia-when-vitamin-d-less-than-30-ng-etc-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-preeclampsia-when-vitamin-d-less-than-30-ng-etc-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#association-between-maternal-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-and-pregnancy-and-neonatal-outcomes-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-observational-studies">Association between maternal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level and pregnancy and neonatal outcomes: systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#editorial-in-same-issue-vitamin-d-sufficiency-in-pregnancy">Editorial in same issue: Vitamin D sufficiency in pregnancy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references-for-editorial">References for editorial&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-doses-of-vitamin-d-linked-with-harmful-outcomes-during-pregnancyhttpwwwmedicalnewstodaycomarticles258251php">&lt;a href="http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/258251.php">Low Doses Of Vitamin D Linked With Harmful Outcomes During Pregnancy&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="association-between-maternal-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-and-pregnancy-and-neonatal-outcomes-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-observational-studies">Association between maternal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level and pregnancy and neonatal outcomes: systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>British Medical Journal&lt;/strong> (BMJ) 2013; 346 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/http">doi: http&lt;/a>://dx.doi.org/10.1136/bmj.f1169 (Published 26 March 2013)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnesium prevents cardiovascular events – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/magnesium-prevents-cardiovascular-events-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/magnesium-prevents-cardiovascular-events-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="magnesium-and-the-risk-of-cardiovascular-events-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-cohort-studies">Magnesium and the risk of cardiovascular events: a meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2013;8(3):e57720. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0057720.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0057720.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Mar 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Qu X, Jin F, Hao Y, Li H, Tang T, Wang H, Yan W, Dai K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shanghai Key Laboratory of Orthopaedic Implant, Shanghai Ninth People&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Prospective studies that have examined the association between dietary magnesium intake and serum magnesium concentrations and the risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD) events have reported conflicting findings. We undertook a meta-analysis to evaluate the association between dietary magnesium intake and serum magnesium concentrations and the risk of total CVD events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D receptor gene associated with 50 percent more type 2 Diabetes – meta-analyses 2013, 2016</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-gene-associated-with-50-percent-more-type-2-diabetes-meta-analyses-2013-2016.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-gene-associated-with-50-percent-more-type-2-diabetes-meta-analyses-2013-2016.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#type-2-diabetes-in-chinese-is-50-percent-more-likely-if-have-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-problem--meta-analysis-2016">Type 2 Diabetes in Chinese is 50 percent more likely if have Vitamin D Receptor gene problem – meta-analysis 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-and-type-2-diabetes-a-meta-analysis--march-2013">Vitamin D Receptor Gene Polymorphisms and Type 2 Diabetes: A Meta-analysis.- March 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="type-2-diabetes-in-chinese-is-50-percent-more-likely-if-have-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-problem--meta-analysis-2016">Type 2 Diabetes in Chinese is 50 percent more likely if have Vitamin D Receptor gene problem – meta-analysis 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The genetic polymorphisms in vitamin D receptor and the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus: an updated meta-analysis.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular disease 50 % more likely if low vitamin D - meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-50-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-50-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="circulating-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-and-risk-of-cardiovascular-disease-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Circulating 25-hydroxy-vitamin D and risk of cardiovascular disease: a meta-analysis of prospective studies.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2012 Nov;5(6):819-29. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.112.967604.">doi: 10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.112.967604.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Nov 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wang L, Song Y, Manson JE, Pilz S, März W, Michaëlsson K, Lundqvist A, Jassal SK, Barrett-Connor E, Zhang C, Eaton CB, May HT, Anderson JL, Sesso HD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brigham and Women’s Hospital, Boston, MA 02215, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:luwang@rics.bwh.harvard.edu">luwang@rics.bwh.harvard.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D status has been linked to the risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD). However, the optimal 25-hydroxy-vitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>-vitamin D) levels for potential cardiovascular health benefits remain unclear.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduced risk of death of Chronic Kidney Disease by 30 percent: Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-risk-of-death-of-chronic-kidney-disease-by-30-percent-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduced-risk-of-death-of-chronic-kidney-disease-by-30-percent-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-treatment-and-mortality-in-chronic-kidney-disease">Vitamin D Treatment and Mortality in Chronic Kidney Disease:&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Nephrol. 2013 Mar 5;37(3):239-248.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Duranton F, Rodriguez-Ortiz ME, Duny Y, Rodriguez M, Daurès JP, Argilés A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RD-Néphrologie, Institut Universitaire de Recherche Clinique, Montpellier, France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aims: Hypovitaminosis D has been associated with an increased cardiovascular mortality in the general population and in patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD). Still, whether prescribing vitamin D reduces the risk of mortality in renal patients remains controversial.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypertension 30 percent more likely if low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hypertension-30-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypertension-30-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-risk-of-future-hypertension-meta-analysis-of-283537-participants">Vitamin D and risk of future hypertension: meta-analysis of 283,537 participants.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eur J Epidemiol. 2013 Mar 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kunutsor SK, Apekey TA, Steur M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Public Health and Primary Care, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, CB1 8RN, UK, &lt;a href="mailto:skk31@cantab.net">skk31@cantab.net&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The evidence on the association between baseline vitamin D status and risk of incident hypertension in general populations is limited and has not been reliably quantified. We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis of published prospective studies evaluating the associations of baseline vitamin D status (circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and dietary vitamin D intake) with risk of hypertension. Eligible studies were identified in a literature search of MEDLINE, EMBASE, and Web of Science up to November 2012. Pooled relative risks (RRs) with 95 % confidence intervals were calculated using random effects models. Generalized least-squares trend estimation was used to assess dose-response relationships.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X more likely to be depressed if low vitamin D (cohort studies) - Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/2x-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-low-vitamin-d-cohort-studies-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-likely-to-be-depressed-if-low-vitamin-d-cohort-studies-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-depression-in-adults-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D deficiency and depression in adults: systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The British Journal of Psychiatry (2013) 202: 100-107&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rebecca E. S. Anglin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zainab Samaan,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen D. Walter and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah D. McDonald&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rebecca E. S. Anglin, MD, PhD, FRCPC, Department of Psychiatry and Behavioural Neurosciences and Medicine, McMaster University; Zainab Samaan, MRCPsych, PhD, Department of Psychiatry and Behavioural Neurosciences, McMaster University; Stephen D. Walter, PhD, Department of Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, McMaster University; Sarah D. McDonald, MD, MSc, Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine, Departments of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Diagnostic Imaging and Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X more likely to have preeclampsia if less than 20 ng of vitamin D – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/2x-more-likely-to-have-preeclampsia-if-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-likely-to-have-preeclampsia-if-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-and-adverse-pregnancy-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Maternal Vitamin D Status and Adverse Pregnancy Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2013 Jan 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wei SQ, Qi HP, Luo ZC, Fraser WD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Saint-Justine Hospital, University of Montreal, Montreal, Canada;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To estimate the associations between maternal vitamin D status and adverse pregnancy outcomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>STUDY DESIGN: We searched electronic databases of the human literature in PubMed, EMBASE and the Cochrane Library up to October, 2012 using the following keywords: &amp;lsquo;vitamin D&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;status&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;deficiency&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;insufficiency&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;pregnancy&amp;rsquo;. A systematic review and meta-analysis were conducted on observational studies that reported the association between maternal blood vitamin D levels and adverse pregnancy outcomes including preeclampsia, gestational diabetes mellitus, preterm birth or small-for-gestational age.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Juvenile Rheumatoid Arthritis associated with low vitamin D, but how low – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/juvenile-rheumatoid-arthritis-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-but-how-low-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/juvenile-rheumatoid-arthritis-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-but-how-low-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="what-do-we-know-about-juvenile-idiopathic-arthritis-and-vitamin-d-a-systematic-literature-review-and-meta-analysis-of-current-evidence">What do we know about juvenile idiopathic arthritis and vitamin D? A systematic literature review and meta-analysis of current evidence.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Rheumatol. 2013 Jan 8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10067-012-2159-1">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10067-012-2159-1&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nisar MK, Masood F, Cookson P, Sansome A, Ostör AJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatology Research Unit, Addenbrooke&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, CUHNHSFT, Box 194, Cambridge, CB2 2QQ, UK, &lt;a href="mailto:drnisar12@yahoo.co.uk">drnisar12@yahoo.co.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last decade vitamin D (Vit D) has been the focus of considerable interest as a potential immunomodulator in a variety of conditions including autoimmune disease. Its influence in juvenile idiopathic arthritis (JIA) however is unclear. We therefore wished to clarify a possible link with the currently available evidence. A systematic literature review was undertaken using Embase, Cochrane and Medline for manuscripts up to May 2011. Search results were then assessed by two independent reviewers and relevant articles were further screened by full text review. Only those specifically reporting Vit D levels or its supplementation in JIA (ages between 0 and 18 years) were selected. Meta-analysis was performed where possible with those papers reporting similar data and analysis techniques. In total, 19 papers (n = 745) were included in the review.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolic Syndrome in children is associated with low vitamin D – review</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-in-children-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-in-children-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-association-between-vitamin-d-and-cardiometabolic-risk-factors-in-children---a-systematic-review">The Association Between Vitamin D and Cardiometabolic Risk Factors in Children - A Systematic Review&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>CLIN PEDIATR January 8, 2013 0009922812470742&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diana H. Dolinsky, MD, MPH&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah Armstrong, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Caren Mangarelli, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alex R. Kemper, MD, MPH, MS&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Duke University Medical Center, Durham, NC, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah Armstrong, Department of Pediatrics, Duke University Medical Center, 4020 North Roxboro Street, Durham, NC 27704, USA Email: &lt;a href="mailto:sarah.c.armstrong@dm.duke.edu">sarah.c.armstrong@dm.duke.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this systematic review was to evaluate the association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) and cardiometabolic risk in children and the effect of vitamin D supplementation on risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D associated with 50 percent less ischemic stroke – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-associated-with-50-percent-less-ischemic-stroke-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-associated-with-50-percent-less-ischemic-stroke-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-symptomatic-ischemic-stroke-an-original-study-and-meta-analysis---2012">25-Hydroxyvitamin D and symptomatic ischemic stroke: An Original Study and Meta-Analysis - 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ischemic-stroke-19x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---july-2015">Ischemic Stroke 1.9X more likely if low vitamin D - July 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-symptomatic-ischemic-stroke-an-original-study-and-meta-analysis---2012">25-Hydroxyvitamin D and symptomatic ischemic stroke: An Original Study and Meta-Analysis - 2012&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ann Neurol. 2012 Aug 25. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.23738.">doi: 10.1002/ana.23738.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brøndum-Jacobsen P, Nordestgaard BG, Schnohr P, Benn M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Herlev Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital; Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Receptor genes bb and BB and Osteoporosis, esp. for blacks – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-genes-bb-and-bb-and-osteoporosis-esp-for-blacks-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-genes-bb-and-bb-and-osteoporosis-esp-for-blacks-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-bsmi-polymorphism-and-osteoporosis-risk-a-meta-analysis-from-26-studies">Vitamin D Receptor BsmI Polymorphism and Osteoporosis Risk: A Meta-Analysis from 26 Studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Genetic Testing and Molecular Biomarkers – Nov 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rui-Fen Sun,2,* Qun-Hui Li,1 Da-Xing Wang,1 Feng Zhao,1 Jun-Min Li,1 Qi Pu,1 Zhong-Zi Zhang,1 Yan Jin,1 Bai-Lian Liu,1 and Ying Xiong1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Orthopedics, Kunming Medical University, National Clinical Key Specialty, Yanan Hospital, Kunming, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Central Laboratory, Yunnan University of Chinese Traditional Medicine, Kunming, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces respiratory tract infections by 40 percent– meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-respiratory-tract-infections-by-40-percent-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-respiratory-tract-infections-by-40-percent-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hip fractures greatly reduced by sunshine, vitamin D, and vitamin K – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-greatly-reduced-by-sunshine-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-greatly-reduced-by-sunshine-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="strategy-for-prevention-of-hip-fractures-in-patients-with-parkinsons-disease">Strategy for prevention of hip fractures in patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>World J Orthop. 2012 Sep 18;3(9):137-41. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5312/wjo.v3.i9.137.">doi: 10.5312/wjo.v3.i9.137.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Iwamoto J, Sato Y, Takeda T, Matsumoto H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jun Iwamoto, Tsuyoshi Takeda, Hideo Matsumoto, Institute for Integrated Sports Medicine, Keio University School of Medicine, Tokyo 160-8582, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypovitaminosis D and K due to malnutrition or sunlight deprivation, increased bone resorption due to immobilization, low bone mineral density (BMD) and an increased risk of falls may contribute to an increased risk of hip fractures in patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease. The purpose of the present study was to clarify the efficacy of interventions intended to prevent hip fractures in elderly patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease. PubMed was used to search the literature for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) regarding Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease and hip fractures. The inclusion criteria were 50 or more subjects per group and a study period of 1 year or longer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Acute respiratory infection treated by vitamin D in 6 of 12 clinical trials – review</title><link>/posts/acute-respiratory-infection-treated-by-vitamin-d-in-6-of-12-clinical-trials-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/acute-respiratory-infection-treated-by-vitamin-d-in-6-of-12-clinical-trials-review.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis 23 percent more likely if born in April vs. Oct – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-23-percent-more-likely-if-born-in-april-vs-oct-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-23-percent-more-likely-if-born-in-april-vs-oct-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-month-of-birth-effect-in-multiple-sclerosis-systematic-review-meta-analysis-and-effect-of-latitude">The month of birth effect in multiple sclerosis: systematic review, meta-analysis and effect of latitude&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry doi:10.1136/jnnp-2012-303934&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ruth Dobson1, Gavin Giovannoni1, Sreeram Ramagopalan1,2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Queen Mary University of London, Blizard Institute, Barts and the London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Wellcome Trust Centre for Human Genetics, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Clinical Neurology, John Radcliffe Hospital, Oxford, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence to: Dr Ruth Dobson, Queen Mary University of London, Blizard Institute, Newark Street, London E1 2AT; &lt;a href="mailto:ruth.dobson@qmul.ac.uk">ruth.dobson@qmul.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer's Disease more likely with low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-disease-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-disease-more-likely-with-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D may prevent falls and fractures without Calcium – an overview of 9 meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-may-prevent-falls-and-fractures-without-calcium-an-overview-of-9-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-may-prevent-falls-and-fractures-without-calcium-an-overview-of-9-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="do-we-need-to-take-calcium-with-vitamin-d-supplements-to-prevent-falls-fractures-and-death">Do we need to take calcium with vitamin D supplements to prevent falls, fractures, and death?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2012 Oct 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scragg R, School of Population Health, University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE OF REVIEW:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 2011 report by the US Institute of Medicine (IOM) on dietary reference intakes for calcium and vitamin D is based on meta-analyses of randomized controlled trials (RCTs), which concluded that vitamin D supplements need to be taken with calcium supplements to prevent falls, fractures, and all-cause mortality. This study reviews recent meta-analyses of RCTs of vitamin D supplementation to determine whether their conclusions are consistent with the meta-analyses underpinning the IOM report.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer disease associated with 2.5 ng less vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/alzheimer-disease-associated-with-25-ng-less-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimer-disease-associated-with-25-ng-less-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Omega-3 does not help heart patients – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/omega-3-does-not-help-heart-patients-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-does-not-help-heart-patients-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="clipped-from-la-times-sept-2012httpwwwlatimescomnewssciencela-sci-omega-3s-heart-health-2012091203265313story20">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/science/la-sci-omega-3s-heart-health-20120912,0,3265313.story%20">LA Times Sept 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The study, reexamined the results of 20 previous studies dating back to 1989 that included nearly 70,000 patients.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;This evidence,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;should not be generalized to any type of patients or apparently healthy individuals.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="clipped-from-time-magazinehttphealthlandtimecom20120912omega-3-supplements-dont-lower-heart-disease-risk-after-all20">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://healthland.time.com/2012/09/12/omega-3-supplements-dont-lower-heart-disease-risk-after-all/%20">Time Magazine&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Volunteers in the studies, &lt;strong>most of whom were heart patients&lt;/strong> , were randomly assigned to take either 1.5 g of omega-3 supplementation or a placebo every day for about two years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cerebrovascular disease 40 percent less likely if high level of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cerebrovascular-disease-40-percent-less-likely-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cerebrovascular-disease-40-percent-less-likely-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rheumatoid arthritis 24 percent more likely if low vitamin D consumption– meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/rheumatoid-arthritis-24-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-consumption-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rheumatoid-arthritis-24-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-consumption-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="association-between-vitamin-d-intake-and-the-risk-of-rheumatoid-arthritis-a-meta-analysis">Association between vitamin D intake and the risk of rheumatoid arthritis: a meta-analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Gwan Gyu Song, Sang-Cheol Bae and Young Ho Lee&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CLINICAL RHEUMATOLOGY; 2012, DOI: 10.1007/s10067-012-2080-7, International League of Associations for Rheumatology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study was to summarize published results on the association between vitamin D intake and the development of rheumatoid arthritis (RA) and between serum vitamin D levels and RA activity. Evidence of a relationship between vitamin D intake and the development of RA and between serum vitamin D levels and RA activity was studied by summarizing published results using a meta-analysis approach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half as many heart deaths for those with high levels of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/half-as-many-heart-deaths-for-those-with-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-as-many-heart-deaths-for-those-with-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pregnancy and vitamin D meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/pregnancy-and-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pregnancy-and-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-maternal-neonatal-and-infant-health-outcomes">Vitamin D During Pregnancy and Maternal, Neonatal and Infant Health Outcomes:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Andrew Thorne-Lyman1,*, Wafaie W. Fawzi1,2,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paediatric and Perinatal Epidemiology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Special Issue: Improving maternal, newborn, and child health outcomes through better designed policies and programs that enhance the nutrition of women&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 26, Issue Supplement s1, pages 75–90, July 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has well-defined classical functions related to calcium metabolism and bone health but also has non-classical effects that may influence other aspects of health. There has been considerable recent interest in the role of vitamin D on outcomes related to pregnancy and young child health but few efforts have been made to systematically consolidate this evidence to inform the research and policy agenda for low-income countries. A systematic review was undertaken to identify intervention and observational studies of vitamin D supplementation, intake or status (25-hydroxy-vitamin D) during pregnancy on perinatal and infant health outcomes. Data from trials and observational studies isolating the effect of vitamin D supplementation and intake were extracted and study quality was evaluated. Meta-analysis was used to pool effect estimates. We identified five randomised trials with outcomes of relevance to our review. All had small sample size and dosage amount, duration and frequency varied as did the ability to correct deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypertension 2X more likely when vitamin D levels lower than 14 ng – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hypertension-2x-more-likely-when-vitamin-d-levels-lower-than-14-ng-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypertension-2x-more-likely-when-vitamin-d-levels-lower-than-14-ng-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="spanmeta-analysis-on-the-relationship-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-and-hypertensionspan">&lt;span>[Meta-analysis on the relationship between 25-hydroxyvitamin D level and hypertension.]&lt;/span>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[Article in Chinese]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhonghua Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2012 May;92(18):1268-1271.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liu YT, Cai YF, Shi JP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Epidemiology, First Affiliated Hospital, China Medical University, Shenyang 110001, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To explore the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D level and hypertension so as to provide rationales for developing preventive strategies and understanding the etiology of hypertension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The articles on the association of 25-hydroxyvitamin D level and hypertension were retrieved by searching international and national databases from 2000 to 2011. The relationship between 25-hydroxyvitamin D level and hypertension was assessed by Meta-analysis with Stata11.0 software.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cognitive Impairment 2.4X more likely if low vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cognitive-impairment-24x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cognitive-impairment-24x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-cognitive-impairment-and-dementia-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D Deficiency, Cognitive Impairment and Dementia: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord 2012 Vol. 33, No. 5, 2012 ;33:297-305&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thorleif Etgena,b &lt;a href="mailto:thorleif.etgen@klinikum-traunstein.de">thorleif.etgen@klinikum-traunstein.de&lt;/a>, Dirk Sanderc,d, Horst Bickela, Kerstin Sanderd, Hans Förstla&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Technische Universität München,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Department of Neurology, Kliniken Südostbayern – Klinikum Traunstein,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Department of Neurology, Benedictus Krankenhaus Tutzing, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>D Department of Neurology, Technische Universität München, Munich, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Recent preventive strategies for patients with cognitive impairment include the identification of modifiable somatic risk factors like vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shift workers 23 percent more likely to have cardiovascular events – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/shift-workers-23-percent-more-likely-to-have-cardiovascular-events-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shift-workers-23-percent-more-likely-to-have-cardiovascular-events-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="shift-work-and-vascular-events-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Shift work and vascular events: systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>BMJ 2012; 345 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.e4800">doi: 10.1136/bmj.e4800&lt;/a> (Published 26 July 2012)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cite this as: BMJ 2012;345:e4800&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manav V Vyas, graduate student1, Amit X Garg, professor123, Arthur V Iansavichus, information specialist3, John Costella, research and instructional librarian4, Allan Donner, professor15, Lars E Laugsand, PhD candidate6, Imre Janszky, researcher67, Marko Mrkobrada, assistant professor25, Grace Parraga, associate professor8, Daniel G Hackam, associate professor125&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Western University, London, ON, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fractures reduced 30 percent with 800 IU of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-pooled-analysis-of-vitamin-d-dose-requirements-for-fracture-prevention">A pooled analysis of vitamin D dose requirements for fracture prevention.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med. 2012 Jul 5;367(1):40-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Willett WC, Orav EJ, Lips P, Meunier PJ, Lyons RA, Flicker L, Wark J, Jackson RD, Cauley JA, Meyer HE, Pfeifer M, Sanders KM, Stähelin HB, Theiler R, Dawson-Hughes B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center on Aging and Mobility, University of Zurich and Waid City Hospital, Zurich, Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The results of meta-analyses examining the relationship between vitamin D supplementation and fracture reduction have been inconsistent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D increased probability of low birth weight by 60 percent – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increased-probability-of-low-birth-weight-by-60-percent-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increased-probability-of-low-birth-weight-by-60-percent-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-maternal-neonatal-and-infant-health-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D During Pregnancy and Maternal, Neonatal and Infant Health Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Andrew Thorne-Lyman1,*, Wafaie W. Fawzi1,2,3; Article first published online: 28 JUN 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2012 Blackwell Publishing Ltd&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paediatric and Perinatal Epidemiology, Volume 26, Issue Supplement s1, pages 75–90, July 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Special Issue: Improving maternal, newborn, and child health outcomes through better designed policies and programs that enhance the nutrition of women&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:>85%">
&lt;p>The only daily vitamin D data used in the meta-analysis was 1000 IU of vitamin &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">D2&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X variation in response to dose of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/3x-variation-in-response-to-dose-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-variation-in-response-to-dose-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-systematic-review">A Systematic Review:&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="influence-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration">Influence of Vitamin D Supplementation on Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism June 14, 2012 jc.2012-1238&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Philippe Autier, Sara Gandini and Patrick Mullie&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International Prevention Research Institute (P.A., P.M.), 69006 Lyon, France; and European Institute of Oncology (S.G.), 20139 Milano, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address all correspondence and requests for reprints to: Philippe Autier, M.D., International Prevention Research Institute (iPRI), 95 Cours Lafayette, 69006 Lyon, France. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:philippe.autier@i-pri.org">philippe.autier@i-pri.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Example of a vitamin D meta-analysis which ignored the data</title><link>/posts/example-of-a-vitamin-d-meta-analysis-which-ignored-the-data.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/example-of-a-vitamin-d-meta-analysis-which-ignored-the-data.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="we-never-cease-to-be-amazed-at-the-stupidity-of-some-meta-analysis">We never cease to be amazed at the stupidity of some meta-analysis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Sometimes they take no account of the IUs of vitamin D taken by each of the trials they are analyzing&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Example: Vitamin D and gestational diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>European Journal of Internal Medicine 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The authors ignore that there was no statistical difference in vitamin D levels in three trials&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Farrant, Makgoba, and Baker stated that they had NO statistical difference between the two arms&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 is much better than D2, especially if not taken daily – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-is-much-better-than-d2-especially-if-not-taken-daily-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-is-much-better-than-d2-especially-if-not-taken-daily-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="comparison-of-vitamin-d2-and-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-raising-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis123">Comparison of vitamin D2 and vitamin D3 supplementation in raising serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status: a systematic review and meta-analysis1,2,3&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2012 June; 95(6): 1357–1364.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2012 May 2. Doi: 10.3945/ajcn.111.031070&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3349454&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laura Tripkovic, Helen Lambert, Kathryn Hart, Colin P Smith, Giselda Bucca, Simon Penson, Gemma Chope, Elina Hyppönen, Jacqueline Berry, Reinhold Vieth, and Susan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Currently, there is a lack of clarity in the literature as to whether there is a definitive difference between the effects of vitamins D2 and D3 in the raising of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D with Calcium reduces mortality by 7 percent – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-with-calcium-reduces-mortality-by-7-percent-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-with-calcium-reduces-mortality-by-7-percent-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 much better than D2 for loading doses– meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-much-better-than-d2-for-loading-doses-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-much-better-than-d2-for-loading-doses-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="comparison-of-vitamin-d2-and-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-raising-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-123">Comparison of vitamin D2 and vitamin D3 supplementation in raising serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status: a systematic review and meta-analysis 1,2,3&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Laura Tripkovic, Helen Lambert, Kathryn Hart, Colin P Smith, Giselda Bucca, Simon Penson, Gemma Chope, Elina Hyppönen, Jacqueline Berry, Reinhold Vieth, and Susan Lanham-New&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 From the Departments of Nutrition and Metabolism (LT, HL, SL-N, and KH) and Microbial and Cellular Sciences (CPS and GB), Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Surrey, Guildford, United Kingdom; Campden BRI, Chipping Campden, United Kingdom (SP and GC); the Institute of Child Health, University College London, London, United Kingdom (EH); the Vitamin D Research Group, Department of Medicine, University of Manchester, Manchester, United Kingdom (JB); and the Departments of Nutritional Sciences and Laboratory Medicine and Pathobiology, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada (RV).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10 percent of colon cancer linked to Vitamin D Receptor – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/10-percent-of-colon-cancer-linked-to-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10-percent-of-colon-cancer-linked-to-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-and-colorectal-cancer-risk-a-systematic-meta-analysis">Vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms and colorectal cancer risk: A systematic meta-analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>World J Gastroenterol. 2012 Apr 14;18(14):1672-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bai YH, Lu H, Hong D, Lin CC, Yu Z, Chen BC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yong-Heng Bai, Dan Hong, Cheng-Cheng Lin, Bi-Cheng Chen, Wenzhou Key Laboratory of Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical College, Wenzhou 325000, Zhejiang Province, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the relationship between polymorphisms present in the vitamin D receptor (VDR) gene and colorectal cancer risk, a systematic meta-analysis of population-based studies was performed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Food fortified by 440 IU increased vitamin D levels by 8 ng – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/food-fortified-by-440-iu-increased-vitamin-d-levels-by-8-ng-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/food-fortified-by-440-iu-increased-vitamin-d-levels-by-8-ng-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D plus steroids helps psoriasis 2X more than vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-plus-steroids-helps-psoriasis-2x-more-than-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-plus-steroids-helps-psoriasis-2x-more-than-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>50 percent fewer strokes with vitamin D, even though ignored dose size – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/50-percent-fewer-strokes-with-vitamin-d-even-though-ignored-dose-size-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/50-percent-fewer-strokes-with-vitamin-d-even-though-ignored-dose-size-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bone fracture meta-analysis – vitamin D and Calcium are OK</title><link>/posts/bone-fracture-meta-analysis-vitamin-d-and-calcium-are-ok.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-fracture-meta-analysis-vitamin-d-and-calcium-are-ok.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="comparative-effectiveness-of-drug-treatments-to-prevent-fragility-fractures-a-systematic-review-and-network-meta-analysis">Comparative Effectiveness of Drug Treatments to Prevent Fragility Fractures: A Systematic Review and Network Meta-Analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism March 30, 2012 jc.2011-3060&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Calcium &amp;amp; Vitamin D 19% reduction (unknown amounts of each)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Teriparatide 70% reduction of hip fractures&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Mohammad Hassan Murad &lt;a href="mailto:Murad.mohammad@mayo.edu">Murad.mohammad@mayo.edu&lt;/a> , Matthew T. Drake, Rebecca J. Mullan, Karen F. Mauck, Louise M. Stuart, Melanie A. Lane, Nisrin O. Abu Elnour, Patricia J. Erwin, Ahmad Hazem, Milo A. Puhan, Tianjing Li and Victor M. Montori&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low density lipoprotein cholesterol is predictable from vitamin D levels – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/low-density-lipoprotein-cholesterol-is-predictable-from-vitamin-d-levels-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-density-lipoprotein-cholesterol-is-predictable-from-vitamin-d-levels-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="influence-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-plasma-lipid-profiles-a-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials">Influence of vitamin D supplementation on plasma lipid profiles: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Hao Wang, Ning Xia, Yang Yang and Dao-Quan Peng&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lipids in Health and Disease 2012, 11:42 doi:10.1186/1476-511X-11-42, Published: 20 March 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract (provisional) &lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/ldl-metal-analysis-march-2012.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Observational studies have shown that low serum levels of vitamin D have been associated with an atherogenic lipid profile. However, the intervention studies gave divergent results. We conducted a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials that evaluated the effects of vitamin D supplementation on blood lipids. A systematic literature search was conducted via MEDLINE, Cochrane library, and EMBASE for randomized controlled clinical trials assessing the effects of vitamin D supplementation on lipids. The mean change in total cholesterol (TC), &lt;strong>low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C)&lt;/strong> , high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C) and triglycerides (TG) from baseline was treated as a continuous variable. In all, 12 clinical trials consisting of 1346 participants were included in the analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gestational diabetes 60 percent more likely below 20 ng of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/gestational-diabetes-60-percent-more-likely-below-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gestational-diabetes-60-percent-more-likely-below-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-gestational-diabetes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D and gestational diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#maternal-vitamin-d-status-as-a-critical-determinant-in-gestational-diabetes">Maternal vitamin d status as a critical determinant in gestational diabetes.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-gestational-diabetes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D and gestational diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Internal Medicine, online 20 February 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Y.H.M. Poel a, Corresponding author contact information, E-mail the corresponding author,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P. Hummel b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P. Lips c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>F. Stam a,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>T. van der Ploeg d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. Simseka c&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Internal Medicine, Gynaecology and Reproductive Medicine, Medical Centre Alkmaar, Alkmaar, The Netherlands&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death rate reduced 8 percent for 8 nanogram more vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/death-rate-reduced-8-percent-for-8-nanogram-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-rate-reduced-8-percent-for-8-nanogram-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D and omega-3 are the only supplements which show benefit in meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-omega-3-are-the-only-supplements-which-show-benefit-in-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-omega-3-are-the-only-supplements-which-show-benefit-in-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Graphs of Vitamin D and Cancer – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/graphs-of-vitamin-d-and-cancer-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/graphs-of-vitamin-d-and-cancer-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-with-or-without-calcium-supplementation-for-prevention-of-cancer-and-fractures-an-updated-meta-analysis-for-the-us-preventive-services-task-force">Vitamin D With or Without Calcium Supplementation for Prevention of Cancer and Fractures: An Updated Meta-analysis for the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-high-vitamin-d-levels-are-from-those-individuals-with-high-responses-to-only-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d">The high vitamin D levels are from those individuals with high responses to only 1,000 IU of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-with-or-without-calcium-supplementation-for-prevention-of-cancer-and-fractures-an-updated-meta-analysis-for-the-us-preventive-services-task-force">Vitamin D With or Without Calcium Supplementation for Prevention of Cancer and Fractures: An Updated Meta-analysis for the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Intern Med. 2011 Dec 20;155(12):827-38.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Psoriasis best treated by combinations such as vitamin D and UVB – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/psoriasis-best-treated-by-combinations-such-as-vitamin-d-and-uvb-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/psoriasis-best-treated-by-combinations-such-as-vitamin-d-and-uvb-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>40 ng Vitamin D perhaps optimal for reduced mortality – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/40-ng-vitamin-d-perhaps-optimal-for-reduced-mortality-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/40-ng-vitamin-d-perhaps-optimal-for-reduced-mortality-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-mortality-risk-in-the-general-population-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-cohort-studies">Vitamin D deficiency and mortality risk in the general population: a meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Dec 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zittermann A, Iodice S, Pilz S, &lt;strong>Grant WB&lt;/strong> , Bagnardi V, Gandini S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinic for Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery, Heart Centre North Rhine-Westphalia, Ruhr University Bochum, Bad Oeynhausen, Germany, San Francisco, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Low vitamin D status may increase mortality risk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: We used nonparametric (&amp;ldquo;highest compared with lowest&amp;rdquo; categories) and parametric (&amp;gt;2 categories) statistical models to evaluate associations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> serum concentrations and mortality in observational studies among general populations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon cancer probability increases with decreased vitamin D – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-probability-increases-with-decreased-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-probability-increases-with-decreased-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="meta-analysis-serum-vitamin-d-and-colorectal-adenoma-risk">Meta-analysis: Serum vitamin D and colorectal adenoma risk.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Prev Med. 2011 Jul-Aug;53(1-2):10-6. Epub 2011 Jun 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yin L, Grandi N, Raum E, Haug U, Arndt V, Brenner H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Clinical Epidemiology and Aging Research, German Cancer Research Center, Bergheimer Strasse 20, Heidelberg, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To perform a systematic review and meta-analysis of human studies on the association between serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and incident, sporadic colorectal adenoma (CRA) and CRA recurrence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Influenza vaccine meta-analysis found moderate protection – Lancet</title><link>/posts/influenza-vaccine-meta-analysis-found-moderate-protection-lancet.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/influenza-vaccine-meta-analysis-found-moderate-protection-lancet.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="efficacy-and-effectiveness-of-influenza-vaccines-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Efficacy and effectiveness of influenza vaccines: a systematic review and meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Lancet Infect Dis. 2011 Oct 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osterholm MT, Kelley NS, Sommer A, Belongia EA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Infectious Disease Research and Policy, University of Minnesota, MN, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/7x-less-risk-of-influenza-if-vitamin-d-levels-higher-than-30-ng" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: 7X less risk of influenza if Vitamin D levels higher than 30 ng – Oct 2017">7X less risk of influenza if Vitamin D levels higher than 30 ng – Oct 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: No published meta-analyses have assessed efficacy and effectiveness of licensed influenza vaccines in the USA with sensitive and highly specific diagnostic tests to confirm influenza.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Non-cancer colon growths 7 % less likely per 10 ng increase in Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/non-cancer-colon-growths-7-percent-less-likely-per-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/non-cancer-colon-growths-7-percent-less-likely-per-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#circulating-levels-of-vitamin-d-vitamin-d-receptor-polymorphisms-and-colorectal-adenoma-a-meta-analysis">Circulating levels of vitamin D, vitamin D receptor polymorphisms, and colorectal adenoma: a meta-analysis.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="circulating-levels-of-vitamin-d-vitamin-d-receptor-polymorphisms-and-colorectal-adenoma-a-meta-analysis">Circulating levels of vitamin D, vitamin D receptor polymorphisms, and colorectal adenoma: a meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr Res Pract. 2011 Oct;5(5):464-70&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee JE; Department of Food and Nutrition, Sookmyung Women&amp;rsquo;s University, 52 Hyochangwon gil, Yongsan-gu, Seoul 140-742, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Growing evidence suggests an elevated risk for colorectal neoplasia among individuals with low levels of vitamin D, the biological actions of which are mediated by the vitamin D receptor (VDR). To investigate the association among vitamin D status, VDR polymorphisms (FokI, and BsmI), and colorectal adenoma, we conducted a meta-analysis of nine studies of circulating levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and five studies of FokI or BsmI polymorphisms in relation to colorectal adenomas. Study-specific relative risks (RRs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were pooled using a random-effects model. A total of 3398 colorectal adenomas for 25(OH)D and 1754 colorectal adenomas for VDR were included in the meta-analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 but not D2 reduces mortality – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-but-not-d2-reduces-mortality-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-but-not-d2-reduces-mortality-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces falls – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-falls-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-falls-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-falls-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">The Effect of Vitamin D on Falls: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism October 1, 2011 vol. 96 no. 10 2997-3006&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohammad Hassan Murad,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Khalid B. Elamin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nisrin O. Abu Elnour,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohamed B. Elamin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aziz A. Alkatib,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mitra M. Fatourechi,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jaime P. Almandoz,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rebecca J. Mullan,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Melanie A. Lane,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hau Liu,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patricia J. Erwin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Donald D. Hensrud and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Victor M. Montori&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Knowledge and Encounter Research Unit (M.H.M., N.O.A.E., M.B.E., A.A.A., M.M.F., J.P.A., R.J.M., M.A.L., P.J.E., V.M.M.), and Division of Preventive, Occupational, and Aerospace Medicine (M.H.M., D.D.H.), Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota 55905; Department of Medicine (K.B.E.), Case Western Reserve University, Metrohealth Medical Center, Cleveland, Ohio 44109; Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes, Metabolism, and Nutrition (V.M.M.), Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota 55905; and Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism (H.L.), Santa Clara Valley Medical Center, San Jose, California 95128&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active form of vitamin D (calcitriol) cut in half the fractures following organ transplant – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/active-form-of-vitamin-d-calcitriol-cut-in-half-the-fractures-following-organ-tr-t-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-form-of-vitamin-d-calcitriol-cut-in-half-the-fractures-following-organ-tr-t-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D has a complex relationship with Cancer – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-has-a-complex-relationship-with-cancer-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-has-a-complex-relationship-with-cancer-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-deciphering-the-truth">Vitamin D and cancer: Deciphering the truth&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Biochimica et Biophysica Acta&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simone Mocellin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Oncological and Surgical Sciences, University ofPadova, Padova, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 16 April 2011, Accepted 4 July 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a hormone-like micronutrient involved not only in calcium metabolism but also in a variety of biological activities (e.g., cell proliferation, apoptosis, angiogenesis, inflammation) that makes it a candidate anticancer agent. Preclinical studies support the therapeutic potential of vitamin D both alone and in combination with other therapeutics. Overall, epidemiological data suggest the existence of a link between vitamin D and cancer risk, whereas the results of clinical trials are quite conflicting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2311 Systematic Reviews or Meta-Analyses of Vitamin D in PubMed</title><link>/posts/2311-systematic-reviews-or-meta-analyses-of-vitamin-d-in-pubmed.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2311-systematic-reviews-or-meta-analyses-of-vitamin-d-in-pubmed.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Colorectal cancer 26 percent less likely for every 10 ng of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colorectal-cancer-26-percent-less-likely-for-every-10-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-cancer-26-percent-less-likely-for-every-10-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>800 IU Vitamin D does not help heart – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-cardiovascular-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D and Cardiovascular Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mohamed B. Elamin, Nisrin O. Abu Elnour, Khalid B. Elamin, Mitra M. Fatourechi, Aziz A. Alkatib, Jaime P. Almandoz, Hau Liu, Melanie A. Lane, Rebecca J. Mullan, Ahmad Hazem, Patricia J. Erwin, Donald D. Hensrud, Mohammad Hassan Murad &lt;a href="mailto:murad.mohammad@mayo.edu">murad.mohammad@mayo.edu&lt;/a>. , Victor M. Montori&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Knowledge and Evaluation Research Unit (M.B.E., N.O.A.E., M.M.F., A.A.A., M.A.L., R.J.M., A.H., P.J.E., M.H.M., V.M.M.), Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota 55905;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recent Vitamin D Meta-analysis and Reviews</title><link>/posts/recent-vitamin-d-meta-analysis-and-reviews.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/recent-vitamin-d-meta-analysis-and-reviews.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Diabetes down 13 percent if more than 500 IU of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/diabetes-down-13-percent-if-more-than-500-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-down-13-percent-if-more-than-500-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-type-2-diabetes-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D and type 2 diabetes: a systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2011.118.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2011.118.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mitri J, Muraru MD, Pittas AG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes and Metabolism, Tufts Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Objectives:Vitamin D may modify the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus. The aim of this review was to examine the association between vitamin D status and incident type 2 diabetes, and the effect of vitamin D supplementation on glycemic outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Premature or low birth weight resulted in children 3X more likely to be anxious – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/premature-or-low-birth-weight-resulted-in-children-3x-more-likely-to-be-anxious-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/premature-or-low-birth-weight-resulted-in-children-3x-more-likely-to-be-anxious-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-psychiatric-diagnoses-in-preterm-and-full-term-children-adolescents-and-young-adults-a-meta-analysis">Prevalence of psychiatric diagnoses in preterm and full-term children, adolescents and young adults: a meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Psychological Medicine, Published online: 20 May 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. C. Burnetta1a2a3 &lt;a href="mailto:aburnett@unimelb.edu.au">aburnett@unimelb.edu.au&lt;/a>, P. J. Andersona3a4, J. Cheonga3a5a6, L. W. Doylea3a4a5a6, C. G. Daveya2a7 and S. J. Wooda2a8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a1 Department of Psychology, The University of Melbourne, VIC, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a2 Melbourne Neuropsychiatry Centre, Department of Psychiatry, The University of Melbourne and Melbourne Health, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a3 Murdoch Childrens Research Institute, Parkville, VIC, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon polyps reduced 15 percent by increasing vitamin D by 20 ng – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colon-polyps-reduced-15-percent-by-increasing-vitamin-d-by-20-ng-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-polyps-reduced-15-percent-by-increasing-vitamin-d-by-20-ng-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="meta-analysis-serum-vitamin-d-and-colorectal-adenoma-risk">Meta-analysis: Serum vitamin D and colorectal adenoma risk.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Prev Med. 2011 Jun 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yin L, Grandi N, Raum E, Haug U, Arndt V, Brenner H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To perform a systematic review and meta-analysis of human studies on the association between serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and incident, sporadic colorectal adenoma (CRA) and CRA recurrence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relevant studies among humans were identified by systematically searching Ovid Medline, EMBASE, and ISI Web of Knowledge databases and by cross-referencing. Due to the heterogeneity across studies in categorizing serum vitamin D levels, all results were recalculated for an increase of serum 25(OH)D by 20ng/ml. Summary odds ratios (ORs) were calculated using meta-analysis methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Each 10 ng increase in vitamin D decreased kidney disease death by 14 percent</title><link>/posts/each-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-disease-death-by-14-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/each-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-decreased-kidney-disease-death-by-14-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-and-mortality-risk-in-ckd-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Vitamin D Status and Mortality Risk in CKD: A Meta-analysis of Prospective Studies.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Kidney Dis. 2011 May 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pilz S, Iodice S, Zittermann A, Grant WB, Gandini S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria; Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics and EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency, assessed as low 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) level, is highly prevalent in patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) and is associated with various adverse health outcomes. Whether low 25(OH)D levels in patients with CKD are an independent risk factor for mortality remains to be studied in detail, and this was the objective of our work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Risk of Prostate Cancer weakly associated with vitamin D - meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/risk-of-prostate-cancer-weakly-associated-with-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/risk-of-prostate-cancer-weakly-associated-with-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="associations-of-circulating-and-dietary-vitamin-d-with-prostate-cancer-risk-a-systematic-review-and-dose-response-meta-analysis">Associations of circulating and dietary vitamin D with prostate cancer risk: a systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2011 Mar;22(3):319-40. Epub 2011 Jan 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Associations of circulating and dietary vitamin D with prostate cancer risk: a systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gilbert R, Martin RM, Beynon R, Harris R, Savovic J, Zuccolo L, Bekkering GE, Fraser WD, Sterne JA, Metcalfe C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Social and Community Medicine, University of Bristol, Canynge Hall, 39 Whatley Road, Bristol BS8 2PS, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:Becky.Gilbert@Bristol.ac.uk">Becky.Gilbert@Bristol.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Kidney Disease meta-analysis of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-kidney-disease-meta-analysis-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-chronic-kidney-disease-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-observational-studies-and-randomized-controlled-trials">Vitamin D Supplementation in Chronic Kidney Disease: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Observational Studies and Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>CJASN January 2011 vol. 6 no. 1 50-62 , published by American Society of Nephrology&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Praveen Kandula,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Mirela Dobre,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Jesse D. Schold,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Martin J. Schreiber ,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rajnish Mehrotra,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sankar D. Navaneethan&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Author Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> *Department of Nephrology, Indiana University, Indianapolis, Indiana;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Department of Internal Medicine, Huron Hospital, Cleveland, Ohio;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Department of Nephrology, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Department of Nephrology and Hypertension, Glickman Urological and Kidney Institute, and
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Quantitative Health Sciences, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Los Angeles Biomedical Research Institute at Harbor–University of California–Los Angeles Medical Center, Torrance, California; and
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> David Geffen School of Medicine at University of California–Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Correspondence:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>16 percent less Prostate Cancer sometimes for each 10 ng vitamin D increase - meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/16-percent-less-prostate-cancer-sometimes-for-each-10-ng-vitamin-d-increase-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/16-percent-less-prostate-cancer-sometimes-for-each-10-ng-vitamin-d-increase-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="associations-of-circulating-and-dietary-vitamin-d-with-prostate-cancer-risk-a-systematic-review-and-dose-response-meta-analysis">Associations of circulating and dietary vitamin D with prostate cancer risk: a systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2011 Jan 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gilbert R, Martin RM, Beynon R, Harris R, Savovic J, Zuccolo L, Bekkering GE, Fraser WD, Sterne JA, Metcalfe C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Social and Community Medicine, University of Bristol, Canynge Hall, 39 Whatley Road, Bristol, BS8 2PS, UK, &lt;a href="mailto:Becky.Gilbert@Bristol.ac.uk">Becky.Gilbert@Bristol.ac.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: We systematically reviewed and meta-analyzed literature examining associations of vitamin D (dietary intake, circulating 25-hydroxy-vitamin-D (25(OH)D), and 1,25-dihydroxy-vitamin-D (1,25(OH)(2)D) concentrations) with prostate cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium without vitamin D increased heart risk by 30 percent</title><link>/posts/calcium-without-vitamin-d-increased-heart-risk-by-30-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-without-vitamin-d-increased-heart-risk-by-30-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="strong-bones-equals-weak-heart">Strong Bones Equals Weak Heart&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="-abstract-and-link-to-article-is-at-the-bottom-of-this-page">&lt;strong># Abstract and link to article is at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="by-jennifer-gibson-pharmdhttpbrainbloggercom20110102strong-bones-equals-weak-heart">&lt;a href="http://brainblogger.com/2011/01/02/strong-bones-equals-weak-heart/">by Jennifer Gibson, PharmD&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Adequate calcium intake is an important nutritional factor for skeletal health. Calcium (when taken with adequate Vitamin D) prevents bone loss and decreases the risk of fractures and associated morbidity and mortality. Most adults require 1000 mg of calcium daily. (Children and postmenopausal women require slightly more.) For decades, physicians and pharmacists have been advocating calcium supplementation to ensure adequate intake for patients, particularly postmenopausal women, owing to a belief that calcium supplementation offered significant benefits without many adverse consequences. Now, a new meta-analysis in the British Medical Journal (BMJ) claims that calcium supplementation, in fact, leads to an increased risk for cardiovascular events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meta-analysis found hypertension reduced with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/meta-analysis-found-hypertension-reduced-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/meta-analysis-found-hypertension-reduced-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="blood-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-and-hypertension-a-meta-analysis">Blood 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration and hypertension: a meta-analysis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Hypertens. 2010 Dec 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burgaz A, Orsini N, Larsson SC, Wolk A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Environmental Medicine, Karolinska Institiute, Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: Increasing evidence indicates that vitamin D may influence the risk of hypertension, which is a major risk factor for cardiovascular disease. We conducted a meta-analysis to quantitatively review and summarize the results on the association between blood 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations and hypertension.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D trials, studies, and meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-trials-studies-and-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-trials-studies-and-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="on-dec-5-2010">On Dec 5, 2010&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="searched-pubmedhttpwwwncbinlmnihgovpubmed-with-vitamin-d-in-titleabstract-and-found">Searched &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/">PubMed&lt;/a> with &amp;ldquo;Vitamin D&amp;rdquo; in title/abstract and found&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="141-meta-analysis--overview-of-many-random-controlled-trials">141 Meta-Analysis = overview of many Random Controlled Trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="4784-reviews">4784 Reviews&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="998-random-controlled-trials">998 Random Controlled Trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="1668-clinical-trials">1668 Clinical Trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="38-practice-guidelines">38 Practice Guidelines&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="more-pubmed-articles-every-year-with-vitamin-d-in-title-or-abstract">More PubMed articles every year with vitamin D in title or abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="year-ending-2010----2429--ending-2009----1783--ending-2008----1541">year ending 2010 - &lt;strong>2429&lt;/strong> ; ending 2009 - &lt;strong>1783&lt;/strong> ; ending 2008 - &lt;strong>1541&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h5 id="whereas-vitamin-a-was-mentioned-only-2389-times-in-the-past-5-years">whereas, &amp;ldquo;vitamin A&amp;rdquo; was mentioned only 2389 times in the past 5 years&lt;/h5>
&lt;h2 id="searched-us-clinical-trials-databasehttpclinicaltrialsgovct2resultsterm22vitamind22t-for-vitamin-d">Searched &lt;a href="http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/results?term=%22vitamin+d%22T">US Clinical Trials database&lt;/a> for Vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="720-clinical-trials">720 clinical trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="421-clinical-trials-updated-since-jan-1-2010">421 clinical trials updated since Jan 1, 2010&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;333&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>