<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Headache on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/headache.html</link><description>Recent content in Headache on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/headache/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fewer headaches and other benefits of higher vitamin D</title><link>/posts/fewer-headaches-and-other-benefits-of-higher-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fewer-headaches-and-other-benefits-of-higher-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Acute Migraine 35 times more likely if low Magnesium levels</title><link>/posts/acute-migraine-35-times-more-likely-if-low-magnesium-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/acute-migraine-35-times-more-likely-if-low-magnesium-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.newsweek.com/vitamin-deficiency-causes-chronic-migraines-469227">VITAMIN DEFICIENCIES MAY PROMPT CHRONIC MIGRAINES&lt;/a> Newsweek June 2016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Comment by Dr. Andrew Hershey, director of the Migraine Center at the Cincinnati Children’s Hospital Medical Center on the above study&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;Hershey questions the use of magnesium supplements for treating migraines because he says only about 1 percent is absorbed by the body, and it is also difficult to measure in the blood.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://headacheandmigrainenews.com/magnesium-for-migraine-graphic/">http://headacheandmigrainenews.com/magnesium-for-migraine-graphic/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/mg-mig.jpg" alt="image" width="300">
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Magnesium Solution for Migraine - 2004 book&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/mg-mig-book.jpg" alt="image">&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Migraine headaches quickly reduced with Magnesium – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/migraine-headaches-quickly-reduced-with-magnesium-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/migraine-headaches-quickly-reduced-with-magnesium-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Migraine headaches reduced with 50,000 IU vitamin D weekly – RCT</title><link>/posts/migraine-headaches-reduced-with-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/migraine-headaches-reduced-with-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-symptoms-and-c-reactive-protein-in-migraine-patients">Effect of Vitamin D supplementation on symptoms and C-reactive protein in migraine patients&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Research in Medical Sciences&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tayebeh Mottaghi, Gholamreza Askari, Fariborz Khorvash, Mohammad Reza Maracy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Migarine is the most common headache around the world including Iran. In recent years, Vitamin D deficiency has been shown to a global health problem. A few studies have been determined inverse association between serum levels of Vitamin D with a headache. So, in this study, we investigated the effect of Vitamin D supplementation on symptoms and C-reactive protein(CRP) among patients with migraine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pain not reduced by vitamin D (only used 1,000 IU) - RCT</title><link>/posts/pain-not-reduced-by-vitamin-d-only-used-1000-iu-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pain-not-reduced-by-vitamin-d-only-used-1000-iu-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-on-musculoskeletal-pain-and-headache-a-randomized-double-blind-placebo-controlled-trial-among-adult-ethnic-minorities-in-norway">Effect of vitamin D on musculoskeletal pain and headache: A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial among adult ethnic minorities in Norway.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pain. 2014 Dec;155(12):2591-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pain.2014.09.024.">doi: 10.1016/j.pain.2014.09.024.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Sep 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Knutsen KV1, Madar AA2, Brekke M3, Meyer HE4, Natvig B3, Mdala I3, Lagerløv P3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Immigrants from South Asia, the Middle East, and Africa living in Northern Europe frequently have low vitamin D levels and more pain compared to the native Western population. The aim of this study was to examine whether daily vitamin D3 &lt;strong>(25 μg/d&lt;/strong> or 10 μg/d) supplementation for 16 weeks would improve musculoskeletal pain or headache compared to placebo. This randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group trial recruited 251 participants aged 18 to 50 years, and 215 (86%) attended the follow-up visit. The pain measures were occurrence, anatomical localization, and degree of musculoskeletal pain, as measured by visual analogue scale (VAS) score during the past 2 weeks. Headache was measured with VAS and the Headache Impact Test (HIT-6) questionnaire. At baseline, females reported more pain sites (4.7) than males (3.4), and only 7% reported no pain in the past 2 weeks. During the past 4 weeks, 63% reported headache with a high mean HIT-6 score of 60 (SD 7). At follow-up, vitamin D level, measured as serum 25(OH)D3, increased from &lt;strong>27 nmol/L to 52 nmol/L&lt;/strong> and from 27 nmol/L to 43 nmol/L in the 25-μg and 10-μg supplementation groups, respectively, whereas serum 25(OH)D3 did not change in the placebo group. &lt;strong>Pain scores and headache scores were improved at follow-up compared with baseline&lt;/strong> . The use of vitamin D supplements, however, showed no significant effect on the occurrence, anatomical localization, and degree of pain or headache compared to placebo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Childhood migraine in Vitamin D deficient children reduced 6X by addition of daily 5,000 IU and amitriptyline</title><link>/posts/childhood-migraine-in-vitamin-d-deficient-children-reduced-6x-by-addition-of-dai-d-amitriptyline.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/childhood-migraine-in-vitamin-d-deficient-children-reduced-6x-by-addition-of-dai-d-amitriptyline.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-therapy-in-addition-to-amitriptyline-on-migraine-attacks-in-pediatric-patients">Effect of vitamin D therapy in addition to amitriptyline on migraine attacks in pediatric patients.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Braz J Med Biol Res. 2014 Apr;47(4):349-54. Epub 2014 Apr 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cayir A1, Turan MI2, Tan H3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of supplementary vitamin D therapy in addition to amitriptyline on the frequency of migraine attacks in pediatric migraine patients. Fifty-three children 8-16 years of age and diagnosed with migraine following the International Headache Society 2005 definition, which includes childhood criteria, were enrolled.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migranes not reduced by those having a fraction of a nanogram more vitamin D (no surprise)</title><link>/posts/migranes-not-reduced-by-those-having-a-fraction-of-a-nanogram-more-vitamin-d-no-surprise.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/migranes-not-reduced-by-those-having-a-fraction-of-a-nanogram-more-vitamin-d-no-surprise.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-in-migraine-patients-a-case-control-study">Vitamin D Status in Migraine Patients: A Case-Control Study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>BioMed Research International; Volume 2014 (2014), Article ID 514782, 7 pages; &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/514782">http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/514782&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alireza Zandifar,1,2 Samaneh sadat Masjedi,2 Mahboobeh Banihashemi,2 Fatemeh Asgari,2 Navid Manouchehri,2 Homa Ebrahimi,3 Faraidoon Haghdoost,1,2 and Mohammad Saadatnia1,4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Physiology Research Center, Department of Physiology, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan 81745-319, Iran&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Medical Student Research Center, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan 81745-319, Iran&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Medical Student Research Center, Faculty of Medicine, Islamic Azad University, NajafAbad Branch, NajafAbad 8514143131, Iran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis– Chronic headache and musculoskeletal pain both result from low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-chronic-headache-and-musculoskeletal-pain-both-result-from-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-chronic-headache-and-musculoskeletal-pain-both-result-from-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="interrelationships-between-chronic-tension-type-headache-musculoskeletal-pain-and-vitamin-d-deficiency">Interrelationships between chronic tension-type headache, musculoskeletal pain, and vitamin D deficiency:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Is osteomalacia responsible for both headache and musculoskeletal pain?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ann Indian Acad Neurol. 2013 Oct;16(4):650-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4103/0972-2327.120487.">doi: 10.4103/0972-2327.120487.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prakash S, Kumar M, Belani P, Susvirkar A, Ahuja S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:Headache, musculoskeletal symptoms, and vitamin D deficiency are common in the general population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, the interrelations between these three have not been delineated in the literature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MATERIALS AND METHODS:We retrospectively studied a consecutive series of patients who were diagnosed as having chronic tension-type headache (CTTH) and were subjected to the estimation of serum vitamin D levels. The subjects were divided into two groups according to serum 25(OH) D levels as normal (&amp;gt;20 ng/ml) or vitamin D deficient (&amp;lt;20 ng/ml).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cluster headaches virtually eliminated in 7,000 people with high-dose vitamin D and cofactors</title><link>/posts/cluster-headaches-virtually-eliminated-in-7000-people-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-and-cofactors.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cluster-headaches-virtually-eliminated-in-7000-people-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-and-cofactors.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="fda-approved-cluster-headache-drug-in-spring-2019">FDA approved Cluster Headache drug in Spring 2019&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>$550/mo only slightly better than placebo, major side effects, &lt;a href="https://dgalerts.docguide.com/first-treatment-approved-fda-episodic-cluster-headache?nl_ref=newsletter&amp;amp;pk_campaign=newsletter&amp;amp;nl_eventid=29908%20">News Release&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Emgality experienced 8.7 fewer weekly cluster headache attacks than they did at baseline, compared to 5.2 fewer attacks for patients on placebo. &amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Emgality is given by patient self-injection. It was first approved by the FDA in September 2018 for the preventive treatment of migraine in adults. The FDA granted the approval of Emgality to Eli Lilly. &amp;quot;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Headache 20 pcnt more likely if low vitamin D, even after adjusting for vitamin D problems</title><link>/posts/headache-20-pcnt-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-even-after-adjusting-for-vitamin-d-problems.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/headache-20-pcnt-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-even-after-adjusting-for-vitamin-d-problems.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>