<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Headache on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/headache.html</link><description>Recent content in Headache on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/headache/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migraine and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/migraine-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/migraine-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dr-gominak-in-texas-has-some-interesting-ideas-about-migraines-sleep-and-vitamind">Dr. Gominak in Texas has some interesting ideas about Migraines, Sleep, and Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="see-new-publication-by-dr-gominak-nov-2011-poor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d---nov2011postspoor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d">see new publication by Dr. Gominak Nov 2011 &lt;a href="/posts/poor-sleep-and-lack-of-vitamin-d">Poor sleep and lack of vitamin D - Nov 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="click-herehttpdrgominakcomheadache-migraine-for-her-web-page-on-migraines-and-vitamind">&lt;a href="http://drgominak.com/headache-migraine">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for her web page on Migraines and Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="notes-from-pdf-spantiki-download_filephpfileid1658span-forpdf">Notes from PDF &lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1658]&lt;/span> for PDF&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Migraine pain transmitters are mutant genes that turn on the pain receptors that evolved to be activated only with concussions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you do not have a migraine gene, a sleep disorder will not cause headache pain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Migraine</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-migraine.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-migraine.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-migraine-and-healthmedical-complications--optimize-therapy">Vitamin D, Migraine and HealthMedical Complications: Optimize Therapy!&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Steve D. Wheeler, MD, FAAN, FAHS; Barclay R. Gang, MS; and Frederick R. Taylor, MD, FAHS&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From: &lt;a href="http://www.achenet.org/education/patients/VitaminDMigraineandHealthOptimizeTherapy.asp">http://www.achenet.org/education/patients/VitaminDMigraineandHealthOptimizeTherapy.asp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-points">Key Points:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Vitamin D deficiency occurs in 30-100% of various populations, particularly the ill, elderly, highly pigmented ethic groups, obese, postmenopausal, pregnant and lactating women, children, young adults and those who avoid sun exposure—all populations, including migraineurs, are at risk.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Vitamin D is not a vitamin but a non-sex hormone.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>Vitamin D deficiency is associated with many diseases including multiple cancers and inflammatory disorders including cardiovascular disease and severe arthritic conditions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>Vitamin D has anti-inflammatory and analgesic activities. Deficiency may play a role in mechanisms responsible for migraine and other pain syndromes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>Vitamin D deficiency is diagnosed by a simple, inexpensive blood test, a 25-hydroxyvitamin D level, and is easy and inexpensive to treat.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="6">
&lt;li>To obtain optimum levels for health, typically an average of 1000 international units (IU) vitamin D3 per 25-30 pounds of body weight daily is required. This is not a toxic dose.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We make vitamin D from sunlight at certain times of the year dependent on where we live. We get small amounts of vitamin D from our diets, like oily fish, and fortified foods, particularly milk, and supplements. Vitamin D deficiency is a worldwide problem. You may be surprised to learn that recent studies show vitamin D deficiency occurs in 32% of healthy students, physicians, and hospital residents, 73% of pregnant women, and 40-100% of community dwelling elderly. Studies on the ill show that 93% of people admitted to hospital emergency departments with muscle aches, bone pain, and a variety of diagnoses, including fibromyalgia, chronic fatigue syndrome, and depression, are vitamin D deficient. Low back pain is associated with vitamin D deficiency and reports show that improved vitamin D levels result in pain relief. Furthermore, breast cancer survivors who experience Femara® (letrozole) associated joint or muscular pains improve dramatically with vitamin D supplements.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>