<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Toxicity of Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/toxicity-of-vitamin-d.html</link><description>Recent content in Toxicity of Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/toxicity-of-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D intoxication if more than 150 ng</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-intoxication-if-more-than-150-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-intoxication-if-more-than-150-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-intoxication">Vitamin D intoxication&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Turkish Journal of Pediatrics 2012; 54: 93-98 March&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Behzat Ozkan1, §ukru Hatun2, Abdullah Bereket3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Pediatric Endocrinology, 1istanbul Medeniyet University Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul, 2Kocaeli University Faculty of Medicine, Kocaeli, and 3Marmara University Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul, Turkey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUMMARY:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D intoxication (VDI) may result from supplementation rarely, but it has been reported more frequently in recent years. This may be attributable to an increase in vitamin D supplement intake due to an understanding of the role of vitamin D (25OHD) in the pathogenesis of several diseases. The symptoms and findings associated with VDI are closely related to serum calcium concentration and duration of hypercalcemia. In patients with VDI, hypercalcemia, normal or high serum phosphorus levels, normal or low levels of alkaline phosphatase (ALP), high levels of serum 25OHD, low serum parathyroid hormone (PTH), and high urine calcium/creatinine are usually present. Serum 25OHD levels above 150 ng/ml are considered as VDI. The main goal of treatment for VDI is correction of the hypercalcemia. When the calcium concentration exceeds 14 mg/dl, emergency intervention is necessary because of the adverse effects of hypercalcemia on cardiac, central nervous system, renal, and gastrointestinal functions. However, since vitamin D is stored in fat tissues, effects of toxicity may last for months despite the removal of the exogenous source of vitamin D. Treatment for VDI includes: discontinuation of intake, a diet with low calcium and phosphorus content, intravenous hydration with saline, loop diuretics, glucocorticoids, calcitonin, and bisphosphonates. In conclusion, the diagnosis of vitamin D deficiency rickets (VDDR) without checking serum 25OHD level may cause redundant treatment that leads to VDI. All patients who are clinically suspected of VDDR should be checked for serum vitamin D status and questioned for previous vitamin D administration before starting vitamin D therapy. On the other hand, parents of all infants should be asked whether they are using dietary or oral supplements, and serial questioning may be required during supplementation to avoid excessive intake.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1000 IU of vitamin D (per kg) can indeed be toxic – 1947</title><link>/posts/1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-can-indeed-be-toxic-1947.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-can-indeed-be-toxic-1947.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="there-were-many-studies-in-the-1940s-stating-that">There were many studies in the 1940’s stating that&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>    1000 IU of vitamin D &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">per kilogram of body weight&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> was toxic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The average weight of an adult was approximately 70 kg, so yes, I agree, 70,000 IU of vitamin D can be toxic.&lt;br>
I had often wondered why doctors had been told that 1,000 or 2,000 IU of vitamin D was toxic.&lt;br>
My guess is that the old message was trimmed to 1,000 IU of vitamin D is toxic,&lt;br>
Note in the clipping belows that even 35 X higher was sometimes not toxic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D: Is It the Best Thing Under the Sun - Medscape</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-it-the-best-thing-under-the-sun-medscape.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-it-the-best-thing-under-the-sun-medscape.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert Finn; Deborah Flapan; Darbe Rotach&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-following-is-the-first-of-25-images">The following is the first of 25 images&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image"> 
&lt;p>The number of research studies on vitamin D has soared in recent years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Citations of studies involving vitamin D increased from 1142 in the year 2000 to 3877 in 2012.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In comparison, citations for research on vitamin A and vitamin C have remained more or less level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to register with &lt;a href="http://www.medscape.com/features/slideshow/vitamin-d#20">Medscape&lt;/a> to see the other images, with text&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is High Dose Vitamin D Harmful</title><link>/posts/is-high-dose-vitamin-d-harmful.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-high-dose-vitamin-d-harmful.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-high-dose-vitamin-d-harmful">Is High Dose Vitamin D Harmful?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Calcif Tissue Int Dec 2012 DOI 10.1007/s00223-012-9679-1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kerrie M. Sanders • Geoffrey C. Nicholson • Peter R. Ebeling&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K. M. Sanders (&amp;amp;) • G. C. Nicholson • P. R. Ebeling Department of Medicine, Western Health, NorthWest Academic Centre, University of Melbourne, PO Box 294, St Albans, VIC 3021, Australia e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:ksanders@unimelb.edu.au">ksanders@unimelb.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G. C. Nicholson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rural Clinical School, School of Medicine, University of Queensland, Toowoomba, QLD, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10,000 IU vitamin D daily is safe, toxicity start at 150 ng (for monotherapy)</title><link>/posts/10000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-is-safe-toxicity-start-at-150-ng-for-monotherapy.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-is-safe-toxicity-start-at-150-ng-for-monotherapy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="anti-cancer-agents-in-medicinal-chemistry-volume-13-issue-1-pp4-10-7">Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.4-10 (7)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Authors: Armin Zittermann, Sylvana Prokop, Jan F. Gummert, Jochen Borgermann&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-toxicity-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 898">Overview Toxicity of vitamin D&lt;/a> which has the following summary&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="color:#390;">Many weeks for a really large DAILY dose of vitamin D to&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#F0C;">become toxic&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h4 id="summary-of-points-of-this-paper-by-vitamin-d-councilhttpblogvitamindcouncilorg20121218vitamin-d-safety-risks-and-benefits-of-fortification-and-supplementation-dec-2012">Summary of points of this paper by &lt;a href="http://blog.vitamindcouncil.org/2012/12/18/vitamin-d-safety-risks-and-benefits-of-fortification-and-supplementation/">Vitamin D Council&lt;/a> Dec 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Data on skin synthesis of vitamin D indicate oral intake of 10,000 IU/day is safe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Concern about accidentally giving infant too much liquid vitamin D</title><link>/posts/concern-about-accidentally-giving-infant-too-much-liquid-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/concern-about-accidentally-giving-infant-too-much-liquid-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#too-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-dhttpwwwindependentiehealthtoo-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-d-3190474html">&lt;a href="http://www.independent.ie/health/too-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-d-3190474.html">Too easy to overdose on infant vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#extremely-unlikely-that-there-would-be-any-problem-with-giving-a-months-worth-of-vitamin-d-accidentally">Extremely unlikely that there would be any problem with giving a months worth of vitamin D accidentally.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="too-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-dhttpwwwindependentiehealthtoo-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-d-3190474html">&lt;a href="http://www.independent.ie/health/too-easy-to-overdose-on-infant-vitamin-d-3190474.html">Too easy to overdose on infant vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>By EILISH O’REGAN, Monday August 06 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A growing number of parents are contacting the National Poisons Unit with fears that they have harmed their baby by giving them too much vitamin D supplement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The unit, based in Beaumont Hospital in Dublin, pointed out that since May 2010 it has been the policy of the Department of Health that all infants, from birth to 12 months, be given a daily supplement of 5 micrograms (200IU) of vitamin D3, to help development of bones and teeth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dosing error gave 12000 IU daily vitamin D to infant, but no indication of any problem</title><link>/posts/dosing-error-gave-12000-iu-daily-vitamin-d-to-infant-but-no-indication-of-any-problem.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dosing-error-gave-12000-iu-daily-vitamin-d-to-infant-but-no-indication-of-any-problem.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dosing-error-with-over-the-counter-vitamin-d-supplement-a-risk-for-vitamin-d-toxicity-in-infants">Dosing Error With Over-the-Counter Vitamin D Supplement: A Risk for Vitamin D Toxicity in Infants.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2012 Apr 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rajakumar K, Reis EC, Holick MF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of 400 IU an infant was given 12,000 IU of vitamin D daily for 20 days&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to parents giving 1 mil liter as they were used to instead of 1 drop, from the new product&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors were extremely concerned about infant toxicity&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>As much as 10000 IU vitamin D is safe – review</title><link>/posts/as-much-as-10000-iu-vitamin-d-is-safe-review.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/as-much-as-10000-iu-vitamin-d-is-safe-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-21st-century-evaluation-of-the-safety-of-oral-vitamin-d">A 21st century evaluation of the safety of oral vitamin D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrition. 2012 Apr;28(4):344-56.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glade MJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Nutrition Doctor, Skokie, Illinois, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The safety of daily consumption of vitamin D was examined. A detailed literature search was conducted using the search term vitamin D; primary and secondary sources of original data and meta-analyses and systematic reviews were evaluated and summarized. A large body of scientific evidence demonstrates that long-term daily intakes of 600 to 800 IU of vitamin D are insufficient to achieve and sustain vitamin D adequacy (serum 25-hydroxyergocalciferol + 25-hydroxycholecalciferol concentration &amp;gt;75 nmol/L). Maximization of the physiologic benefits of vitamin D to the musculoskeletal system, the central and peripheral nervous systems, the heart and central and peripheral cardiovascular systems, the respiratory system, the skin, the eyes, dentition, glucoregulation, immunoregulation, and disease resistance requires daily vitamin D intakes of at least 1500 IU. Because long-term daily intakes up to and including 10 000 IU of vitamin D do not produce signs or symptoms of vitamin D toxicity and are safe for the entire general population of otherwise healthy adults, even daily vitamin D intakes of 2000 IU allow for the often-cited and excessively conservative five-fold safety factor. In conclusion, long-term daily intakes of up to and including 10 000 IU of vitamin D maximize physiologic benefits and are safe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Replentishment (Loading doses are not toxic)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-replentishment-loading-doses-are-not-toxic.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-replentishment-loading-doses-are-not-toxic.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D stigma in the 1980's established toxic level as 1000 IU</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-stigma-in-the-1980s-established-toxic-level-as-1000-iu.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-stigma-in-the-1980s-established-toxic-level-as-1000-iu.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="clipped-from-experience-lifehttpwwwexperiencelifemagcomissuesdecember-2011healthy-eatingthe-vitamin-d-debatephp-dec-2011">clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.experiencelifemag.com/issues/december-2011/healthy-eating/the-vitamin-d-debate.php">Experience Life&lt;/a> Dec 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Fast forward to the 1980s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s when doctors in India treated six tuberculosis patients with &lt;strong>3,800 international units (IU) of vitamin D&lt;/strong> daily for three months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The patients developed dangerously high blood levels of calcium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The doctors blaimed the vitamin D, but they never measured the patients’ blood levels of the vitamin, or acknowledged that super-high calcium levels could be common in people with tuberculosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Name a rat poison crucial to health and safer than water</title><link>/posts/name-a-rat-poison-crucial-to-health-and-safer-than-water.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/name-a-rat-poison-crucial-to-health-and-safer-than-water.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="answer-vitamin-dhttpwwwthaifoodandtravelcomfeaturesvitamindhtml--apparently-from-vitamin-d-council-2005">&lt;a href="http://www.thaifoodandtravel.com/features/vitaminD.html">Answer: Vitamin D&lt;/a> apparently from Vitamin D Council 2005&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="yes-cholecalciferol-is-a-rat-poison">Yes, cholecalciferol is a rat poison.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If it&amp;rsquo;s a rat poison, why did Professor Heaney just recommend up to 4,000 units every day? J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2005 Jul 15; &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer is dosage. To demonstrate the point, I recently swallowed an entire bottle (100 capsules) of vitamin D (40,000 units) in front of a skeptical audience to convince them that vitamin D is safer than water. Here&amp;rsquo;s why. Eight glasses of water a day is fine for healthy adults. Ten times that amount, eighty glasses of water, will make you sick from water intoxication.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increasing deaths - perhaps an epidemic</title><link>/posts/increasing-deaths-perhaps-an-epidemic.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increasing-deaths-perhaps-an-epidemic.html</guid><description>&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;755&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="big-increase-in-deaths-in-america-over-the-past-decade-in-the-middle-line">Big increase in deaths in America over the past decade in the middle line&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="if-the-deaths-were-due-to-a-disease-the-increase-death-rate-would-be-called-an-epidemic">If the deaths were due to a disease the increase death rate would be called an epidemic&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="since-the-increase-in-deaths-is-due-to-drugs-it-should-have-a-different-name">Since the increase in deaths is due to drugs it should have a different name.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="click-here-for-the-la-times-articlehttpwwwlatimescomnewsla-me-drugs-epidemic-2011091803660682story-sept-2011">&lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/la-me-drugs-epidemic-20110918,0,3660682.story">CLICK HERE for the LA Times article&lt;/a> Sept 2011&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The top line is deaths due to automobiles&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The middle increasing line is deaths due to &lt;strong>prescription drugs&lt;/strong> (accidental overdoses, suicides, and fatal diseases caused by drugs)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>50000 IU vitamin D daily toxic after 3 months</title><link>/posts/50000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-toxic-after-3-months.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/50000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-toxic-after-3-months.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hypervitaminosis-d-associated-with-a-vitamin-d-dispensing-error">Hypervitaminosis D Associated with a Vitamin D Dispensing Error&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ann Pharmacother September 13, 2011 aph.1Q330&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ryan B Jacobsen, PharmD, Clinical Pharmacy Specialist?1 &lt;a href="mailto:ryan-jacobsen@uiowa.edu">ryan-jacobsen@uiowa.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brett W Hronek, MD, Resident Physician?2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ginelle A Schmidt, PharmD, Assistant Professor?3 and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Margo L Schilling, MD, Professor?1*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 University of Iowa Hospitals and Clinics; Assistant Professor (Clinical), College of Pharmacy, University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Internal Medicine, University of Iowa Hospitals and Clinics&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CYP24A1 gene mutation is a cause of rare infant vitamin D toxicity</title><link>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-mutation-is-a-cause-of-rare-infant-vitamin-d-toxicity.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp24a1-gene-mutation-is-a-cause-of-rare-infant-vitamin-d-toxicity.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mutations-in-cyp24a1-and-idiopathic-infantile-hypercalcemia">Mutations in CYP24A1 and Idiopathic Infantile Hypercalcemia.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med. 2011 Jun 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schlingmann KP, Kaufmann M, Weber S, Irwin A, Goos C, John U, Misselwitz J, Klaus G, Kuwertz-Bröking E, Fehrenbach H, Wingen AM, Güran T, Hoenderop JG, Bindels RJ, Prosser DE, Jones G, Konrad M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Muenster (K.P.S., E.K.-B., M. Konrad); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Marburg (K.P.S., C.G.); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Essen (S.W., A.M.W.); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Jena (U.J., J.M.); Kuratorium für Heimdialyse Pediatric Kidney Center, Marburg (G.K.); and Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Memmingen (H.F.) - all in Germany; Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Kingston, ON, Canada (M. Kaufmann, A.I., D.E.P., G.J.); University Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey (T.G.); and Radboud University, Nijmegen, the Netherlands (J.G.H., R.J.B.).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium Magnesium softgels recall by NOW Foods – excessive vitamin D</title><link>/posts/calcium-magnesium-softgels-recall-by-now-foods-excessive-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-magnesium-softgels-recall-by-now-foods-excessive-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 softgels daily for the following amounts&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D3 600 IU &lt;strong>but was actually 30,000 – 40,000 IU&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Calcium 1,000 mg&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Magnesium 500 mg&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Zinc 	10 mg&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Now Foods said it has received reports of nausea and elevated blood vitamin D levels&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Symptoms of high vitamin D dietary intake also can include fatigue, headaches and loss of appetite, among other side effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="click-herehttpwwwnowfoodscom082727htm-for-details">&lt;a href="http://www.nowfoods.com/082727.htm">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for details&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>– – – – – – – –&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D overdose items from Easy Immune System Health</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-overdose-items-from-easy-immune-system-health.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-overdose-items-from-easy-immune-system-health.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Controversy: Too much Calcium if increase Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/controversy-too-much-calcium-if-increase-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/controversy-too-much-calcium-if-increase-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#50-percent-of-elderly-got-hypercalcimia-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d--feb-2011">50 percent of elderly got hypercalcimia with 2000 IU of vitamin D – Feb 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="50-percent-of-elderly-got-hypercalcimia-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d--feb-2011">50 percent of elderly got hypercalcimia with 2000 IU of vitamin D – Feb 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Evaluation of the effectiveness of cholecalciferol in long-term care elderly patients with hypovitaminosis d.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consult Pharm. 2011 Feb;26(2):101-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shin M, Minden C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sullivan University College of Pharmacy, Louisville, Kentucky.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To study the efficacy and safety of cholecalciferol &lt;strong>(vitamin D3) 2,000 units&lt;/strong> daily for 12 weeks in elderly patients with hypovitaminosis D. Secondarily, to postulate causes for those patients who did not return to normal 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25-OHD) levels.Design: One-group, pretest post-test. Retrospective chart review. Data collected from Computerized Patient Record System.Setting: Long-term care facility at Central Arkansas Veterans Healthcare System.Patients, Participants: Potential study subjects were elderly patients (? 65 years of age) treated with total daily dose of cholecalciferol 2,000 units daily by mouth, for at least 12 weeks&amp;rsquo; duration period between July 1, 2007, and July 31, 2009, with documented 25-OHD levels before and after treatment.Interventions: None.Main Outcome Measures: Efficacy of cholecalciferol was assessed by categorizing patients as responders (25-OHD levels ? 30 ng/mL) and nonresponders (25-OHD levels &amp;lt; 30 ng/mL).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is toxic to mice at 400 ng level</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-toxic-to-mice-at-400-ng-level.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-toxic-to-mice-at-400-ng-level.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-is-not-responsible-for-toxicity-caused-by-vitamin-d-or-25-hydroxyvitamin-d">1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D is not responsible for toxicity caused by vitamin D or 25-hydroxyvitamin D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arch Biochem Biophys 505(2):226-30 (2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hector F Deluca, Jean M Prahl and Lori A Plum&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Biochemistry, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D intoxication was produced with oral doses of either vitamin D(3) or 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3) in CYP27B1 -/- (1?-hydroxylase knockout) and wild-type mice. These compounds were equally toxic in wild-type and the mutant mice. Since the null mutant mice are unable to produce 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D, it is clear 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D is not responsible for vitamin D intoxication. On the other hand, 25-hydroxyvitamin D rises to levels of &lt;strong>400-700ng/ml&lt;/strong> or 1000-1750nM in the serum of both groups of mice. Toxicity was evidenced by severe hypercalcemia and weight loss. Measurement of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) in serum confirmed its absence from serum of the CYP27B1 -/- mice given 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3). Since high concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D can bind the vitamin D receptor and can induce transcription, 25-hydroxyvitamin D is likely responsible for toxicity of vitamin D excess. Copyright Â© 2010 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved. DOI: 10.1016/j.abb.2010.10.012 * PMID: 20965147&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero Deaths from Vitamins Minerals Amino Acids or Herbs</title><link>/posts/zero-deaths-from-vitamins-minerals-amino-acids-or-herbs.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/zero-deaths-from-vitamins-minerals-amino-acids-or-herbs.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="us-govt-report-for-2009httporthomolecularorgresourcesomnsv07n01shtml">&lt;a href="http://orthomolecular.org/resources/omns/v07n01.shtml">US Govt report for 2009&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="prescription-drug-overdose-deaths-in-us-may-be-20000-x-higher-than-deaths-due-to-all-vitamins-herbs-etc">Prescription drug overdose deaths in US may be 20,000 X higher than deaths due to all vitamins, herbs, etc.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="deaths-due-to-prescription-drugs--180000-x-higher-than-deaths-due-to-all-vitamins-herbs-etc">Deaths due to prescription drugs &amp;gt; 180,000 X higher than deaths due to all vitamins, herbs, etc.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="the-new-200-page-annual-report-of-the-american-association-of-poison-control-centers-published-in-the-journal-clinical-toxicology-shows">The new 200-page annual report of the American Association of Poison Control Centers, published in the journal Clinical Toxicology, shows&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>zero deaths from multiple vitamins;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>zero deaths from any of the B vitamins;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Masterjohn on relationships between Vitamin A D and K</title><link>/posts/masterjohn-on-relationships-between-vitamin-a-d-and-k.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/masterjohn-on-relationships-between-vitamin-a-d-and-k.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-vitamin-d-safe-still-depends-on-vitamins-a-and-k-testimonials-and-a-human-study">Is Vitamin D Safe? Still Depends on Vitamins A and K! Testimonials and a Human Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.westonaprice.org/blogs/is-vitamin-d-safe-still-depends-on-vitamins-a-and-k-testimonials-and-a-human-study.html">Christopher Masterjohn in WAPF Blog on 12/15/10&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the last several weeks, two momentous occasions have occurred in the world of vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, the Institute of Medicine (IOM) released its new report. It tripled the recommended intakes, doubled the upper limit, and commissioned researchers to go forth and test the effects of intakes higher than the upper limit, as this would be safe under proper supervision and provide valuable information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>860000 IU vitamin D along with 123000 vitamin A is toxic - but not deadly</title><link>/posts/860000-iu-vitamin-d-along-with-123000-vitamin-a-is-toxic-but-not-deadly.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/860000-iu-vitamin-d-along-with-123000-vitamin-a-is-toxic-but-not-deadly.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Price and Masterjohn on Vitamin A Vitamin D and Vitamin K – 2010</title><link>/posts/price-and-masterjohn-on-vitamin-a-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/price-and-masterjohn-on-vitamin-a-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-2010.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>IoM again fails to look at interactions</title><link>/posts/iom-again-fails-to-look-at-interactions.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/iom-again-fails-to-look-at-interactions.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>