<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stroke on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/stroke.html</link><description>Recent content in Stroke on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/stroke/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Better outcome following Ischemic stroke if injected with 600,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/better-outcome-following-ischemic-stroke-if-injected-with-600000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/better-outcome-following-ischemic-stroke-if-injected-with-600000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ischemic Stroke risk best predicted by Vitamin D, including PTH improves the prediction</title><link>/posts/ischemic-stroke-risk-best-predicted-by-vitamin-d-including-pth-improves-the-prediction.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ischemic-stroke-risk-best-predicted-by-vitamin-d-including-pth-improves-the-prediction.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="parathyroid-hormone-levels-in-the-prediction-of-ischemic-stroke-risk">Parathyroid Hormone Levels in the Prediction of Ischemic Stroke Risk.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dis Markers. 2017;2017:4343171. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/4343171.">doi: 10.1155/2017/4343171.&lt;/a> Epub 2017 Jan 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Çelik G1, Doğan A2, Dener Ş3, Öztürk Ş4, Kulaksızoğlu S5, Ekmekçi H4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Beyhekim State Hospital, Department of Neurology, Konya, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Bandırma State Hospital, Department of Neurology, Balıkesir, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Neurology, Başkent University, Konya Training and Research Hospital, Konya, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4Department of Neurology, Selçuk Medical Faculty, Selçuk University, Konya, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>5Department of Biochemistry, Başkent University, Konya Training and Research Hospital, Konya, Turkey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stroke rates increasing in youth and decreasing in elderly (perhaps due to Vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/stroke-rates-increasing-in-youth-and-decreasing-in-elderly-perhaps-due-to-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stroke-rates-increasing-in-youth-and-decreasing-in-elderly-perhaps-due-to-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="stroke-rates-rising-in-younger-peoplehttpwwwnytimescom20161129welllivestroke-rates-rising-in-younger-peoplehtml_r0-new-york-times">&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/29/well/live/stroke-rates-rising-in-younger-people.html?_r=0">Stroke Rates Rising in Younger People&lt;/a> New York Times&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Jersey 227,000 strokes over 20 years&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>| | |
| &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; |
| Age |     Stroke rates &lt;br>1995-99 to 2010-14 |
| 35-39 | 147 % |
| 40-44 | 101 % |
| 45-49 | 68 % |
| 50-54 | 23 % |
| 55-59 | 11 % |
| 60-64 | -22 % |
| 65-69 | -8 % |&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blacks with strokes having low Vitamin D were 3 times more likely to have cognitive impairment</title><link>/posts/blacks-with-strokes-having-low-vitamin-d-were-3-times-more-likely-to-have-cognitive-impairment.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blacks-with-strokes-having-low-vitamin-d-were-3-times-more-likely-to-have-cognitive-impairment.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Both Spinal cord injury and stroke with one side disabled have similar low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/both-spinal-cord-injury-and-stroke-with-one-side-disabled-have-similar-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/both-spinal-cord-injury-and-stroke-with-one-side-disabled-have-similar-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-profile-of-patients-with-spinal-cord-injury-and-post-stroke-hemiplegia-all-in-the-same-boat">Vitamin D profile of patients with spinal cord injury and post-stroke hemiplegia: All in the same boat.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2016 Apr 27;29(2):205-210.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coskun Benlidayi I1, Basaran S1, Seydaoglu G2, Guzel R1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Medicine, Cukurova University, Adana, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Biostatistics, Faculty of Medicine, Cukurova University, Adana, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-repaired-nerve-in-rat-50000-iu-daily-dose-equivalent-for-human">Vitamin D repaired nerve in rat (50,000 IU daily dose equivalent for human) – June 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ischaemic stroke – Vitamin D doubled survival (Injection followed by monthly 60,000 IU) – RCT</title><link>/posts/ischaemic-stroke-vitamin-d-doubled-survival-injection-followed-by-monthly-60000-iu-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ischaemic-stroke-vitamin-d-doubled-survival-injection-followed-by-monthly-60000-iu-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effect-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-supplementation-on-ischaemic-stroke-outcome-a-randomised-controlled-open-label-trial">Effect of Vitamin D and calcium supplementation on ischaemic stroke outcome: a randomised controlled open-label trial&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-supplementation-on-ischaemic-stroke-outcome-a-randomised-controlled-open-label-trial">Effect of Vitamin D and calcium supplementation on ischaemic stroke outcome: a randomised controlled open-label trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>International Journal of Clinical Practice , Early View, DOI: 10.1111/ijcp.12866&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anu Gupta, Sudesh Prabhakar, Manish Modi, Sanjay K Bhadada, Mani Kalaivani, Vivek Lal, Dheeraj Khurana&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and aims&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is a common problem in stroke survivors. Observational studies have reported an association of low vitamin D levels with greater stroke severity, poststroke mortality and functional disability. Randomised clinical trials are lacking. We sought to assess the effect of calcium and vitamin D supplementation in ischaemic stroke survivors with vitamin D deficiency/insufficiency on disability/mortality outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twice as likely to die during neurological critical care if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/twice-as-likely-to-die-during-neurological-critical-care-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/twice-as-likely-to-die-during-neurological-critical-care-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-prospective-analysis-of-hypovitaminosis-d-and-mortality-in-400-patients-in-the-neurocritical-care-setting">A prospective analysis of hypovitaminosis D and mortality in 400 patients in the neurocritical care setting.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Neurosurg. 2016 Jul 1:1-7. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Guan J1, Karsy M1, Brock AA1, Eli IM1, Ledyard HK2, Hawryluk GW1, Park MS1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Departments of 1 Neurosurgery and.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Neurology, Clinical Neurosciences Center, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE Hypovitaminosis D is highly prevalent among the general population. Studies have shown an association between hypovitaminosis D and multiple negative outcomes in critical care patients, but there has been no prospective evaluation of vitamin D in the neurological critical care population. The authors examined the impact of vitamin D deficiency on in-hospital mortality and a variety of secondary outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Major heart problems if have less than 15 ng of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/major-heart-problems-if-have-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/major-heart-problems-if-have-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vascular dementia (after strokes) 32X more likely in Hypertensives with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/vascular-dementia-after-strokes-32x-more-likely-in-hypertensives-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vascular-dementia-after-strokes-32x-more-likely-in-hypertensives-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-vascular-dementia-due-to-cerebral-small-vessel-disease-in-the-elderly-asian-indian-population">Vitamin D status and vascular dementia due to cerebral small vessel disease in the elderly Asian Indian population&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of the Neurological Sciences, Online: October 30, 2015, DOI: &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2015.10.050">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2015.10.050&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Puttachandra Prabhakar, Sadanandavalli Retnaswami Chandra, Manjunath Supriya, Thomas Gregor Issac, Chandrajit Prasad, Rita Christopher &lt;a href="mailto:rita.nimhans@yahoo.com">rita.nimhans@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•Vitamin D deficiency is associated with 2.2-fold increase in odds of vascular dementia due to cerebral small vessel disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•In hypertensives with vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency, the odds were found to be 30.6-fold and 14.4-fold, respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular Disease and vitamin D – no proof yet</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-and-vitamin-d-no-proof-yet.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-and-vitamin-d-no-proof-yet.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="optimal-vitamin-d-supplementation-levels-for-cardiovascular-disease-protection">Optimal Vitamin D Supplementation Levels for Cardiovascular Disease Protection.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dis Markers. 2015;2015:864370. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1155/2015/864370.">doi: 10.1155/2015/864370.&lt;/a> Epub 2015 Sep 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lugg ST1, Howells PA1, Thickett DR1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1School of Clinical and Experimental Medicine, College of Medical and Dental Sciences, Centre for Translational Inflammation Research (CTIR), University of Birmingham Laboratories, Queen Elizabeth Hospital Birmingham, Birmingham B15 2TH, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First described in relation to musculoskeletal disease, there is accumulating data to suggest that vitamin D may play an important role in cardiovascular disease (CVD). In this review we aim to provide an overview of the role of vitamin D status as both a marker of and potentially causative agent of hypertension, coronary artery disease, heart failure, atrial fibrillation, stroke, and peripheral vascular disease. The role of vitamin D levels as a disease marker for all-cause mortality is also discussed. We review the current knowledge gathered from experimental studies, observational studies, randomised controlled trials, and subsequent systematic reviews in order to suggest the optimal vitamin D level for CVD protection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stroke results in 8 years of cognitive decline (vitamin D not mentioned)</title><link>/posts/stroke-results-in-8-years-of-cognitive-decline-vitamin-d-not-mentioned.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stroke-results-in-8-years-of-cognitive-decline-vitamin-d-not-mentioned.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#does-stroke-contribute-to-racial-differences-in-cognitive-decline">Does Stroke Contribute to Racial Differences in Cognitive Decline?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#trajectory-of-cognitive-decline-after-incident-stroke-no-mention-of-vitamin-d">Trajectory of Cognitive Decline After Incident Stroke (no mention of vitamin D)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#stroke-cognitive-decline-and-vascular-dementia-the-silent-epidemic-of-the-21st-century---2003">Stroke, Cognitive Decline and Vascular Dementia: The Silent Epidemic of the 21st Century - 2003&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="does-stroke-contribute-to-racial-differences-in-cognitive-decline">Does Stroke Contribute to Racial Differences in Cognitive Decline?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>STROKEAHA.114.008156v1 46/7/1897&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deborah A. Levine, MD, MPH, &lt;a href="mailto:deblevin@umich.edu">deblevin@umich.edu&lt;/a> Mohammed Kabeto, MS, Kenneth M. Langa, MD, PhD, Lynda D. Lisabeth, PhD, Mary A.M. Rogers, PhD and Andrzej T. Galecki, MD, PhD&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Links between Vitamin D Deficiency and Cardiovascular Diseases</title><link>/posts/links-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-cardiovascular-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/links-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-cardiovascular-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Biomed Res Int. 2015;2015:109275. Epub 2015 Apr 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mozos I1, Marginean O2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Functional Sciences, &amp;ldquo;Victor Babes&amp;rdquo; University of Medicine and Pharmacy, 300173 Timisoara, Romania.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Pediatrics, &amp;ldquo;Victor Babes&amp;rdquo; University of Medicine and Pharmacy, 300173 Timisoara, Romania.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:400px">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-cardiovascular-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Cardiovascular and vitamin D">Overview Cardiovascular and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-stroke-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Stroke and vitamin D">Overview Stroke and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular Diseases and Vitamin D – Review</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-diseases-and-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-diseases-and-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Links between Vitamin D Deficiency and Cardiovascular Diseases - Review Article&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BioMed Research International, Volume 2015 (2015), Article ID 109275, 12 pages&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2015/109275">http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2015/109275&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ioana Mozos 1 and Otilia Marginean 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Functional Sciences, “Victor Babes” University of Medicine and Pharmacy, 300173 Timisoara, Romania&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Pediatrics, “Victor Babes” University of Medicine and Pharmacy, 300173 Timisoara, Romania&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 31 October 2014; Accepted 8 February 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of the present paper was to review the most important mechanisms explaining the possible association of vitamin D deficiency and cardiovascular diseases, focusing on recent experimental and clinical data. Low vitamin D levels favor atherosclerosis enabling vascular inflammation, endothelial dysfunction, formation of foam cells, and proliferation of smooth muscle cells. The antihypertensive properties of vitamin D include suppression of the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system, renoprotective effects, direct effects on endothelial cells and calcium metabolism, inhibition of growth of vascular smooth muscle cells, prevention of secondary hyperparathyroidism, and beneficial effects on cardiovascular risk factors. Vitamin D is also involved in glycemic control, lipid metabolism, insulin secretion, and sensitivity, explaining the association between vitamin D deficiency and metabolic syndrome. Vitamin D deficit was associated in some studies with the number of affected coronary arteries, postinfarction complications, inflammatory cytokines and cardiac remodeling in patients with myocardial infarction, direct electromechanical effects and inflammation in atrial fibrillation, and neuroprotective effects in stroke. In peripheral arterial disease, vitamin D status was related to the decline of the functional performance, severity, atherosclerosis and inflammatory markers, arterial stiffness, vascular calcifications, and arterial aging. Vitamin D supplementation should further consider additional factors, such as phosphates, parathormone, renin, and fibroblast growth factor 23 levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stroke – many MRI measures are strongly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/stroke-many-mri-measures-are-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stroke-many-mri-measures-are-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-is-associated-with-chronic-cerebral-small-vessel-disease">25-hydroxyvitamin D status is associated with chronic cerebral small vessel disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Stroke. 2015 Jan;46(1):248-51. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.114.007706.">doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.114.007706.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Nov 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chung PW 1, Park KY 2 &lt;a href="mailto:kwangyeol.park@gmail.com">kwangyeol.park@gmail.com&lt;/a>, Kim JM 1, Shin DW1, Park MS1, Chung YJ1, Ha SY1, Ahn SW1, Shin HW1, Kim YB1, Moon HS1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study was to determine the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and neuroimaging correlates of cerebral small vessel disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ischemic Stroke with low vitamin D resulted in larger lesions</title><link>/posts/ischemic-stroke-with-low-vitamin-d-resulted-in-larger-lesions.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ischemic-stroke-with-low-vitamin-d-resulted-in-larger-lesions.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-serum-vitamin-d-is-independently-associated-with-larger-lesion-volumes-after-ischemic-stroke">Low Serum Vitamin D Is Independently Associated with Larger Lesion Volumes after Ischemic Stroke&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Stroke and Cerebrovascular Diseases, doi:10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2015.03.051, Available online 23 May 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anya Turetsky, MD∗, Richard P. Goddeau Jr., DO∗, Nils Henninger, MD∗&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address correspondence to Nils Henninger, MD, Departments of Neurology and Psychiatry, University of Massachusetts Medical School, 55 Lake Ave, North, Worcester, MA 01655.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite its high prevalence, known association with vascular disease and stroke incidence and fatality, little is known about the contribution of vitamin D status to a worse outcome after ischemic stroke. Therefore, we sought to assess whether low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D), a marker of vitamin D status, is predictive of the ischemic infarct volume and whether it relates to a worse outcome.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No longer depressed, but risk of stroke is still 1.7X higher (did not consider low vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/no-longer-depressed-but-risk-of-stroke-is-still-17x-higher-did-not-consider-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-longer-depressed-but-risk-of-stroke-is-still-17x-higher-did-not-consider-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="depression-tied-to-stroke-risk-even-if-symptoms-easehttpwellblogsnytimescom20150518depression-tied-to-stroke-risk-even-if-symptoms-ease-new-york-times">&lt;a href="http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2015/05/18/depression-tied-to-stroke-risk-even-if-symptoms-ease/">Depression Tied to Stroke Risk, Even if Symptoms Ease&lt;/a> New York Times&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The study was published in (J Am Heart Assoc. 2015;4:e001923 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.115.001923">doi: 10.1161/JAHA.115.001923&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="increased-risk-of-stroke--all-ages">Increased risk of stroke – all ages&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="-no-longer">|| |No longer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>depressed |Still&lt;br>
depressed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>White Non-Hispanic | 1.66 | 2.00&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Black Non-Hispanic |1.67 | 2.53&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hispanic | 2.36 | 4.14&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Female |1.86 |1.96 ||&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/depression-then-stroke.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stroke when less than 75 years old and with low vitamin D – 3X more likely to die in 1 year</title><link>/posts/stroke-when-less-than-75-years-old-and-with-low-vitamin-d-3x-more-likely-to-die-in-1-year.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stroke-when-less-than-75-years-old-and-with-low-vitamin-d-3x-more-likely-to-die-in-1-year.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-between-serum-concentration-of-vitamin-d-and-1-year-mortality-in-stroke-patients">Association between serum concentration of vitamin D and 1-year mortality in stroke patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cerebrovasc Dis. 2014;37(5):364-7. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1159/000362534.">doi: 10.1159/000362534.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Jun 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daubail B1, Jacquin A, Guilland JC, Khoumri C, Aboa-Eboulé C, Giroud M, Béjot Y &lt;a href="mailto:ybejot@yahoo.fr">ybejot@yahoo.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dijon Stroke Registry, EA4184, University Hospital and Medical School of Dijon, University of Burgundy, Dijon, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The prevalence of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> deficiency is high in patients presenting with an acute stroke, and it may be associated with greater clinical severity and a poor early functional prognosis. However, no data about its impact on long-term prognosis is available. In this study, we aimed to assess the association between 25(OH)D levels and 1-year mortality in stroke patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stroke is 13.5 X more likely if low vitamin D and high blood pressure</title><link>/posts/stroke-is-135-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-and-high-blood-pressure.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stroke-is-135-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-and-high-blood-pressure.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-hypertension-and-ischemic-stroke-a-clinical-perspective--2015">Vitamin D status, hypertension and ischemic stroke: a clinical perspective -2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-hypertension-and-ischemic-stroke-in-116-655-individuals-from-the-general-population-a-genetic-study-2017">Vitamin D, Hypertension, and Ischemic Stroke in 116 655 Individuals From the General Population: A Genetic Study 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-hypertension-and-ischemic-stroke-a-clinical-perspective--2015">Vitamin D status, hypertension and ischemic stroke: a clinical perspective -2015&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Human Hypertension , (26 March 2015) | doi:10.1038/jhh.2015.10&lt;/p>
&lt;p>V Majumdar, P Prabhakar, G B Kulkarni and R Christopher&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between vitamin D deficiency and stroke was cross-sectionally evaluated in the high-risk Asian Indian population. Age- and gender-matched, 239 ischemic stroke patients and 241 control subjects were recruited. Vitamin D status was estimated by measuring serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;a href="25(OH)D">Publisher rents the PDF for $5 &lt;/a>%20levels.%20After%20multivariate%20adjustment%20for%20a%20range%20of%20potential%20covariates%20in%20a%20logistic%20regression%20model,%20an%20inverse%20association%20was%20found%20between%20serum%2025(OH)D%20concentration%20and%20risk%20of%20ischemic%20stroke:%20subjects%20with%20severely%20low%2025(OH)D%20levels%20(less%20than%20or%20equal%20to%209.33 ng ml−1)%20were%20found%20to%20be%20at%203.13-fold%20(95%%20confidence%20interval%20(CI),%20(1.22–8.07))%20increased%20risk%20of%20ischemic%20stroke%20as%20compared%20with%20those%20with%20high%20levels.%20Adjustment%20for%20systolic%20blood%20pressure%20levels%20was%20found%20to%20abrogate%20this%20association%20(odds%20ratio%20(OR)=2.00,%2095%%20CI=0.61–6.50).%20On%20stratification,%20a%20pronounced%20association%20was%20found%20between%20__low%2025(OH)D%20and%20risk%20of%20ischemic%20stroke%20in%20hypertensives,%20OR=13.54,__%2095%%20CI=1.94–94.43%20as%20compared%20with%20no%20association%20in%20non-hypertensives,%20(Pinteraction=0.04).%20&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Second stroke 2X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/second-stroke-2x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/second-stroke-2x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vascular-events-occur-more-frequently-in-stroke-patients-with-lower-concentrations-of-vitamin-d-a-prospective-cohort-analysis--abstract-151">Vascular Events Occur More Frequently In Stroke Patients With Lower Concentrations of Vitamin D: A Prospective Cohort Analysis – Abstract 151&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>International Stroke Conference Feb 2015, Session Title: Community/Risk Factors Oral Abstracts II&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sebastian K Khoo1; Jayne Y Tan1; Leonard Y Yeo2; Prakash Paliwal2; Hock L Teoh2; Bernard P Chan2; Vijay K Sharma1; Yiong Huak Chan1; Raymond C Seet1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Medicine, National Univ of Singapore, Singapore, Singapore&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Medicine, National Univ Hosp, Singapore, Singapore&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ALL of the top 10 health problems of women are associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/all-of-the-top-10-health-problems-of-women-are-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/all-of-the-top-10-health-problems-of-women-are-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="major-causes-of-all-dalys-2003--2023--females">Major Causes of all DALYs 2003 &amp;amp; 2023 – Females&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="condition2003-2023">||Condition|2003| |2023|&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=48&amp;amp;deep=off&amp;amp;type=">Anxiety - Depression&lt;/a>|10.0%|1|8.7%|1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-diabetes-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Diabetes and vitamin D">Type 2 Diabetes&lt;/a>|4.9%|4|8.0%|2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-alzheimers-cognition-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Alzheimer's-Cognition and Vitamin D">Dementia&lt;/a>|4.8%|5|7.4%|3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-cardiovascular-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Cardiovascular and vitamin D">Ischaemic Heart&lt;/a> |8.9%|2|6.1%|4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-stroke-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Overview Stroke and vitamin D">Stroke&lt;/a>|5.1%|3|3.8%|5&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ischemic Stroke 3X more likely if Vitamin D Receptor gene change (Fok 1)</title><link>/posts/ischemic-stroke-3x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-change-fok-1.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ischemic-stroke-3x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-change-fok-1.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="genetic-variants-of-vitamin-d-receptor-and-susceptibility-to-ischemic-stroke">Genetic variants of vitamin D receptor and susceptibility to ischemic stroke&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, Volume 456, Issue 2, 9 January 2015, Pages 631–636; doi:10.1016/j.bbrc.2014.12.007&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Puttachandra Prabhakara, Vijaya Majumdara, Girish Baburao Kulkarnib, Rita Christophera, , ,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Show more&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006291X1402172X">Purchase from publisher $41.95&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Fok I polymorphism of VDR gene was associated with ischemic stroke in women.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• VDR Apa I and Taq I polymorphisms were not linked to ischemic stroke.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ischemic stroke 2X more likely if Vitamin D Receptor gene problem</title><link>/posts/ischemic-stroke-2x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-problem.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ischemic-stroke-2x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-problem.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Post stroke depression 9X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/post-stroke-depression-9x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/post-stroke-depression-9x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="low-serum-levels-of-vitamin-d-are-associated-with-post-stroke-depression">Low serum levels of vitamin D are associated with post-stroke depression.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Eur J Neurol. 2014 Dec 2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.12607.">doi: 10.1111/ene.12607.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Han B1, Lyu Y, Sun H, Wei Y, He J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low serum levels of vitamin D have been associated with depression in non-stroke subjects. Our aim was to examine the possible association between serum vitamin D levels and the development of post-stroke depression (PSD).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Following a stroke, 10 ng less vitamin D associated with 2X more white matter hyperintensities</title><link>/posts/following-a-stroke-10-ng-less-vitamin-d-associated-with-2x-more-white-matter-hyperintensities.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/following-a-stroke-10-ng-less-vitamin-d-associated-with-2x-more-white-matter-hyperintensities.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-is-associated-with-chronic-cerebral-small-vessel-disease">25-Hydroxyvitamin D Status Is Associated With Chronic Cerebral Small Vessel Disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Stroke. 2014 Nov 25. pii: STROKEAHA.114.007706. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chung PW1, Park KY2, Kim JM1, Shin DW1, Park MS1, Chung YJ1, Ha SY1, Ahn SW1, Shin HW1, Kim YB1, Moon HS1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 From the Department of Neurology, Kangbuk Samsung Hospital, Sungkyunkwan University School of Medicine, Seoul, Korea (P.-W.C., Y.B.K., H.-S.M.); Department of Neurology (K.-Y.P., J.-M.K., D.-W.S., M.-S.P., S.-W.A., H.-W.S.) and Division of Endocrinology, Department of Internal Medicine (Y.J.C.), Chung-Ang University Hospital, Chung-Ang University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea; and Department of Neurology, Haeundae Paik Hospital, Inje University College of Medicine, Busan, Korea (S.-Y.H.).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stroke patients with low vitamin D were 10X more likely to become depressed</title><link>/posts/stroke-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-were-10x-more-likely-to-become-depressed.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stroke-patients-with-low-vitamin-d-were-10x-more-likely-to-become-depressed.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="association-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-with-symptoms-of-depression-after-6-months-in-stroke-patients">Association of Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D with Symptoms of Depression After 6 Months in Stroke Patients.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Neurochem Res. 2014 Aug 26. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yue W1, Xiang L, Zhang YJ, Ji Y, Li X.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Neurology, Tianjin Huanhu Hospital, Tianjin, 300060, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:>60%">
&lt;p>Vitamin D levels were measured immediately after the stroke&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 in 3 were depressed 6 months after surviving their stroke&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those with levels &amp;lt; 11 ng were, on average, 10X more likely to be depressed 6 months later&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stroke mortality 3X worse among seniors with less than 26 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/stroke-mortality-3x-worse-among-seniors-with-less-than-26-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stroke-mortality-3x-worse-among-seniors-with-less-than-26-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="association-between-serum-concentration-of-vitamin-d-and-1-year-mortality-in-stroke-patients">Association between Serum Concentration of Vitamin D and 1-Year Mortality in Stroke Patients&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Daubail B.a · Jacquin A.a · Guilland J.-C.b · Khoumri C.a · Aboa-Eboulé C.a · Giroud M.a · Béjot Y.a &lt;a href="mailto:ybejot@yahoo.fr">ybejot@yahoo.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>aDijon Stroke Registry, EA4184, University Hospital and Medical School of Dijon, University of Burgundy, and bBiochimie Spécialisée, Dijon University Hospital, Dijon, France&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/stroke-mortality.jpg" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;p>Background: The prevalence of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> deficiency is high in patients presenting with an acute stroke, and it may be associated with greater clinical severity and a poor early functional prognosis. However, no data about its impact on long-term prognosis is available. In this study, we aimed to assess the association between 25(OH)D levels and 1-year mortality in stroke patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fewer white spots in MRI brain scans if had more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/fewer-white-spots-in-mri-brain-scans-if-had-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fewer-white-spots-in-mri-brain-scans-if-had-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-of-white-matter-hyperintensities-with-low-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels">Association of White Matter Hyperintensities with Low Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Neuroradiology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J.M. Prager, &lt;a href="mailto:jprager@northshore.org">jprager@northshore.org&lt;/a>, C. Thomas, W.J. Ankenbrandt, J.R. Meyer, Y. Gao, A. Ragin, S. Sidharthan, R. Hutten and Y.G. Wu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Department of Radiology (J.M.P., W.J.A., J.R.M., R.H., Y.G.W.), NorthShore University Health System, Evanston, Illinois; Department of Endocrinology (C.T.), University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois; Departments of Statistics (Y.G.) and Radiology (A.R.), Northwestern University, Evanston, Illinois; and Department of Radiology (S.S.), Monmouth Medical Center, Long Branch, New Jersey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thrombosis (leads to stroke) worse with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/thrombosis-leads-to-stroke-worse-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/thrombosis-leads-to-stroke-worse-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="is-there-any-association-between-thrombosis-and-tissue-factor-pathway-inhibitor-levels-in-patients-with-vitamin-d-deficiency">Is There Any Association Between Thrombosis and Tissue Factor Pathway Inhibitor Levels in Patients With Vitamin D Deficiency?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>CLIN APPL THROMB HEMOST November 6, 2013 1076029613509477&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oya Topaloglu, MD &lt;a href="mailto:oyasude@gmail.com">oyasude@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Muyesser Sayki Arslan, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Melia Karakose, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bekir Ucan, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zeynep Ginis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evrim Cakir, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Esra Tutal Akkaymak, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mustafa Sahin, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mustafa Ozbek, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Erman Cakal, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tuncay Delibasi, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: The aim of this study was to evaluate the relationship between vitamin D levels and hemostatic factors like tissue factor pathway inhibitor (TFPI).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Acute ischemic stroke 19 percent more likely if even lower vitamin D</title><link>/posts/acute-ischemic-stroke-19-percent-more-likely-if-even-lower-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/acute-ischemic-stroke-19-percent-more-likely-if-even-lower-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-predicts-the-short-term-outcomes-of-chinese-patients-with-acute-ischemic-stroke">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D predicts the short-term outcomes of Chinese patients with acute ischemic stroke.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Clin Sci (Lond). 2013 Sep 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tu Sr WJ, Zhao SJ, Xu DJ, Chen H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background Low vitamin D levels have been reported to contribute to the risk of cardiovascular events and mortality, especially stroke. We therefore evaluated the short-term prognostic value of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH) D]&lt;/span> in Chinese patients with an acute ischemic stroke (AIS).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Following a stroke, a hip fracture is 6X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/following-a-stroke-a-hip-fracture-is-6x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/following-a-stroke-a-hip-fracture-is-6x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-risk-of-hip-fractures-among-disabled-elderly-stroke-patients">Vitamin D deficiency and risk of hip fractures among disabled elderly stroke patients.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Stroke. 2001 Jul;32(7):1673-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sato Y, Asoh T, Kondo I, Satoh K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Kurume University Medical Center, Japan. &lt;a href="mailto:noukenrs@cc.hirosaki-u.ac.jp">noukenrs@cc.hirosaki-u.ac.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE: Risk of hip fracture after stroke is 2 to 4 times that in a reference population. Osteomalacia is present in some patients with hip fractures in the absence of stroke, while disabled elderly stroke patients occasionally have severe deficiency in serum concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) (&amp;lt;/=5 ng/mL). To determine the effects of vitamin D status on hip fracture risk, we prospectively studied a cohort of patients with hemiplegia after stroke who were aged at least 65 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D is a risk factor for vascular diseases in African Americans</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-is-a-risk-factor-for-vascular-diseases-in-african-americans.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-is-a-risk-factor-for-vascular-diseases-in-african-americans.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="hypovitaminosis-d-as-a-contributory-factor-to-vascular-disease-in-african-americans-a-graded-literature-review">Hypovitaminosis D as a Contributory Factor to Vascular Disease in African-Americans: A graded literature review&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>James H. Moorman MS Thesis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D associated with 50 percent less ischemic stroke – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-associated-with-50-percent-less-ischemic-stroke-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-associated-with-50-percent-less-ischemic-stroke-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-symptomatic-ischemic-stroke-an-original-study-and-meta-analysis---2012">25-Hydroxyvitamin D and symptomatic ischemic stroke: An Original Study and Meta-Analysis - 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ischemic-stroke-19x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---july-2015">Ischemic Stroke 1.9X more likely if low vitamin D - July 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-symptomatic-ischemic-stroke-an-original-study-and-meta-analysis---2012">25-Hydroxyvitamin D and symptomatic ischemic stroke: An Original Study and Meta-Analysis - 2012&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ann Neurol. 2012 Aug 25. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.23738.">doi: 10.1002/ana.23738.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brøndum-Jacobsen P, Nordestgaard BG, Schnohr P, Benn M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Herlev Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital; Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cerebrovascular disease 40 percent less likely if high level of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cerebrovascular-disease-40-percent-less-likely-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cerebrovascular-disease-40-percent-less-likely-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>