<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stroke on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/stroke/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stroke on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/stroke/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ischemic Stroke is 18% more likely if poor Vitamin D genes (unless take more Vitamin D)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ischemic-stroke-is-18-percent-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-genes-unless-take-more-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ischemic-stroke-is-18-percent-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-genes-unless-take-more-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;causal-effect-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-on-cardioembolic-stroke-evidence-from-two-sample-mendelian-randomization&#34;&gt;Causal effect of serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D concentration on cardioembolic stroke: Evidence from two-sample Mendelian randomization&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrition, Metabolism, and Cardiovascular Disease :&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.numecd.2024.02.013&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.numecd.2024.02.013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It seems that there are two groups of genes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genetically predicted serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D concentration is associated with the risk of cardioembolic stroke.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mendelian Randomization analysis provides suggestive evidence that increased 25(OH)D levels may play a protective role in the development of cardioembolic stroke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stroke 3 times more likely if dark skin woman has Hypertension before age 35</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/stroke-3-times-more-likely-if-dark-skin-woman-has-hypertension-before-age-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/stroke-3-times-more-likely-if-dark-skin-woman-has-hypertension-before-age-35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;hypertension-before-35-tied-to-triple-stroke-risk-inmidlife&#34;&gt;Hypertension Before 35 Tied to Triple Stroke Risk in Midlife&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdedge.com/cardiology/article/267662/hypertension/hypertension-35-tied-triple-stroke-risk-midlife?ecd=WNL_EVE_240202_mdedge&#34;&gt;MD Edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Black women who develop high blood pressure before age 35 have a threefold increased risk of having a midlife stroke, new observational data suggested.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Black Women’s Health Study, which has followed 59,000 participants in the United States since the 1990s, also showed that those who develop hypertension before age 45 have twice the risk of suffering a stroke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D is the best Vitamin to prevent a stroke - meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-is-the-best-vitamin-to-prevent-a-stroke-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-is-the-best-vitamin-to-prevent-a-stroke-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;from-a-to-e-uniting-vitamins-against-stroke-risk-a-systematic-review-and-network-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;From A to E: Uniting vitamins against stroke risk-A systematic review and network meta-analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eur J Clin Invest. 2024 Jan 30:e14165. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/eci.14165&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1111/eci.14165&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shashank Tripathi 1, Manabesh Nath 1, Shubham Misra 2, Pradeep Kumar 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background and aim: Stroke represents a significant public health challenge, necessitating the exploration of preventive measures. This network meta-analysis aimed to assess the efficacy of different vitamin treatments compared to a placebo in preventing stroke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low Vitamin D associated with CHD, stroke, death, etc, (Mendelian analhysis)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-chd-stroke-death-etc-mendelian-analhysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-chd-stroke-death-etc-mendelian-analhysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;estimating-dose-response-relationships-for-vitamin-d-with-coronary-heart-disease-stroke-and-all-cause-mortality-observational-and-mendelian-randomisation-analyses&#34;&gt;Estimating dose-response relationships for vitamin D with coronary heart disease, stroke, and all-cause mortality: observational and Mendelian randomisation analyses&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emerging Risk Factors Collaboration/EPIC-CVD/Vitamin D Studies Collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2021; 9: 837-46  &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.1016/&#34;&gt;http://doi.org/10.1016/&lt;/a&gt; S2213-8587(21)00263-1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background Randomised trials of vitamin D supplementation for cardiovascular disease and all-cause mortality have generally reported null findings. However, generalisability of results to individuals with low vitamin D status is unclear. We aimed to characterise dose-response relationships between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span&gt;[OH]&lt;/span&gt;D) concentrations and risk of coronary heart disease, stroke, and all-cause mortality in observational and Mendelian randomisation frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After stroke, 40% less likely to die if 400 mg of Magnesium daily</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/after-stroke-40-percent-less-likely-to-die-if-400-mg-of-magnesium-daily/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/after-stroke-40-percent-less-likely-to-die-if-400-mg-of-magnesium-daily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;magnesium-intake-and-all-cause-mortality-after-stroke-a-cohort-study&#34;&gt;Magnesium intake and all-cause mortality after stroke: a cohort study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrition Journal volume 22, Article number: 54 (2023)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mengyan Wang, Jianhong Peng, Caili Yang, Wenyuan Zhang, Zicheng Cheng &amp;amp; Haibin Zheng&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: Adults often consume 2,000 calories/day, so Q4 would be ~400 mg of Magnesium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Population-based studies have shown that adequate magnesium intake is associated with a lower risk of stroke and all-cause mortality. Whether adequate magnesium intake is important for reducing all-cause mortality risk after stroke remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Omega-3 reduced risk of Ischemic stroke by 18%</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-omega-3-reduced-risk-of-ischemic-stroke-by-18-percent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-omega-3-reduced-risk-of-ischemic-stroke-by-18-percent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;omega-3-blood-levels-and-stroke-risk-a-pooled-and-harmonized-analysis-of-183291-participants-from-29-prospective-studies&#34;&gt;Omega-3 Blood Levels and Stroke Risk: A Pooled and Harmonized Analysis of 183 291 Participants From 29 Prospective Studies&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stroke. 2024;55:50–58 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.123.044281&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.123.044281&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;James H. O’Keefe, Nathan L. Tintle, William S. Harris, Evan L. O’Keefe, Aleix Sala-Vila, John Attia, G. Manohar Garg, Alexis Hure, …&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BACKGROUND:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The effect of marine omega-3 PUFAs on risk of stroke remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;METHODS:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We investigated the associations between circulating and tissue omega-3 PUFA levels and incident stroke (total, ischemic, and hemorrhagic) in 29 international prospective cohorts. Each site conducted a de novo individual-level analysis using a prespecified analytical protocol with defined exposures, covariates, analytical methods, and outcomes; the harmonized data from the studies were then centrally pooled. Multivariable-adjusted HRs and 95% CIs across omega-3 PUFA quintiles were computed for each stroke outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8X increased risk of stroke if COVID vaccinated and catch COVID within 3 weeks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/8x-increased-risk-of-stroke-if-covid-vaccinated-and-catch-covid-within-3-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/8x-increased-risk-of-stroke-if-covid-vaccinated-and-catch-covid-within-3-weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;factors-associated-with-stroke-after-covid-19-vaccination-a-statewide-analysis&#34;&gt;Factors associated with stroke after COVID-19 vaccination: a statewide analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front Neurol. 2023 Jun 28;14:1199745. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2023.1199745&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3389/fneur.2023.1199745&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fadi Nahab 1, Rana Bayakly 2, Mary Elizabeth Sexton 3, Manet Lemuel-Clarke 4, Laura Henriquez 4, Srikant Rangaraju 4, Moges Ido 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: The objective of our study was to evaluate vaccine type, COVID-19 infection, and their association with stroke soon after COVID-19 vaccination.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Methods: In a retrospective cohort study, we estimated the 21-day post-vaccination incidence of stroke among the recipients of the first dose of a COVID-19 vaccine. We linked the Georgia Immunization Registry with the Georgia Coverdell Acute Stroke Registry and the Georgia State Electronic Notifiable Disease Surveillance System data to assess the relative risk of stroke by the vaccine type.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin K, cardiovascular health, and stroke - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-k-cardiovascular-health-and-stroke-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-k-cardiovascular-health-and-stroke-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-k-intake-in-chronic-stroke-implications-for-dietary-recommendations---oct-2020&#34;&gt;Vitamin K Intake in Chronic Stroke: Implications for Dietary Recommendations - Oct 2020&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2020, 12(10), 3059; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu12103059&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu12103059&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Chad Wessinger,Charlene Hafer-Macko andAlice S. Ryan *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VA Research Service, Department of Medicine, Division of Gerontology and Geriatric Medicine at the University of Maryland School of Medicine, and the Baltimore VA Medical Center Geriatric Research, Education and Clinical Center (GRECC), VA Maryland Health Care System, Baltimore, MD 21201, USA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Previous research has identified a possible association between vitamin K intake and cardiometabolic disease. This could mean that the assessment of vitamin K intake is a meaningful tool when monitoring individuals with preexisting cardiovascular disease. Sixty chronic stroke survivors (men and women, body mass index (BMI) 30.36 ± 6.61 kg/m2, age 61.7 ± 7.2 years) completed food records which were analyzed for energy, macronutrient, micronutrient, and food group servings. Participants were divided into two groups: below vitamin K recommendation (BEL, n = 49) and met vitamin K recommendation (MET, n = 11). Energy and macronutrient intake did not differ between groups (all p &amp;gt; 0.127). Vegetable intake was higher in the MET group (p = 0.0001). Vitamin K intake was higher in the MET group (p = 0.0001). Calcium (p = 0.003), vitamin A (p = 0.007), and vitamin E (p = 0.005) intakes were higher in the MET group. There were no differences in sodium, potassium, vitamin D, vitamin C, and iron intakes between groups (all p &amp;gt; 0.212). In this sample of chronic stroke survivors, 82% reported consuming below the Dietary Reference Intake (DRI) for vitamin K. Given that the majority of this study population did not reach the DRI for vitamin K, it is advisable to promote the adequate intake of food rich in vitamin K. Further work is needed to determine the significance of low vitamin K intake in this population.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-stroke Vitamin D supplementation helped in 11 ways</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-stroke-vitamin-d-supplementation-helped-in-11-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-stroke-vitamin-d-supplementation-helped-in-11-ways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-systematic-review-examining-the-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-functional-outcomes-post-stroke&#34;&gt;A systematic review examining the effect of vitamin D supplementation on functional outcomes post-stroke&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clin Rehabil. 2023 May 11 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/02692155231174599&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1177/02692155231174599&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jamie L Fleet 1 2 3, Amanda McIntyre 3 4, Shannon Janzen 3, Marcus Saikaley 3, Michael Qaqish 5, Robert Cianfarani 5, Alexandra Papaioannou 5 6 7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objective: The objective of this systematic review was to explore the effect of vitamin D supplementation on functional outcomes (motor function, mobility, activities of daily living and stroke impairment) among individuals post-stroke (PROSPERO CRD42022296462).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inflammation of small blood vessels in the brain is associated with low vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/inflammation-of-small-blood-vessels-in-the-brain-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/inflammation-of-small-blood-vessels-in-the-brain-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;low-vitamin-d-status-is-associated-with-inflammatory-response-in-older-patients-with-cerebral-small-vessel-disease&#34;&gt;Low vitamin D status is associated with inflammatory response in older patients with cerebral small vessel disease&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J Neuroimmunol . 2023 Apr 15;377:578057. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2023.578057&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2023.578057&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;  (behind a paywall), free access to citations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Manjunath Supriya 1, Rita Christopher 2, Puttachandra Prabhakar 1, Sadanandavalli Retnaswami Chandra 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objectives: This study aimed to determine the association of the NF-κB inflammatory signaling pathway with vitamin D status in older cerebral small vessel disease (SVD) patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recurrent Stroke 5X more-likely if very low vitamin D - meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/recurrent-stroke-5x-more-likely-if-very-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/recurrent-stroke-5x-more-likely-if-very-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-and-risk-of-recurrent-stroke-a-dose-response-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;25-Hydroxy-Vitamin D and Risk of Recurrent Stroke: A Dose Response Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients  . 2023 Jan 18;15(3):512. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15030512.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/nu15030512.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anita Vergatti 1, Veronica Abate 1, Aquilino Flavio Zarrella 1, Fiore Manganelli 2, Stefano Tozza 2, Rosa Iodice 2, Gianpaolo De Filippo 3, Lanfranco D&amp;rsquo;Elia 1, Pasquale Strazzullo 4, Domenico Rendina 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;700&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stroke recurrence significantly improves the prognosis quoad vitam et valetudinem of patients with a first ischemic or haemorrhagic stroke. Other than in bone and skeletal metabolism, vitamin D is involved in the pathogenesis of cardiovascular disorders. This meta-analysis was performed to evaluate the relationship between 25OH-vitamin D &lt;span&gt;[25(OH)D]&lt;/span&gt; levels at the first stroke and the stroke recurrence. To 31 July 2022, four prospective studies were identified. The potential non-linear relationship was evaluated by modelling 25(OH)D, using restricted cubic splines of 25(OH)D distribution. The pooled estimated risk (and 95% CI) of the recurrence of stroke, comparing the highest and the lowest levels, was assessed using a random-effect model. A non-linear association was found by dose-response analysis. This study found that 25(OH)D levels at the first stroke ≥9.3 ng/mL were associated with a lower risk of stroke recurrence, compared with 25(OH)D levels ≤8.5 ng/mL. In the pooled analysis, higher 25(OH)D levels at the first stroke significantly reduce the risk of stroke recurrence, with a significant heterogeneity among studies. In conclusion, 25(OH)D levels ≤8.5 ng/mL at the first stroke are significantly associated with a higher risk of recurrent stroke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CYP2R1 gene reduces response to Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyp2r1-gene-reduces-response-to-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyp2r1-gene-reduces-response-to-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People with a poor CYP2R1 genes are poor Vitamin D responders%%%    Possible solution: take larger doses of Vitamin D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamindwiki---geneticscategoriesgenetics-chart-shows-the-vitamin-d-genes&#34;&gt;VitaminDWiki - &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/categories/genetics&#34;&gt;Genetics&lt;/a&gt; chart shows the vitamin D genes&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;genes-and-other-reasons-for-poor-blood-response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation&#34;&gt;Genes and other reasons for poor blood response to Vitamin D supplementation&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/poor-or-no-response-to-vitamin-d-was-associated-with-poor-genes-cystic-fibrosis-4-genes&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Poor or no response to vitamin D was associated with poor genes (cystic fibrosis, 4 genes) Sept 2022&#34;&gt;Poor or no response to vitamin D was associated with poor genes (cystic fibrosis, 4 genes) Sept 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
