<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Women on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/women/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Women on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/women/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bone loss reduced in women by vitamin D supplementation - Meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bone-loss-reduced-in-women-by-vitamin-d-supplementation-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bone-loss-reduced-in-women-by-vitamin-d-supplementation-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-or-fortification-on-bone-turnover-markers-in-women-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;Effect of vitamin D supplementation or fortification on bone turnover markers in women: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Br J Nutr  2024 Jan 15:1-34. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0007114524000060&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1017/S0007114524000060&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nasrin Nasimi 1 2, Sanaz Jamshidi 3, Aida Askari 1, Nazanin Zolfaghari 1, Erfan Sadeghi 4, Mehran Nouri 1, Nick Bellissimo 5, Shiva Faghih 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D is a vital indicator of musculoskeletal health, as it plays an important role through the regulation of bone and mineral metabolism. This meta-analysis was performed to investigate the effects of vitamin D supplementation/fortification on bone turnover markers in women. All human randomized clinical trials (RCTs) reported changes in bone resorption markers (serum C-terminal Telopeptide of type-I collagen (sCTX) and urinary type I collagen cross-linked N-telopeptide (uNTX)) or bone formation factors (osteocalcin (OC), bone alkaline phosphatase (BALP), and Procollagen type-1 intact N-terminal Propeptide (P1NP)) following vitamin D administration in women (aged ≥18 years old) were considered. Mean differences (MDs) and their respective 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were calculated based on fixed or random effects models according to the heterogeneity status. Subgroup analyses, meta-regression models, sensitivity analysis, risk of bias, publication bias, and the quality of the included studies were also evaluated. We found that vitamin D supplementation had considerable effect on sCTX (MD: -0.038, n= 22) and OC (MD: -0.610, n=24) with high heterogeneity and uNTX (MD: -8.188, n= 6) without heterogeneity. Our results showed that age, sample size, dose, duration, baseline vitamin D level, study region, and quality of studies might be sources of heterogeneity in this meta-analysis. Subgroup analysis also revealed significant reductions in P1NP level in dose less than 600IU/day and larger study sample size (&amp;gt;100 participants). Moreover, no significant change was found in BALP level.  &lt;strong&gt;Vitamin D supplementation/fortification significantly reduced bone resorption markers in women&lt;/strong&gt; . However, results were inconsistent for bone formation markers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PMS reduced by 50,000 IU every two weeks - RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pms-reduced-by-50000-iu-every-two-weeks-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pms-reduced-by-50000-iu-every-two-weeks-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-symptoms-severity-in-vitamin-d-insufficient-women-with-premenstrual-syndrome-a-randomized-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;Effect of vitamin D supplementation on symptoms severity in vitamin D insufficient women with premenstrual syndrome: A randomized controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2024 Feb:59:241-248. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnesp.2023.11.014&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.clnesp.2023.11.014&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hajar Heidari 1, Khadijeh Abbasi 2, Awat Feizi 3, Shahnaz Kohan 4, Reza Amani 5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Premenstrual syndrome (PMS) is one of the most prevalent disorders among reproductive women worldwide that negatively impact women&amp;rsquo;s quality of life. This study aimed to investigate the effect of vitamin D supplementation on the severity of PMS symptoms in vitamin D insufficient women with PMS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D Danger - Women need 70 ng for optimal Estrogen - video and transcript</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-danger-women-need-70-ng-for-optimal-estrogen-video-and-transcript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-danger-women-need-70-ng-for-optimal-estrogen-video-and-transcript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-1-vitamin-d-danger-you-must-know--dr-mindy-pelz&#34;&gt;The #1 Vitamin D Danger You Must Know! | Dr. Mindy Pelz&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5lc1jOp1LA4&amp;amp;ab_channel=Dr.MindyPelz&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; 14 minute&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;0:00:00.1 Pelz:  &lt;strong&gt;vitamin d&lt;/strong&gt; , we gotta talk about it. It&amp;rsquo;s too important. And I have done videos quoting many studies here. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot more for you to understand about  &lt;strong&gt;vitamin d&lt;/strong&gt; . I will put all the studies and all the links to those of you that are science hounds in the notes to this video. But I feel like this is one of those videos, we gotta roll up our sleeves and we gotta have a serious talk because so many of you are low in  &lt;strong&gt;vitamin d&lt;/strong&gt; . And  &lt;strong&gt;vitamin d&lt;/strong&gt; , hopefully, you know, is not only supportive of the immune system, but you need it for hormonal production. In fact,  &lt;strong&gt;vitamin d&lt;/strong&gt;  is not even considered a vitamin, it&amp;rsquo;s a hormone and it&amp;rsquo;s in charge of a thousand different processes in your body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Senior women having low vitamin D were 2X more likely to die</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/senior-women-having-low-vitamin-d-were-2x-more-likely-to-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/senior-women-having-low-vitamin-d-were-2x-more-likely-to-die/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;association-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-with-all-cause-and-cause-specific-mortality-among-postmenopausal-females-results-from-nhanes&#34;&gt;Association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels with all-cause and cause-specific mortality among postmenopausal females: results from NHANES&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jia-Wei Shi, Jiang-Nan Wu, Xiao-Yong Zhu, Wen-Hui Zhou, Jin-Ying Yang &amp;amp; Ming-Qing Li&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Journal of Translational Medicine volume 21, Article number: 629 (2023)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note:  &amp;ldquo;Adjusted for  &lt;strong&gt;age, race/ethnicity&lt;/strong&gt; , education level, PIR,  &lt;strong&gt;BMI, smoking status, alcohol intake, hypertension and diabetes&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;.  - Should not &amp;ldquo;adjust&amp;rdquo; for variables that are strongly related to low vitamin D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Menopause delayed and symptoms decreased by Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/menopause-delayed-and-symptoms-decreased-by-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/menopause-delayed-and-symptoms-decreased-by-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange16span-vitamindwiki-pages-having-menopause-etc-in-the-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;16+&lt;/span&gt; VitaminDWiki pages having MENOPAUSE etc in the title&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{list max=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;MENOPAUSE&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; shownbitems=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xA;&#xA;{column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=title format=&amp;ldquo;objectlink&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamindwiki--&#34;&gt;VitaminDWiki -&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {SQL(db=&gt;vitamind)}SELECT COUNT(*) FROM (SELECT catObjectId, COUNT(*) FROM `tiki_category_objects` WHERE categId = 5  OR categId = 115 GROUP BY catObjectId HAVING COUNT(*) &gt; 1) AS categs INNER JOIN tiki_objects ON tiki_objects.objectId = categs.catObjectId WHERE type = &#34;wiki page&#34;{SQL} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   studies for Senior Women&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pelvic Organ Prolapse after menopause 5.6 X more likely if low Vitamin D (weak muscles)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pelvic-organ-prolapse-after-menopause-56-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-weak-muscles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pelvic-organ-prolapse-after-menopause-56-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-weak-muscles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;association-of-low-vitamin-d-level-with-pelvic-organ-prolapse-in-post-menopausal-women-a-case-control-study--oct-2023&#34;&gt;Association of Low Vitamin D Level with Pelvic Organ Prolapse in Post Menopausal Women: A Case Control Study – Oct 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mymensingh Med J . 2023 Oct;32(4):1109-1117.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Z R Paul 1, N N Khanam, S C Barai, A A Chowdhury, S G Krishna, R Masud, D Rafaha, S Akter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pelvic organ prolapse refers to protrusion of the pelvic organ into or out of the vaginal canal. One in four women in the USA suffer from some type of pelvic floor disorder including pelvic organ prolapse and frequency of pelvic organ prolapse is more with increasing age. In Bangladesh, 15.6% women suffered from pelvic organ prolapse and more than 11.0% of women require surgical correction of prolapse in their life times. According to few researches, there is an observed association between low vitamin D levels with pelvic organ prolapse but this finding is not unequivocal. This case control study has been conducted in the Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University (BSMMU), Bangladesh from October 2018 to August 2020 to investigate the level of vitamin D in patients with and without pelvic organ prolapse to explore the association of low vitamin D with pelvic organ prolapse. A total 148 participants of 52 years or older attending the out or inpatient department were enrolled in the study. The study population was divided into two groups, a case group (n=74) consisting of patients with pelvic organ prolapse and a control group (n=74) comprising of women without pelvic organ prolapse. After taking informed written consent the serum vitamin D level of all participants was measured by CMIA technology with flexible assay protocols at Biochemistry and Molecular Biology department of the same institute. All necessary Data were collected on variables of interest by using the structured questionnaire pre-designed for interview, observation, clinical examination, and biochemical Data collection. Distributions were expressed by mean and standard deviation for continuous variables and by frequency and percentage for qualitative variables. Student&amp;rsquo;s t-test and Chi square test were done to see the significance of differences between Group I and Group II. Odds ratio, correlation coefficient, and multivariate logistic regression analysis was done to assess the association of low vitamin D level with pelvic organ prolapse. Mean±SD level of Vitamin D in the case group was 13.96±5.18ng/ml and in the control group was 21.08±5.77ng/ml respectively. The difference was statistically significant (p&amp;lt;0.05). Moreover, the vitamin D levels were inversely proportionate with the severity of pelvic organ prolapse. OR (95% CI), of two groups showed risk of developing pelvic organ prolapse  &lt;strong&gt;5.63 times higher in women with decreased vitamin D level&lt;/strong&gt; . Thus it can be concluded that women having low level of vitamin D have more chance of developing pelvic organ prolapse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muscles improved in women with 50,000 IU vitamin D weekly (8 weeks) plus daily Magnesium – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/muscles-improved-in-women-with-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-8-weeks-plus-daily-magnesium-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/muscles-improved-in-women-with-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-8-weeks-plus-daily-magnesium-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;randomized-study-of-the-effects-of-vitamin-d-and-magnesium-co-supplementation-on-muscle-strength-and-function-body-composition-and-inflammation-in-vitamin-d-deficient-middle-aged-women----sept-2020&#34;&gt;Randomized Study of the Effects of Vitamin D and Magnesium Co-Supplementation on Muscle Strength and Function, Body Composition, and Inflammation in Vitamin D-Deficient Middle-Aged Women  - Sept 2020&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biological Trace Element Research volume 199, pages 2523–2534 (2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fatemeh Kheyruri, Javad Sarrafzadeh, Agha Fatemeh Hosseini, Behnaz Abiri &amp;amp; Mohammadreza Vafa&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;700&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study aimed to investigate the effects of vitamin D and magnesium co-supplementation on muscle strength and function, body composition, and inflammation in vitamin D-deficient middle-aged women. In this study, 83 healthy middle-aged women (40–55 years) with vitamin D deficiency were randomly assigned into two groups: (1) intervention: receiving a 50,000-IU vitamin D soft gel (weekly) plus a 250-mg magnesium tablet (daily); (2) control: receiving a vitamin D placebo (weekly) plus a magnesium placebo (daily), for 8 weeks. Before and after the intervention, anthropometric indices, muscle strength, muscle function, and some inflammatory markers were measured. After 8 weeks of supplementation, significant difference was observed in handgrip strength and time for Time Get Up and Go (TGUG) test between the intervention and placebo groups (P &amp;lt; 0.05). Regarding percentage of fat mass (FM%) and fat free mass (FFM%), and knee extension strength, there was no significant difference between the two groups at the end of intervention (P &amp;gt; .05). Serum 25(OH)-D levels increased significantly (P &amp;lt; 0.001) and its change was significantly different between the two groups, at the end of the intervention (P &amp;lt; 0.001). Serum level of hs-CRP decreased significantly in the intervention group compared to baseline (P &amp;lt; 0.001), and the change in hs-CRP was significant between the two groups at the end of the intervention (P &amp;lt; 0.01). Furthermore, serum level of TNF-α declined significantly in the intervention group compared to baseline (P &amp;lt; 0.001) but, no significant differences were seen between the two groups in regard of serum levels of TNF-α and IL-6 after the intervention (P &amp;gt; 0.05).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shorter reproductive livespan in women is 1.5X more likely if low vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/shorter-reproductive-livespan-in-women-is-15x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/shorter-reproductive-livespan-in-women-is-15x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;relationship-between-vitamin-d-levels-and-age-of-menopause-and-reproductive-lifespan-analysis-based-on-the-national-health-and-nutrition-examination-survey-nhanes-20012018&#34;&gt;Relationship between vitamin D levels and age of menopause and reproductive lifespan: Analysis based on the National health and nutrition examination survey (NHANES) 2001–2018&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FULL LENGTH ARTICLE| VOLUME 289, P183-189, OCTOBER 2023 DOI:https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejogrb.2023.09.003&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tahereh Alinia, Siamak Sabour, Mahin Hashemipour, Silva Hovsepian, Homeyra Rais Pour, Shayesteh Jahanfar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objectives&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To determine the association between serum vitamin D levels and age at menopause and reproductive lifespan in a group of US postmenopausal women.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Menopause is earlier in black women (low vitamin D)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/menopause-is-earlier-in-black-women-low-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/menopause-is-earlier-in-black-women-low-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;menopause-is-different-for-women-of-color&#34;&gt;Menopause Is Different for Women of Color&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/08/23/well/live/menopause-symptoms-women-of-color.html&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;   vitamin D is not mentioned&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;7-related-studies-for-dark-skinned-women&#34;&gt;7 related studies for Dark-Skinned women&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/risk-of-early-menopause-reduced-17-percent-by-a-modest-amount-of-vitamin-d&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Risk of early menopause reduced 17 percent by a modest amount of vitamin D – May 2017&#34;&gt;Risk of early menopause reduced 17 percent by a modest amount of vitamin D – May 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/poor-menstrual-cycles-2x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-levels-many-studies&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Poor menstrual cycles 2X more likely if poor vitamin D levels - many studies&#34;&gt;Poor menstrual cycles 2X more likely if poor vitamin D levels - many studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Menstrual pain reduced by Vitamin D (50,000 weekly or 300,000 monthly) – meta-analyses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/menstrual-pain-reduced-by-vitamin-d-50000-weekly-or-300000-monthly-meta-analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/menstrual-pain-reduced-by-vitamin-d-50000-weekly-or-300000-monthly-meta-analyses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-50k-weekly-or-300k-monthly-reduced-menstural-pain---meta-analysis-april-2024&#34;&gt;Vitamin D: 50K weekly or 300K monthly reduced menstural pain - meta-analysis April 2024&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vitamin D Supplementation for Patients with Dysmenorrhoea: A Meta-Analysis with Trial Sequential Analysis of Randomised Controlled Trials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2024, 16(7), 1089; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu16071089&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu16071089&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;700&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D reduces prostaglandin levels and inflammation, making it a promising treatment option for dysmenorrhoea. However, its effects on pain intensity in different types of dysmenorrhoea remain unclear. We examined whether vitamin D supplementation decreases pain intensity in patients with dysmenorrhoea. The Cochrane Library, Embase, Google Scholar, Medline, and Scopus databases were searched from inception to 30 December 2023. Randomised controlled trials (RCTs) evaluating vitamin D supplementation effects on such patients were included. The primary and secondary outcomes were measured by the changes in pain intensity and rescue analgesic use, respectively. Pooled mean differences and rate ratios were calculated using a random-effect model; trial sequential analysis (TSA) was also performed. Overall, 11 studies involving 687 participants were included. Vitamin D supplementation significantly decreased pain intensity in patients with dysmenorrhoea compared with controls (pooled mean difference, −1.64; 95% confidence interval, −2.27 to −1.00; p &amp;lt; 0.001; CoE, moderate; I2 statistic, 79.43%) and indicated substantial heterogeneity among the included studies. TSA revealed that the current RCTs provide sufficient information. In subgroup analyses, vitamin D supplement reduced primary dysmenorrhoea pain but not secondary dysmenorrhoea pain. In conclusion, although substantial heterogeneity persists, vitamin D supplementation decreased pain intensity in patients with dysmenorrhea, especially in those with primary dysmenorrhoea. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-file-pdf&#34; style=&#34;margin-right: 0.3em;&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fibrocystic breasts associated with Vitamin D deficiency (2X)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fibrocystic-breasts-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-2x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fibrocystic-breasts-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-2x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-association-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-fibrocystic-breast-disorder&#34;&gt;The association between Vitamin D deficiency and fibrocystic breast disorder&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Curr Mol Med. 2023 Jun 23. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2174/1566524023666230623155659&#34;&gt;doi: 10.2174/1566524023666230623155659&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sheida Shabanian 1, Aliyeh Rozbeh 2, Belgheis Mohammadi 1, Ali Ahmadi 3, Mohammad-Hassan Arjmand 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: The role of deficiency of vitamin D in a wide range of human cancer, including breast cancer, has been proven, but its role in benign breast diseases remains unknown. This study aimed to determine the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in patients with fibrocystic breast (FB) disease.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immune systems of males and females differ through life – focus on TB and COVID</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/immune-systems-of-males-and-females-differ-through-life-focus-on-tb-and-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/immune-systems-of-males-and-females-differ-through-life-focus-on-tb-and-covid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-and-estrogen-steroid-hormones-and-their-immunogenetic-roles-in-infectious-respiratory-tb-and-covid-19-diseases&#34;&gt;Vitamin D and estrogen steroid hormones and their immunogenetic roles in Infectious respiratory (TB and COVID-19) diseases&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genetics and Molecular Biology, 46, 1(suppl 2), e20220158 (2023) DOI: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1590/1678-4685-GMB-2022-0158&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1590/1678-4685-GMB-2022-0158&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maria Eduarda de Albuquerque Borborema1,2, Thays Maria Costa de Lucena1,2 and Jaqueline de Azevedo Silva1,2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Universidade Federal de Pernambuco, Departamento de Genética, Laboratòrio de Genética e Biologia Molecular Humana (LGBMH), Recife, PE, Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Universidade Federal de Pernambuco, Laboratório de Imunopatologia Keizo Asami (LIKA), Recife, PE, Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italian women taking Vitamin D (Osteoporosis, etc)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/italian-women-taking-vitamin-d-osteoporosis-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/italian-women-taking-vitamin-d-osteoporosis-etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;update-on-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-the-prevention-of-osteoporosis&#34;&gt;Update on the role of vitamin D in the prevention of osteoporosis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D - Updates 2022;5(1):4-7. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.30455/2611-2876-2022-1e&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.30455/2611-2876-2022-1e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stefano Berardi, Francesco Paolo Cantatore&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rheumatology Clinic, Department of Medical and Surgical Sciences, University of Foggia&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Packages of Vitamin D for Italian Women&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years the possible multiple positive effects of vitamin D (antineoplastic, cardioprotective, immunomodulatory, etc.) have aroused growing interest and an increase in scientific (and non-scientific) publications on the subject. However, uncertainties about its usefulness in the prevention of osteoporosis have also been raised, following discordant results in the literature, beyond any reasonable doubt on extra-skeletal effects. Osteoporosis has a burdensome impact on the healthcare system: in Italy approximately 3.5 million women and 1 million men are affected by the disease. Incidence increases with age (the steady ageing of the population leads to more cases). From age 50, the incidence of fragility fractures increases progressively, becoming comparable to that of stroke and breast cancer 1. Annual costs attributable to such fractures (acute management and longterm disability) grow with the ageing of the population. What is needed is an acceptable prevention strategy that makes the best use of available resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
