<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cardiovascular on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cardiovascular.html</link><description>Recent content in Cardiovascular on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cardiovascular/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Large abdominal aortic aneurysm 5.4X less frequent if have lots of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/large-abdominal-aortic-aneurysm-54x-less-frequent-if-have-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/large-abdominal-aortic-aneurysm-54x-less-frequent-if-have-lots-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="is-hypovitaminosis-d-associated-with-abdominal-aortic-aneurysm-and-is-there-a-dose-response-relationship">Is hypovitaminosis D associated with abdominal aortic aneurysm, and is there a dose-response relationship?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2013 Jun;45(6):657-64. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejvs.2013.03.015.">doi: 10.1016/j.ejvs.2013.03.015.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Apr 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wong YY, Flicker L, Yeap BB, McCaul KA, Hankey GJ, Norman PE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Western Australian Centre for Health and Ageing, Centre for Medical Research, Western Australian Institute for Medical Research, Perth, Australia. &lt;a href="mailto:ewong@meddent.uwa.edu.au">ewong@meddent.uwa.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: This study aims to investigate the association between plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentrations with the presence of abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) and aortic diameter.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Heart Failure helped with 2,000 IU of vitamin D (PRA reduced) – RCT</title><link>/posts/chronic-heart-failure-helped-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-pra-reduced-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chronic-heart-failure-helped-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-pra-reduced-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="short-term-vitamin-d3-supplementation-lowers-plasma-renin-activity-in-patients-with-stable-chronic-heart-failure">Short-term vitamin D3 supplementation lowers plasma renin activity in patients with stable chronic heart failure:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>An open-label, blinded end point, randomized prospective trial (VitD-CHF trial)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nicolas F. Schroten, MD; Willem P.T. Ruifrok, MD, PhD; Lennaert Kleijn, MD; Martin M. Dokter, BASc&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Herman H. Silljé, PhD; Hiddo J. Lambers Heerspink, PhD; Stephan J.L. Bakker, MD, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ido P. Kema, PhD; Wiek H. van Gilst, PhD; Dirk J. van Veldhuisen, MD, PhD&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Low maternal vitamin D increases probability of heart disease later in adult</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-low-maternal-vitamin-d-increases-probability-of-heart-disease-later-in-adult.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-low-maternal-vitamin-d-increases-probability-of-heart-disease-later-in-adult.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-early-life-and-the-potential-programming-of-cardiovascular-disease-in-adulthood">Vitamin D Deficiency in Early Life and the Potential Programming of Cardiovascular Disease in Adulthood.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Cardiovasc Transl Res. 2013 May 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gezmish O, &lt;a href="mailto:Oksan.Gezmish@med.monash.edu.au">Oksan.Gezmish@med.monash.edu.au&lt;/a>, Black MJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Anatomy and Developmental Biology, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, 3800, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is a major worldwide public health problem affecting people of all ages, from infants to the elderly. Of particular concern is the high incidence of vitamin D deficiency in women during pregnancy and lactation, leading to the exposure of the growing fetus/infant to inadequate levels of vitamin D, which is essential for normal development. Vitamin D deficiency in adulthood is linked to the etiology of hypertension and to a multitude of adverse cardiovascular outcomes. It is now well-established that the antecedents of cardiovascular disease can originate very early in life. The purpose of this review is to highlight how maternal vitamin D deficiency, and its effects in upregulating the fetal renin-angiotensin system and altering cardiomyocyte growth in the fetal heart, has the potential to program long-term vulnerability to cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Congestive Heart Failure patients helped with Vitamin D intervention</title><link>/posts/congestive-heart-failure-patients-helped-with-vitamin-d-intervention.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/congestive-heart-failure-patients-helped-with-vitamin-d-intervention.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="can-vitamin-d-supplementation-improve-the-severity-of-congestive-heart-failure">Can Vitamin D Supplementation Improve the Severity of Congestive Heart Failure?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Congest Heart Fail. 2013 Mar 21. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/chf.12026.">doi: 10.1111/chf.12026.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amin A, Minaee S, Chitsazan M, Naderi N, Taghavi S, Ardeshiri M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Heart Failure and Transplantation, Fellowship in Heart Failure &amp;amp; Transplantation, Rajaei Cardiovascular, Medical and Research Center, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of the present study was to investigate whether vitamin D supplementation could improve biochemical findings and functional capacity of patients with heart failure (HF). One hundred patients with New York Heart Association (NYHA) class I through III HF were included in this prospective study and their 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were evaluated. Only 6% of the participants had a sufficient serum concentration of 25(OH) D &amp;gt;30 nmol/L. Patients with insufficient or deficient serum levels of 25(OH) D (&amp;lt;30 ng/mL and &amp;lt;20 ng/mL, respectively) received oral vitamin D3 (cholecalciferol) for a total period of 4 months.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects against many types of health problems – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-effects-on-musculoskeletal-health-immunity-autoimmunity-cardiovascular-disease-cancer-fertility-pregnancy-dementia-and-mortality-a-review-of-recent-evidence">Vitamin D effects on musculoskeletal health, immunity, autoimmunity, cardiovascular disease, cancer, fertility, pregnancy, dementia and mortality-A review of recent evidence.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmun Rev. 2013 Mar 28. pii: S1568-9972(13)00040-2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.">doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pawel Pludowski a &lt;a href="mailto:p.pludowski@czd.pl">p.pludowski@czd.pl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael F. Holick b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Pilzc, d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carol L. Wagner e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce W. Hollis e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant f,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yehuda Shoenfeld g,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elisabeth Lerchbaum c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David J. Llewellyn h,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katharina Kienreich c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maya Soni h&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Biochemistry, Radioimmunology and Experimental Medicine, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Health Institute, Warsaw, Poland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart Damage and low vitamin D greatly increases chance of dying</title><link>/posts/heart-damage-and-low-vitamin-d-greatly-increases-chance-of-dying.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-damage-and-low-vitamin-d-greatly-increases-chance-of-dying.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25ohd-is-a-2-year-predictor-of-all-cause-mortality-cardiac-death-and-sudden-cardiac-death">Serum 25(OH)D is a 2-year predictor of all-cause mortality, cardiac death and sudden cardiac death&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>in chest pain patients from Northern Argentina.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(9):e43228. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0043228.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0043228.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Sep 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Naesgaard PA, León De La Fuente RA, Nilsen ST, Woie L, Aarsland T, Brede C, Staines H, Nilsen DW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardiology, Stavanger University Hospital, Stavanger, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Several studies have shown an association between vitamin D deficiency and cardiovascular risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Faster heart rate and higher systolic blood pressure associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/faster-heart-rate-and-higher-systolic-blood-pressure-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/faster-heart-rate-and-higher-systolic-blood-pressure-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="relation-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-to-heart-rate-and-cardiac-work">Relation of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D to heart rate and cardiac work&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>(from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Surveys).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am J Cardiol. 2010 Jan 1;105(1):122-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjcard.2009.08.661.">doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2009.08.661.&lt;/a> Epub 2009 Nov 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scragg RK, Camargo CA Jr, Simpson RU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand. &lt;a href="mailto:r.scragg@auckland.ac.nz">r.scragg@auckland.ac.nz&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D may protect against cardiovascular disease, but its association with cardiac function is unclear. The aim of this study was to examine the associations of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) with heart rate, systolic blood pressure, and the rate-pressure product (RPP). Data analyses were carried out on 27,153 participants aged &amp;gt; or =20 years, with measurements of serum 25(OH)D, heart rate (from radial pulse), and systolic blood pressure, in the National Health and Nutrition Examination Surveys (NHANES) carried out from 1988 to 1994 and from 2001 to 2006. RPP was calculated as heart rate times systolic blood pressure. Results were adjusted for age, gender, race or ethnicity, body mass index, physical activity, tobacco smoking, co-morbidities, and blood pressure treatment. Compared to participants with 25(OH)D &amp;gt; or =35 ng/ml, the adjusted mean +/- SE heart rate was significantly (p &amp;lt;0.001) higher, by 2.1 +/- 0.6 beats/min, in participants with 25(OH)D &amp;lt;10.0 ng/ml, while mean systolic blood pressure was 1.9 +/- 0.8 mm Hg higher (p &amp;lt;0.05) for participants with 25(OH)D &amp;lt;10.0 ng/ml and 1.7 +/- 0.6 mm Hg higher (p &amp;lt;0.01) for those with 25(OH)D of 10.0 to 14.9 ng/ml. As a consequence, adjusted mean RPP was 408 +/- 110 beats/min . mm Hg higher (p &amp;lt;0.001) for participants with 25(OH)D &amp;lt;10.0 ng/ml and 245 +/- 80 beats/min . mm Hg higher (p &amp;lt;0.01) for participants with 25(OH)D of 10.0 to 14.9 ng/ml, compared to those with 25(OH)D &amp;gt; or =35 ng/ml. In conclusion, these results show that low serum 25(OH)D levels are associated with increased heart rate, systolic blood pressure, and RPP and suggest that low vitamin D status may increase cardiac work. Vitamin D intervention studies are required to confirm these findings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart failure 2X more likely if less than 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/heart-failure-2x-more-likely-if-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-failure-2x-more-likely-if-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Death from Coronary Heart Disease related to low Magnesium intake</title><link>/posts/death-from-coronary-heart-disease-related-to-low-magnesium-intake.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-from-coronary-heart-disease-related-to-low-magnesium-intake.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dietary-and-plasma-magnesium-and-risk-of-coronary-heart-disease-among-women">Dietary and plasma magnesium and risk of coronary heart disease among women.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Am Heart Assoc. 2013 Mar 18;2(2):e000114. Doi: 10.1161/JAHA.113.000114.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chiuve SE, Sun Q, Curhan GC, Taylor EN, Spiegelman D, Willett WC, Manson JE, Rexrode KM, Albert CM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Arrhythmia Prevention, Department of Medicine Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Magnesium is associated with lower risk of sudden cardiac death, possibly through antiarrhythmic mechanisms. Magnesium influences endothelial function, inflammation, blood pressure, and diabetes, but a direct relation with coronary heart disease (CHD) risk has not been established.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lacking data, claimed evidence of cardiac probems if too much vitamin D</title><link>/posts/lacking-data-claimed-evidence-of-cardiac-probems-if-too-much-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lacking-data-claimed-evidence-of-cardiac-probems-if-too-much-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-levels-for-preventing-acute-coronary-syndrome-and-mortality-evidence-of-a-non-linear-association">Vitamin D Levels for Preventing Acute Coronary Syndrome and Mortality: Evidence of a Non-Linear Association&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism March 26, 2013 jc.2013-1185&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yosef Dror, PhD*,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shmuel Giveon, MD, MPH.*,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moshe Hoshen, PhD.,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ilan Feldhamer, MA.,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ran Balicer, MD, PhD, MPH. and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Becca Feldman, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yosef Dror PhD*, School of Nutrition, Faculty of Agriculture, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Rehovot, Israel. Clalit Research Institute and Chief Physician Office, Clalit Health Services, Israel; Shmuel Giveon MD,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnesium prevents cardiovascular events – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/magnesium-prevents-cardiovascular-events-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/magnesium-prevents-cardiovascular-events-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="magnesium-and-the-risk-of-cardiovascular-events-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-cohort-studies">Magnesium and the risk of cardiovascular events: a meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2013;8(3):e57720. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0057720.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0057720.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Mar 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Qu X, Jin F, Hao Y, Li H, Tang T, Wang H, Yan W, Dai K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shanghai Key Laboratory of Orthopaedic Implant, Shanghai Ninth People&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Prospective studies that have examined the association between dietary magnesium intake and serum magnesium concentrations and the risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD) events have reported conflicting findings. We undertook a meta-analysis to evaluate the association between dietary magnesium intake and serum magnesium concentrations and the risk of total CVD events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular disease 50 % more likely if low vitamin D - meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-50-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-50-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="circulating-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-and-risk-of-cardiovascular-disease-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Circulating 25-hydroxy-vitamin D and risk of cardiovascular disease: a meta-analysis of prospective studies.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2012 Nov;5(6):819-29. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.112.967604.">doi: 10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.112.967604.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Nov 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wang L, Song Y, Manson JE, Pilz S, März W, Michaëlsson K, Lundqvist A, Jassal SK, Barrett-Connor E, Zhang C, Eaton CB, May HT, Anderson JL, Sesso HD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brigham and Women’s Hospital, Boston, MA 02215, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:luwang@rics.bwh.harvard.edu">luwang@rics.bwh.harvard.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D status has been linked to the risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD). However, the optimal 25-hydroxy-vitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>-vitamin D) levels for potential cardiovascular health benefits remain unclear.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of role of Vitamin D in Cardiometabolic diseases</title><link>/posts/review-of-role-of-vitamin-d-in-cardiometabolic-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-role-of-vitamin-d-in-cardiometabolic-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="role-of-vitamin-d-in-cardiometabolic-diseases">Role of Vitamin D in Cardiometabolic Diseases&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Hindawi Publishing Corporation, Journal of Diabetes Research, Volume 2013, Article ID 243934,10 pages&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chaoxun Wang&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology, Shanghai Pudong Hospital, 2800 Gongwei Road, Huinan Town, Pudong, Shanghai 201399, China Correspondence should be addressed to Chaoxun Wang; &lt;a href="mailto:xunshdonger@hotmail.com">xunshdonger@hotmail.com&lt;/a> Received 23 November 2012; Revised 9 January 2013; Accepted 9 January 2013 Academic Editor: T. S. Kern&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is a highly prevalent condition. Low vitamin D levels have long been associated with bone diseases, such as rickets in children and osteomalacia and osteoporosis in adults. However, it has become apparent in recent years that adequate vitamin D levels are also important for optimal functioning of many organs and tissues throughout the body, including the cardiovascular system. Evolving data indicate that vitamin D deficiency is associated with an increased risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD). Studies have shown that low vitamin D levels are associated with hypertension, diabetes, metabolic syndrome, left ventricular hypertrophy, and chronic vascular inflammation, all of which are risk factors for CVD. This paper reviews the definition and pathophysiology of vitamin D deficiency, clinical evidence linking vitamin D and CVD risk, diabetes and its complications, and metabolic syndrome.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces inflammation (heat shock protein)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-inflammation-heat-shock-protein.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-inflammation-heat-shock-protein.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="regulatory-effects-of-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d3-on-vascular-smooth-muscle-cells">Regulatory effects of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 on vascular smooth muscle cells.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Biochim Pol. 2012;59(3):395-400. Epub 2012 Aug 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tukaj S, Trzonkowski P, Tukaj C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Plant Physiology and Biotechnology, University of Gdańsk, Poland. &lt;a href="mailto:stefantukaj@gmail.com">stefantukaj@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inflammatory response has been recognized as a central feature in the development and progression of atherosclerosis, and VSMCs (Vascular Smooth Muscle Cells) - the main cellular component of media, play an important role in this process. Many reports indicate that the biologically active vitamin D metabolite - 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) (1,25(OH)(2)D(3) = calcitriol), besides its well established role in calcium homeostasis, plays an essential role in the regulation of the inflammation process. The aim of this study was to determine the regulatory effects of calcitriol, applied at two supra-physiological doses (10 nM and 100 nM), in VSMC culture. Secretion of the pro-inflammatory cytokines, IL-6 and TNF-α, was significantly attenuated in calcitriol-treated VSMC culture, but the level of anti-inflammatory TGF-β was generally unchanged. Since in advanced atherosclerosis lesions several cell types, including VSMCs, overproduce the HSP70 chaperone protein, we also checked the effects of calcitriol on its synthesis. The presence of 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) did not affect HSP70 synthesis under physiological conditions but the synthesis of HSP70 in VSMCs exposed to heat shock was significantly inhibited by calcitriol (=100 nM). We observed that 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) induced SOD 1 activity, stimulated the expression of IκB-α, and did not influence the level of NF-κB-p65 in VSMCs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Major Heart attacks occur 40 percent more often if vitamin D lower than 7 ng</title><link>/posts/major-heart-attacks-occur-40-percent-more-often-if-vitamin-d-lower-than-7-ng.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/major-heart-attacks-occur-40-percent-more-often-if-vitamin-d-lower-than-7-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-prognosis-in-acute-myocardial-infarction">Vitamin D and prognosis in acute myocardial infarction.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Cardiol. 2013 Feb 13. pii: S0167-5273(13)00070-3. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijcard.2013.01.030.">doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2013.01.030.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ng LL, Sandhu JK, Squire IB, Davies JE, Jones DJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Leicester, Department of Cardiovascular Sciences, Leicester Royal Infirmary, Leicester, United Kingdom; NIHR Leicester Cardiovascular Biomedical Research Unit, Glenfield Hospital, Leicester, United Kingdom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D status (VDS) has been linked to mortality and incident acute myocardial infarction (AMI) in healthy cohorts. Associations with recurrent adverse cardiovascular events in those with cardiovascular disease are less clear. Our objective was to assess the prevalence and prognostic impact of VDS on patients presenting with AMI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Peripheral Arterial Disease 3X less prevalent at 40 ng of vitamin D – 2008</title><link>/posts/peripheral-arterial-disease-3x-less-prevalent-at-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-2008.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/peripheral-arterial-disease-3x-less-prevalent-at-40-ng-of-vitamin-d-2008.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-the-prevalence-of-peripheral-arterial-disease-results-from-nhanes-20012004">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D Levels and the Prevalence of Peripheral Arterial Disease: Results from NHANES 2001–2004&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2008 June; 28(6): 1179–1185.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michal L. Melamed,1,* Paul Muntner,2,* Erin D. Michos,3 Jaime Uribarri,2 Collin Weber,4 Jyotirmay Sharma,4 and Paolo Raggi5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels and the prevalence of peripheral arterial disease (PAD) in the general United States population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods and Results: We analyzed data from 4,839 participants of the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2001–2004 to evaluate the relationship between 25(OH)D and PAD (defined as an ankle-brachial index &amp;lt;0.9). Across quartiles of 25(OH)D, from lowest to highest, the prevalence of PAD was 8.1%, 5.4%, 4.9%, and 3.7% (p-trend&amp;lt;0.001). After multivariable adjustment for demographics, co-morbidities, physical activity level and laboratory measures, the prevalence ratio of PAD for the lowest, compared to the highest, 25(OH)D quartile (&amp;lt;17.8 and ≥29.2 ng/mL, respectively) was 1.80 (95% confidence interval: 1.19, 2.74). For each 10 ng/mL lower 25(OH)D level, the multivariable-adjusted prevalence ratio of PAD was 1.35 (95% confidence interval: 1.15, 1.59).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More than 400 mg of Calcium supplements caused cardiovascular deaths in men</title><link>/posts/more-than-400-mg-of-calcium-supplements-caused-cardiovascular-deaths-in-men.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-400-mg-of-calcium-supplements-caused-cardiovascular-deaths-in-men.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="full-text-will-be-here-soon">full text will be here soon&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/calcium-cvd-1.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/caclium-cvd-2.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>for now&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong> !!full text will be here soon&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="note-calcium-is-far-less-of-a-problem-if-taken-with-vitamin-d-and--or-vitamin-d-2">Note: Calcium is far less of a problem if taken with Vitamin D and / or Vitamin D-2&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Decreasing Magnesium and increasing CaMg ratio are increasing health problems – 2012 - 2013</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-decreasing-magnesium-and-increasing-camg-ratio-are-increasing-health-problems-2012-2013.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-decreasing-magnesium-and-increasing-camg-ratio-are-increasing-health-problems-2012-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="2-items-by-a-rosanoff">2 items by A Rosanoff&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="suboptimal-magnesium-status-in-the-united-states-are-the-health-consequences-underestimated">Suboptimal magnesium status in the United States: are the health consequences underestimated?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr Rev. 2012 Mar;70(3):153-64. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1753-4887.2011.00465.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1753-4887.2011.00465.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Feb 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rosanoff A, Weaver CM, Rude RK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Magnesium Education &amp;amp; Research, 13-1255 Malama Street, Pahoa, HI 96778, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:ARosanoff@gmail.com">ARosanoff@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In comparison with calcium, magnesium is an &amp;ldquo;orphan nutrient&amp;rdquo; that has been studied considerably less heavily. Low magnesium intakes and blood levels have been associated with type 2 diabetes, metabolic syndrome, elevated C-reactive protein, hypertension, atherosclerotic vascular disease, sudden cardiac death, osteoporosis, migraine headache, asthma, and colon cancer. Almost half (48%) of the US population consumed less than the required amount of magnesium from food in 2005-2006, and the figure was down from 56% in 2001-2002. Surveys conducted over 30 years indicate rising calcium-to-magnesium food-intake ratios among adults and the elderly in the United States, excluding intake from supplements, which favor calcium over magnesium.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular system benefits from both Omega-3 and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-system-benefits-from-both-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-system-benefits-from-both-omega-3-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="omega-3-fatty-acids-and-vitamin-d-in-cardiology">Omega-3 Fatty acids and vitamin d in cardiology.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cardiol Res Pract. 2012;2012:729670. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1155/2012/729670.">doi: 10.1155/2012/729670.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Dec 31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Güttler N, Zheleva K, Parahuleva M, Chasan R, Bilgin M, Neuhof C, Burgazli M, Niemann B, Erdogan A, Böning A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardiology and Angiology, University Hospital Giessen, 35390 Giessen, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dietary modification and supplementation play an increasingly important role in the conservative treatment of cardiovascular disease. Current interest has focused on n-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFA) and vitamin D. Clinical trial results on this subject are contradictory in many aspects. Several studies indicate that n-3 PUFA consumption improves&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Almost 6X more likely to die after coronary bypass if vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/almost-6x-more-likely-to-die-after-coronary-bypass-if-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/almost-6x-more-likely-to-die-after-coronary-bypass-if-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="pre-hospital-serum-vitamin-d-levels-and-mortality-following-coronary-artery-bypass-grafting">Pre-Hospital Serum Vitamin D Levels and Mortality Following Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Critical Care Medicine: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/01.ccm.0000424294.93940.c5">doi: 10.1097/01.ccm.0000424294.93940.c5&lt;/a>, Oral Abstract Session&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moromizato, Takuhiro; Litonjua, Augusto; Braun, Andrea; Gibbons, Fiona; Giovannucci, Edward; Christopher, Kenneth&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Whether the degree of vitamin D deficiency affects survival following coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) is not clear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypothesis: We hypothesize that pre-hospital vitamin D deficiency is associated with mortality following CABG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: We performed a retrospective cohort study between 2001 and 2010 in two teaching hospitals in Boston, Massachusetts utilizing an institutional Research Patient Data Registry. We studied 322 patients, age = 18 years, in whom 25(OH)D was measured prior to hospitalization. The exposure of interest was pre-admission 25(OH)D categorized a priori as deficiency in 25(OH)D (=15ng/mL), insufficiency (15-30 ng/mL) and sufficiency (=30ng/mL). The primary outcome was all cause mortality 90 days following CABG. Vital status was obtained from the Social Security Administration Death Master File. Associations between vitamin D groups and mortality were estimated by bivariable and multivariable logistic regression models.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D increases risk of cardiovascular disease in African Americans – 2011</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increases-risk-of-cardiovascular-disease-in-african-americans-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increases-risk-of-cardiovascular-disease-in-african-americans-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cardiovascular-disease-potential-role-in-health-disparities">Vitamin D and cardiovascular disease: potential role in health disparities.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Health Care Poor Underserved. 2011;22(4 Suppl):23-38. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1353/hpu.2011.0161.">doi: 10.1353/hpu.2011.0161.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Artaza JN, Contreras S, Garcia LA, Mehrotra R, Gibbons G, Shohet R, Martins D, Norris KC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Charles R. Drew University of Medicine &amp;amp; Science, 1731 East 120th Street, Los Angeles, CA 90059, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:jorgeartaza@cdrewu.edu">jorgeartaza@cdrewu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular disease (CVD), which includes coronary artery disease and stroke, is the leading cause of mortality in the nation. Excess CVD morbidity and premature mortality in the African American community is one of the most striking examples of racial/ ethnic disparities in health outcomes. African Americans also suffer from increased rates of hypovitaminosis D, which has emerged as an independent risk factor for all-cause and cardiovascular mortality. This overview examines the potential role of hypovitaminosis D as a contributor to racial and ethnic disparities in cardiovascular disease (CVD). We review the epidemiology of vitamin D and CVD in African Americans and the emerging biological roles of vitamin D in key CVD signaling pathways that may contribute to the epidemiological findings and provide the foundation for future therapeutic strategies for reducing health disparities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D is a risk factor for vascular diseases in African Americans</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-is-a-risk-factor-for-vascular-diseases-in-african-americans.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-is-a-risk-factor-for-vascular-diseases-in-african-americans.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="hypovitaminosis-d-as-a-contributory-factor-to-vascular-disease-in-african-americans-a-graded-literature-review">Hypovitaminosis D as a Contributory Factor to Vascular Disease in African-Americans: A graded literature review&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>James H. Moorman MS Thesis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Predicted cardiac surgery death associated with low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/predicted-cardiac-surgery-death-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/predicted-cardiac-surgery-death-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-cross-sectional-study-of-the-association-between-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-predicted-operative-mortality-of-patients-with-cardiovascular-disease">A Cross-Sectional Study of the Association between Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels and Predicted Operative Mortality of Patients with Cardiovascular Disease.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Nutr Sci Vitaminol (Tokyo). 2012;58(5):327-32.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tsutsumi Y, Sanui M, Shimojima A, Ishioka H, Urashima M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Molecular Epidemiology, Jikei University School of Medicine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent studies have suggested that low levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) are associated with cardiovascular risks in medical patients. However, these associations have not been well documented in high risk surgical patients. We hypothesized that serum 25OHD, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25OHD) would be associated with the cardiac operative risk stratification score. The study was conducted with a cross-sectional design at a single academic medical center in Japan. Two hundred five adult patients scheduled for major cardiovascular surgery were included consecutively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nitric oxide (from Sun, UVA, Vitamin D) reduces cardiovascular problems</title><link>/posts/nitric-oxide-from-sun-uva-vitamin-d-reduces-cardiovascular-problems.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nitric-oxide-from-sun-uva-vitamin-d-reduces-cardiovascular-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dr-richard-weller-dermatologist-found-that-nitric-oxide-is-produced-in-the-skin-by-uva-uvb-was-not-needed">Dr. Richard Weller, Dermatologist Found that nitric oxide is produced in the skin by UVA (UVB was not needed)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#no-release">NO Release&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#nitric-oxide-test-strips-for-saliva-50-for-32-amazonhttpswwwamazoncomberkeley-test-nitric-oxide-stripsdpb06xnx7q3h----">Nitric Oxide test strips for saliva: 50 for $32** &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Berkeley-Test-Nitric-Oxide-Strips/dp/B06XNX7Q3H">Amazon&lt;/a> **&amp;mdash;&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sunlight-has-cardiovascular-benefits-independently-of-vitamin-d---2016-weller">Sunlight Has Cardiovascular Benefits Independently of Vitamin D - 2016 Weller&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#is-sunlight-good-for-our-heart---2010-weller-2010httpwwwncbinlmnihgovpubmed2021512320-feelisch-m-kolb-bachofen-v-liu-d-lundberg-jo-revelo-lp-suschek-cv-weller-rb">Is sunlight good for our heart? - 2010** &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20215123%20">Weller 2010&lt;/a> **Feelisch M, Kolb-Bachofen V, Liu D, Lundberg JO, Revelo LP, Suschek CV, Weller RB.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#uva-can-produce-nitric-oxide-in-the-blood-stream---weller-2009">UVA can produce Nitric Oxide in the blood stream - Weller 2009&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#nitric-oxide-and-vitamin-d---aug-2014">Nitric Oxide and vitamin D - Aug 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#uva-irradiation-of-human-skin-vasodilates-arterial-vasculature-and-lowers-blood-pressure-independently-of-nitric-oxide-synthase--weller-2014">UVA Irradiation of Human Skin Vasodilates Arterial Vasculature and Lowers Blood Pressure Independently of Nitric Oxide Synthase -Weller 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="dr-richard-weller-dermatologist-found-that-nitric-oxide-is-produced-in-the-skin-by-uva-uvb-was-not-needed">Dr. Richard Weller, Dermatologist Found that nitric oxide is produced in the skin by UVA (UVB was not needed)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>His &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/richard_weller_could_the_sun_be_good_for_your_heart.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TEDTalks_video+%28TEDTalks+Main+%28SD%29+-+Site%29">15 minute TedTalk video&lt;/a> **** More blood flow **&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/more-blood-flow.jpg" alt="image">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X more complications after heart surgery associated with high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/2x-more-complications-after-heart-surgery-associated-with-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-complications-after-heart-surgery-associated-with-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-the-risk-of-major-adverse-cardiac-and-cerebrovascular-events-in-cardiac-surgery">Vitamin D status and the risk of major adverse cardiac and cerebrovascular events in cardiac surgery&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur Heart J (2013) &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehs468">doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehs468&lt;/a> First published online: January 12, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Armin Zittermann 1,*; Joachim Kuhn 2; Jens Dreier 2; Cornelius Knabbe 2; Jan F. Gummert 1; Jochen Börgermann 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Clinic for Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery, Heart and Diabetes Center North Rhine-Westphalia, Ruhr University Bochum, Georgstrasse 11, Bad Oeynhausen, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Institute for Laboratory and Transfusion Medicine, Heart and Diabetes Center North Rhine-Westphalia, Ruhr University Bochum, Georgstrasse 11, Bad Oeynhausen, Germany&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cholesterol, Vitamins D3 and K2, heart disease, sulfates, LDL, – Masterjohn Interview</title><link>/posts/cholesterol-vitamins-d3-and-k2-heart-disease-sulfates-ldl-masterjohn-interview.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cholesterol-vitamins-d3-and-k2-heart-disease-sulfates-ldl-masterjohn-interview.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="mercola-interviewed-dr-chris-masterohnhttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20130116cholesterol-regulates-cell-signalingaspxe_cid20130116_dnl_art_220">&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2013/01/16/cholesterol-regulates-cell-signaling.aspx?e_cid=20130116_DNL_art_2%20">Mercola interviewed Dr. Chris Masterohn&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Video is 15 minutes long&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Transcript follows&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="update-nutritional-adjuncts-to-the-fat-soluble-vitamins-a-d-and-k-httparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20130318fat-soluble-vitaminsaspxe_cid20130318_dnl_art_2utm_sourcednlutm_mediumemailutm_contentart2utm_campaign20130318_edn4-mercola-march-2013">Update &lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2013/03/18/fat-soluble-vitamins.aspx?e_cid=20130318_DNL_art_2&amp;amp;utm_source=dnl&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=art2&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20130318#_edn4">Nutritional Adjuncts to the Fat-Soluble Vitamins A, D, and K &lt;/a> Mercola March 2013&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eventually earning a reputation as “the most toxic of all the vitamins. still in textbooks in 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Zinc added to vitamin A greatly reduced conjunctiva of the eye&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="here-is-the-73-minute-transcript">Here is the 73+ minute transcript&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-special-interview-with-chris-masterjohn-jan-2013">A Special Interview with Chris Masterjohn Jan 2013&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By Dr. Joseph Mercola&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4000 IU vitamin D daily for just 5 days reduced inflammation after heart attack – RCT</title><link>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-for-just-5-days-reduced-inflammation-after-heart-attack-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-for-just-5-days-reduced-inflammation-after-heart-attack-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-inflammatory-cytokines-and-coronary-events-a-comprehensive-review">Vitamin D Inflammatory Cytokines and Coronary Events: A Comprehensive Review.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2013 Jan 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arnson Y, Itzhaky D, Mosseri M, Barak V, Tzur B, Agmon-Levin N, Amital H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiology Division, Meir Medical Center, Kfar Saba, Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Myocardial infarction (MI) is the most common cause of cardiac injury in the Western world. Cardiac injury activates innate immune mechanisms initiating an inflammatory reaction. Inflammatory cytokines and vascular cell adhesion molecules (VCAM) promote adhesive interactions between leukocytes and endothelial cells, resulting in the transmigration of inflammatory cells into the site of injury. Low vitamin D levels are associated with higher prevalence of cardiovascular risk factors and a higher risk of MI. In this paper, we examine the effects of short-term vitamin D supplementation on inflammatory cytokine levels after an acute coronary syndrome. We recruited patients arriving to the hospital with an acute MI. All patients received optimal medical therapy and underwent a coronary catheterization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Higher vitamin D levels associated with fewer vein clots decades later</title><link>/posts/higher-vitamin-d-levels-associated-with-fewer-vein-clots-decades-later.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/higher-vitamin-d-levels-associated-with-fewer-vein-clots-decades-later.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-and-risk-of-venous-thromboembolism-in-the-general-population-with-18791-participants">25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations and risk of venous thromboembolism in the general population with 18,791 participants.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Brøndum-Jacobsen P, Benn M, Tybjaerg-Hansen A, Nordestgaard BG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Herlev Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital, Denmark; The Copenhagen General Population Study, Herlev Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital, Denmark; The Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/blood-clot.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has potential antithrombotic effects suggesting that vitamin D analogs could be used as adjunctive antithrombotic agents. However, epidemiological evidence of an association between reduced 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations and risk of venous thromboembolism is lacking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Excess vitamin A caused calcification of heart valves in mice</title><link>/posts/excess-vitamin-a-caused-calcification-of-heart-valves-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/excess-vitamin-a-caused-calcification-of-heart-valves-in-mice.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>7100 IU vitamin D2 for 3 months did not treat Coronary Artery Disease</title><link>/posts/7100-iu-vitamin-d2-for-3-months-did-not-treat-coronary-artery-disease.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7100-iu-vitamin-d2-for-3-months-did-not-treat-coronary-artery-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-effects-of-vitamin-d-repletion-on-endothelial-function-and-inflammation-in-patients-with-coronary-artery-disease">The effects of vitamin D repletion on endothelial function and inflammation in patients with coronary artery disease&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vasc Med December 2012 vol. 17 no. 6 394-404&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seth I Sokol1,2,3; Vankeepuram Srinivas1,2; Jill P Crandall4; Mimi Kim5; George Tellides6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amir Lebastchi6; Yiting Yu5; Alok K Gupta7; Michael H Alderman2,5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Medicine, Division of Cardiology, Jacobi Medical Center, Bronx, NY, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Medicine, Albert Einstein College of Medicine, Bronx, NY, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Timeline of Heart Disease, Diabetes, fats, lard, HFCS, and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/timeline-of-heart-disease-diabetes-fats-lard-hfcs-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/timeline-of-heart-disease-diabetes-fats-lard-hfcs-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#subset-of--illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015httpdietheartnewscom201208illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-201520-diet-heart-news-aug-2012">Subset of &lt;a href="http://dietheartnews.com/2012/08/illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015/%20">Illustrated History of Heart Disease 1825-2015&lt;/a> Diet Heart News Aug 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-trans-fats">See also trans-fats&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#more-cholesterol-is-associated-with-fewer-deaths---around-the-entire-world">MORE cholesterol is associated with FEWER deaths - around the entire world&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsoverview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-889overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-da-has-the-following-chart">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 889">Overview Deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/a> has the following chart&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="subset-of--illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015httpdietheartnewscom201208illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-201520-diet-heart-news-aug-2012">Subset of &lt;a href="http://dietheartnews.com/2012/08/illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015/%20">Illustrated History of Heart Disease 1825-2015&lt;/a> Diet Heart News Aug 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Note: &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">lard&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">butter&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> used to have lots of vitamin D and &lt;a href="/posts/omega-3" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 3467">Omega-3&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>14X more likely to die after first cardiovascular event if vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/14x-more-likely-to-die-after-first-cardiovascular-event-if-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/14x-more-likely-to-die-after-first-cardiovascular-event-if-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="relation-of-severe-deficiency-of-vitamin-d-to-cardiovascular-mortality-during-acute-coronary-syndromes">Relation of Severe Deficiency of Vitamin D to Cardiovascular Mortality During Acute Coronary Syndromes.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Cardiol. 2012 Nov 20. pii: S0002-9149(12)02282-5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjcard.2012.10.006.">doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2012.10.006.&lt;/a> Correia LC, Sodré F, Garcia G, Sabino M, Brito M, Kalil F, Barreto B, Lima JC, Noya-Rabelo MM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical School of Bahia, Salvador, Brazil; Cardiology Division, San Rafael Hospital, Monte Tabor, Salvador, Brazil. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:lccorreia@terra.com.br">lccorreia@terra.com.br&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is associated with risk for a first cardiovascular event in the general population, possibly because of inflammation, insulin resistance, and neurohumoral activation. However, its relation with outcomes in acute coronary syndromes has not been reported.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soft Bones, Hard Arteries, Vitamin D, Vitamin K2 and antibiotics</title><link>/posts/soft-bones-hard-arteries-vitamin-d-vitamin-k2-and-antibiotics.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/soft-bones-hard-arteries-vitamin-d-vitamin-k2-and-antibiotics.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Heart attacks did not reduce vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/heart-attacks-did-not-reduce-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-attacks-did-not-reduce-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Heart problems such as Afib related to little Magnesium, Omega-3, Vitamin D getting to tissues</title><link>/posts/heart-problems-such-as-afib-related-to-little-magnesium-omega-3-vitamin-d-getting-to-tissues.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-problems-such-as-afib-related-to-little-magnesium-omega-3-vitamin-d-getting-to-tissues.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="for-40-years-cardiovascular-problems-associated-with-low-magnesium">For 40+ years Cardiovascular problems associated with low Magnesium&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJM196904102801504%20">Sudden Death and Ischemic Heart Disease: Correlation With Hardness of the Local Water Supply.&lt;/a> 1969, New England Journal of Medicine&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>People who died suddenly had far lower levels of Magnesium than those who died in accidents&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed?term=magnesium%20(heart%20OR%20cardiac)">PubMed search for magnesium (heart OR cardiac)&lt;/a> 7879 items as of Dec 2018&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17560883%20">Meta-analysis of magnesium therapy for the acute management of rapid atrial fibrillation.&lt;/a> 2007&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D level higher than 30 ng reduces diabetic blood clotting</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-level-higher-than-30-ng-reduces-diabetic-blood-clotting.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-level-higher-than-30-ng-reduces-diabetic-blood-clotting.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>3 X increased chance of death if have asthma – study of 200,000 people over 10 years</title><link>/posts/3-x-increased-chance-of-death-if-have-asthma-study-of-200000-people-over-10-years.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-x-increased-chance-of-death-if-have-asthma-study-of-200000-people-over-10-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="adult-asthma-and-risk-of-coronary-heart-disease-cerebrovascular-disease-and-heart-failure-a-prospective-study-of-2-matched-cohorts">Adult Asthma and Risk of Coronary Heart Disease, Cerebrovascular Disease, and Heart Failure: A Prospective Study of 2 Matched Cohorts&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Epidemiology, (2012), &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/aje/kws181">doi: 10.1093/aje/kws181&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carlos Iribarren*, Irina V. Tolstykh, Mary K. Miller, Erica Sobel and Mark D. Eisner&lt;/p>
&lt;p>?*Correspondence to Dr. Carlos Iribarren, Division of Research, Kaiser Permanente Medical Care Program, 2000 Broadway, Oakland, CA 94612 (e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:cgi@dor.kaiser.org">cgi@dor.kaiser.org&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abbreviations: CHD, coronary heart disease; CVD, cardiovascular disease; ICD-9, International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision; KPNC, Kaiser Permanente Northern California.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increased heart attacks in the winter may be due to lack of sunshine</title><link>/posts/increased-heart-attacks-in-the-winter-may-be-due-to-lack-of-sunshine.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-heart-attacks-in-the-winter-may-be-due-to-lack-of-sunshine.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Increased probability of chest aorta aneurisms with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/increased-probability-of-chest-aorta-aneurisms-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-probability-of-chest-aorta-aneurisms-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Off topic: CVD: the primary cause of death in senior women, is increasing</title><link>/posts/off-topic-cvd-the-primary-cause-of-death-in-senior-women-is-increasing.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-cvd-the-primary-cause-of-death-in-senior-women-is-increasing.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="changing-long-held-beliefs-is-never-easy">Changing Long-Held Beliefs is Never Easy:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-proposal-for-multimodal-approaches-in-female-healthcare---an-integrative-view">A Proposal for Multimodal Approaches in Female Healthcare - An Integrative View&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The EPMA Journal 2012, 3:14 &lt;a href="http://www.epmajournal.eom/content/3/14">http://www.epmajournal.eom/content/3/14&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olga Golubnitschaja, Secretary-General of EPMA, and Vincenzo Costigliola, President of EPMA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>   {EPMA = European Association for Predictive, Preventive and Personalised Medicine.}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="worldwide-cardiovascular-disease-cvd-is-the-leading-cause-of-mortality-in-women-cardiovascular-health-in-females-is-not-improving-as-fast-as-that-of-males">Worldwide cardiovascular disease (CVD) is the leading cause of mortality in women: cardiovascular health in females is not improving as fast as that of males&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Worldwide a third of all deaths of women and &lt;strong>half of all deaths of women over 50 years old in developing countries are caused by CVD&lt;/strong> &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. Several studies have been recently dedicated to the question of CVD-related death with particular focus on gender-dependent aspects. Although CVD is traditionally considered as the major health burden of male subpopulations surprising statistics have been collected for worsening the situation in females. New trends obviously demonstrate a shifting of the problem into healthcare of female populations: from 25 countries selected by World Health Organisation in the years 1990-2000, more than a half (15 countries, 60%) currently demonstrate either increase in CVD-related death in females or, even if the rates are decreased then less compared to men &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vertebral fracture 3X more likely with aortic calcification – Vitamins D3 and K2</title><link>/posts/vertebral-fracture-3x-more-likely-with-aortic-calcification-vitamins-d3-and-k2.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vertebral-fracture-3x-more-likely-with-aortic-calcification-vitamins-d3-and-k2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="aortic-calcification-and-bone-metabolism">Aortic Calcification and Bone Metabolism:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="the-relationship-between-aortic-calcification-bmd-vertebral-fracture-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-osteocalcin">The Relationship between Aortic Calcification, BMD, Vertebral Fracture, 25-Hydroxyvitamin D, and Osteocalcin.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Calcif Tissue Int. 2012 Sep 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim KJ, Kim KM, Park KH, Choi HS, Rhee Y, Lee YH, Cha BS, Kim MJ, Oh SM, Brown JK, Lim SK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Department of Internal Medicine, Yonsei University College of Medicine, 134 Shinchon-dong, Seodaemun-gu, Seoul, 120-752, South Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study was to investigate the relationship between aortic calcification (AC) and low bone mineral density (BMD), 25(OH)D, C-terminal telopeptide (CTx), and osteocalcin levels in Asian women. We also tried to find the association between AC and the risk of vertebral fracture. We included 769 patients in this study. All patients underwent QCT. Aortic calcium score (ACS) was quantified by the Agatston scoring method. Spinal fracture was defined by lumbar spine radiography.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Best heart geometry associated with vitamin D of 30-37 ng</title><link>/posts/best-heart-geometry-associated-with-vitamin-d-of-30-37-ng.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/best-heart-geometry-associated-with-vitamin-d-of-30-37-ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Low levels of vitamin D associated with all cause mortality</title><link>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-all-cause-mortality.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-all-cause-mortality.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="circulating-25ohd-dietary-vitamin-d-pth-and-calcium-associations-with-incident-cardiovascular-disease-and-mortality-the-midspan-family-study">Circulating 25OHD, Dietary Vitamin D, PTH, and Calcium Associations with Incident Cardiovascular Disease and Mortality: The MIDSPAN Family Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism October 15, 2012 jc.2012-2272&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paul Welsh, Orla Doolin, Alex McConnachie, Emma Boulton, Geraldine McNeil, Helen Macdonald, Antonia Hardcastle, Carole Hart, Mark Upton, Graham Watt and Naveed Sattar&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Cardiovascular and Medical Sciences (P.W., E.B., N.S.), Robertson Centre for Biostatistics (O.D., A.M.), Institute of Health and Wellbeing (C.H.), and General Practice and Primary Care (G.W.), University of Glasgow, Glasgow G12 8TA, United Kingdom; Public Health Nutrition Research Group (G.M., H.M., A.H.), University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen AB24 3FX, United Kingdom; and Woodlands Family Medical Centre (M.U.), Stockton-on-Tees TS18 1YE, United Kingdom&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypertension experts want still more vitamin D proof</title><link>/posts/hypertension-experts-want-still-more-vitamin-d-proof.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypertension-experts-want-still-more-vitamin-d-proof.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Omega-3 does not help heart patients – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/omega-3-does-not-help-heart-patients-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-3-does-not-help-heart-patients-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="clipped-from-la-times-sept-2012httpwwwlatimescomnewssciencela-sci-omega-3s-heart-health-2012091203265313story20">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/science/la-sci-omega-3s-heart-health-20120912,0,3265313.story%20">LA Times Sept 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The study, reexamined the results of 20 previous studies dating back to 1989 that included nearly 70,000 patients.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;This evidence,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;should not be generalized to any type of patients or apparently healthy individuals.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="clipped-from-time-magazinehttphealthlandtimecom20120912omega-3-supplements-dont-lower-heart-disease-risk-after-all20">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://healthland.time.com/2012/09/12/omega-3-supplements-dont-lower-heart-disease-risk-after-all/%20">Time Magazine&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Volunteers in the studies, &lt;strong>most of whom were heart patients&lt;/strong> , were randomly assigned to take either 1.5 g of omega-3 supplementation or a placebo every day for about two years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half as many heart deaths for those with high levels of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/half-as-many-heart-deaths-for-those-with-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-as-many-heart-deaths-for-those-with-high-levels-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Petrie dish experiment confirms that active vitamin D reduces arterial inflammation</title><link>/posts/petrie-dish-experiment-confirms-that-active-vitamin-d-reduces-arterial-inflammation.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/petrie-dish-experiment-confirms-that-active-vitamin-d-reduces-arterial-inflammation.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Echocardiograms confirm problems with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/echocardiograms-confirm-problems-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/echocardiograms-confirm-problems-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="relationship-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-to-echocardiography-findings-in-veterans">Relationship of Vitamin D Deficiency to Echocardiography Findings in Veterans&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Joshi et al., J Clin Exp Cardiolog 2012, S:3 &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.4172/2155-9880.S3-005">http://dx.doi.org/10.4172/2155-9880.S3-005&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hetvi Joshi 1, Pablo Lopez 1, Beth Bailey 2, Costy Mattar 3, Todd Manning 4 and Alan Peiris 5 &lt;a href="mailto:peiris@etsu.edu">peiris@etsu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;East Tennessee State University, Department of Internal Medicine, USA 2East Tennessee State University, Department of Family Medicine, USA &amp;lsquo;Division of Cardiology, Mountain Home Veterans Affairs Medical Center, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received April &amp;lsquo;2, 2012; Accepted May 2&amp;rsquo;, 2012; Published May 23, 2012&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death in less than 2 years of Heart Failure associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/death-in-less-than-2-years-of-heart-failure-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-in-less-than-2-years-of-heart-failure-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-a-predictor-of-reduced-survival-in-patients-with-heart-failure">Vitamin D Deficiency is a Predictor of Reduced Survival in Patients With Heart Failure&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Israel Gotsman; Ayelet Shauer; Donna R. Zwas; Yaron Hellman; Andre Keren; Chaim Lotan; Dan Admon&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eur J Heart Fail. 2012;14(4):357-366. © 2012 Oxford University Press&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aims Vitamin D deficiency is a highly prevalent, global phenomenon. The prevalence in heart failure (HF) patients and its effect on outcome are less clear. We evaluated vitamin D levels and vitamin D supplementation in patients with HF and its effect on mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>100000 IU vitamin D did not help Peripheral Arerial Disease in one month</title><link>/posts/100000-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-help-peripheral-arerial-disease-in-one-month.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/100000-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-help-peripheral-arerial-disease-in-one-month.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Statins associated with 14X increase in Polymyalgia Rheumatica (a new disease)</title><link>/posts/statins-associated-with-14x-increase-in-polymyalgia-rheumatica-a-new-disease.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/statins-associated-with-14x-increase-in-polymyalgia-rheumatica-a-new-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="new-research-statins-increase-risk-of-polymalgia-rheumatica-14-foldhttpwwwgreenmedinfocomblognew-greek-name-statin-toxicity-polymyalgia-rheumatica20-greenmedinfo-aug-2012">&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/new-greek-name-statin-toxicity-polymyalgia-rheumatica%20">New Research: Statins Increase Risk of Polymalgia Rheumatica 14-Fold&lt;/a> GreenMedInfo Aug 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>300+ adverse health effects have been linked to statins.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>such as: Liver Damage, Coenzyme Q10 Deficiency, Type 2 Diabetes, Cataract, Pancreatitits, Cognitive Decline/Dysfunction, Erectile Dysfunction, Peripheral Neuropathies, Mitochondrial Dysfunction&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Polymyalgia translates from the Greek &amp;ldquo;pain in many muscles,&amp;rdquo; and rheumatic means &amp;ldquo;flux.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22844450">Statin-Associated Polymyalgia Rheumatica&lt;/a> PLOS July 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1000 IU vitamin D did not reduce cardiovascular risk factors</title><link>/posts/1000-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-reduce-cardiovascular-risk-factors.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/1000-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-reduce-cardiovascular-risk-factors.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d3-supplementation-has-no-effect-on-conventional-cardiovascular-risk-factors">Vitamin D3 Supplementation Has No Effect on Conventional Cardiovascular Risk Factors.&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-parallel-group-double-blind-placebo-controlled-rct">A Parallel-Group, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled RCT&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism August 3, 2012 jc.2012-2126 Adrian D. Wood, Karen R. Secombes, Frank Thies, Lorna Aucott, Alison J. Black, Alexandra Mavroeidi, William G. Simpson, William D. Fraser, David M. Reid and Helen M. Macdonald&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Medicine and Dentistry (A.D.W., K.R.S., F.T., L.A., D.M.R., H.M.M.), Medical Sciences (A.M.), University of Aberdeen, Foresterhill, Aberdeen AB252ZD, United Kingdom; Grampian Osteoporosis Service (A.J.B.), Woolmanhill Hospital, Aberdeen AB251LD, United Kingdom; Department of Clinical Biochemistry (W.G.S.), Aberdeen Royal Infirmary, Foresterhill AB252ZD, United Kingdom; and Norwich Medical School (W.D.F.), University of East Anglia, Norwich NR47TJ, United Kingdom&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Deficiency may be an Independent Risk Factor for Arterial Disease</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-may-be-an-independent-risk-factor-for-arterial-disease.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-may-be-an-independent-risk-factor-for-arterial-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2012 Jul 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van de Luijtgaarden KM, Voûte MT, Hoeks SE, Bakker EJ, Chonchol M, Stolker RJ, Rouwet EV, Verhagen HJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Vascular Surgery, Erasmus University Medical Center, Rotterdam, The Netherlands; Department of Anesthesiology, Erasmus University Medical Center, Rotterdam, The Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: The aim of this study was to assess the vitamin D status in patients with occlusive or aneurysmatic arterial disease in relation to clinical cardiovascular risk profiles and markers of atherosclerotic disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shift workers 23 percent more likely to have cardiovascular events – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/shift-workers-23-percent-more-likely-to-have-cardiovascular-events-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shift-workers-23-percent-more-likely-to-have-cardiovascular-events-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="shift-work-and-vascular-events-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Shift work and vascular events: systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>BMJ 2012; 345 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.e4800">doi: 10.1136/bmj.e4800&lt;/a> (Published 26 July 2012)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cite this as: BMJ 2012;345:e4800&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manav V Vyas, graduate student1, Amit X Garg, professor123, Arthur V Iansavichus, information specialist3, John Costella, research and instructional librarian4, Allan Donner, professor15, Lars E Laugsand, PhD candidate6, Imre Janszky, researcher67, Marko Mrkobrada, assistant professor25, Grace Parraga, associate professor8, Daniel G Hackam, associate professor125&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Western University, London, ON, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atrial Fibrillation associated with lower levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/atrial-fibrillation-associated-with-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atrial-fibrillation-associated-with-lower-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cardiovascular risk factors in children associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-risk-factors-in-children-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-risk-factors-in-children-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="associations-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d2-and-d3-with-cardiovascular-risk-factors-in-childhood-cross-sectional-findings-from-the-avon-longitudinal-study-of-parents-and-children">Associations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D2 and D3 with cardiovascular risk factors in childhood: cross-sectional findings from the Avon Longitudinal Study of Parents and Children.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012 May;97(5):1563-71. Epub 2012 Feb 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Williams DM, Fraser A, Sayers A, Fraser WD, Hingorani A, Deanfield J, Davey Smith G, Sattar N, Lawlor DA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical Research Council Centre for Causal Analyses in Translational Epidemiology, School of Social and Community Medicine, University of Bristol, Bristol BS8 2BN, United Kingdom. &lt;a href="mailto:dylan.williams@bristol.ac.uk">dylan.williams@bristol.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D not associated with PAD after adjusting for race, diabetes and BMI</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-not-associated-with-pad-after-adjusting-for-race-diabetes-and-bmi.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-not-associated-with-pad-after-adjusting-for-race-diabetes-and-bmi.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-status-and-functional-performance-in-peripheral-artery-disease">Vitamin D status and functional performance in peripheral artery disease&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Vascular Med July 19, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary M McDermott &lt;a href="mailto:mdm608@northwestern.edu">mdm608@northwestern.edu&lt;/a>, Department of Medicine, Northwestern University’s Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kiang Liu. Department of Preventive Medicine, Northwestern University’s Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luigi Ferrucci. Longitudinal Studies Section, National Institute on Aging, Baltimore, MD, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lu Tian, Department of Health and Research Policy, Stanford University, Palo Alto, CA, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blackouts due to low blood pressure associated with 8 nanograms lower vitamin D</title><link>/posts/blackouts-due-to-low-blood-pressure-associated-with-8-nanograms-lower-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blackouts-due-to-low-blood-pressure-associated-with-8-nanograms-lower-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-orthostatic-hypotension">Vitamin D and orthostatic hypotension&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Kevin Gerald McCarroll1,2?, David J. Robinson3, Avril Coughlan4, Martin Healy5, Rose Anne Kenny6 and Conal Cunningham3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Age and Ageing First published online: July 11, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Gerontology, St James&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, James&amp;rsquo;s St, Dublin D8, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Mercers&amp;rsquo;s Institute for Research on Ageing, Hospital 4, Top Floor, St James&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, James&amp;rsquo;s St, Dublin D8, Ireland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Gerontology, St James&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Dublin D8, Ireland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High triglycerides in Metabolic Syndrome associated with low Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/high-triglycerides-in-metabolic-syndrome-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-triglycerides-in-metabolic-syndrome-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-relationship-of-vitamin-d-with-non-traditional-risk-factors-for-cardiovascular-disease-in-subjects-with-metabolic-syndrome">The relationship of vitamin D with non-traditional risk factors for cardiovascular disease in subjects with metabolic syndrome&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Stefania Makariou 1,2, Evangelos Liberopoulos 2, Matilda Florentin 2, Konstantinos Lagos 2, Irene Gazi 2, Anna Challa 1, Moses Elisaf 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>department of Child Health, Medical School, University of Ioannina, Greece Corresponding author:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Internal Medicine, Medical School, University of Ioannina, Greece Prof. Moses Elisaf MD, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine Submitted: 20 November 2011 Medical School&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stiff arteries in seniors associated with low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/stiff-arteries-in-seniors-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stiff-arteries-in-seniors-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="arterial-stiffness-and-vitamin-d-levels-the-baltimore-longitudinal-study-of-aging">Arterial Stiffness and Vitamin D Levels: the Baltimore Longitudinal Study of Aging&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism July 5, 2012 jc.2012-1584&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Francesco Giallauria &lt;a href="mailto:giallauriaf@mail.nih.gov">giallauriaf@mail.nih.gov&lt;/a>, Yuri Milaneschi, Toshiko Tanaka, Marcello Maggio, Marco Canepa, Palchamy Elango, Carlo Vigorito, Edward G. Lakatta, Luigi Ferrucci and James Strait&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Longitudinal Studies Section (F.G., Y.M., T.T., P.E., L.F.), Clinical Research Branch, National Institute on Aging, Baltimore, Maryland 21225; Department of Clinical Medicine (F.G., C.V.), Cardiovascular and Immunological Sciences, University of Naples “Federico II”, 80131 Naples, Italy; Department of Psychiatry (Y.M.), VU University Medical Center/GGZ inGeest, 1081 HZ Amsterdam, The Netherlands; Department of Internal Medicine and Biomedical Sciences (M.M.), Section of Geriatrics, University of Parma, 43100 Parma, Italy; Laboratory of Cardiovascular Science (M.C., E.G.L., J.S.), National Institute on Aging, Baltimore, Maryland 21225&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aortic Calcification 85 percent more likely if vitamin D level lower than 29 ng</title><link>/posts/aortic-calcification-85-percent-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-level-lower-than-29-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/aortic-calcification-85-percent-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-level-lower-than-29-ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Heart Failure early death 2X more likely if less than 20 nanograms of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/heart-failure-early-death-2x-more-likely-if-less-than-20-nanograms-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-failure-early-death-2x-more-likely-if-less-than-20-nanograms-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-and-mortality-from-heart-failure-and-cardiovascular-disease-and-premature-mortality-from-all-cause-in-united-states-adults">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration and Mortality From Heart Failure and Cardiovascular Disease, and Premature Mortality from All-Cause in United States Adults&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Cardiol. 2012 Jun 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liu L, Chen M, Hankins SR, Nùñez AE, Watson RA, Weinstock PJ, Newschaffer CJ, Eisen HJ; Drexel Cardiovascular Health Collaborative Education, Research, and Evaluation Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Drexel University School of Public Health, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We aimed to examine associations between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) concentration and mortality from heart failure (HF) and cardiovascular disease (CVD) and premature death from all causes using data from the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, which included 13,131 participants (6,130 men, 7,001 women) =35 years old at baseline (1988 to 1994) and followed through December 2000.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular disease predicted by CRP and vitamin D, not cholesterol</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-predicted-by-crp-and-vitamin-d-not-cholesterol.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-predicted-by-crp-and-vitamin-d-not-cholesterol.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="cardiovascular-disease-statins-and-vitamin-d">Cardiovascular disease, statins and vitamin D.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Br J Nurs. 2012 Feb 23-Mar 7;21(4):214-20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wilding PM. Rheumatology Infusion Nurse, Lincoln County Hospital Rheumatology Unit, Lincoln. &lt;a href="mailto:peterwilding@hotmail.com">peterwilding@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular disease is the number one killer in the UK, causing more than 50 000 premature deaths per year, at a cost of over £30 billion to the economy (British Heart Foundation, 2010). Reducing this burden is a priority of the Government and health professionals (Department of Health, 2000).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2500 IU vitamin D did not reduce risk of CVD risk in 4 months</title><link>/posts/2500-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-reduce-risk-of-cvd-risk-in-4-months.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2500-iu-vitamin-d-did-not-reduce-risk-of-cvd-risk-in-4-months.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D interactions with cardiovascular disease - unsure</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-interactions-with-cardiovascular-disease-unsure.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-interactions-with-cardiovascular-disease-unsure.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-cardiovascular-disease-update-and-outlook">Vitamin D and cardiovascular disease: Update and outlook&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Scandinavian Journal of Clinical &amp;amp; Laboratory Investigation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>April 2012, Vol. 72, No. S243 , Pages 83-91&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Pilz1,2, Katharina Kienreich1, Andreas Tomaschitz1, Elisabeth Lerchbaum1, Andreas Meinitzer3, Winfried März3,4,5, Armin Zittermann6 &amp;amp; Jacqueline M. Dekker2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics and EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, The Netherlands&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Coronary Artery Disease predicted by low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/coronary-artery-disease-predicted-by-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/coronary-artery-disease-predicted-by-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Old concern about high vitamin D and atherosclerosis – 2003</title><link>/posts/old-concern-about-high-vitamin-d-and-atherosclerosis-2003.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/old-concern-about-high-vitamin-d-and-atherosclerosis-2003.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="controversies-in-vitamin-d-supplementation">Controversies in Vitamin D Supplementation&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal Issue: Nutrition Bytes, 9(1) (Peer reviewed)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tseng, Lisa, University of California, Los Angeles, 2003&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrition Bytes, Department of Biological Chemistry, UCLA, David Geffen School of Medicine, UC Los Angeles&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Permalink: &lt;a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/4m84d4fn">http://escholarship.org/uc/item/4m84d4fn&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Concurrent with the rise in vitamin D ingestion were the epidemic onsets of atherosclerosis and osteoporosis, which led to the hypothesis that vitamin D excess contributes to the development of these illnesses (1). A recent study found that vitamin D induced an increase in vascular smooth muscle cell migration in rat aorta, suggesting a possible mechanism of vitamin D in atherosclerosis (2). On the other hand, Rucker and colleagues found that 34% of the 188 healthy Canadians whom they tested were vitamin D insufficient in at least one occasion and recommended more aggressive vitamin D supplementation (3). Chapuy et al. reported that elderly women who took calcium and vitamin D supplements had reduced hip bone loss and risk of hip fracture (4). Although the research on vitamin D supplementation is still inconclusive, the potential association between high vitamin D ingestion and diseases such as atherosclerosis provides ample reason for caution. Since 15 minutes of exposure to sunlight three times a week is sufficient to produce the body&amp;rsquo;s requirement of vitamin D, there is no need for healthy individuals to take vitamin D supplements (5). In addition, the current practice of rampant fortification of foods with vitamin D should be reevaluated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular Disease and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="can-vitamin-d-deficiency-break-your-heart">Can Vitamin D Deficiency Break Your Heart?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>LETTERS TO THE EDITOR Mayo Clin Proc. April 2012;87(4):412-415 © 2012 Mayo Foundation for Medical Education and Research&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To the Editor:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We congratulate Hoang et al1 from the Cooper Center Longitudinal Study on their article reporting a signifi­cant association between low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and depression among the largest group of in­dividuals in whom this potential link has been explored to date. The fact that this study was done as part of a medical stu­dent summer research program makes it even more impressive. In the same issue of Mayo Clinic Proceedings, Chamberlain et al 2 report that among a cohort of patients with preexisting cardiovascular (CV) dis­ease, depression independently predicted hospitalization and all-cause mortality over a 17-year follow-up period. We have recently documented strong independent associations between low vitamin D levels and adverse CV events,3-5 and some meta-analyses show that vitamin D supplemen­tation appears to significantly lower all-cause mortality,6 whereas others do not.7 Thus, it is biologically plausible that vita­min D deficiency-induced depression may, in part, be responsible for increased CV risk associated with low vitamin D levels. Additionally, the tendency for de­pressed patients to stay indoors and be physically inactive (both risk factors for vitamin D deficiency) may lead to low vitamin D levels, which, in turn, are as­sociated with increased CV risk.2 Al­though the study from Hoang et al 1 dem­onstrates that the association between low 25(OH)D levels was independent of phys­ical activity, we were surprised that these Cooper Center Longitudinal Study data were also not corrected for precisely mea­sured levels of cardiorespiratory fitness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Statistical paradox of vitamin D deficiency and heart disease</title><link>/posts/statistical-paradox-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-heart-disease.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/statistical-paradox-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-heart-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="simpsons-paradox-and-the-association-between-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-increased-heart-disease-editorial">Simpson&amp;rsquo;s Paradox and the Association Between Vitamin D Deficiency and Increased Heart Disease: Editorial&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The American Journal of Cardiology, Available online 29 March 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William K. Chan, BHSca, b, Donald A. Redelmeier, MDa, b, c, d, ,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Institute for Clinical Evaluative Sciences in Ontario, Toronto, Ontario, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c Clinical Epidemiology Program, Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre, Toronto, Ontario, Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>d Center for Leading Injury Prevention Practice Education &amp;amp; Research, Toronto, Ontario, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yet again – 1700 IU vitamin D average does not reduce heart problems</title><link>/posts/yet-again-1700-iu-vitamin-d-average-does-not-reduce-heart-problems.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yet-again-1700-iu-vitamin-d-average-does-not-reduce-heart-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-markers-of-vascular-function-after-myocardial-infarction-a-randomised-controlled-trial">Effects of Vitamin D supplementation on markers of vascular function after myocardial infarction-A randomised controlled trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int J Cardiol. 2012 Mar 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Witham MD, Dove FJ, Khan F, Lang CC, Belch JJ, Struthers AD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ageing and Health, University of Dundee, Ninewells Hospital, Dundee DD1 9SY, United Kingdom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low vitamin D levels are common, and are associated with a higher incidence of future vascular events. We tested whether vitamin D supplementation could improve endothelial function and other markers of vascular function in patients with a history of myocardial infarction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Abu Dhabi 2012 - Grant</title><link>/posts/abu-dhabi-2012-grant.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/abu-dhabi-2012-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="presented-at-international-symposium-on-vitamin-d-deficiency---abu-dhabi-march-2012">Presented at International Symposium on Vitamin D Deficiency - Abu Dhabi March 2012&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;1182&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prof-william-b-grant">Prof. William B. Grant&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Qualifications: Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Position: Director, Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center (SUNARC), San Francisco, California, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-reducing-risk-of-cardiovascular-disease">1) The Role of Vitamin D in Reducing Risk of Cardiovascular Disease&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The aim of this presentation is to make the audience aware of the benefits of vitamin D in reducing the risk of cardiovascular diseases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Included in the talk will be an overview of the epidemiological findings regarding vitamin D and risk of cardiovascular diseases, the mechanisms whereby vitamin D might reduce the risk of cardiovascular disease, and the amount of vitamin D required to achieve optimal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low density lipoprotein cholesterol is predictable from vitamin D levels – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/low-density-lipoprotein-cholesterol-is-predictable-from-vitamin-d-levels-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-density-lipoprotein-cholesterol-is-predictable-from-vitamin-d-levels-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="influence-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-plasma-lipid-profiles-a-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials">Influence of vitamin D supplementation on plasma lipid profiles: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Hao Wang, Ning Xia, Yang Yang and Dao-Quan Peng&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lipids in Health and Disease 2012, 11:42 doi:10.1186/1476-511X-11-42, Published: 20 March 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract (provisional) &lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/ldl-metal-analysis-march-2012.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Observational studies have shown that low serum levels of vitamin D have been associated with an atherogenic lipid profile. However, the intervention studies gave divergent results. We conducted a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials that evaluated the effects of vitamin D supplementation on blood lipids. A systematic literature search was conducted via MEDLINE, Cochrane library, and EMBASE for randomized controlled clinical trials assessing the effects of vitamin D supplementation on lipids. The mean change in total cholesterol (TC), &lt;strong>low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C)&lt;/strong> , high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C) and triglycerides (TG) from baseline was treated as a continuous variable. In all, 12 clinical trials consisting of 1346 participants were included in the analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular problems for teens if low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-problems-for-teens-if-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-problems-for-teens-if-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-are-correlated-with-cardiometabolic-risk-among-american-black-and-white-adolescents-living-in-a-year-round-sunny-climate">Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentrations Are Correlated With Cardiometabolic Risk Among American Black and White Adolescents Living in a Year-Round Sunny Climate.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care. 2012 Mar 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parikh S, Guo DH, Pollock NK, Petty K, Bhagatwala J, Gutin B, Houk C, Zhu H, Dong Y.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Internal Medicine, Department of Medicine, Georgia Health Sciences University, Augusta, Georgia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: Low vitamin D status is common among healthy black and white adolescents residing at southern U.S. latitudes with a year-round sunny climate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Congestive heart failure in infants virtually cured by 1000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/congestive-heart-failure-in-infants-virtually-cured-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/congestive-heart-failure-in-infants-virtually-cured-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="highlights-of-the-paper-from-vitamin-d-councilhttpblogvitamindcouncilorg20120228infant-heart-failure-and-vitamin-d-supplementation20">Highlights of the paper from &lt;a href="http://blog.vitamindcouncil.org/2012/02/28/infant-heart-failure-and-vitamin-d-supplementation/%20">Vitamin D Council&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="which-is-behind-a-paywall">which is behind a paywall&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>80 infants: 40 got 1000 IU of vitamin D daily, 40 got no vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>% of blood normally emptied from heart &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">55-60&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>% of blood emptied by infants with poor function &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">30%&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> at beginning of study&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>% of blood emptied by vitamin D infants at the end of the vitamin D arm of the RCT &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">52%&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> (virtually normal)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D associated with obesity-related diseases for ethnic minorities</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-obesity-related-diseases-for-ethnic-minorities.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-obesity-related-diseases-for-ethnic-minorities.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-obesity-and-obesity-related-chronic-disease-among-ethnic-minorities-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D, obesity, and obesity-related chronic disease among ethnic minorities: a systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrition. 2011 Sep;27(9):868-79. Epub 2011 Jun 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renzaho AM, Halliday JA, Nowson C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WHO Collaborating Centre for Obesity Prevention, Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria, Australia. &lt;a href="mailto:andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au">andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="for-ethnic-minorities-this-study-has-found-that-span-stylecolor00flow-vitamin-d-diabetes-etcspan">For ethnic minorities this study has found that &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">low vitamin D==&amp;gt; diabetes etc&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="rather-than-the-conventional-hypothesis-span-stylecolor00flow-vitamin-d--obesity--diabetes-etcspan">rather than the conventional hypothesis: &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">low vitamin D ==&amp;gt; obesity ==&amp;gt; diabetes etc&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To assess the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) status and obesity, cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), the metabolic syndrome, and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in ethnic minorities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chance of death after heart failure reduced by 1000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chance-of-death-after-heart-failure-reduced-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chance-of-death-after-heart-failure-reduced-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-a-predictor-of-reduced-survival-in-patients-with-heart-failure-vitamin-d-supplementation-improves-outcome">Vitamin D deficiency is a predictor of reduced survival in patients with heart failure; vitamin D supplementation improves outcome.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Eur J Heart Fail. 2012 Feb 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gotsman I, Shauer A, Zwas DR, Hellman Y, Keren A, Lotan C, Admon D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heart Institute, Hadassah University Hospital, POB 12000, Jerusalem, Israel IL-91120.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIMS: Vitamin D deficiency is a highly prevalent, global phenomenon. The prevalence in heart failure (HF) patients and its effect on outcome are less clear. We evaluated vitamin D levels and vitamin D supplementation in patients with HF and its effect on mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency might cause diabetes and cardiovascular diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-might-cause-diabetes-and-cardiovascular-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-might-cause-diabetes-and-cardiovascular-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="can-vitamin-d-deficiency-cause-diabetes-and-cardiovascular-diseases">Can vitamin D deficiency cause diabetes and cardiovascular diseases?&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="present-evidence-and-future-perspectives">Present evidence and future perspectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>G. Muscogiuria, &lt;a href="mailto:giovanna.muscogiuri@edu.rm.unicatt.it">giovanna.muscogiuri@edu.rm.unicatt.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G.P. Soricea,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R. Ajjanb,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>T. Mezzaa,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. Pilzc,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. Priolettaa,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R. Scraggd,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S.L. Volpee,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M.D. Withamf,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. Giaccaria&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Endocrinologia e Malattie del Metabolismo, Università Cattolica, Rome, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Division of Cardiovascular and Diabetes Research, University of Leeds, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D accounts for 25 percent of the racial differences in blood pressure</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-accounts-for-25-percent-of-the-racial-differences-in-blood-pressure.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-accounts-for-25-percent-of-the-racial-differences-in-blood-pressure.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Baby aspirin reduces heart problems - Vitamin D much better</title><link>/posts/baby-aspirin-reduces-heart-problems-vitamin-d-much-better.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/baby-aspirin-reduces-heart-problems-vitamin-d-much-better.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="new-york-times--on-baby-aspirin---jan-16-2012httpwellblogsnytimescom20120116daily-aspirin-is-not-for-everyone-study-suggests">&lt;a href="http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/01/16/daily-aspirin-is-not-for-everyone-study-suggests/">New York Times on Baby Aspirin - Jan 16, 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="analysis-from-meta-study-of-100000-people">Analysis from meta-study of 100,000 people&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>10% less likely to have any type of heart event,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>20% less likely to have a nonfatal heart attack.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>30% more likely to have a serious gastrointestinal bleeding event&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how-many-americans-take-a-baby-aspirin-daily">How many Americans take a baby aspirin daily?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>19% of all ages&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>27% of middle-aged&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>50% of &amp;gt;65&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="estimates-of-benefits-and-harms-of-prophylactic-useof-aspirin-in-the-general-populationhttpannoncoxfordjournalsorgcontentearly20140730annoncmdu225fullpdfhtml20-aug-2014">&lt;a href="http://annonc.oxfordjournals.org/content/early/2014/07/30/annonc.mdu225.full.pdf+html%20">Estimates of benefits and harms of prophylactic useof aspirin in the general population&lt;/a> Aug 2014&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>10 years of baby asprin starting at age 55: net reduction in total deaths&lt;br>
But NO change in Heart Attack deaths&lt;br>
Nothing about non-deadly problems due to taking aspirin - such as serious gastrointestinal bleeding&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Does C-Reactive Protein increase modestly with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/does-c-reactive-protein-increase-modestly-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/does-c-reactive-protein-increase-modestly-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="that-was-the-result-computed-by-a-oct-2011-study--1-2--below">That was the result computed by a Oct 2011 study ( &lt;strong>1. 2&lt;/strong> below)&lt;/h3>
&lt;h1 id="reasons-that-the-results-of-the-study-are-not-a-concern-to-anyone">Reasons that the results of the study are not a concern to anyone&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Actual raw data does NOT show C-Reactive Protein increasing with vitamin D (but it does increase when adjusted for obesity)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Even after data manipulation by the study, the increase in C-Reactive Protein at 50 ng of vitamin D is tiny&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>C-Reactive Protein &lt;a href="http://www.clinchem.org/content/43/1/52.full%20">test results have a huge variability&lt;/a> – even with the same patient (see graph below)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>800 IU Vitamin D doesn't prevent heart attack or cancer</title><link>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-doesnt-prevent-heart-attack-or-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-doesnt-prevent-heart-attack-or-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="title-of-this-page-without-800-iu--is-fromreuters-articlehttpwwwreuterscomarticle20111208us-vitamin-d-idustre7b72av2011120820">Title of this page (without 800 IU) is from&lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/12/08/us-vitamin-d-idUSTRE7B72AV20111208%20">Reuters article&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="more-precise-title-for-the-article-would-have-been">More precise title for the article would have been:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="span-stylecolorf00once-again-it-has-been-proven-that-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-not-enough-to-prevent-heart-attacks-or-reduce-cancerspan">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">&amp;ldquo;Once again it has been proven that 800 IU of vitamin D is not enough to prevent heart attacks or reduce cancer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="need-at-least-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-to-start-to-prevent-cancercategoriescancer-or-a-hrefpostsheart-attacks-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1422heart-attacksa">Need at least 2,000 IU of vitamin D to start to PREVENT &lt;a href="/categories/cancer">Cancer&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="/posts/heart-attacks" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1422">heart attacks&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="similar-article-800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart--meta-analysis-aug-2011posts800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart-meta-analysis">Similar article: &lt;a href="/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart-meta-analysis">800 IU Vitamin D does not help heart – meta-analysis Aug 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="the-following-chart-shows-how-much-vitamin-d-has-to-be-in-blood-to-prevent-many-medical-problems">The following chart shows how much vitamin D has to be in blood to prevent many medical problems&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It is virtually impossible for 800 IU to result in a 40 ng vitamin D level in the blood&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and peripheral arterial disease</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-peripheral-arterial-disease.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-peripheral-arterial-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-and-peripheral-arterial-disease-evidence-so-far">Vitamin D status and peripheral arterial disease: evidence so far.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vasc Health Risk Manag. 2011;7:671-5. Epub 2011 Nov 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chua G, Chan Y, Cheng S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Vascular Surgery, Department of Surgery, University of Hong Kong Medical Centre, Queen Mary Hospital, Pokfulam, Hong Kong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D deficiency has recently been implicated as a contributory factor in the development of peripheral arterial disease (PAD).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: A review of the published literature on PAD and vitamin D was undertaken using Medline, PubMed, and Embase, and cross-referenced. All relevant published papers on the subject were reviewed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D helped cardiovascular patients in many ways</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helped-cardiovascular-patients-in-many-ways.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helped-cardiovascular-patients-in-many-ways.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-supplementation-and-relation-to-cardiovascular-health">Vitamin D Deficiency and Supplementation and Relation to Cardiovascular Health&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="summary-by-vitamindwiki">Summary by VitaminDWiki:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>11,000 cardiology patients in Kansas (2004-2009) were allowed to take any amount of vitamin D they wanted&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They were analyzed as being in one of two groups: sufficient and deficient&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those with an average of 40 ng/ml of vitamin D did MUCH better than those with an average of only 17 ng/ml&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2X fewer deaths after 5 years, lower blood pressure, less atrial fibrillation, less diabetes, lower weight, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Striking ethnic health disparity – blacks dying due to lack of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/striking-ethnic-health-disparity-blacks-dying-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/striking-ethnic-health-disparity-blacks-dying-due-to-lack-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-cardiovascular-disease-potential-role-in-health-disparities">Vitamin D and Cardiovascular Disease: Potential Role in Health Disparities&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Health Care for the Poor and Underserved&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 22, Number 4, November 2011, Supplement; E-ISSN: 1548-6869 Print ISSN: 1049-2089; DOI: 10.1353/hpu.2011.0161&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorge N. Artaza, Sandra Contreras, Leah A. Garcia, Rajnish Mehrotra, Gary Gibbons, Ralph Shohet, David Martins, Keith C. Norris&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Johns Hopkins University Press&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular disease (CVD), which includes coronary artery disease and stroke, is the leading cause of mortality in the nation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yup, 2500 IU of vitamin D does not help the heart in the short term</title><link>/posts/yup-2500-iu-of-vitamin-d-does-not-help-the-heart-in-the-short-term.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yup-2500-iu-of-vitamin-d-does-not-help-the-heart-in-the-short-term.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="paper-presented-at-the-american-heart-associationhttpwwwtheheartorgarticle1315347do">&lt;a href="http://www.theheart.org/article/1315347.do">Paper presented at the American Heart Association&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>no evidence of change across multiple surrogate end points, including&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>endothelial function,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>arterial stiffness,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>C-reactive protein (CRP) levels, and&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>blood pressure&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="actually-would-have-been-surprising-if-they-found-any-benefit-with-less-than-3500-iu">Actually would have been surprising if they found any benefit with less than 3,500 IU&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-cardiovascular-and-vitamin-d">Overview Cardiovascular and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>147 Cardiovascular and vitamin D intervention studies (that is, give vitamin D and see what happens) - as of Feb 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More than 800 mg of Calcium increases Cardiovascular events by 85 percent</title><link>/posts/more-than-800-mg-of-calcium-increases-cardiovascular-events-by-85-percent.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-800-mg-of-calcium-increases-cardiovascular-events-by-85-percent.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>CV event 56 percent more likely after vascular surgery if low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cv-event-56-percent-more-likely-after-vascular-surgery-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cv-event-56-percent-more-likely-after-vascular-surgery-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-boosts-postsurgical-cv-events">Low Vitamin D Boosts Postsurgical CV Events&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Volume 9, Issue 10, Page 32 (October 2011) Cardiology News&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Annual Congress of the European Society of Cardiology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MITCHEL L. ZOLER&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Major Finding: During the 30 days following vascular surgery, patients with severe vitamin D deficiency at baseline had a statistically significant, 56% increased rate of cardiovascular events, compared with patients with sufficient plasma levels of vitamin D in a multivariate analysis that controlled for baseline differences in demographics, medical history, and medication.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D relationship with HDL and LDL is uncertain</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-relationship-with-hdl-and-ldl-is-uncertain.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-relationship-with-hdl-and-ldl-is-uncertain.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-metabolic-health-with-special-reference-to-the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-serum-lipids">Vitamin D and metabolic health with special reference to the effect of vitamin D on serum lipids.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Prog Lipid Res. 2011 Oct;50(4):303-12. Epub 2011 May 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorde R, Grimnes G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinology Research Group, Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, and Medical Clinic, University Hospital of North Norway, 9038 Tromsø, Norway; University of Queensland at Princess Alexandra Hospital, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Considering that the vitamin D receptor as well as the 1-?-hydroxylase enzyme that converts 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) to its active form 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D have been found in tissues throughout the body, it is likely that vitamin D is important for more than the calcium balance. Accordingly, low serum levels of 25(OH)D have been associated with mortality, cardiovascular disease, type 2 diabetes, hypertension and obesity. Low serum levels of 25(OH)D have also been associated with an unfavourable lipid profile, which could possible explain the relation with cardiovascular disease and mortality. However, the relation between vitamin D and lipids have so far received little attention and is therefore the main focus of the present review.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is excess calcium harmful to health - 2010</title><link>/posts/is-excess-calcium-harmful-to-health-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-excess-calcium-harmful-to-health-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#1-introduction">1. Introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2-calcium-supplementation-cardiovascular-disease-and-mortality">2. Calcium Supplementation, Cardiovascular Disease and Mortality&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#3-calcium-supplementation-lipids-and-blood-pressure">3. Calcium Supplementation, Lipids and Blood Pressure&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#4-calcium-supplementation-and-vascular-calcification">4. Calcium Supplementation and Vascular Calcification&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#5-calcium-supplementation-and-cerebrovascular-disease-risk">5. Calcium Supplementation and Cerebrovascular Disease Risk&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#6-calcium-supplementation-and-kidney-stones">6. Calcium Supplementation and Kidney Stones&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#7-serum-calcium-and-cardiovascular-disease-risk">7. Serum Calcium and Cardiovascular Disease Risk&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#8-conclusion">8. Conclusion&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Text is extracted from PDF for ease of translation to other languages - tables not included&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="review-is-excess-calcium-harmful-to-health">Review: Is Excess Calcium Harmful to Health?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2010, 2, 505-522; doi:10.3390/nu2050505&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>24X less Calcification of Aorta for PAD with modest level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/24x-less-calcification-of-aorta-for-pad-with-modest-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/24x-less-calcification-of-aorta-for-pad-with-modest-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="aortic-stiffness-and-vitamin-d-are-independent-markers-of-aortic-calcification-in-patients-with-peripheral-arterial-disease-and-in-healthy-subjects">Aortic Stiffness and Vitamin D are Independent Markers of Aortic Calcification in Patients with Peripheral Arterial Disease and in Healthy Subjects&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Vascular and Endovascular Surgery; doi:10.1016/j.ejvs.2011.07.027&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. Zaguraa, b, Corresponding Author Contact Information, E-mail The Corresponding Author, M. Sergb, c, P. Kampusa, b, c, M. Zilmera, b, J. Ehab, c, E. Untd, e, J. Liebergf, g, J.R. Cockcrofth and J. Kalsa, b, f&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Biochemistry, Centre of Excellence for Translational Medicine, University of Tartu, Tartu, Estonia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium can create heart problems - vitamin D neutral</title><link>/posts/calcium-can-create-heart-problems-vitamin-d-neutral.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-can-create-heart-problems-vitamin-d-neutral.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-calcium-and-cardiovascular-mortality-a-perspective-from-a-plenary-lecture-given-at-the-annual-meeting-of-the-american-association-of-clinical-endocrinologists">Vitamin D, Calcium, and Cardiovascular Mortality: A Perspective from a Plenary Lecture given at the Annual Meeting of the American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2011 Aug 19:1-30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Miller PD. &lt;a href="mailto:MillerCCBR@aol.com">MillerCCBR@aol.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ColoradoCenter for Bone Research, University of Colorado Health Sciences Center.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To examine the data showing any associations between the serum levels of 25(OH) vitamin D, calcium intake and cardiovascular mortality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: The articles reviewed from the literature that form the basis of this authors opinion include published articles from 1992-2011 derived from search engines (PubMed; Scopus; MedScape) using search terms-vitamin D, calcium, cardiovascular events, cardiovascular mortality, all-cause mortality, vascular calcification, chronic-kidney disease, renal stones, hypercalciuria. Because these articles were not weighted (graded) on the level of evidence, this review reflects my own perspective on the data and how it should be applied in clinical management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>800 IU Vitamin D does not help heart – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-cardiovascular-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D and Cardiovascular Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mohamed B. Elamin, Nisrin O. Abu Elnour, Khalid B. Elamin, Mitra M. Fatourechi, Aziz A. Alkatib, Jaime P. Almandoz, Hau Liu, Melanie A. Lane, Rebecca J. Mullan, Ahmad Hazem, Patricia J. Erwin, Donald D. Hensrud, Mohammad Hassan Murad &lt;a href="mailto:murad.mohammad@mayo.edu">murad.mohammad@mayo.edu&lt;/a>. , Victor M. Montori&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Knowledge and Evaluation Research Unit (M.B.E., N.O.A.E., M.M.F., A.A.A., M.A.L., R.J.M., A.H., P.J.E., M.H.M., V.M.M.), Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota 55905;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular disease may be reduced by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-may-be-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-may-be-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-cardiovascular-disease-and-mortality">Vitamin D, cardiovascular disease and mortality.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2011 Jun 17. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2265.2011.04147.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2265.2011.04147.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pilz S, Tomaschitz A, März W, Drechsler C, Ritz E, Zittermann A, Cavalier E, Pieber TR, Lappe JM, Grant WB, Holick MF, Dekker JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics and EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, The Netherlands Clinical Institute of Medical and Chemical Laboratory Diagnostics, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria Mannheim Institute of Public Health, Ruperto Carola University Heidelberg, Medical Faculty Mannheim, Mannheim, Germany Synlab Center of Laboratory Diagnostics, Heidelberg, Germany Department of Medicine, Division of Nephrology, University of Würzburg, Würzburg, Germany Department of Nephrology, University of Heidelberg, Heidelberg, Germany Clinic for Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery, Heart Centre North Rhine-Westphalia, Ruhr University Bochum, Bad Oeynhausen, Germany Department of Clinical Chemistry, University of Liege, CHU Sart-Tilman, Liege, Belgium Osteoporosis Research Center, Creighton University Medical Center, Omaha, Nebraska, USA Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, San Francisco, California, USA Department of Medicine, Section of Endocrinology, Nutrition, and Diabetes, Vitamin D, Skin, and Bone Research Laboratory, Boston University Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Statin pain eliminated by 7100 IU vitamin D (50000 IU weekly)</title><link>/posts/statin-pain-eliminated-by-7100-iu-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/statin-pain-eliminated-by-7100-iu-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-myositis-myalgia-and-reversible-statin-intolerance">Vitamin D deficiency, myositis-myalgia, and reversible statin intolerance.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Curr Med Res Opin. 2011 Jul 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glueck CJ, Budhani SB, Masineni SS, Abuchaibe C, Khan N, Wang P, Goldenberg N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cholesterol Center, Jewish Hospital of Cincinnati , Cincinnati, OH , USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract Objective: In 150 hypercholesterolemic patients, unable to tolerate ?1 statin because of myositis-myalgia, selected by low (&amp;lt;32?ng/ml) serum 25 (OH) vitamin D, we prospectively assessed whether vitamin D supplementation with resolution of vitamin D deficiency would result in statin tolerance, free of myositis-myalgia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atherosclerosis associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/atherosclerosis-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atherosclerosis-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-subclinical-carotid-atherosclerosis-the-northern-manhattan-study">Vitamin D Deficiency Is Associated With Subclinical Carotid Atherosclerosis: The Northern Manhattan Study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Stroke. 2011 Jun 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carrelli AL, Walker MD, Lowe H, McMahon DJ, Rundek T, Sacco RL, Silverberg SJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, College of Physicians and Surgeons, Columbia University, New York, NY; and the Department of Neurology, University of Miami Miller School of Medicine, Miami, FL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this study was to assess the association of vitamin D deficiency and indices of mineral metabolism with subclinical carotid markers that predict cardiovascular events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Arterial stiffness reduced by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/arterial-stiffness-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/arterial-stiffness-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/arterial-stiffness-reduced-by-omega-3-vitamin-d-vitamin-k2-magnesium-etc" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Arterial stiffness reduced by Omega-3, Vitamin D, Vitamin K2, Magnesium, etc.">Arterial stiffness reduced by Omega-3, Vitamin D, Vitamin K2, Magnesium, etc.&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#arterial-stiffness-reduced-by-monthly-120000-iu-vitamin-d-overweight-african-americans--rct-dec-2017">Arterial stiffness reduced by monthly 120,000 IU Vitamin D (overweight African-Americans) – RCT Dec 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#less-arterial-stiffness-if-take-enough-vitamin-d-and-calcium--sept-2014">Less arterial stiffness if take enough Vitamin D and Calcium – Sept 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#arterial-stiffness-reduced-with-vitamin-d-intervention--june-2011">Arterial stiffness reduced with vitamin D intervention – June 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#aortic-stiffness-9-for-20-ng-vitamin-d--vs-77-for-highest-level-of-vitamin-d---oct-2011">Aortic stiffness 9 for &amp;lt;20 ng vitamin D vs 7.7 for highest level of vitamin D - Oct 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="arterial-stiffness-reduced-by-monthly-120000-iu-vitamin-d-overweight-african-americans--rct-dec-2017">Arterial stiffness reduced by monthly 120,000 IU Vitamin D (overweight African-Americans) – RCT Dec 2017&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dose responses of vitamin D3 supplementation on arterial stiffness in overweight African Americans with vitamin D deficiency: A placebo controlled randomized trial.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB increasing vitamin D to 34 ng did not lower blood pressure</title><link>/posts/uvb-increasing-vitamin-d-to-34-ng-did-not-lower-blood-pressure.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-increasing-vitamin-d-to-34-ng-did-not-lower-blood-pressure.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="no-effect-of-ultraviolet-radiation-on-blood-pressure-and-other-cardiovascular-risk-factors">No effect of ultraviolet radiation on blood pressure and other cardiovascular risk factors.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Hypertens. 2011 Jun 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scragg R, Wishart J, Stewart A, Ofanoa M, Kerse N, Dyall L, Lawes CM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>aSchool of Population Health, University of Auckland bEpsom, Auckland, New Zealand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent epidemiological studies have reported inverse associations between vitamin D status and blood pressure. The study aim is to determine if exposure to ultraviolet B radiation, which synthesizes vitamin D, lowers blood pressure, compared with ultraviolet A radiation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Studies linked low vitamin D and dark skin to Obesity, Diabetes, and heart</title><link>/posts/studies-linked-low-vitamin-d-and-dark-skin-to-obesity-diabetes-and-heart.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/studies-linked-low-vitamin-d-and-dark-skin-to-obesity-diabetes-and-heart.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-obesity-and-obesity-related-chronic-disease-among-ethnic-minorities-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D, obesity, and obesity-related chronic disease among ethnic minorities: A systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrition. 2011 Jun 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renzaho AM, Halliday JA, Nowson C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WHO Collaborating Centre for Obesity Prevention, Deakin University, Burwood , Victoria, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To assess the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) status and obesity, cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), the metabolic syndrome, and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in ethnic minorities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Databases searched were CINHAL with full text, Global Health, MEDLINE with full text, and PsycINFO from 1980 through 2010 (February). Studies were included if they 1) targeted immigrants from low- to high-income countries or ethnic minorities, 2) focused primarily on 25(OH)D and its relation to obesity, T2DM, and/or CVDs, and 3) were published in peer-reviewed journals. The influences of key confounders such as age, gender, and ethnicity on any observed relations were also assessed. Due to the heterogeneity of study characteristics, only a narrative synthesis was undertaken.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increasing vitamin D levels will probably reduce CVD and mortality</title><link>/posts/increasing-vitamin-d-levels-will-probably-reduce-cvd-and-mortality.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increasing-vitamin-d-levels-will-probably-reduce-cvd-and-mortality.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-cardiovascular-disease-and-mortality">Vitamin D, cardiovascular disease and mortality.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2011 Jun 17. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2265.2011.04147.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2265.2011.04147.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pilz S, Tomaschitz A, März W, Drechsler C, Ritz E, Zittermann A, Cavalier E, Pieber TR, Lappe JM, Grant WB, Holick MF, Dekker JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics and EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, The Netherlands Clinical Institute of Medical and Chemical Laboratory Diagnostics, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria Mannheim Institute of Public Health, Ruperto Carola University Heidelberg, Medical Faculty Mannheim, Mannheim, Germany Synlab Center of Laboratory Diagnostics, Heidelberg, Germany Department of Medicine, Division of Nephrology, University of Würzburg, Würzburg, Germany Department of Nephrology, University of Heidelberg, Heidelberg, Germany Clinic for Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery, Heart Centre North Rhine-Westphalia, Ruhr University Bochum, Bad Oeynhausen, Germany Department of Clinical Chemistry, University of Liege, CHU Sart-Tilman, Liege, Belgium&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Patent for patients of Chronic Heart Failure includes vitamin D</title><link>/posts/patent-for-patients-of-chronic-heart-failure-includes-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/patent-for-patients-of-chronic-heart-failure-includes-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>World Patent Office June 9 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Awarded to NEPHROCEUTICALS, LLC &lt;a href="US/US">US/US&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/detail.jsf?docId=WO2011068920&amp;amp;recNum=34&amp;amp;maxRec=12428&amp;amp;office=&amp;amp;prevFilter=&amp;amp;sortOption=Pub+Date+Desc&amp;amp;queryString=ALL%3A%28%22vitamin+d%22%29&amp;amp;tab=PCT+Biblio%20">WO2011068920)&lt;/a> NUTRITIONAL SUPPLEMENT FOR PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC HEART FAILURE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any amount of Vitamin D: 400 – 10,000 IU&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In combination with many other ingredients&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-cardiovascular-and-vitamin-d">Overview Cardiovascular and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>There are many indications that vitamin D can both PREVENT and TREAT many cardiovascular problems&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=13&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">All items in Cardiovascular and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/who-said-vitamin-d-could-not-be-patented" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 972">Who said vitamin D could not be patented&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More than 600 IU of vitamin D reduced male CVD risk by 16 percent</title><link>/posts/more-than-600-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-male-cvd-risk-by-16-percent.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-600-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-male-cvd-risk-by-16-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-intake-and-risk-of-cardiovascular-disease-in-us-men-and-women-123">Vitamin D intake and risk of cardiovascular disease in US men and women 1,2,3&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Qi Sun, &lt;a href="mailto:qisun@hsph.harvard.edu">qisun@hsph.harvard.edu&lt;/a>, Ling Shi, Eric B Rimm, Edward L Giovannucci, Frank B Hu, JoAnn E Manson, and Kathryn M Rexrode&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Departments of Nutrition (QS, EBR, ELG, and FBH) and Epidemiology (EBR, ELG, FBH, and JEM), Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, MA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the College of Nursing and Health Sciences, University of Massachusetts–Boston, Boston, MA (LS); the Channing Laboratory (QS, EBR, ELG, FBH, and JEM) and&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Calcium – Vitamin D - Cardiovascular Disease</title><link>/posts/review-of-calcium-vitamin-d-cardiovascular-disease.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-calcium-vitamin-d-cardiovascular-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="calcium-vitamin-d-and-cardiovascular-disease--review">Calcium, Vitamin D and Cardiovascular Disease – Review&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Kidney and Blood Pressure Research, Vol. 34, No. 6, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Idris Guessousa, b, Murielle Bochud b, Olivier Bonny c, Michel Burnier c&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Unit of Population Epidemiology, Division of Primary Care Medicine, Department of Community Medicine, Primary Care and Emergency Medicine, Geneva University Hospitals, Geneva,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Community Prevention Unit, University Institute of Social and Preventive Medicine (IUMSP),&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Department of Medicine, Service of Nephrology, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois (CHUV), Lausanne, Switzerland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monkeys each got 1000 IU daily - but vitamin D in blood varied with HDL</title><link>/posts/monkeys-each-got-1000-iu-daily-but-vitamin-d-in-blood-varied-with-hdl.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/monkeys-each-got-1000-iu-daily-but-vitamin-d-in-blood-varied-with-hdl.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="identification-of-a-mechanism-for-increased-cardiovascular-risk-among-individuals-with-low-vitamin-d-concentrations">Identification of a mechanism for increased cardiovascular risk among individuals with low vitamin D concentrations.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Menopause. 2011 May 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schnatz PF, Nudy M, O&amp;rsquo;Sullivan DM, Ethun K, Appt SE, Clarkson TB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Departments of 1 ObGyn and 2 Internal Medicine, The Reading Hospital and Medical Center, Reading, PA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of 3 ObGyn and 4 Internal Medicine, Jefferson Medical College of Thomas Jefferson University, Philadelphia, PA; and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>5 Department of Pathology/Comparative Medicine, Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, NC.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of vitamin D associated with many cardiovascular problems</title><link>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-many-cardiovascular-problems.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-many-cardiovascular-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-congestive-heart-failure-mechanisms-manifestations-and-management">Vitamin D Deficiency in Patients with Congestive Heart Failure: Mechanisms, Manifestations, and Management&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Patel, Ronak BS; Rizvi, Ali A. MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Southern Medical Journal:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>May 2011 - Volume 104 - Issue 5 - pp 325-330&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/SMJ.0b013e318213cf6b">doi: 10.1097/SMJ.0b013e318213cf6b&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent research suggests that vitamin D may play a role in cardiovascular (CV) health. Although its exact role is still debated and is a matter of controversy,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>vitamin D deficiency has been linked to increased prevalence of CV risk factors and events. Factors that predispose persons with congestive heart failure (CHF) to hypovitaminosis D include nutritional deficiency, decreased skin production, reduced intestinal absorption, and hepatorenal disease. It is possible that low vitamin D can in turn aggravate CHF.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart patients 10 percent more likely to die for every 4 ng less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/heart-patients-10-percent-more-likely-to-die-for-every-4-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-patients-10-percent-more-likely-to-die-for-every-4-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-and-outcomes-in-heart-failure-patients">Vitamin D status and outcomes in heart failure patients.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#219-studies-cited-this-one-as-of-oct-2022">219 studies cited this one as of Oct 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-outcomes-in-heart-failure-patients">Vitamin D status and outcomes in heart failure patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Heart Fail. 2011 May 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liu LC, Voors AA, van Veldhuisen DJ, van der Veer E, Belonje AM, Szymanski MK, Silljé HH, van Gilst WH, Jaarsma T, de Boer RA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardiology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Hanzeplein 1, PO Box 30.001, 9700 RB Groningen, The Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart Failure associated with vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/heart-failure-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-failure-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="is-vitamin-d-deficiency-associated-with-heart-failure-a-review-of-current-evidence">Is Vitamin D Deficiency Associated With Heart Failure? A Review of Current Evidence.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Cardiovasc Pharmacol Ther. 2011 Feb 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Agarwal M, Phan A, Willix R Jr, Barber M, Schwarz ER.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cedars Sinai Heart Institute, Cedars Sinai Medical Center, Los Angeles, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An estimated 1 billion people worldwide have deficient or insufficient levels of vitamin D. Even more alarming is the association of vitamin D deficiency with many types of diseases, particularly heart failure (HF). Hypovitaminosis D has been observed to be highly prevalent in the HF community with rates varying from approximately &lt;strong>80% to 95%&lt;/strong> . Higher rates of deficiency have been linked to winter months, in patients with protracted decompensated HF, darker skin pigmentation, and higher New York Heart Association (NYHA) classes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>50000 IU vitamin D2 weekly helped blacks with heart problems</title><link>/posts/50000-iu-vitamin-d2-weekly-helped-blacks-with-heart-problems.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/50000-iu-vitamin-d2-weekly-helped-blacks-with-heart-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="supplemental-vitamin-d-and-calcium-in-the-management-of-african-americans-with-heart-failure-having-hypovitaminosis-d">Supplemental vitamin D and calcium in the management of African Americans with heart failure having hypovitaminosis D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Med Sci. 2011 Feb;341(2):113-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zia AA, Komolafe BO, Moten M, Ahokas RA, McGee JE, William Rosenberg E, Bhattacharya SK, Weber KT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, 38163, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: A dyshomeostasis of macro- and micronutrients, including vitamin D and oxidative stress, are common pathophysiologic features in patients with congestive heart failure (CHF). In African Americans (AA) with CHF, reductions in plasma 25(OH)D are of moderate-to-marked severity (&amp;lt;20 ng/mL) and may be accompanied by ionized hypocalcemia with compensatory increases in serum parathyroid hormone (PTH). The management of hypovitaminosis D in AA with CHF has not been established.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>96 percent of heart failure patients had less than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/96-percent-of-heart-failure-patients-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/96-percent-of-heart-failure-patients-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-acute-myocardial-infarction">Prevalence of Vitamin D Deficiency in Patients With Acute Myocardial Infarction.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Cardiol. 2011 Mar 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee JH, Gadi R, Spertus JA, Tang F, O&amp;rsquo;Keefe JH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mid America Heart and Vascular Institute and University of Missouri-Kansas City, Kansas City, Missouri.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deficiency in 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) is a treatable condition that has been associated with coronary artery disease and many of its risk factors. A practical time to assess for 25(OH)D deficiency, and to initiate treatment, is at the time of an acute myocardial infarction. The prevalence of 25(OH)D deficiency and the characteristics associated with it in patients with acute myocardial infarction are unknown. In this study, 25(OH)D was assessed in 239 subjects enrolled in a 20-hospital prospective myocardial infarction registry. Patients enrolled from June 1 to December 31, 2008, had serum samples sent to a centralized laboratory for analysis using the DiaSorin 25(OH)D assay. Normal 25(OH)D levels are ?30 ng/ml, and patients with levels &amp;lt;30 and &amp;gt;20 ng/ml were classified as insufficient and those with levels ?20 ng/ml as deficient. Vitamin D levels and other baseline characteristics were analyzed with the linear or Mantel-Haenszel trend test.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Vitamin D and Vitamin K: brittle bones and hardened arteries – LEF</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-brittle-bones-and-hardened-arteries-lef.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-brittle-bones-and-hardened-arteries-lef.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Not yet certain that vitamin D reduces cardiovascular and diabetes in blacks</title><link>/posts/not-yet-certain-that-vitamin-d-reduces-cardiovascular-and-diabetes-in-blacks.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/not-yet-certain-that-vitamin-d-reduces-cardiovascular-and-diabetes-in-blacks.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="does-vitamin-d-deficiency-contribute-to-increased-rates-of-cardiovascular-disease-and-type-2-diabetes-in-african-americans">Does vitamin D deficiency contribute to increased rates of cardiovascular disease and type 2 diabetes in African Americans?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Mar 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harris SS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jean Mayer US Department of Agriculture Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging at Tufts University, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>African Americans have higher rates of type 2 diabetes (T2D) and some forms of cardiovascular disease (CVD) than do European Americans. African Americans also have much higher rates of vitamin D deficiency. There is emerging evidence that vitamin D deficiency may be a risk factor for hypertension, T2D, and CVD, but the extent to which racial disparities in disease rates are explained by racial differences in vitamin D status is uncertain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Cardiovascular and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-cardiovascular-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-cardiovascular-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="why-cardio-event-rcts-are-so-difficult-to-design-and-analyze">Why Cardio Event RCTs are so difficult to design and analyze&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Difficulties in Designing Randomised Controlled Trials of Vitamin D Supplementation for Reducing Acute Cardiovascular Events and in the Analysis of Their Outcomes - July 2020&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/cardio-rct-grant.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular benefits of vitamin D - Feb 2014, &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://heart.bmj.com/content/97/9/766.extract">Arrhythmias in chronic kidney disease&lt;/a> 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.lef.org/protocols/heart_circulatory/arrhythmias_01.htm">Arrhythmias&lt;/a> Life Extension date unknown - perhaps 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review is unsure if supplementing vitamin D will decrease heart failure</title><link>/posts/review-is-unsure-if-supplementing-vitamin-d-will-decrease-heart-failure.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-is-unsure-if-supplementing-vitamin-d-will-decrease-heart-failure.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="is-vitamin-d-deficiency-associated-with-heart-failure-a-review-of-current-evidence">Is Vitamin D Deficiency Associated With Heart Failure? A Review of Current Evidence.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Cardiovasc Pharmacol Ther. 2011 Feb 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Agarwal M, Phan A, Willix R Jr, Barber M, Schwarz ER.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cedars Sinai Heart Institute, Cedars Sinai Medical Center, Los Angeles, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An estimated 1 billion people worldwide have deficient or insufficient levels of vitamin D. Even more alarming is the association of vitamin D deficiency with many types of diseases, particularly heart failure (HF). Hypovitaminosis D has been observed to be highly prevalent in the HF community with rates varying from approximately 80% to 95%.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improved blood flow in blacks with just 2000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/improved-blood-flow-in-blacks-with-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/improved-blood-flow-in-blacks-with-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Vitamin D(3) Supplementation for 16 Weeks Improves Flow-Mediated Dilation in Overweight African-American Adults.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am J Hypertens. 2011 Feb 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harris RA, Pedersen-White J, Guo DH, Stallmann-Jorgensen IS, Keeton D, Huang Y, Shah Y, Zhu H, Dong Y.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Georgia Prevention Institute, Department of Pediatrics, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta, Georgia, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background A growing body of evidence has linked vitamin D deficiency to increased risk of cardiovascular disease. Vitamin D deficiency is also more common in African Americans for whom an increased cardiovascular disease risk exists. This study sought to test the hypothesis that 16 weeks of 60,000 IU monthly supplementation of oral vitamin D(3) would improve flow-mediated dilation (FMD) in African Americans, whereas no change would be observed in the placebo group.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium with Vitamin D2 then D3 helps A-A after heart failure</title><link>/posts/calcium-with-vitamin-d2-then-d3-helps-a-a-after-heart-failure.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-with-vitamin-d2-then-d3-helps-a-a-after-heart-failure.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="supplemental-vitamin-d-and-calcium-in-the-management-of-african-americans-with-heart-failure-having-hypovitaminosis-d">Supplemental Vitamin D and Calcium in the Management of African Americans With Heart Failure Having Hypovitaminosis D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Med Sci. 2011 Jan 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zia AA, Komolafe BO, Moten M, Ahokas RA, McGee JE, William Rosenberg E, Bhattacharya SK, Weber KT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Division of Cardiovascular Diseases (aaz, mm, jem, skb, ktw), Department of Medicine, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; Department of Medicine (bok), Graduate Medical Education, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology (raa), University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; Division of Dermatology(ewr), Department of Medicine, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; and Veterans Affairs Medical Center (mm, jem), Memphis, Tennessee.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D helps organ transplant - many studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-organ-transplant-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-organ-transplant-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary-of-many-studies-of-vitamin-d-and-organ-transplantation">Summary of many studies of Vitamin D and organ transplantation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-in-organ-transplantation---2011">Vitamin D in organ transplantation - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#survive-heart-transplant-better-if-have-more-vitamin-d">Survive heart transplant better if have more vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#immune-system-is-often-supressed-so-that-a-new-organ-can-be-accepted-by-the-body">Immune system is often supressed so that a new organ can be accepted by the body&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="summary-of-many-studies-of-vitamin-d-and-organ-transplantation">Summary of many studies of Vitamin D and organ transplantation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>More vitamin D needed especially needed if organ = liver or kidney (low vitamin d ==&amp;gt; poor bones)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium without vitamin D increased heart risk by 30 percent</title><link>/posts/calcium-without-vitamin-d-increased-heart-risk-by-30-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-without-vitamin-d-increased-heart-risk-by-30-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="strong-bones-equals-weak-heart">Strong Bones Equals Weak Heart&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="-abstract-and-link-to-article-is-at-the-bottom-of-this-page">&lt;strong># Abstract and link to article is at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="by-jennifer-gibson-pharmdhttpbrainbloggercom20110102strong-bones-equals-weak-heart">&lt;a href="http://brainblogger.com/2011/01/02/strong-bones-equals-weak-heart/">by Jennifer Gibson, PharmD&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Adequate calcium intake is an important nutritional factor for skeletal health. Calcium (when taken with adequate Vitamin D) prevents bone loss and decreases the risk of fractures and associated morbidity and mortality. Most adults require 1000 mg of calcium daily. (Children and postmenopausal women require slightly more.) For decades, physicians and pharmacists have been advocating calcium supplementation to ensure adequate intake for patients, particularly postmenopausal women, owing to a belief that calcium supplementation offered significant benefits without many adverse consequences. Now, a new meta-analysis in the British Medical Journal (BMJ) claims that calcium supplementation, in fact, leads to an increased risk for cardiovascular events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why we need large-scale heart trials of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/why-we-need-large-scale-heart-trials-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-we-need-large-scale-heart-trials-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-the-heart-why-we-need-large-scale-clinical-trials">Vitamin D and the heart: Why we need large-scale clinical trials&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>JOANN E. MANSON, MD, DrPH, FAHA*&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Author Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Chief, Division of Preventive Medicine; Co-Director, Connors Center for Women’s Health and Gender Biology, Brigham and Women’s Hospital; Professor of Medicine, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA; Principal Investigator, Vitamin D and Omega-3 Trial (VITAL)&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>ADDRESS: JoAnn E. Manson, MD, DrPH, Division of Preventive Medicine, Brigham and Women’s Hospital, Harvard Medical School, 900 Commonwealth Avenue, Boston, MA 02215; e-mail &lt;a href="mailto:jmanson@rics.bwh.harvard.edu">jmanson@rics.bwh.harvard.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Although vitamin D supplementation appears to be a promising intervention for reducing risks of cancer, cardiovascular disease, and other chronic diseases, existing evidence on its benefits and risks is limited and inconclusive. Recruitment is now under way for the Vitamin D and Omega-3 Trial (VITAL), the first large-scale randomized clinical trial of these nutritional agents for the primary prevention of cancer and cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Editorial on Vitamin D deficiency– Current Drug topics</title><link>/posts/editorial-on-vitamin-d-deficiency-current-drug-topics.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/editorial-on-vitamin-d-deficiency-current-drug-topics.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="editorial-hot-topic-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-cardiovascular-and-renal-disease">Editorial: Hot topic: Vitamin D Deficiency in Cardiovascular and Renal Disease:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="new-light-shed-on-an-old-enemy-guest-editor-martin-h-de-borst">New Light Shed on an Old Enemy (Guest Editor: Martin H. de Borst)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Current Drug Targets, Volume 12, Number 1, January 2011 , pp. 1-3(3)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fat-soluble secosteroid hormone vitamin D is best known for its role in bone metabolism. From a historical perspective, the study of vitamin D deficiency has been intimately related to the study of (possible treatment of) rickets. Although diseases characterized by bone deformations have been described in ancient medical writings from the 1st and 2nd centuries, it was Galen who described the classic bone deformities noted in rickets &lt;sup>[1, 2]&lt;/sup>. More clear descriptions originate from the 17th century, reporting rickets to be endemic in England &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. In the early 20th century, observations that artificial UV light or sunlight provides protection against rickets coincided with results suggesting that rickets may be the consequence of a nutritional deficiency &lt;sup>[3, 4]&lt;/sup>. The responsible vitamin was identified by McCollum et al., who stated in their paper in the Journal of Biological Chemistry in 1922: “These experiments clearly demonstrate the existence of a fourth vitamin whose specific property, as far as we can tell at present, is to regulate the metabolism of the bones” &lt;sup>[5]&lt;/sup>. This “fourth vitamin” was named vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of heart failure and vitamin D mechanisms</title><link>/posts/review-of-heart-failure-and-vitamin-d-mechanisms.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-heart-failure-and-vitamin-d-mechanisms.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-biology-in-heart-failure-molecular-mechanisms-and-systematic-review">Vitamin d biology in heart failure: molecular mechanisms and systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Drug Targets. 2011 Jan 1;12(1):29-41.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meems LM, van der Harst P, van Gilst WH, de Boer RA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardiology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, The Netherlands. &lt;a href="mailto:r.a.de.boer@thorax.umcg.nl">r.a.de.boer@thorax.umcg.nl&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has recently been suggested as an important mediator of blood pressure and cardiovascular disease, including heart failure. In patient with heart failure, low vitamin D levels are associated with adverse outcome and correlate with established clinical correlates and biomarkers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D might deal with atherosclerosis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-might-deal-with-atherosclerosis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-might-deal-with-atherosclerosis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-in-atherosclerosis-vascular-disease-and-endothelial-function">Vitamin d in atherosclerosis, vascular disease, and endothelial function.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Drug Targets. 2011 Jan 1;12(1):54-60.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brewer LC, Michos ED, Reis JP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Cardiovascular Sciences, National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, Bethesda, MD, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:reisjp@nhlbi.nih.gov">reisjp@nhlbi.nih.gov&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been linked to an increased risk of hypertension, diabetes, congestive heart failure, peripheral arterial disease, myocardial infarction, stroke, and related mortality, even after adjustment for traditional cardiovascular risk factors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accumulating evidence from experimental, clinical, and epidemiological studies suggests that vitamin D may also be associated with several indices of vascular function, including the development and progression of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Not all statins increase vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/not-all-statins-increase-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/not-all-statins-increase-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-relationship-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-to-statin-myopathy">The Relationship of Vitamin D Deficiency to Statin Myopathy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2010.11.039&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ankur Guptaa and Paul D. Thompson &lt;a href="mailto:pthomps@harthosp.org">pthomps@harthosp.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Division of Cardiology, Harford Hospital, Hartford, CT&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 26 October 2010; revised 24 November 2010; accepted 25 November 2010. Available online 5 December 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective Our goal was to examine the interaction between vitamin D and statins and the possible role of vitamin D deficiency in statin myopathy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background The vitamin D receptor is present in skeletal muscle and vitamin D deficiency can cause myopathy. Statins (3-hydroxy-3-methyl-glutaryl-CoA reductase inhibitors) are generally well tolerated, but have been associated with a spectrum of skeletal muscle complaints, ranging from myalgia and asymptomatic mild elevations of creatine kinase (CK) to rhabdomyolysis. There has been recent interest in the possible interaction between statin myopathy and vitamin D deficiency. We performed a systematic medical literature review to examine this possible relationship.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bypass surgery and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/bypass-surgery-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bypass-surgery-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="acute-fluid-shifts-influence-the-assessment-of-serum-vitamin-d-status-in-critically-ill-patients">Acute fluid shifts influence the assessment of serum vitamin D status in critically ill patients&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Anand Krishnan email, Judith Ochola email, Julie Mundy email, Mark Jones email, Peter Kruger email, Emma Duncan email and Bala Venkatesh email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Critical Care 2010, 14:R216doi:10.1186/cc9341, 26 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent reports have highlighted the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency and suggested an association with excess mortality in critically ill patients. Serum vitamin D concentrations in these studies were measured following resuscitation. It is unclear whether aggressive fluid resuscitation independently influences serum vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart pumped more blood after heart failure if more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/heart-pumped-more-blood-after-heart-failure-if-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-pumped-more-blood-after-heart-failure-if-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-is-associated-with-functional-capacity-in-older-adults-with-heart-failure">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration is associated with functional capacity in older adults with heart failure.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am Heart J. 2010 Nov;160(5):893-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boxer RS, Kenny AM, Cheruvu VK, Vest M, Fiutem JJ, Piña II.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D is a fat-soluble hormone necessary for calcium homeostasis. Recently, studies have demonstrated that vitamin D may be important to the health of the cardiovascular system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: Adults ?50 years of age with heart failure were recruited for assessment of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) concentrations. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing was used to assess functional capacity. Proximal muscle strength was evaluated with a Biodex leg press (Biodex, Shirley, NY), and health status was assessed with the Kansas City Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire. Univariate associations between physical performance and health status measures and 25OHD followed by a linear regression model were used to study associations, adjusting for other potential explanatory variables.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Youthful heart attacks associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/youthful-heart-attacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/youthful-heart-attacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="markers-of-bone-metabolism-in-premature-myocardial-infarction--40-years-of-age">Markers of Bone Metabolism in premature myocardial infarction (? 40 years of age).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Bone. 2010 Nov 12&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goliasch G, Blessberger H, Azar D, Heinze G, Wojta J, Bieglmayer C, Wagner O, Schillinger M, Huber K, Maurer G, Haas M, Wiesbauer F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardiology, Vienna General Hospital/Medical University of Vienna and 6Wilhelminen Hospital Vienna.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Acute myocardial infarction (AMI) at young age is a rare disease with a poor prognosis. Bone metabolism parameters such as 1,25 (OH)(2) vitamin D(3), 25 (OH) vitamin D(3) and osteocalcin have been recently implicated in the development of coronary heart disease (CHD). We evaluated the role of these serum markers in a study population of very young AMI survivors (? 40 years).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>11 ng less vitamin D increases hypertension probability by 14 percent</title><link>/posts/11-ng-less-vitamin-d-increases-hypertension-probability-by-14-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/11-ng-less-vitamin-d-increases-hypertension-probability-by-14-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="lifestyles-and-cardiovascular-risk-factors">Lifestyles and Cardiovascular Risk Factors&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Core 2. Epidemiology and Prevention of CV Disease: Physiology, Pharmacology and Lifestyle&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract 21058: Association Between Serum Vitamin D and Prehypertension&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Circulation. 2010;122:A21058&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 122, Issue 21 Supplement; November 23, 2010 / Abstracts From Scientific Sessions 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charumathi Sabanayagam; Anoop Shankar&lt;/p>
&lt;p>West virginia Univ, Morgantown, WV&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Low serum levels of vitamin D increases the risk of diabetes and cardiovascular disease. It has also been suggested that serum vitamin D levels are associated with blood pressure. Prehypertension is a preclinical stage where prevention efforts have been shown to be effective in delaying or preventing the onset of hypertension.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>