<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cardiovascular on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cardiovascular.html</link><description>Recent content in Cardiovascular on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cardiovascular/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>More than 800 mg of Calcium increases Cardiovascular events by 85 percent</title><link>/posts/more-than-800-mg-of-calcium-increases-cardiovascular-events-by-85-percent.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-800-mg-of-calcium-increases-cardiovascular-events-by-85-percent.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>CV event 56 percent more likely after vascular surgery if low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cv-event-56-percent-more-likely-after-vascular-surgery-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cv-event-56-percent-more-likely-after-vascular-surgery-if-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="low-vitamin-d-boosts-postsurgical-cv-events">Low Vitamin D Boosts Postsurgical CV Events&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Volume 9, Issue 10, Page 32 (October 2011) Cardiology News&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Annual Congress of the European Society of Cardiology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MITCHEL L. ZOLER&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Major Finding: During the 30 days following vascular surgery, patients with severe vitamin D deficiency at baseline had a statistically significant, 56% increased rate of cardiovascular events, compared with patients with sufficient plasma levels of vitamin D in a multivariate analysis that controlled for baseline differences in demographics, medical history, and medication.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D relationship with HDL and LDL is uncertain</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-relationship-with-hdl-and-ldl-is-uncertain.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-relationship-with-hdl-and-ldl-is-uncertain.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-metabolic-health-with-special-reference-to-the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-serum-lipids">Vitamin D and metabolic health with special reference to the effect of vitamin D on serum lipids.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Prog Lipid Res. 2011 Oct;50(4):303-12. Epub 2011 May 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorde R, Grimnes G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinology Research Group, Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, and Medical Clinic, University Hospital of North Norway, 9038 Tromsø, Norway; University of Queensland at Princess Alexandra Hospital, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Considering that the vitamin D receptor as well as the 1-?-hydroxylase enzyme that converts 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) to its active form 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D have been found in tissues throughout the body, it is likely that vitamin D is important for more than the calcium balance. Accordingly, low serum levels of 25(OH)D have been associated with mortality, cardiovascular disease, type 2 diabetes, hypertension and obesity. Low serum levels of 25(OH)D have also been associated with an unfavourable lipid profile, which could possible explain the relation with cardiovascular disease and mortality. However, the relation between vitamin D and lipids have so far received little attention and is therefore the main focus of the present review.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is excess calcium harmful to health - 2010</title><link>/posts/is-excess-calcium-harmful-to-health-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/is-excess-calcium-harmful-to-health-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#1-introduction">1. Introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2-calcium-supplementation-cardiovascular-disease-and-mortality">2. Calcium Supplementation, Cardiovascular Disease and Mortality&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#3-calcium-supplementation-lipids-and-blood-pressure">3. Calcium Supplementation, Lipids and Blood Pressure&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#4-calcium-supplementation-and-vascular-calcification">4. Calcium Supplementation and Vascular Calcification&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#5-calcium-supplementation-and-cerebrovascular-disease-risk">5. Calcium Supplementation and Cerebrovascular Disease Risk&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#6-calcium-supplementation-and-kidney-stones">6. Calcium Supplementation and Kidney Stones&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#7-serum-calcium-and-cardiovascular-disease-risk">7. Serum Calcium and Cardiovascular Disease Risk&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#8-conclusion">8. Conclusion&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Text is extracted from PDF for ease of translation to other languages - tables not included&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="review-is-excess-calcium-harmful-to-health">Review: Is Excess Calcium Harmful to Health?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2010, 2, 505-522; doi:10.3390/nu2050505&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>24X less Calcification of Aorta for PAD with modest level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/24x-less-calcification-of-aorta-for-pad-with-modest-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/24x-less-calcification-of-aorta-for-pad-with-modest-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="aortic-stiffness-and-vitamin-d-are-independent-markers-of-aortic-calcification-in-patients-with-peripheral-arterial-disease-and-in-healthy-subjects">Aortic Stiffness and Vitamin D are Independent Markers of Aortic Calcification in Patients with Peripheral Arterial Disease and in Healthy Subjects&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Vascular and Endovascular Surgery; doi:10.1016/j.ejvs.2011.07.027&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. Zaguraa, b, Corresponding Author Contact Information, E-mail The Corresponding Author, M. Sergb, c, P. Kampusa, b, c, M. Zilmera, b, J. Ehab, c, E. Untd, e, J. Liebergf, g, J.R. Cockcrofth and J. Kalsa, b, f&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Biochemistry, Centre of Excellence for Translational Medicine, University of Tartu, Tartu, Estonia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium can create heart problems - vitamin D neutral</title><link>/posts/calcium-can-create-heart-problems-vitamin-d-neutral.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-can-create-heart-problems-vitamin-d-neutral.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-calcium-and-cardiovascular-mortality-a-perspective-from-a-plenary-lecture-given-at-the-annual-meeting-of-the-american-association-of-clinical-endocrinologists">Vitamin D, Calcium, and Cardiovascular Mortality: A Perspective from a Plenary Lecture given at the Annual Meeting of the American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2011 Aug 19:1-30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Miller PD. &lt;a href="mailto:MillerCCBR@aol.com">MillerCCBR@aol.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ColoradoCenter for Bone Research, University of Colorado Health Sciences Center.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To examine the data showing any associations between the serum levels of 25(OH) vitamin D, calcium intake and cardiovascular mortality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: The articles reviewed from the literature that form the basis of this authors opinion include published articles from 1992-2011 derived from search engines (PubMed; Scopus; MedScape) using search terms-vitamin D, calcium, cardiovascular events, cardiovascular mortality, all-cause mortality, vascular calcification, chronic-kidney disease, renal stones, hypercalciuria. Because these articles were not weighted (graded) on the level of evidence, this review reflects my own perspective on the data and how it should be applied in clinical management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>800 IU Vitamin D does not help heart – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-vitamin-d-does-not-help-heart-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-cardiovascular-outcomes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D and Cardiovascular Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mohamed B. Elamin, Nisrin O. Abu Elnour, Khalid B. Elamin, Mitra M. Fatourechi, Aziz A. Alkatib, Jaime P. Almandoz, Hau Liu, Melanie A. Lane, Rebecca J. Mullan, Ahmad Hazem, Patricia J. Erwin, Donald D. Hensrud, Mohammad Hassan Murad &lt;a href="mailto:murad.mohammad@mayo.edu">murad.mohammad@mayo.edu&lt;/a>. , Victor M. Montori&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Knowledge and Evaluation Research Unit (M.B.E., N.O.A.E., M.M.F., A.A.A., M.A.L., R.J.M., A.H., P.J.E., M.H.M., V.M.M.), Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota 55905;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular disease may be reduced by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-may-be-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cardiovascular-disease-may-be-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-cardiovascular-disease-and-mortality">Vitamin D, cardiovascular disease and mortality.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2011 Jun 17. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2265.2011.04147.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2265.2011.04147.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pilz S, Tomaschitz A, März W, Drechsler C, Ritz E, Zittermann A, Cavalier E, Pieber TR, Lappe JM, Grant WB, Holick MF, Dekker JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics and EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, The Netherlands Clinical Institute of Medical and Chemical Laboratory Diagnostics, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria Mannheim Institute of Public Health, Ruperto Carola University Heidelberg, Medical Faculty Mannheim, Mannheim, Germany Synlab Center of Laboratory Diagnostics, Heidelberg, Germany Department of Medicine, Division of Nephrology, University of Würzburg, Würzburg, Germany Department of Nephrology, University of Heidelberg, Heidelberg, Germany Clinic for Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery, Heart Centre North Rhine-Westphalia, Ruhr University Bochum, Bad Oeynhausen, Germany Department of Clinical Chemistry, University of Liege, CHU Sart-Tilman, Liege, Belgium Osteoporosis Research Center, Creighton University Medical Center, Omaha, Nebraska, USA Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, San Francisco, California, USA Department of Medicine, Section of Endocrinology, Nutrition, and Diabetes, Vitamin D, Skin, and Bone Research Laboratory, Boston University Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Statin pain eliminated by 7100 IU vitamin D (50000 IU weekly)</title><link>/posts/statin-pain-eliminated-by-7100-iu-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/statin-pain-eliminated-by-7100-iu-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-myositis-myalgia-and-reversible-statin-intolerance">Vitamin D deficiency, myositis-myalgia, and reversible statin intolerance.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Curr Med Res Opin. 2011 Jul 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glueck CJ, Budhani SB, Masineni SS, Abuchaibe C, Khan N, Wang P, Goldenberg N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cholesterol Center, Jewish Hospital of Cincinnati , Cincinnati, OH , USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract Objective: In 150 hypercholesterolemic patients, unable to tolerate ?1 statin because of myositis-myalgia, selected by low (&amp;lt;32?ng/ml) serum 25 (OH) vitamin D, we prospectively assessed whether vitamin D supplementation with resolution of vitamin D deficiency would result in statin tolerance, free of myositis-myalgia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atherosclerosis associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/atherosclerosis-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atherosclerosis-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-subclinical-carotid-atherosclerosis-the-northern-manhattan-study">Vitamin D Deficiency Is Associated With Subclinical Carotid Atherosclerosis: The Northern Manhattan Study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Stroke. 2011 Jun 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carrelli AL, Walker MD, Lowe H, McMahon DJ, Rundek T, Sacco RL, Silverberg SJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, College of Physicians and Surgeons, Columbia University, New York, NY; and the Department of Neurology, University of Miami Miller School of Medicine, Miami, FL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this study was to assess the association of vitamin D deficiency and indices of mineral metabolism with subclinical carotid markers that predict cardiovascular events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Arterial stiffness reduced by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/arterial-stiffness-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/arterial-stiffness-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/arterial-stiffness-reduced-by-omega-3-vitamin-d-vitamin-k2-magnesium-etc" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Arterial stiffness reduced by Omega-3, Vitamin D, Vitamin K2, Magnesium, etc.">Arterial stiffness reduced by Omega-3, Vitamin D, Vitamin K2, Magnesium, etc.&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#arterial-stiffness-reduced-by-monthly-120000-iu-vitamin-d-overweight-african-americans--rct-dec-2017">Arterial stiffness reduced by monthly 120,000 IU Vitamin D (overweight African-Americans) – RCT Dec 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#less-arterial-stiffness-if-take-enough-vitamin-d-and-calcium--sept-2014">Less arterial stiffness if take enough Vitamin D and Calcium – Sept 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#arterial-stiffness-reduced-with-vitamin-d-intervention--june-2011">Arterial stiffness reduced with vitamin D intervention – June 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#aortic-stiffness-9-for-20-ng-vitamin-d--vs-77-for-highest-level-of-vitamin-d---oct-2011">Aortic stiffness 9 for &amp;lt;20 ng vitamin D vs 7.7 for highest level of vitamin D - Oct 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="arterial-stiffness-reduced-by-monthly-120000-iu-vitamin-d-overweight-african-americans--rct-dec-2017">Arterial stiffness reduced by monthly 120,000 IU Vitamin D (overweight African-Americans) – RCT Dec 2017&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dose responses of vitamin D3 supplementation on arterial stiffness in overweight African Americans with vitamin D deficiency: A placebo controlled randomized trial.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB increasing vitamin D to 34 ng did not lower blood pressure</title><link>/posts/uvb-increasing-vitamin-d-to-34-ng-did-not-lower-blood-pressure.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-increasing-vitamin-d-to-34-ng-did-not-lower-blood-pressure.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="no-effect-of-ultraviolet-radiation-on-blood-pressure-and-other-cardiovascular-risk-factors">No effect of ultraviolet radiation on blood pressure and other cardiovascular risk factors.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Hypertens. 2011 Jun 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scragg R, Wishart J, Stewart A, Ofanoa M, Kerse N, Dyall L, Lawes CM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>aSchool of Population Health, University of Auckland bEpsom, Auckland, New Zealand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent epidemiological studies have reported inverse associations between vitamin D status and blood pressure. The study aim is to determine if exposure to ultraviolet B radiation, which synthesizes vitamin D, lowers blood pressure, compared with ultraviolet A radiation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Studies linked low vitamin D and dark skin to Obesity, Diabetes, and heart</title><link>/posts/studies-linked-low-vitamin-d-and-dark-skin-to-obesity-diabetes-and-heart.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/studies-linked-low-vitamin-d-and-dark-skin-to-obesity-diabetes-and-heart.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-obesity-and-obesity-related-chronic-disease-among-ethnic-minorities-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D, obesity, and obesity-related chronic disease among ethnic minorities: A systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrition. 2011 Jun 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renzaho AM, Halliday JA, Nowson C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WHO Collaborating Centre for Obesity Prevention, Deakin University, Burwood , Victoria, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To assess the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) status and obesity, cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), the metabolic syndrome, and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in ethnic minorities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Databases searched were CINHAL with full text, Global Health, MEDLINE with full text, and PsycINFO from 1980 through 2010 (February). Studies were included if they 1) targeted immigrants from low- to high-income countries or ethnic minorities, 2) focused primarily on 25(OH)D and its relation to obesity, T2DM, and/or CVDs, and 3) were published in peer-reviewed journals. The influences of key confounders such as age, gender, and ethnicity on any observed relations were also assessed. Due to the heterogeneity of study characteristics, only a narrative synthesis was undertaken.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increasing vitamin D levels will probably reduce CVD and mortality</title><link>/posts/increasing-vitamin-d-levels-will-probably-reduce-cvd-and-mortality.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increasing-vitamin-d-levels-will-probably-reduce-cvd-and-mortality.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-cardiovascular-disease-and-mortality">Vitamin D, cardiovascular disease and mortality.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2011 Jun 17. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2265.2011.04147.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2265.2011.04147.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pilz S, Tomaschitz A, März W, Drechsler C, Ritz E, Zittermann A, Cavalier E, Pieber TR, Lappe JM, Grant WB, Holick MF, Dekker JM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics and EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research, VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam, The Netherlands Clinical Institute of Medical and Chemical Laboratory Diagnostics, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria Mannheim Institute of Public Health, Ruperto Carola University Heidelberg, Medical Faculty Mannheim, Mannheim, Germany Synlab Center of Laboratory Diagnostics, Heidelberg, Germany Department of Medicine, Division of Nephrology, University of Würzburg, Würzburg, Germany Department of Nephrology, University of Heidelberg, Heidelberg, Germany Clinic for Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery, Heart Centre North Rhine-Westphalia, Ruhr University Bochum, Bad Oeynhausen, Germany Department of Clinical Chemistry, University of Liege, CHU Sart-Tilman, Liege, Belgium&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Patent for patients of Chronic Heart Failure includes vitamin D</title><link>/posts/patent-for-patients-of-chronic-heart-failure-includes-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/patent-for-patients-of-chronic-heart-failure-includes-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>World Patent Office June 9 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Awarded to NEPHROCEUTICALS, LLC &lt;a href="US/US">US/US&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/detail.jsf?docId=WO2011068920&amp;amp;recNum=34&amp;amp;maxRec=12428&amp;amp;office=&amp;amp;prevFilter=&amp;amp;sortOption=Pub+Date+Desc&amp;amp;queryString=ALL%3A%28%22vitamin+d%22%29&amp;amp;tab=PCT+Biblio%20">WO2011068920)&lt;/a> NUTRITIONAL SUPPLEMENT FOR PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC HEART FAILURE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any amount of Vitamin D: 400 – 10,000 IU&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In combination with many other ingredients&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-cardiovascular-and-vitamin-d">Overview Cardiovascular and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>There are many indications that vitamin D can both PREVENT and TREAT many cardiovascular problems&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=13&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">All items in Cardiovascular and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/who-said-vitamin-d-could-not-be-patented" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 972">Who said vitamin D could not be patented&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More than 600 IU of vitamin D reduced male CVD risk by 16 percent</title><link>/posts/more-than-600-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-male-cvd-risk-by-16-percent.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-than-600-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-male-cvd-risk-by-16-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-intake-and-risk-of-cardiovascular-disease-in-us-men-and-women-123">Vitamin D intake and risk of cardiovascular disease in US men and women 1,2,3&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Qi Sun, &lt;a href="mailto:qisun@hsph.harvard.edu">qisun@hsph.harvard.edu&lt;/a>, Ling Shi, Eric B Rimm, Edward L Giovannucci, Frank B Hu, JoAnn E Manson, and Kathryn M Rexrode&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Departments of Nutrition (QS, EBR, ELG, and FBH) and Epidemiology (EBR, ELG, FBH, and JEM), Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, MA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the College of Nursing and Health Sciences, University of Massachusetts–Boston, Boston, MA (LS); the Channing Laboratory (QS, EBR, ELG, FBH, and JEM) and&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Calcium – Vitamin D - Cardiovascular Disease</title><link>/posts/review-of-calcium-vitamin-d-cardiovascular-disease.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-calcium-vitamin-d-cardiovascular-disease.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="calcium-vitamin-d-and-cardiovascular-disease--review">Calcium, Vitamin D and Cardiovascular Disease – Review&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Kidney and Blood Pressure Research, Vol. 34, No. 6, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Idris Guessousa, b, Murielle Bochud b, Olivier Bonny c, Michel Burnier c&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Unit of Population Epidemiology, Division of Primary Care Medicine, Department of Community Medicine, Primary Care and Emergency Medicine, Geneva University Hospitals, Geneva,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B Community Prevention Unit, University Institute of Social and Preventive Medicine (IUMSP),&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Department of Medicine, Service of Nephrology, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois (CHUV), Lausanne, Switzerland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monkeys each got 1000 IU daily - but vitamin D in blood varied with HDL</title><link>/posts/monkeys-each-got-1000-iu-daily-but-vitamin-d-in-blood-varied-with-hdl.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/monkeys-each-got-1000-iu-daily-but-vitamin-d-in-blood-varied-with-hdl.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="identification-of-a-mechanism-for-increased-cardiovascular-risk-among-individuals-with-low-vitamin-d-concentrations">Identification of a mechanism for increased cardiovascular risk among individuals with low vitamin D concentrations.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Menopause. 2011 May 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schnatz PF, Nudy M, O&amp;rsquo;Sullivan DM, Ethun K, Appt SE, Clarkson TB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Departments of 1 ObGyn and 2 Internal Medicine, The Reading Hospital and Medical Center, Reading, PA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of 3 ObGyn and 4 Internal Medicine, Jefferson Medical College of Thomas Jefferson University, Philadelphia, PA; and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>5 Department of Pathology/Comparative Medicine, Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, NC.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of vitamin D associated with many cardiovascular problems</title><link>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-many-cardiovascular-problems.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-many-cardiovascular-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-congestive-heart-failure-mechanisms-manifestations-and-management">Vitamin D Deficiency in Patients with Congestive Heart Failure: Mechanisms, Manifestations, and Management&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Patel, Ronak BS; Rizvi, Ali A. MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Southern Medical Journal:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>May 2011 - Volume 104 - Issue 5 - pp 325-330&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/SMJ.0b013e318213cf6b">doi: 10.1097/SMJ.0b013e318213cf6b&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent research suggests that vitamin D may play a role in cardiovascular (CV) health. Although its exact role is still debated and is a matter of controversy,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>vitamin D deficiency has been linked to increased prevalence of CV risk factors and events. Factors that predispose persons with congestive heart failure (CHF) to hypovitaminosis D include nutritional deficiency, decreased skin production, reduced intestinal absorption, and hepatorenal disease. It is possible that low vitamin D can in turn aggravate CHF.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart patients 10 percent more likely to die for every 4 ng less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/heart-patients-10-percent-more-likely-to-die-for-every-4-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-patients-10-percent-more-likely-to-die-for-every-4-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-and-outcomes-in-heart-failure-patients">Vitamin D status and outcomes in heart failure patients.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#219-studies-cited-this-one-as-of-oct-2022">219 studies cited this one as of Oct 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-outcomes-in-heart-failure-patients">Vitamin D status and outcomes in heart failure patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Heart Fail. 2011 May 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liu LC, Voors AA, van Veldhuisen DJ, van der Veer E, Belonje AM, Szymanski MK, Silljé HH, van Gilst WH, Jaarsma T, de Boer RA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardiology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Hanzeplein 1, PO Box 30.001, 9700 RB Groningen, The Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart Failure associated with vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/heart-failure-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-failure-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="is-vitamin-d-deficiency-associated-with-heart-failure-a-review-of-current-evidence">Is Vitamin D Deficiency Associated With Heart Failure? A Review of Current Evidence.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Cardiovasc Pharmacol Ther. 2011 Feb 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Agarwal M, Phan A, Willix R Jr, Barber M, Schwarz ER.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cedars Sinai Heart Institute, Cedars Sinai Medical Center, Los Angeles, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An estimated 1 billion people worldwide have deficient or insufficient levels of vitamin D. Even more alarming is the association of vitamin D deficiency with many types of diseases, particularly heart failure (HF). Hypovitaminosis D has been observed to be highly prevalent in the HF community with rates varying from approximately &lt;strong>80% to 95%&lt;/strong> . Higher rates of deficiency have been linked to winter months, in patients with protracted decompensated HF, darker skin pigmentation, and higher New York Heart Association (NYHA) classes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>50000 IU vitamin D2 weekly helped blacks with heart problems</title><link>/posts/50000-iu-vitamin-d2-weekly-helped-blacks-with-heart-problems.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/50000-iu-vitamin-d2-weekly-helped-blacks-with-heart-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="supplemental-vitamin-d-and-calcium-in-the-management-of-african-americans-with-heart-failure-having-hypovitaminosis-d">Supplemental vitamin D and calcium in the management of African Americans with heart failure having hypovitaminosis D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Med Sci. 2011 Feb;341(2):113-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zia AA, Komolafe BO, Moten M, Ahokas RA, McGee JE, William Rosenberg E, Bhattacharya SK, Weber KT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, 38163, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: A dyshomeostasis of macro- and micronutrients, including vitamin D and oxidative stress, are common pathophysiologic features in patients with congestive heart failure (CHF). In African Americans (AA) with CHF, reductions in plasma 25(OH)D are of moderate-to-marked severity (&amp;lt;20 ng/mL) and may be accompanied by ionized hypocalcemia with compensatory increases in serum parathyroid hormone (PTH). The management of hypovitaminosis D in AA with CHF has not been established.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>96 percent of heart failure patients had less than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/96-percent-of-heart-failure-patients-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/96-percent-of-heart-failure-patients-had-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-acute-myocardial-infarction">Prevalence of Vitamin D Deficiency in Patients With Acute Myocardial Infarction.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Cardiol. 2011 Mar 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee JH, Gadi R, Spertus JA, Tang F, O&amp;rsquo;Keefe JH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mid America Heart and Vascular Institute and University of Missouri-Kansas City, Kansas City, Missouri.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deficiency in 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) is a treatable condition that has been associated with coronary artery disease and many of its risk factors. A practical time to assess for 25(OH)D deficiency, and to initiate treatment, is at the time of an acute myocardial infarction. The prevalence of 25(OH)D deficiency and the characteristics associated with it in patients with acute myocardial infarction are unknown. In this study, 25(OH)D was assessed in 239 subjects enrolled in a 20-hospital prospective myocardial infarction registry. Patients enrolled from June 1 to December 31, 2008, had serum samples sent to a centralized laboratory for analysis using the DiaSorin 25(OH)D assay. Normal 25(OH)D levels are ?30 ng/ml, and patients with levels &amp;lt;30 and &amp;gt;20 ng/ml were classified as insufficient and those with levels ?20 ng/ml as deficient. Vitamin D levels and other baseline characteristics were analyzed with the linear or Mantel-Haenszel trend test.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Vitamin D and Vitamin K: brittle bones and hardened arteries – LEF</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-brittle-bones-and-hardened-arteries-lef.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-brittle-bones-and-hardened-arteries-lef.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Not yet certain that vitamin D reduces cardiovascular and diabetes in blacks</title><link>/posts/not-yet-certain-that-vitamin-d-reduces-cardiovascular-and-diabetes-in-blacks.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/not-yet-certain-that-vitamin-d-reduces-cardiovascular-and-diabetes-in-blacks.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="does-vitamin-d-deficiency-contribute-to-increased-rates-of-cardiovascular-disease-and-type-2-diabetes-in-african-americans">Does vitamin D deficiency contribute to increased rates of cardiovascular disease and type 2 diabetes in African Americans?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Mar 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harris SS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jean Mayer US Department of Agriculture Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging at Tufts University, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>African Americans have higher rates of type 2 diabetes (T2D) and some forms of cardiovascular disease (CVD) than do European Americans. African Americans also have much higher rates of vitamin D deficiency. There is emerging evidence that vitamin D deficiency may be a risk factor for hypertension, T2D, and CVD, but the extent to which racial disparities in disease rates are explained by racial differences in vitamin D status is uncertain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Cardiovascular and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-cardiovascular-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-cardiovascular-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="why-cardio-event-rcts-are-so-difficult-to-design-and-analyze">Why Cardio Event RCTs are so difficult to design and analyze&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Difficulties in Designing Randomised Controlled Trials of Vitamin D Supplementation for Reducing Acute Cardiovascular Events and in the Analysis of Their Outcomes - July 2020&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/cardio-rct-grant.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular benefits of vitamin D - Feb 2014, &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://heart.bmj.com/content/97/9/766.extract">Arrhythmias in chronic kidney disease&lt;/a> 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.lef.org/protocols/heart_circulatory/arrhythmias_01.htm">Arrhythmias&lt;/a> Life Extension date unknown - perhaps 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review is unsure if supplementing vitamin D will decrease heart failure</title><link>/posts/review-is-unsure-if-supplementing-vitamin-d-will-decrease-heart-failure.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-is-unsure-if-supplementing-vitamin-d-will-decrease-heart-failure.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="is-vitamin-d-deficiency-associated-with-heart-failure-a-review-of-current-evidence">Is Vitamin D Deficiency Associated With Heart Failure? A Review of Current Evidence.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Cardiovasc Pharmacol Ther. 2011 Feb 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Agarwal M, Phan A, Willix R Jr, Barber M, Schwarz ER.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cedars Sinai Heart Institute, Cedars Sinai Medical Center, Los Angeles, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An estimated 1 billion people worldwide have deficient or insufficient levels of vitamin D. Even more alarming is the association of vitamin D deficiency with many types of diseases, particularly heart failure (HF). Hypovitaminosis D has been observed to be highly prevalent in the HF community with rates varying from approximately 80% to 95%.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improved blood flow in blacks with just 2000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/improved-blood-flow-in-blacks-with-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/improved-blood-flow-in-blacks-with-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Vitamin D(3) Supplementation for 16 Weeks Improves Flow-Mediated Dilation in Overweight African-American Adults.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am J Hypertens. 2011 Feb 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harris RA, Pedersen-White J, Guo DH, Stallmann-Jorgensen IS, Keeton D, Huang Y, Shah Y, Zhu H, Dong Y.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Georgia Prevention Institute, Department of Pediatrics, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta, Georgia, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background A growing body of evidence has linked vitamin D deficiency to increased risk of cardiovascular disease. Vitamin D deficiency is also more common in African Americans for whom an increased cardiovascular disease risk exists. This study sought to test the hypothesis that 16 weeks of 60,000 IU monthly supplementation of oral vitamin D(3) would improve flow-mediated dilation (FMD) in African Americans, whereas no change would be observed in the placebo group.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium with Vitamin D2 then D3 helps A-A after heart failure</title><link>/posts/calcium-with-vitamin-d2-then-d3-helps-a-a-after-heart-failure.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-with-vitamin-d2-then-d3-helps-a-a-after-heart-failure.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="supplemental-vitamin-d-and-calcium-in-the-management-of-african-americans-with-heart-failure-having-hypovitaminosis-d">Supplemental Vitamin D and Calcium in the Management of African Americans With Heart Failure Having Hypovitaminosis D.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Med Sci. 2011 Jan 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zia AA, Komolafe BO, Moten M, Ahokas RA, McGee JE, William Rosenberg E, Bhattacharya SK, Weber KT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Division of Cardiovascular Diseases (aaz, mm, jem, skb, ktw), Department of Medicine, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; Department of Medicine (bok), Graduate Medical Education, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology (raa), University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; Division of Dermatology(ewr), Department of Medicine, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis, Tennessee; and Veterans Affairs Medical Center (mm, jem), Memphis, Tennessee.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D helps organ transplant - many studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-organ-transplant-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-organ-transplant-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary-of-many-studies-of-vitamin-d-and-organ-transplantation">Summary of many studies of Vitamin D and organ transplantation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-in-organ-transplantation---2011">Vitamin D in organ transplantation - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#survive-heart-transplant-better-if-have-more-vitamin-d">Survive heart transplant better if have more vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#immune-system-is-often-supressed-so-that-a-new-organ-can-be-accepted-by-the-body">Immune system is often supressed so that a new organ can be accepted by the body&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="summary-of-many-studies-of-vitamin-d-and-organ-transplantation">Summary of many studies of Vitamin D and organ transplantation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>More vitamin D needed especially needed if organ = liver or kidney (low vitamin d ==&amp;gt; poor bones)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium without vitamin D increased heart risk by 30 percent</title><link>/posts/calcium-without-vitamin-d-increased-heart-risk-by-30-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-without-vitamin-d-increased-heart-risk-by-30-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="strong-bones-equals-weak-heart">Strong Bones Equals Weak Heart&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="-abstract-and-link-to-article-is-at-the-bottom-of-this-page">&lt;strong># Abstract and link to article is at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="by-jennifer-gibson-pharmdhttpbrainbloggercom20110102strong-bones-equals-weak-heart">&lt;a href="http://brainblogger.com/2011/01/02/strong-bones-equals-weak-heart/">by Jennifer Gibson, PharmD&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Adequate calcium intake is an important nutritional factor for skeletal health. Calcium (when taken with adequate Vitamin D) prevents bone loss and decreases the risk of fractures and associated morbidity and mortality. Most adults require 1000 mg of calcium daily. (Children and postmenopausal women require slightly more.) For decades, physicians and pharmacists have been advocating calcium supplementation to ensure adequate intake for patients, particularly postmenopausal women, owing to a belief that calcium supplementation offered significant benefits without many adverse consequences. Now, a new meta-analysis in the British Medical Journal (BMJ) claims that calcium supplementation, in fact, leads to an increased risk for cardiovascular events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why we need large-scale heart trials of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/why-we-need-large-scale-heart-trials-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/why-we-need-large-scale-heart-trials-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-the-heart-why-we-need-large-scale-clinical-trials">Vitamin D and the heart: Why we need large-scale clinical trials&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>JOANN E. MANSON, MD, DrPH, FAHA*&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Author Affiliations&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Chief, Division of Preventive Medicine; Co-Director, Connors Center for Women’s Health and Gender Biology, Brigham and Women’s Hospital; Professor of Medicine, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA; Principal Investigator, Vitamin D and Omega-3 Trial (VITAL)&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>ADDRESS: JoAnn E. Manson, MD, DrPH, Division of Preventive Medicine, Brigham and Women’s Hospital, Harvard Medical School, 900 Commonwealth Avenue, Boston, MA 02215; e-mail &lt;a href="mailto:jmanson@rics.bwh.harvard.edu">jmanson@rics.bwh.harvard.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Although vitamin D supplementation appears to be a promising intervention for reducing risks of cancer, cardiovascular disease, and other chronic diseases, existing evidence on its benefits and risks is limited and inconclusive. Recruitment is now under way for the Vitamin D and Omega-3 Trial (VITAL), the first large-scale randomized clinical trial of these nutritional agents for the primary prevention of cancer and cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Editorial on Vitamin D deficiency– Current Drug topics</title><link>/posts/editorial-on-vitamin-d-deficiency-current-drug-topics.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/editorial-on-vitamin-d-deficiency-current-drug-topics.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="editorial-hot-topic-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-cardiovascular-and-renal-disease">Editorial: Hot topic: Vitamin D Deficiency in Cardiovascular and Renal Disease:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="new-light-shed-on-an-old-enemy-guest-editor-martin-h-de-borst">New Light Shed on an Old Enemy (Guest Editor: Martin H. de Borst)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Current Drug Targets, Volume 12, Number 1, January 2011 , pp. 1-3(3)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fat-soluble secosteroid hormone vitamin D is best known for its role in bone metabolism. From a historical perspective, the study of vitamin D deficiency has been intimately related to the study of (possible treatment of) rickets. Although diseases characterized by bone deformations have been described in ancient medical writings from the 1st and 2nd centuries, it was Galen who described the classic bone deformities noted in rickets &lt;sup>[1, 2]&lt;/sup>. More clear descriptions originate from the 17th century, reporting rickets to be endemic in England &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. In the early 20th century, observations that artificial UV light or sunlight provides protection against rickets coincided with results suggesting that rickets may be the consequence of a nutritional deficiency &lt;sup>[3, 4]&lt;/sup>. The responsible vitamin was identified by McCollum et al., who stated in their paper in the Journal of Biological Chemistry in 1922: “These experiments clearly demonstrate the existence of a fourth vitamin whose specific property, as far as we can tell at present, is to regulate the metabolism of the bones” &lt;sup>[5]&lt;/sup>. This “fourth vitamin” was named vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of heart failure and vitamin D mechanisms</title><link>/posts/review-of-heart-failure-and-vitamin-d-mechanisms.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-heart-failure-and-vitamin-d-mechanisms.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-biology-in-heart-failure-molecular-mechanisms-and-systematic-review">Vitamin d biology in heart failure: molecular mechanisms and systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Drug Targets. 2011 Jan 1;12(1):29-41.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meems LM, van der Harst P, van Gilst WH, de Boer RA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardiology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, The Netherlands. &lt;a href="mailto:r.a.de.boer@thorax.umcg.nl">r.a.de.boer@thorax.umcg.nl&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has recently been suggested as an important mediator of blood pressure and cardiovascular disease, including heart failure. In patient with heart failure, low vitamin D levels are associated with adverse outcome and correlate with established clinical correlates and biomarkers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D might deal with atherosclerosis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-might-deal-with-atherosclerosis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-might-deal-with-atherosclerosis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-in-atherosclerosis-vascular-disease-and-endothelial-function">Vitamin d in atherosclerosis, vascular disease, and endothelial function.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Drug Targets. 2011 Jan 1;12(1):54-60.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brewer LC, Michos ED, Reis JP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Cardiovascular Sciences, National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, Bethesda, MD, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:reisjp@nhlbi.nih.gov">reisjp@nhlbi.nih.gov&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been linked to an increased risk of hypertension, diabetes, congestive heart failure, peripheral arterial disease, myocardial infarction, stroke, and related mortality, even after adjustment for traditional cardiovascular risk factors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accumulating evidence from experimental, clinical, and epidemiological studies suggests that vitamin D may also be associated with several indices of vascular function, including the development and progression of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Not all statins increase vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/not-all-statins-increase-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/not-all-statins-increase-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-relationship-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-to-statin-myopathy">The Relationship of Vitamin D Deficiency to Statin Myopathy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>doi:10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2010.11.039&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ankur Guptaa and Paul D. Thompson &lt;a href="mailto:pthomps@harthosp.org">pthomps@harthosp.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Division of Cardiology, Harford Hospital, Hartford, CT&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 26 October 2010; revised 24 November 2010; accepted 25 November 2010. Available online 5 December 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective Our goal was to examine the interaction between vitamin D and statins and the possible role of vitamin D deficiency in statin myopathy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background The vitamin D receptor is present in skeletal muscle and vitamin D deficiency can cause myopathy. Statins (3-hydroxy-3-methyl-glutaryl-CoA reductase inhibitors) are generally well tolerated, but have been associated with a spectrum of skeletal muscle complaints, ranging from myalgia and asymptomatic mild elevations of creatine kinase (CK) to rhabdomyolysis. There has been recent interest in the possible interaction between statin myopathy and vitamin D deficiency. We performed a systematic medical literature review to examine this possible relationship.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bypass surgery and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/bypass-surgery-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bypass-surgery-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="acute-fluid-shifts-influence-the-assessment-of-serum-vitamin-d-status-in-critically-ill-patients">Acute fluid shifts influence the assessment of serum vitamin D status in critically ill patients&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Anand Krishnan email, Judith Ochola email, Julie Mundy email, Mark Jones email, Peter Kruger email, Emma Duncan email and Bala Venkatesh email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Critical Care 2010, 14:R216doi:10.1186/cc9341, 26 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent reports have highlighted the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency and suggested an association with excess mortality in critically ill patients. Serum vitamin D concentrations in these studies were measured following resuscitation. It is unclear whether aggressive fluid resuscitation independently influences serum vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart pumped more blood after heart failure if more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/heart-pumped-more-blood-after-heart-failure-if-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-pumped-more-blood-after-heart-failure-if-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-is-associated-with-functional-capacity-in-older-adults-with-heart-failure">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration is associated with functional capacity in older adults with heart failure.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am Heart J. 2010 Nov;160(5):893-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boxer RS, Kenny AM, Cheruvu VK, Vest M, Fiutem JJ, Piña II.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D is a fat-soluble hormone necessary for calcium homeostasis. Recently, studies have demonstrated that vitamin D may be important to the health of the cardiovascular system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: Adults ?50 years of age with heart failure were recruited for assessment of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) concentrations. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing was used to assess functional capacity. Proximal muscle strength was evaluated with a Biodex leg press (Biodex, Shirley, NY), and health status was assessed with the Kansas City Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire. Univariate associations between physical performance and health status measures and 25OHD followed by a linear regression model were used to study associations, adjusting for other potential explanatory variables.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Youthful heart attacks associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/youthful-heart-attacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/youthful-heart-attacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="markers-of-bone-metabolism-in-premature-myocardial-infarction--40-years-of-age">Markers of Bone Metabolism in premature myocardial infarction (? 40 years of age).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Bone. 2010 Nov 12&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goliasch G, Blessberger H, Azar D, Heinze G, Wojta J, Bieglmayer C, Wagner O, Schillinger M, Huber K, Maurer G, Haas M, Wiesbauer F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardiology, Vienna General Hospital/Medical University of Vienna and 6Wilhelminen Hospital Vienna.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Acute myocardial infarction (AMI) at young age is a rare disease with a poor prognosis. Bone metabolism parameters such as 1,25 (OH)(2) vitamin D(3), 25 (OH) vitamin D(3) and osteocalcin have been recently implicated in the development of coronary heart disease (CHD). We evaluated the role of these serum markers in a study population of very young AMI survivors (? 40 years).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>11 ng less vitamin D increases hypertension probability by 14 percent</title><link>/posts/11-ng-less-vitamin-d-increases-hypertension-probability-by-14-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/11-ng-less-vitamin-d-increases-hypertension-probability-by-14-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="lifestyles-and-cardiovascular-risk-factors">Lifestyles and Cardiovascular Risk Factors&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Core 2. Epidemiology and Prevention of CV Disease: Physiology, Pharmacology and Lifestyle&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract 21058: Association Between Serum Vitamin D and Prehypertension&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Circulation. 2010;122:A21058&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 122, Issue 21 Supplement; November 23, 2010 / Abstracts From Scientific Sessions 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charumathi Sabanayagam; Anoop Shankar&lt;/p>
&lt;p>West virginia Univ, Morgantown, WV&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Low serum levels of vitamin D increases the risk of diabetes and cardiovascular disease. It has also been suggested that serum vitamin D levels are associated with blood pressure. Prehypertension is a preclinical stage where prevention efforts have been shown to be effective in delaying or preventing the onset of hypertension.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>