<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Falls and Fractures on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/falls-and-fractures.html</link><description>Recent content in Falls and Fractures on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/falls-and-fractures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D not associated with PAD after adjusting for race, diabetes and BMI</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-not-associated-with-pad-after-adjusting-for-race-diabetes-and-bmi.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-not-associated-with-pad-after-adjusting-for-race-diabetes-and-bmi.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-status-and-functional-performance-in-peripheral-artery-disease">Vitamin D status and functional performance in peripheral artery disease&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Vascular Med July 19, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary M McDermott &lt;a href="mailto:mdm608@northwestern.edu">mdm608@northwestern.edu&lt;/a>, Department of Medicine, Northwestern University’s Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kiang Liu. Department of Preventive Medicine, Northwestern University’s Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luigi Ferrucci. Longitudinal Studies Section, National Institute on Aging, Baltimore, MD, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lu Tian, Department of Health and Research Policy, Stanford University, Palo Alto, CA, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fractures reduced 30 percent with 800 IU of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-pooled-analysis-of-vitamin-d-dose-requirements-for-fracture-prevention">A pooled analysis of vitamin D dose requirements for fracture prevention.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med. 2012 Jul 5;367(1):40-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Willett WC, Orav EJ, Lips P, Meunier PJ, Lyons RA, Flicker L, Wark J, Jackson RD, Cauley JA, Meyer HE, Pfeifer M, Sanders KM, Stähelin HB, Theiler R, Dawson-Hughes B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center on Aging and Mobility, University of Zurich and Waid City Hospital, Zurich, Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The results of meta-analyses examining the relationship between vitamin D supplementation and fracture reduction have been inconsistent.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>