<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Falls and Fractures on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/falls-and-fractures.html</link><description>Recent content in Falls and Fractures on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/falls-and-fractures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fraser Health in Canada will be giving 20000 IU vitamin D weekly to reduce falls</title><link>/posts/fraser-health-in-canada-will-be-giving-20000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-to-reduce-falls.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fraser-health-in-canada-will-be-giving-20000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-to-reduce-falls.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="news-releasehttpwwwfraserhealthcaabout_usmedia_centrenews_releases2011_news_releasesnew_vitamin_d_protocol_helps_prevent_falls_and_fractures_in_residential_care">&lt;a href="http://www.fraserhealth.ca/about_us/media_centre/news_releases/2011_news_releases/new_vitamin_d_protocol_helps_prevent_falls_and_fractures_in_residential_care">News Release&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Optional for all Fraser Health 7,500 senior residents in Western Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cost per year to Fraser Health of providing the vitamin D is estimated to about that of the cost of a single hip fracture , $20,000&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before vitamin D they had 1,000 to 1,500 falls per year&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They hope to prevent 10% to 25% of the falls per year&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus they hope to prevent 100 to about 300 falls per year&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chance of a fall decreased with vitamin D3 but increased with D2</title><link>/posts/chance-of-a-fall-decreased-with-vitamin-d3-but-increased-with-d2.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chance-of-a-fall-decreased-with-vitamin-d3-but-increased-with-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="relevance-of-vitamin-d-in-muscle-health">Relevance of vitamin D in muscle health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2011 Oct 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bischoff-Ferrari HA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre on Aging and Mobility, University of Zurich and City Hospital Waid, Gloriastrasse 25, 8091, Zurich, Switzerland, &lt;a href="mailto:Heike.Bischoff@usz.ch">Heike.Bischoff@usz.ch&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This review will summarize the impact of vitamin D deficiency on muscle health. Mechanistic evidence regarding the presence of the specific vitamin D receptor in muscle tissue and muscle biopsy abnormalities observed with deficiency will be reviewed, as well as molecular and non-molecular effects of vitamin D in muscle tissue. At the clinical level, the evidence from randomized controlled trials of vitamin D supplementation on functional improvement and fall reduction will be summarized. Further, the manuscript will discuss whether vitamin D effects on fall prevention modulate in part its benefit on fracture prevention and why fall prevention is essential in fracture prevention at higher age. Finally, trial and epidemiological data will be reviewed to assess desirable serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels for optimal muscle health.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces falls – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-falls-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-falls-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-falls-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">The Effect of Vitamin D on Falls: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism October 1, 2011 vol. 96 no. 10 2997-3006&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohammad Hassan Murad,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Khalid B. Elamin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nisrin O. Abu Elnour,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohamed B. Elamin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aziz A. Alkatib,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mitra M. Fatourechi,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jaime P. Almandoz,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rebecca J. Mullan,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Melanie A. Lane,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hau Liu,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patricia J. Erwin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Donald D. Hensrud and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Victor M. Montori&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Knowledge and Encounter Research Unit (M.H.M., N.O.A.E., M.B.E., A.A.A., M.M.F., J.P.A., R.J.M., M.A.L., P.J.E., V.M.M.), and Division of Preventive, Occupational, and Aerospace Medicine (M.H.M., D.D.H.), Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota 55905; Department of Medicine (K.B.E.), Case Western Reserve University, Metrohealth Medical Center, Cleveland, Ohio 44109; Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes, Metabolism, and Nutrition (V.M.M.), Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota 55905; and Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism (H.L.), Santa Clara Valley Medical Center, San Jose, California 95128&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active form of vitamin D (calcitriol) cut in half the fractures following organ transplant – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/active-form-of-vitamin-d-calcitriol-cut-in-half-the-fractures-following-organ-tr-t-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-form-of-vitamin-d-calcitriol-cut-in-half-the-fractures-following-organ-tr-t-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>30 percent less chance of dying after hip fracture if take vitamin D and other drugs – 2011</title><link>/posts/30-percent-less-chance-of-dying-after-hip-fracture-if-take-vitamin-d-and-other-drugs-2011.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/30-percent-less-chance-of-dying-after-hip-fracture-if-take-vitamin-d-and-other-drugs-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="post-hip-fracture-use-of-prescribed-calcium-plus-vitamin-d-or-vitamin-d-supplements-and-anti-osteoporotic-drugs-are-associated-with-lower-mortality-a-nationwide-study-in-finland">Post-hip fracture use of prescribed calcium plus vitamin D or vitamin D supplements and anti-osteoporotic drugs are associated with lower mortality. A nationwide study in Finland†&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ilona Nurmi-Lüthje1,2,* &lt;a href="mailto:ilona.nurmi@pp.inet.fi">ilona.nurmi@pp.inet.fi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reijo Sund3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Merja Juntunen3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter Lüthje4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Center for Injury and Violence Prevention, Health Center of Kouvola, FI-45100 Kouvola, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Hjelt Institute, Department of Public Health, FI-00014 Helsinki University, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 National Institute for Health and Welfare, FI-00271 Helsinki, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 North Kymi Hospital, FI-45750 Kuusankoski, Finland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X more falls for senior men with less than 20ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/2x-more-falls-for-senior-men-with-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-falls-for-senior-men-with-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="relationships-between-serum-vitamin-d-levels-neuromuscular-and-neuropsychological-function-and-falls-in-older-men-and-women">Relationships between serum vitamin D levels, neuromuscular and neuropsychological function and falls in older men and women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Apr 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Menant JC, Close JC, Delbaere K, Sturnieks DL, Trollor J, Sachdev PS, Brodaty H, Lord SR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Falls and Balance Research Group, Neuroscience Research Australia, University of New South Wales, Barker Street, Randwick, NSW, 2031, Sydney, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among 463 community dwellers aged 70-90 years, those with vitamin D insufficiency showed reduced neuromuscular function, balance control and stepping ability and performed worse in tests of cognitive function. In men, vitamin D insufficiency was associated with an increased risk of falling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Role of the orthopaedic surgeon in fragility fractures</title><link>/posts/role-of-the-orthopaedic-surgeon-in-fragility-fractures.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/role-of-the-orthopaedic-surgeon-in-fragility-fractures.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="what-is-the-role-of-the-orthopaedic-surgeon-in-management-of-fragility-fractures">What is the role of the orthopaedic surgeon in management of fragility fractures?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Orthop Trauma. 2011 Jun;25 Suppl 1:S47-50.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sharif KM, Dimitriou R, Giannoudis PV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trauma &amp;amp; Orthopaedics, Manor Hospital, Walsall, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fragility fractures are the most prevalent trauma condition that orthopaedic surgeons face today. Osteoporosis and susceptibility to falls are the key predisposing factors. Despite evidence supporting the impact of treating osteoporosis on reducing the incidence of fragility fractures, it is often left untreated. Orthopaedic surgeons are often the first physicians to assess and treat the patient after a fragility fracture. Their role therefore does not end in the skillful fixation of the fractures, but they have a unique opportunity to ensure that preventive measures are implemented. This includes falls prevention, investigation of possible causes underlying osteoporosis, attention to diet, exercise, calcium, and vitamin D supplementation as well as prescription of anti-resorptive and anabolic medication. The need for a dedicated multidisciplinary team needs to be emphasized and therefore effective communication between the different parties is of paramount importance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Majority of animal bone fractures healed more quickly with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/majority-of-animal-bone-fractures-healed-more-quickly-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/majority-of-animal-bone-fractures-healed-more-quickly-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="is-supplementation-of-vitamin-d-beneficial-for-fracture-healing">Is Supplementation of Vitamin D Beneficial for Fracture Healing?&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-short-review-of-the-literature">A Short Review of the Literature&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Daniel Eschle, Dr. med. &lt;a href="mailto:d.eschle@rehaclinic.ch">d.eschle@rehaclinic.ch&lt;/a>; André G. Aeschlimann&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Geriatric Orthopaedic Surgery &amp;amp; Rehabilitation May 23, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been a surge of interest regarding the benefits of vitamin D supplementation to prevent fractures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But can it also make them heal more quickly once they have occurred—that is, is supplementation of vitamin D beneficial for fracture healing?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fracture patients had only 16 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hip-fracture-patients-had-only-16-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fracture-patients-had-only-16-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-in-hip-and-spine-fracture-patients-in-japan">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status in hip and spine-fracture patients in Japan.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Orthop Sci. 2011 May 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sakuma M, Endo N, Hagino H, Harada A, Matsui Y, Nakano T, Nakamura K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Medical Technology, Niigata University of Health and Welfare, Niigata, Japan, &lt;a href="mailto:m-sakuma@nuhw.ac.jp">m-sakuma@nuhw.ac.jp&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) is used as an index that reflects the level of vitamin D. We have previously reported, on the basis of a study in Sado in Niigata, that patients with hip fracture have lower serum 25(OH)D levels than non-hip-fracture cases. In this study, the serum 25(OH)D status in hip-fracture cases was examined in four regions in Japan. Although most hip-fracture patients have experienced past spine-compression fractures, the relationship of these fractures and 25(OH)D is unknown. Therefore, we also examined the 25(OH)D level in spine-compression fracture patients in the same locations and time periods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Most people with bone fractures still not getting vitamin D</title><link>/posts/most-people-with-bone-fractures-still-not-getting-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/most-people-with-bone-fractures-still-not-getting-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-deficiency-in-the-acute-inpatient-rehabilitation-population-and-its-effect-on-function">Prevalence of 25-hydroxyvitamin d deficiency in the acute inpatient rehabilitation population and its effect on function.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2011 May;92(5):705-11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pellicane AJ, Wysocki NM, Mallinson TR, Schnitzer TJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wayne State University, Rehabilitation Institute of Michigan, Detroit, MI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: To assess the prevalence of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) insufficiency and deficiency in the acute inpatient rehabilitation setting, identify risk factors associated with low serum 25(OH)D levels, and assess whether hypovitaminosis D affects the function of rehabilitation patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Having less than 25 ng of vitamin D was associated with severe hip fracture</title><link>/posts/having-less-than-25-ng-of-vitamin-d-was-associated-with-severe-hip-fracture.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/having-less-than-25-ng-of-vitamin-d-was-associated-with-severe-hip-fracture.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-as-a-risk-factor-of-hip-fracture-severity">Hypovitaminosis D as a risk factor of hip fracture severity.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Mar 11&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Larrosa M, Gomez A, Casado E, Moreno M, Vázquez I, Orellana C, Berlanga E, Ramon J, Gratacos J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatology Department, University Institute Parc Taulí (UAB), Parc Tauli s/n, 08208, Sabadell, Barcelona, Spain, &lt;a href="mailto:mlarrosa@tauli.cat">mlarrosa@tauli.cat&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a cross-sectional study including 324 patients older than 65 years admitted to our hospital for osteoporotic hip fracture, we found that those patients with a more severe vitamin D deficiency had more severe osteoporotic hip fractures (Garden grades III-IV and Kyle III-IV).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Vitamin D and Vitamin K: brittle bones and hardened arteries – LEF</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-brittle-bones-and-hardened-arteries-lef.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-brittle-bones-and-hardened-arteries-lef.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fracture patients with bone diseases lacked vitamin D and calcium</title><link>/posts/fracture-patients-with-bone-diseases-lacked-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fracture-patients-with-bone-diseases-lacked-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="contributors-to-secondary-osteoporosis-and-metabolic-bone-diseases-in-patients-presenting-with-a-clinical-fracture">Contributors to Secondary Osteoporosis and Metabolic Bone Diseases in Patients Presenting with a Clinical Fracture.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Mar 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bours SP, van Geel TA, Geusens PP, Janssen MJ, Janzing HM, Hoffland GA, Willems PC, van den Bergh JP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine (S.P.G.B., J.P.W.v.d.B.), Laboratory of Clinical Chemistry and Haematology (M.J.W.J.), Department of Surgery (H.M.J.J.), Department of Radiology (G.A.H.), VieCuri Medisch Centrum Noord-Limburg, 5912 BL Venlo, The Netherlands; Department of Internal Medicine (S.P.G.B.), Subdivision Endocrinology, and Department of Orthopedic Surgery (P.C.W.), Maastricht University Medical Centre, 6202 AZ Maastricht, The Netherlands; Department of General Practice (T.A.C.M.v.G.), Department of Internal Medicine (P.P.M.M.G.), Subdivision Rheumatology, Maastricht University/CAPHRI School for Public Health and Primary Care, 6200 MD Maastricht, The Netherlands; Biomedical Research Centre (P.P.M.M.G.), University Hasselt, B-3590 Diepenbeek, Belgium; and Department of Internal Medicine (J.P.W.v.d.B.), Maastricht University Medical Centre/School for Nutrition, Toxicology, and Metabolism, 6200 MD Maastricht, The Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fractures worse if very low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-worse-if-very-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-worse-if-very-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-as-a-risk-factor-of-hip-fracture-severity">Hypovitaminosis D as a risk factor of hip fracture severity.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Mar 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Larrosa M, Gomez A, Casado E, Moreno M, Vázquez I, Orellana C, Berlanga E, Ramon J, Gratacos J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatology Department, University Institute Parc Taulí (UAB), Parc Tauli s/n, 08208, Sabadell, Barcelona, Spain, &lt;a href="mailto:mlarrosa@tauli.cat">mlarrosa@tauli.cat&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a cross-sectional study including 324 patients older than 65 years admitted to our hospital for osteoporotic hip fracture, we found that those patients with a more severe vitamin D deficiency had more severe osteoporotic hip fractures (Garden grades III-IV and Kyle III-IV).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of non-bone effects of vitamin D on fall prevention</title><link>/posts/review-of-non-bone-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-fall-prevention.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-non-bone-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-fall-prevention.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="fall-prevention-and-vitamin-d-in-the-elderly-an-overview-of-the-key-role-of-the-non-bone-effects">Fall prevention and vitamin D in the elderly: an overview of the key role of the non-bone effects.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2010 Oct 11;7:50.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annweiler C, Montero-Odasso M, Schott AM, Berrut G, Fantino B, Beauchet O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine and Geriatrics, Angers University Hospital, Angers University Memory Center, UPRES EA 2646, University of Angers, UNAM, Angers, France. &lt;a href="mailto:ceannweiler@chu-angers.fr">ceannweiler@chu-angers.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Preventing falls and fall-related fractures in the elderly is an objective yet to be reached. There is increasing evidence that a supplementation of vitamin D and/or of calcium may reduce the fall and fracture rates. A vitamin D-calcium supplement appears to have a high potential due to its simple application and its low cost. However, published studies have shown conflicting results as some studies failed to show any effect, while others reported a significant decrease of falls and fractures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>75 percent of hip fractures associated with vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/75-percent-of-hip-fractures-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/75-percent-of-hip-fractures-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="three-fourths-of-hip-fractures-in-the-elderly-are-related-to-vitamin-d-deficiency-experts-say">Three-fourths of hip fractures in the elderly are related to vitamin D deficiency, experts say&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.endocrineweb.com/news/osteoporosis/3953-three-fourths-hip-fractures-elderly-are-related-vitamin-d-deficiency-experts">http://www.endocrineweb.com/news/osteoporosis/3953-three-fourths-hip-fractures-elderly-are-related-vitamin-d-deficiency-experts&lt;/a>–&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Researchers from India have found that three-quarters of osteoporosis-related hip fractures are related to vitamin D deficiency, according to statistics delivered at the First Asia-Pacific Regional Osteoporosis Meeting held in Singapore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a study of 90 hip-fracture patients and an equal number of unafflicted peers, scientists in New Delhi measured the levels of a number of vitamins and human hormones in blood donated by participants.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wrist fracture is also associated with vitamin D inadequacy</title><link>/posts/wrist-fracture-is-also-associated-with-vitamin-d-inadequacy.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wrist-fracture-is-also-associated-with-vitamin-d-inadequacy.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="two-items-on-this-page">two items on this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="44-percent-of-postmenopausal-wrist-fractures-had-low-vitamin-d--sept-2011">44 percent of postmenopausal wrist fractures had low vitamin D – Sept 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="from-american-society-for-bone-and-mineral-research-httpwwwasbmrorgitinerarypresentationdetailaspxidfcdadcdd-9898-4825-81be-b13d1e13aed020">From &lt;a href="http://www.asbmr.org/Itinerary/PresentationDetail.aspx?id=fcdadcdd-9898-4825-81be-b13d1e13aed0%20">American Society for Bone and Mineral Research &lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-postmenopausal-women-with-a-distal-radius-fracture">Hypovitaminosis D in Postmenopausal Women with a Distal Radius Fracture&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Poster Sessions, Presentation Number: SU0377&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presenting Author(s): Hyun Sik Gong, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, ROK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>September 18, 2011 11:00 AM — 1:00 PM; San Diego Convention Center, Hall GH&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(later presented at presented at the 2012 Annual Meeting of the American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons (AAOS).)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Fractures and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-fractures-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-fractures-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/09/27/well/live/broken-bone-fracture-risk.html">&amp;quot;..only 9 percent of Medicare patients who sustained a hip or spinal fracture were tested for bone loss and offered treatment to head off a future fracture.&amp;quot;&lt;/a> NYT Sept 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Hip Fractures in Older Adults - JAMA 2019&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most estimates of risk of elderly fracture do not consider the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>    falls, cognitive impairment, urinary incontinence, neurological conditions, and medications&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Continues to recommend Vitamin D sufficiency (&amp;gt;30ng?)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/hip-fractures-in-older-adults-in-2019.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No reduction in Finish fractures with 800 IU Vitamin D3 and Calcium</title><link>/posts/no-reduction-in-finish-fractures-with-800-iu-vitamin-d3-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-reduction-in-finish-fractures-with-800-iu-vitamin-d3-and-calcium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Overview Fractures and Falls and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-fractures-and-falls-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-fractures-and-falls-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="8-of-hospitalisations--for-falls-and-hip-fractures-in-australia-were-attributable-to-vitamin-d-deficiency-20-ng">8% of hospitalisations for falls and hip fractures in Australia were attributable to vitamin D deficiency (&amp;lt;20 ng)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hospitalisations for falls and hip fractures attributable to vitamin D deficiency in older Australians - Jan 2021&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0007114521000416">doi: 10.1017/S0007114521000416&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h5 id="it-has-been-known-since-year-2000-that-nerve-conduction-velocity-speeds-up-with-increased-vitamin-d---see-following-graph">It has been known since year 2000 that nerve conduction velocity speeds up with increased vitamin D - see following graph&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;420&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="juventhttpwwwjuventcomhealth-micro-impact-platform---3500---nov-2017">&lt;a href="http://www.juvent.com/health/">Juvent&lt;/a> Micro-Impact Platform - $3,500 - Nov 2017&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Computer and software find the resonant frequency of the user in a safe range of frequencies (32Hz-37Hz) and therefore is able to use a very small level of energy (.3g) to deliver a physiologically effective energy pulse.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D 2nd most recommended way to prevent next hip fracture</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-2nd-most-recommended-way-to-prevent-next-hip-fracture.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-2nd-most-recommended-way-to-prevent-next-hip-fracture.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="hip-fracture-prevention-strategies-in-long-term-care-a-survey-of-canadian-physicians-opinions">Hip fracture prevention strategies in long-term care: A survey of Canadian physicians’ opinions&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Canadian Family Physician&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol. 56, No. 11, November 2010, pp.e392 - e397&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anna M. Sawka, MD PhD FRCPC -Endocrinologist and clinician scientist at the University Health Network in Toronto, Ont, an Assistant Professor at the University of Toronto, and holds a Health Services Research Chair from Cancer Care Ontario&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nofisat Ismaila - Research analyst at the University Health Network at the time of submission&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 instead of 11 fractures with Parkinson disease when have enough sun</title><link>/posts/3-instead-of-11-fractures-with-parkinson-disease-when-have-enough-sun.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-instead-of-11-fractures-with-parkinson-disease-when-have-enough-sun.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>