<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Falls and Fractures on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/falls-and-fractures.html</link><description>Recent content in Falls and Fractures on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/falls-and-fractures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>20 percent fewer male hip fractures if more Magnesium in the water</title><link>/posts/20-percent-fewer-male-hip-fractures-if-more-magnesium-in-the-water.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/20-percent-fewer-male-hip-fractures-if-more-magnesium-in-the-water.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="nationwide-data-on-municipal-drinking-water-and-hip-fracture">Nationwide data on municipal drinking water and hip fracture:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Could calcium and magnesium be protective? A NOREPOS study&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bone, Available online 2 July 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cecilie Dahl a, b, &lt;a href="mailto:Cecilie.Dahl@fhi.no">Cecilie.Dahl@fhi.no&lt;/a>, Anne Johanne Søgaard a, Grethe S. Tel b, Trond Peder Flaten c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dag Hongve d, Tone Kristin Omsland b, e, Kristin Holvik b, Haakon E. Meyer a, e, Geir Aamodt a&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Division of Epidemiology, Norwegian Institute of Public Health, Oslo, Norway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Public Health and Primary Health Care, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Muscles and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/muscles-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/muscles-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#max-strength-not-improved-by-resistance-training-plus-daily-8000-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-whey-protien--rct-oct-2024">Max strength not improved by resistance training plus daily 8,000 IU of vitamin D and whey protien – RCT Oct 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#surplus-calories-not-put-into-fat-if-good-level-of-vitamin-d-mice-may-2024">Surplus calories not put into fat if good level of Vitamin D (mice) May 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#do-fast-twitch-muscles-respond-more-quickly-if-there-is-a-higher-level-of-vitamin-d-in-the-blood">Do fast twitch muscles respond more quickly if there is a higher level of vitamin D in the blood?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-skeletal-muscle-repair-and-regeneration-in-animal-models-and-humans-a-systematic-review---oct-2023">The Role of Vitamin D in Skeletal Muscle Repair and Regeneration in Animal Models and Humans: A Systematic Review - Oct 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#muscle-health-and-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-sept-2021-not-help-much---ignored-dose-size">Muscle Health and Vitamin D - Meta-analysis Sept 2021 (not help much - ignored dose size)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-promotes-skeletal-muscle-regeneration-and-mitochondrial-health--april-2021">Vitamin D Promotes Skeletal Muscle Regeneration and Mitochondrial Health – April 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-helps-muscles-in-many-ways--sept-2021">Vitamin D helps muscles in many ways – Sept 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-roles-of-vitamin-d-in-skeletal-muscle-feb-2013">The Roles of Vitamin D in Skeletal Muscle Feb 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#small-vitamin-d-doses-given-for-a-few-months-do-not-improve-muscles---meta-analysis-oct-2023">Small Vitamin D doses given for a few months do not improve muscles - meta-analysis Oct 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#48000-iu-monthly-for-a-year-did-not-help-elderly-muscles--june-2019">48,000 IU monthly for a year did not help elderly muscles- June 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sarcopenia-33-x-higher-risk-if-low-bio-available-vitamin-d---august-2021">Sarcopenia: 3.3 X higher risk if low bio-available vitamin D - August 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-reduced-muscle-function-associated-with-many-vitamin-d-genes---review-sept-2021">Some reduced muscle function associated with many Vitamin D genes - Review Sept 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-a-hrefpostsmuscular-dystrophy-probably-treated-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-plus-muscle-rehab-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-muscular-dystrophy-probably-treated-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-plus-muscle-rehabmuscular-dystrophy-probably-treated-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-plus-muscle-rehaba">See also: &lt;a href="/posts/muscular-dystrophy-probably-treated-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-plus-muscle-rehab" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Muscular Dystrophy probably treated by high-dose Vitamin D plus muscle rehab">Muscular Dystrophy probably treated by high-dose Vitamin D plus muscle rehab&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#creatine-might-help-grow-senior-muscles-when-added-to-exercise">Creatine might help grow senior muscles when added to exercise&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="max-strength-not-improved-by-resistance-training-plus-daily-8000-iu-of-vitamin-d-and-whey-protien--rct-oct-2024">Max strength not improved by resistance training plus daily 8,000 IU of vitamin D and whey protien – RCT Oct 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D Supplementation Does Not Enhance Gains in Muscle Strength and Lean Body Mass or Influence Cardiorespiratory Fitness in Vitamin D-Insufficient Middle-Aged Men Engaged in Resistance Training&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half as many hip fractures if take Calcium, hormones, and a tiny amount of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/half-as-many-hip-fractures-if-take-calcium-hormones-and-a-tiny-amount-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-as-many-hip-fractures-if-take-calcium-hormones-and-a-tiny-amount-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="calcium-and-vitamin-d-help-hormones-help-boneshttpwwweurekalertorgpub_releases2013-06tnam-cav062013php20-press-release">&lt;a href="http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2013-06/tnam-cav062013.php%20">Calcium and vitamin D help hormones help bones&lt;/a> Press Release&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Contact: Eileen Petridis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="mailto:epetridis@fallscommunications.com">epetridis@fallscommunications.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>216-696-0229&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The North American Menopause Society (NAMS)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CLEVELAND, Ohio (June 26, 2013)—Should women take calcium and vitamin D supplements after menopause for bone health? Recommendations conflict, and opinions are strong. But now, an analysis from the major Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Initiative (WHI) trial throws weight on the supplement side—at least for women taking hormones after menopause. The analysis was published online today in Menopause, the journal of The North American Menopause Society.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Male Hip fracture 1.65X more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/male-hip-fracture-165x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/male-hip-fracture-165x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="low-serum-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-predict-hip-fracture-in-the-elderly">Low serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D predict hip fracture in the elderly.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A NOREPOS study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013 May 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Holvik K, Ahmed LA, Forsmo S, Gjesdal CG, Grimnes G, Samuelsen SO, Schei B, Blomhoff R, Tell GS, Meyer HE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Public Health and Primary Health Care, University of Bergen, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:Despite considerable interest, the relationship between circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D and risk of hip fracture is not fully established.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D needed to prevent and treat hip fracture, but only 20 percent got any</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-needed-to-prevent-and-treat-hip-fracture-but-only-20-percent-got-any.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-needed-to-prevent-and-treat-hip-fracture-but-only-20-percent-got-any.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="before-and-after-hip-fracture-vitamin-d-deficiency-may-not-be-treated-sufficiently">Before and after hip fracture, vitamin D deficiency may not be treated sufficiently.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2013 May 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maier S, Sidelnikov E, Dawson-Hughes B, Egli A, Theiler R, Platz A, Staehelin HB, Simmen HP, Meier C, Dick W, Grob D, von Eckardstein A, Bischoff-Ferrari HA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre on Aging and Mobility, University of Zurich and Waid City Hospital, Department of Geriatrics and Aging Research, University Hospital Zurich, Gloriastrasse 25, CH-8091, Zurich, Switzerland.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip bone loss stopped with 1000 IU of vitamin D, while 400 IU similar to placebo – RCT</title><link>/posts/hip-bone-loss-stopped-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-while-400-iu-similar-to-placebo-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-bone-loss-stopped-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-while-400-iu-similar-to-placebo-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="hip-bone-loss-is-attenuated-with-1000-iu-but-not-400-iu-daily-vitamin-d3-a-1-year-double-blind-rct-in-postmenopausal-women">Hip bone loss is attenuated with 1000 IU but not 400 IU daily vitamin D3: a 1 year double-blind RCT in postmenopausal women&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Bone and Mineral Research, Vol. 28 Issue 4, DOI: 10.1002/jbmr.1959&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Helen M Macdonald1,‖, &lt;a href="mailto:h.macdonald@abdn.ac.uk">h.macdonald@abdn.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adrian D Wood1,‖,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lorna S Aucott1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alison J Black3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William D Fraser4,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alexandra Mavroeidi2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David M Reid1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karen R Secombes1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William G Simpson5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frank Thies1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Aberdeen, Foresterhill, Aberdeen&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hydroaerobics added to Vitamin D and Ca significantly improved physical function</title><link>/posts/hydroaerobics-added-to-vitamin-d-and-ca-significantly-improved-physical-function.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hydroaerobics-added-to-vitamin-d-and-ca-significantly-improved-physical-function.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="high-intensity-aquatic-exercises-hydros-improve-physical-function-and-reduce-falls-among-postmenopausal-women">High-intensity aquatic exercises (HydrOS) improve physical function and reduce falls among postmenopausal women.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Menopause. 2013 Mar 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Denise Fernandes Moreira L, Fronza FC, Dos Santos RN, Teixeira LR, Kruel LF, Lazaretti-Castro M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Endocrinology, Escola Paulista de Medicina, Universidade Federal de São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Physical Education and Sport, University of São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil; and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Exercise Research Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lower vitamin D in elderly group with fractures</title><link>/posts/lower-vitamin-d-in-elderly-group-with-fractures.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lower-vitamin-d-in-elderly-group-with-fractures.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="connection-between-bone-fractures-vitamin-d-level-and-low-energy-falls-in-hospitalised-elderly-patients">Connection Between Bone Fractures, Vitamin D Level and Low-Energy Falls in Hospitalised Elderly Patients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clinical pharmacy and clinical trials (including case series) CPC-036 &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eur J Hosp Pharm 2013;20:A178 doi:10.1136/ejhpharm-2013-000276.493&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Bor,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P Doró,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M Matuz,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Z Biczók,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R Viola,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G Soós&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Univeristy of Szeged, Department of Clinical Pharmacy, Szeged, Hungary&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background The ageing of the population in developed countries is a growing problem today. Prevalence of chronic diseases, such as osteoporosis, increases with age. It is estimated that 900,000 people (9% of the population) above the age of fifty suffer from osteoporosis in Hungary. This condition greatly increases the risk of fractures of vertebra and the hip bone, which often lead to fatal consequences. Many studies have proven that a low vitamin D level increases the risk of bone fractures. Adequate vitamin D level is essential to prevent bone loss and structural damage of the bone matrix, which also prevents fractures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fracture reduction vs vitamin D - trial history</title><link>/posts/fracture-reduction-vs-vitamin-d-trial-history.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fracture-reduction-vs-vitamin-d-trial-history.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-the-optimal-requirement-for-vitamin-d3-is-probably-much-higher-than-what-is-officially-recommended-for-adults">Why the optimal requirement for Vitamin D3 is probably much higher than what is officially recommended for adults&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Journal of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Volumes 89–90, May 2004, Pages 575–579&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Proceedings of the 12th Workshop on Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reinhold ViethCorresponding author contact information, E-mail the corresponding author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathobiology, University of Toronto, and Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Mount Sinai Hospital, Toronto, Canada M5G 1X5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The physiologic range for circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 &lt;span>[25(OH)D; the measure of Vitamin D nutrient status]&lt;/span> concentration in humans and other primates extends to beyond 200 nmol/L (&amp;gt;80 ng/mL). This biologic “normal” value is greater than current population norms for 25(OH)D. Concentrations of 25(OH)D that correlate with desirable effects extend to at least 70 nmol/L, with no obvious threshold. Randomized clinical trials using 20 mcg (800 IU) per day of Vitamin D show that this suppresses parathyroid hormone, preserves bone mineral density, prevents fractures, lowers blood pressure and improves balance. Calcium absorption from diet correlates with 25(OH)D in the normal range. Health effects of Vitamin D beyond osteoporosis are mostly supported by the circumstantial evidence of epidemiologic studies and laboratory research. These include prevention of cancer and the autoimmune diseases, insulin-dependent diabetes and multiple sclerosis. One mcg per day of Vitamin D3 (cholecalciferol) increases circulating 25(OH)D by about 1 nmol/L (0.4 ng/mL). A recommended dietary allowance (RDA) is the long-term daily intake level that meets the total requirements for the nutrient by nearly all healthy individuals (it would presume no sunshine). If 70 nmol/L is regarded as a minimum desirable target 25(OH)D concentration, then current recommendations of 15 mcg per day do not meet the criterion of an RDA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doubt that vitamin D prevents fractures, especially without Calcium</title><link>/posts/doubt-that-vitamin-d-prevents-fractures-especially-without-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/doubt-that-vitamin-d-prevents-fractures-especially-without-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="commentary-on-a-pooled-analysis-of-vitamin-d-dose-requirements-for-fracture-prevention">COMMENTARY on A pooled analysis of Vitamin D dose requirements for fracture prevention&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>IBMS BoneKEy 10, Article number: 256 (2013) | doi:10.1038/bonekey.2012.256 © 2013 International Bone &amp;amp; Mineral Society All rights reserved 1940-8692/13 &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/bonekey">www.nature.com/bonekey&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bo Abrahamsen1,2, Alison Avenell3, Mark Bolland4, Lars Rejnmark5, Graeme S MacLennan3, Helen M Macdonald6 and Andrew Grey4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Odense Patient Data Exploratory Network (OPEN), Institute of Clinical Research, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Medicine F, Gentofte Hospital, Copenhagen, Denmark.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guideline following hip fracture – 50000 IU vitamin D daily for 7 days</title><link>/posts/guideline-following-hip-fracture-50000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-for-7-days.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/guideline-following-hip-fracture-50000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-for-7-days.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-levels-in-hip-fractures-rationale-and-guidelines-for-rapid-substitution-therapy">Vitamin D levels in hip fractures: rationale and guidelines for rapid substitution therapy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bone Joint J 2013 vol. 95-B no. SUPP 1 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A de Jong, K Woods, M Suresh and M Porteous; Bury St. Edmunds, United Kingdom&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction Assessment for and treatment of osteoporosis is recommended following hip fracture. All forms of osteoporosis treatment require an adequate calcium intake and normal vitamin D levels. This study assesses vitamin D levels in patients with hip fractures and describes guidelines on how to manage low vitamin D levels with high dose oral vitamin D3 (cholecalciferol).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Supra-Optimal Vitamin D Status – great phrase, no detail</title><link>/posts/supra-optimal-vitamin-d-status-great-phrase-no-detail.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/supra-optimal-vitamin-d-status-great-phrase-no-detail.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="higher-serum-vitamin-d-concentration-is-associated-with-better-balance-in-older-adults-with-supra-optimal-vitamin-d-status--letter-to-the-editor">Higher Serum Vitamin D Concentration Is Associated with Better Balance in Older Adults with Supra-Optimal Vitamin D Status – Letter to the Editor&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of the American Geriatrics Society Volume 61, Issue 1, pages 163–165, January 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cedric Annweiler MD, PhD 1,2,3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Susan W. Muir PhD 1,2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shamis Nabeel Bsc 1,2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karen Gopaul Msc 1,2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olivier Beauchet MD, PhD 3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manuel Montero-Odasso MD, PhD, AGSF 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Division of Geriatric Medicine, Department of Medicine, Parkwood Hospital, St. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s Health Care London, London, Ontario, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone fracture healing not a function of vitamin D level</title><link>/posts/bone-fracture-healing-not-a-function-of-vitamin-d-level.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bone-fracture-healing-not-a-function-of-vitamin-d-level.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-concentration-in-patients-with-normal-and-impaired-bone-union">Vitamin D concentration in patients with normal and impaired bone union.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pol Orthop Traumatol. 2013 Jan 2;78:1-3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boszczyk AM, Zakrzewski P, Pomianowski S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Musculoskeletal Trauma Surgery and Orthopaedics CMKP, Otwock, Poland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: The aim of the study was to compare vitamin D concentration in patients treated due to delayed bone union and non-union (pseudoarthrosis) and patients with normal fracture healing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Material/Methods: A retrospective case-control study was conducted. We enrolled 35 patients with inexplicable (standard and correct surgery, closed fracture, no comorbid metabolic diseases) fracture healing impairment, and 35 patients assigned by age and measurement season. Vitamin D (as 25OHD) concentration was measured in all patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The more the elderly got sunshine, the fewer falls they had - 2011</title><link>/posts/the-more-the-elderly-got-sunshine-the-fewer-falls-they-had-2011.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-more-the-elderly-got-sunshine-the-fewer-falls-they-had-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Notes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This is an experiment of extracting a PDF file to HTML&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Extraction was by ABBYY PDF transformer, which operates quicly, but the results are very difficult to read&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Will be experimenting with many other PDF to HTML converter packages&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Trying to find a converter which retains the text, tables, links, and images, and is easy to read&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The PDF file was available as open access to the public in Dec 2012&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fracture 19 percent less likely with just 4 ng higher level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hip-fracture-19-percent-less-likely-with-just-4-ng-higher-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fracture-19-percent-less-likely-with-just-4-ng-higher-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="non-linear-relationship-between-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-and-subsequent-hip-fracture">Non-linear relationship between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration and subsequent hip fracture.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Dec 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>de Koning L, Henne D, Hemmelgarn BR, Woods P, Naugler C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum 25-OH vitamin D levels were compared in 254 hip fracture subjects and 2,402 matched control subjects. There was a significant inverse association between 25-OH vitamin D and hip fracture only between 0 and 70 nmol/L.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D associated with osteoporotic fractures up to 10 years later</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-osteoporotic-fractures-up-to-10-years-later.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-osteoporotic-fractures-up-to-10-years-later.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-risk-of-major-osteoporotic-fractures-in-older-us-adults">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and risk of major osteoporotic fractures in older U.S. adults&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Journal of Bone and Mineral Research&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anne C. Looker Ph.D National Center for Health Statistics, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Hyattsville MD, Email: Anne C. Looker Ph.D (&lt;a href="mailto:ALooker@cdc.gov">ALooker@cdc.gov&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accepted manuscript online: 26 NOV 2012; Manuscript Accepted: 12 NOV 2012; Manuscript Revised: 26 OCT 2012; Manuscript Received: 31 AUG 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article has been accepted for publication and undergone full peer review but has not been through the copyediting, typesetting, pagination and proofreading process, which may lead to differences between this version and the Version of Record. Please cite this article as &lt;a href="https://doi.org/%5B10.1002/jbmr.1828%5D.">doi: [10.1002/jbmr.1828].&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fractures greatly reduced by sunshine, vitamin D, and vitamin K – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-greatly-reduced-by-sunshine-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-greatly-reduced-by-sunshine-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="strategy-for-prevention-of-hip-fractures-in-patients-with-parkinsons-disease">Strategy for prevention of hip fractures in patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>World J Orthop. 2012 Sep 18;3(9):137-41. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5312/wjo.v3.i9.137.">doi: 10.5312/wjo.v3.i9.137.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Iwamoto J, Sato Y, Takeda T, Matsumoto H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jun Iwamoto, Tsuyoshi Takeda, Hideo Matsumoto, Institute for Integrated Sports Medicine, Keio University School of Medicine, Tokyo 160-8582, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypovitaminosis D and K due to malnutrition or sunlight deprivation, increased bone resorption due to immobilization, low bone mineral density (BMD) and an increased risk of falls may contribute to an increased risk of hip fractures in patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease. The purpose of the present study was to clarify the efficacy of interventions intended to prevent hip fractures in elderly patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease. PubMed was used to search the literature for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) regarding Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease and hip fractures. The inclusion criteria were 50 or more subjects per group and a study period of 1 year or longer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vertigo treated by Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/vertigo-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vertigo-treated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vertigo-bppv-greatly-reduced-by-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-april-2025">Vertigo (BPPV) greatly reduced by Vitamin D - meta-analysis April 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#87-reduction-in-recurrence-of-bppv-with-13-weeks-of-vitamin-d-2000-iu-daily---rct-aug-2024">87% reduction in recurrence of BPPV with 13 weeks of Vitamin D (2,000 IU daily) - RCT Aug 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-greatly-reduced-by-vitamin-d-in-those-who-were-deficient--aug-2024">BPPV greatly reduced by Vitamin D in those who were deficient – Aug 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-recurrences-decreased-with-vitamin-d-supplements--4-out-of-5-studies--feb-2024">BPPV recurrences decreased with Vitamin D supplements (4 out of 5 studies) – Feb 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-associated-with-low-vitamin-d---dr-berg-video-april2023">BPPV associated with low vitamin D - Dr. Berg Video April 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#those-still-dizzy-after-bppv-treatment-were-55-x-more-likely-to-have-low-vitamin-d--june2022">Those still dizzy after BPPV treatment were 5.5 X more likely to have low vitamin D – June 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-substantially-reduced-if-raise-vitamin-d-levels--aug2021">BPPV substantially reduced if raise Vitamin D levels – Aug 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vertigo-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-supplementation-reduced-relapse-pdf-costs-36---nov2021">Vertigo associated with low vitamin D, supplementation reduced relapse (PDF costs $36) - Nov 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-has-many-risk-factors-low-vitamin-d-is-one-of-them--meta-analysis-aug2020">BPPV has many risk factors, low Vitamin D is one of them – Meta-analysis Aug 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-risk-reduced-3x-with-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-aug--2020">BPPV risk reduced 3X with Vitamin D - meta-analysis Aug 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-2x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-of-18-studies-jan2020">BPPV 2X more likely if low Vitamin D - meta-analysis of 18 studies Jan 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-is-associated-with-bppv---meta-analysis-oct2019">Vitamin D is associated with BPPV - meta-analysis Oct 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-eliminated-by-vitamin-d--april2019">BPPV eliminated by Vitamin D – April 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-meta-analysis-found-no-association-with-low-vitamin-d-in-the-blood--oct2018">BPPV Meta-analysis found no association with low vitamin D in the blood- Oct 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#calcium-carbonate-crystals-in-ear-decrease-in-elderly-with-low-vit-d---april2018">Calcium Carbonate crystals in ear decrease in elderly with low Vit D - April 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-23x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficient---oct2012">BPPV 23X more likely if vitamin D deficient - Oct 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-reduced-5-x-by-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-every-2-weeks--2016-the-effect-of-serum-vitamin-d-normalization-in-preventing-recurrences-of-benign-paroxysmal-positional-vertigo-a-case-control-study-caspian-j-intern-med-2016-summer73173-177">BPPV reduced 5 X by 50,000 IU of vitamin D every 2 weeks - 2016** The effect of serum vitamin D normalization in preventing recurrences of benign paroxysmal positional vertigo: A case-control study. **Caspian J Intern Med. 2016 Summer;7(3):173-177.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-21-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---dec2017">BPPV 2.1 X more likely if low vitamin D - Dec 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bppv-much-more-common-with-low-vitamin-d---oct2016-serum-vitamin-d-and-recurrent-benign-paroxysmal-positional-vertigo-laryngoscope-investig-otolaryngol-2016-oct-2016150-153-doi-101002lio235httpsdoiorg101002lio235-ecollection-2016-dec">BPPV much more common with low vitamin D - Oct 2016** Serum vitamin D and recurrent benign paroxysmal positional vertigo. **Laryngoscope Investig Otolaryngol. 2016 Oct 20;1(6):150-153. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/lio2.35.">doi: 10.1002/lio2.35.&lt;/a> eCollection 2016 Dec.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vertigo-bppv-greatly-reduced-by-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-april-2025">Vertigo (BPPV) greatly reduced by Vitamin D - meta-analysis April 2025&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Association between vitamin D, vitamin D supplementation and benign paroxysmal positional vertigo: a systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Falls and Fractures</title><link>/posts/falls-and-fractures.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/falls-and-fractures.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h5 id="20-of-women-will-get-a-hip-fracture-in-their-lives">20% of women will get a hip fracture in their lives&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Estimation of the lifetime risk of hip fracture for women and men in Canada March 2012 FREE PDF &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00198-011-1652-8">doi: 10.1007/s00198-011-1652-8&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h5 id="predict-30-day-hip-fracture-mortality--the-only-controllable-variable-is-vitamin-d--sept-2023">Predict 30 day Hip fracture mortality – the only controllable variable is Vitamin D – Sept 2023&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Emergency department prediction model for 30-day mortality after hip fracture: the Spanish National Hip Fracture Registry (RNFC) cohort&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hip Int . 2023 Sep 5;&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/11207000231197818">doi: 10.1177/11207000231197818&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vertebral fracture 3X more likely with aortic calcification – Vitamins D3 and K2</title><link>/posts/vertebral-fracture-3x-more-likely-with-aortic-calcification-vitamins-d3-and-k2.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vertebral-fracture-3x-more-likely-with-aortic-calcification-vitamins-d3-and-k2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="aortic-calcification-and-bone-metabolism">Aortic Calcification and Bone Metabolism:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="the-relationship-between-aortic-calcification-bmd-vertebral-fracture-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-osteocalcin">The Relationship between Aortic Calcification, BMD, Vertebral Fracture, 25-Hydroxyvitamin D, and Osteocalcin.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Calcif Tissue Int. 2012 Sep 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim KJ, Kim KM, Park KH, Choi HS, Rhee Y, Lee YH, Cha BS, Kim MJ, Oh SM, Brown JK, Lim SK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Department of Internal Medicine, Yonsei University College of Medicine, 134 Shinchon-dong, Seodaemun-gu, Seoul, 120-752, South Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study was to investigate the relationship between aortic calcification (AC) and low bone mineral density (BMD), 25(OH)D, C-terminal telopeptide (CTx), and osteocalcin levels in Asian women. We also tried to find the association between AC and the risk of vertebral fracture. We included 769 patients in this study. All patients underwent QCT. Aortic calcium score (ACS) was quantified by the Agatston scoring method. Spinal fracture was defined by lumbar spine radiography.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vertebral fracture 7X more likely in diabetic men who were vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/vertebral-fracture-7x-more-likely-in-diabetic-men-who-were-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vertebral-fracture-7x-more-likely-in-diabetic-men-who-were-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-association-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-vertebral-fractures-in-patients-with-type-2-diabetes">The association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and vertebral fractures in patients with type 2 diabetes.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocr J. 2012 Oct 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim YJ, Park SO, Kim TH, Lee JH, Kim SH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kwandong University College of Medicine, Myongji Hospital, Koyang, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is an important regulator of bone health. Previous studies examining the association between vitamin D deficiency and osteoporotic fractures have reported conflicting results. The relationship between vitamin D status and risk of vertebral fractures in diabetic patients is unknown. The objective of this study was to examine whether low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels were associated with vertebral fractures in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. This cross-sectional study was conducted among 161 postmenopausal women and 180 men with type 2 diabetes. Serum concentrations of 25(OH)D were measured and the presence of vertebral fracture was assessed using lateral plain radiographs of the thoracolumbar spine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D was not a predictor of osteoporosis fractures</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-was-not-a-predictor-of-osteoporosis-fractures.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-was-not-a-predictor-of-osteoporosis-fractures.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D may prevent falls and fractures without Calcium – an overview of 9 meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-may-prevent-falls-and-fractures-without-calcium-an-overview-of-9-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-may-prevent-falls-and-fractures-without-calcium-an-overview-of-9-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="do-we-need-to-take-calcium-with-vitamin-d-supplements-to-prevent-falls-fractures-and-death">Do we need to take calcium with vitamin D supplements to prevent falls, fractures, and death?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2012 Oct 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scragg R, School of Population Health, University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE OF REVIEW:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 2011 report by the US Institute of Medicine (IOM) on dietary reference intakes for calcium and vitamin D is based on meta-analyses of randomized controlled trials (RCTs), which concluded that vitamin D supplements need to be taken with calcium supplements to prevent falls, fractures, and all-cause mortality. This study reviews recent meta-analyses of RCTs of vitamin D supplementation to determine whether their conclusions are consistent with the meta-analyses underpinning the IOM report.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces falls and fractures for some</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-falls-and-fractures-for-some.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-falls-and-fractures-for-some.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-falls-and-fractures">The effect of Vitamin D on falls and fractures&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Scand J Clin Lab Invest Suppl. 2012 Apr;243:73-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ringe JD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>West-German Osteoporosis Center (WOZ), Medizin, Klinik 4, Klinikum Leverkusen, University of Cologne, Germany. &lt;a href="mailto:ringe@klinikum-lev.de">ringe@klinikum-lev.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#090;">Probably presented at the Bermeyer Coonference in Garmishpartenkirchen (Germany) in March 2012&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D (cholecalciferol) is important for normal development and maintenance of the skeleton. The metabolites 25(OH)D and 1,25(OH)(2)D are not only important for treating rickets and osteomalacia but also for all types and clinical stages of osteoporosis. Patients with low calcium intake and a low vitamin D status are at risk to develop secondary hyperparathyroidism, increased bone resorbtion, osteopenia and fractures. This can be counteracted by a lifelong sufficient vitamin D supply plus dietary or supplementary calcium. The effects of vitamin D on muscle, balance and cognitive functions may be an added value in fracture prevention.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D not associated with PAD after adjusting for race, diabetes and BMI</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-not-associated-with-pad-after-adjusting-for-race-diabetes-and-bmi.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-not-associated-with-pad-after-adjusting-for-race-diabetes-and-bmi.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-status-and-functional-performance-in-peripheral-artery-disease">Vitamin D status and functional performance in peripheral artery disease&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Vascular Med July 19, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary M McDermott &lt;a href="mailto:mdm608@northwestern.edu">mdm608@northwestern.edu&lt;/a>, Department of Medicine, Northwestern University’s Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kiang Liu. Department of Preventive Medicine, Northwestern University’s Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luigi Ferrucci. Longitudinal Studies Section, National Institute on Aging, Baltimore, MD, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lu Tian, Department of Health and Research Policy, Stanford University, Palo Alto, CA, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fractures reduced 30 percent with 800 IU of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-reduced-30-percent-with-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-pooled-analysis-of-vitamin-d-dose-requirements-for-fracture-prevention">A pooled analysis of vitamin D dose requirements for fracture prevention.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med. 2012 Jul 5;367(1):40-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Willett WC, Orav EJ, Lips P, Meunier PJ, Lyons RA, Flicker L, Wark J, Jackson RD, Cauley JA, Meyer HE, Pfeifer M, Sanders KM, Stähelin HB, Theiler R, Dawson-Hughes B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center on Aging and Mobility, University of Zurich and Waid City Hospital, Zurich, Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: The results of meta-analyses examining the relationship between vitamin D supplementation and fracture reduction have been inconsistent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ankle strength and vitamin D lowest in winter, and were associated with more elderly falls</title><link>/posts/ankle-strength-and-vitamin-d-lowest-in-winter-and-were-associated-with-more-elderly-falls.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ankle-strength-and-vitamin-d-lowest-in-winter-and-were-associated-with-more-elderly-falls.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="serum-span25ohdspan-status-ankle-strength-and-activity-show-seasonal-variation-in-older-adults">Serum &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> status, ankle strength and activity show seasonal variation in older adults:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>relevance for winter falls in higher latitudes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Age Ageing (2012) Received November 27, 2011.; Accepted April 5, 2012.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First published online: May 14, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marie-Louise Bird1?, Keith D. Hill2, Iain K. Robertson1, Madeleine J. Ball1, Jane Pittaway1 and Andrew D. Williams1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Human Life Sciences, University of Tasmania, Launceston, Tasmania 7250, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Physiotherapy, Curtin University, Perth, Western Australia 6845, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Declining hip fracture rates in the United States – unknown reason</title><link>/posts/declining-hip-fracture-rates-in-the-united-states-unknown-reason.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/declining-hip-fracture-rates-in-the-united-states-unknown-reason.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="declining-hip-fracture-rates-in-the-united-states">Declining hip fracture rates in the United States&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Age Ageing (2010) 39 (4): 500-503. Received September 16, 2009. Revision received April 6, 2010. Accepted April 11, 2010. First published online: May 19, 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Judy A. Stevens &lt;a href="mailto:jas2@cdc.gov">jas2@cdc.gov&lt;/a> and Rose Anne Rudd&lt;/p>
&lt;p>National Center for Injury Prevention and Control, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 4770 Buford Highway NE, Mailstop F-62, Atlanta, GA 30341, USA Tel: (+1) 770 488 4649 ; Fax: (+1) 770 488 1317.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Task force for senior fall prevention finally recommends 800 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/task-force-for-senior-fall-prevention-finally-recommends-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/task-force-for-senior-fall-prevention-finally-recommends-800-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="prevention-of-falls-in-community-dwelling-older-adults">Prevention of Falls in Community-Dwelling Older Adults:&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="us-preventive-services-task-force-recommendation-statement">U.S. Preventive Services Task Force Recommendation Statement&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Virginia A. Moyer, MD, MPH, on behalf of the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force, Rockville, Maryland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annals of Internal Medicine May 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Description: Update of the 1996 U.S. Preventive Services Task Force (USPSTF) recommendation statement on counseling to prevent household and recreational injuries, including falls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: The USPSTF reviewed new evidence on the effectiveness and harms of primary care–relevant interventions to prevent falls in community-dwelling older adults. The interventions were grouped into 5 main categories: multifactorial clinical assessment (with or without direct intervention), clinical management (with or without screening), clinical education or behavioral counseling, home hazard modification, and exercise or physical therapy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium (alone) does not reduce risk of bone fracture</title><link>/posts/calcium-alone-does-not-reduce-risk-of-bone-fracture.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-alone-does-not-reduce-risk-of-bone-fracture.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Falls of elderly whites increasing 5 percent per year</title><link>/posts/falls-of-elderly-whites-increasing-5-percent-per-year.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/falls-of-elderly-whites-increasing-5-percent-per-year.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="unintentional-falls-mortality-among-elderly-in-the-united-states-time-for-action">Unintentional falls mortality among elderly in the United States: Time for action&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Injury January 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hasanat Alamgira, &lt;a href="mailto:Abul.H.Alamgirr@uth.tmc.edu">Abul.H.Alamgirr@uth.tmc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sana Muazzamb,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Muazzam Nasrullahc&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a University of Texas, School of Public Health, TX, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Injury Control Research Center, West Virginia University, Morgantown, WV, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c Rollins School of Public Health, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fall injury is a leading cause of death and disability among older adults. The objective of this study is to identify the groups among the ?65 population by age, gender, race, ethnicity and state of residence which are most vulnerable to unintentional fall mortality and report the trends in falls mortality in the United States.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Only half of bone fracture patients were given treatment, the most popular being vitamin D</title><link>/posts/only-half-of-bone-fracture-patients-were-given-treatment-the-most-popular-being-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/only-half-of-bone-fracture-patients-were-given-treatment-the-most-popular-being-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-fracture---intervention-program-optimizes-the-management-of-osteoporosis">A fracture - intervention program optimizes the management of osteoporosis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Geriatr Psychol Neuropsychiatr Vieil. 2011 Dec 1;9(4):437-444.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Retornaz F, Seux V, Pauly V, Nouvellet S, Flecher X, Soubeyrand J, Reynaud-Levy O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre gérontologique départemental, Marseille, EA3279, Évaluation des systèmes de soins - santé perçue, Université de la Méditerranée, Marseille.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite the high morbidity and mortality rate of osteoporosis, the proportion of patients who receive appropriate diagnosis and treatment remains very low. A specific osteoporosis program increased the percentage of patients receiving diagnosis and/or treatment for osteoporosis. We set up a program to improve diagnosis and treatment of patients with low-trauma fractures or suspicion of osteoporosis. Two geriatricians were especially designated for this program. The program included patients admitted to the emergency room, inpatients and outpatients from the orthopedic department or the internal medicine/geriatric department. The assessment was performed over two visits and included an evaluation of risk factors for osteoporosis and falls, a physical examination, a collection of biological parameters, and Dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry. In the second visit the physician prescribed, if appropriate, anti-osteoporotic treatment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kaiser working to decrease hip and other fractures</title><link>/posts/kaiser-working-to-decrease-hip-and-other-fractures.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kaiser-working-to-decrease-hip-and-other-fractures.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="click-here-for-original-press-releasehttpwwwprnewswirecomnews-releasesleading-health-organizations-and-patient-groups-call-for-20-percent-reduction-in-fractures-by-2020-133909108html20">&lt;a href="http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/leading-health-organizations-and-patient-groups-call-for-20-percent-reduction-in-fractures-by-2020-133909108.html%20">CLICK HERE for original Press Release&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>No mention of vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="leading-health-organizations-and-patient-groups-call-for-20-percent-reduction-in-fractures-by-2020">Leading Health Organizations and Patient Groups Call for 20 Percent Reduction in Fractures by 2020&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;20/20 Vision&amp;rdquo; Summit Shares Best Practices for Osteoporosis/Fracture Prevention and Care&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WASHINGTON, Nov. 15, 2011 /PRNewswire/ &amp;ndash; The National Bone Health Alliance (NBHA) and Kaiser Permanente unveiled on Monday their &amp;ldquo;20/20 Vision&amp;rdquo; for reducing hip and other fractures by 20 percent by 2020 at a best practices sharing event Monday at the &lt;strong>Kaiser Permanente Center for Total Health on Capitol Hill.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Risk of falls minimized with just 24 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/risk-of-falls-minimized-with-just-24-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/risk-of-falls-minimized-with-just-24-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="symposium-1-vitamins-and-cognitive-development-and-performance-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-muscle-atrophy-in-the-elderly">Symposium 1: Vitamins and cognitive development and performance Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and muscle atrophy in the elderly&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Bess Dawson-Hughes &lt;a href="mailto:Bess.Dawson-Hughes@Tufts.edu">Bess.Dawson-Hughes@Tufts.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Proceedings of the Nutrition Society, Page 1 of 4 doi:10.1017/S0029665111003260 © The Author 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A meeting of the Nutrition Society hosted by the Irish Section jointly with the American Society for Nutrition was held at University&lt;/p>
&lt;p>College Cork, Republic of Ireland on 15—17 June 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>70th Anniversary Conference on &amp;lsquo;Vitamins in early development and healthy aging: impact on infectious and chronic disease&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fraser Health in Canada will be giving 20000 IU vitamin D weekly to reduce falls</title><link>/posts/fraser-health-in-canada-will-be-giving-20000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-to-reduce-falls.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fraser-health-in-canada-will-be-giving-20000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-to-reduce-falls.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="news-releasehttpwwwfraserhealthcaabout_usmedia_centrenews_releases2011_news_releasesnew_vitamin_d_protocol_helps_prevent_falls_and_fractures_in_residential_care">&lt;a href="http://www.fraserhealth.ca/about_us/media_centre/news_releases/2011_news_releases/new_vitamin_d_protocol_helps_prevent_falls_and_fractures_in_residential_care">News Release&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Optional for all Fraser Health 7,500 senior residents in Western Canada&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cost per year to Fraser Health of providing the vitamin D is estimated to about that of the cost of a single hip fracture , $20,000&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before vitamin D they had 1,000 to 1,500 falls per year&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They hope to prevent 10% to 25% of the falls per year&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus they hope to prevent 100 to about 300 falls per year&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chance of a fall decreased with vitamin D3 but increased with D2</title><link>/posts/chance-of-a-fall-decreased-with-vitamin-d3-but-increased-with-d2.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chance-of-a-fall-decreased-with-vitamin-d3-but-increased-with-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="relevance-of-vitamin-d-in-muscle-health">Relevance of vitamin D in muscle health.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2011 Oct 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bischoff-Ferrari HA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centre on Aging and Mobility, University of Zurich and City Hospital Waid, Gloriastrasse 25, 8091, Zurich, Switzerland, &lt;a href="mailto:Heike.Bischoff@usz.ch">Heike.Bischoff@usz.ch&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This review will summarize the impact of vitamin D deficiency on muscle health. Mechanistic evidence regarding the presence of the specific vitamin D receptor in muscle tissue and muscle biopsy abnormalities observed with deficiency will be reviewed, as well as molecular and non-molecular effects of vitamin D in muscle tissue. At the clinical level, the evidence from randomized controlled trials of vitamin D supplementation on functional improvement and fall reduction will be summarized. Further, the manuscript will discuss whether vitamin D effects on fall prevention modulate in part its benefit on fracture prevention and why fall prevention is essential in fracture prevention at higher age. Finally, trial and epidemiological data will be reviewed to assess desirable serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels for optimal muscle health.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces falls – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-falls-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-falls-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-falls-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">The Effect of Vitamin D on Falls: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism October 1, 2011 vol. 96 no. 10 2997-3006&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohammad Hassan Murad,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Khalid B. Elamin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nisrin O. Abu Elnour,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohamed B. Elamin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aziz A. Alkatib,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mitra M. Fatourechi,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jaime P. Almandoz,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rebecca J. Mullan,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Melanie A. Lane,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hau Liu,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patricia J. Erwin,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Donald D. Hensrud and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Victor M. Montori&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Knowledge and Encounter Research Unit (M.H.M., N.O.A.E., M.B.E., A.A.A., M.M.F., J.P.A., R.J.M., M.A.L., P.J.E., V.M.M.), and Division of Preventive, Occupational, and Aerospace Medicine (M.H.M., D.D.H.), Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota 55905; Department of Medicine (K.B.E.), Case Western Reserve University, Metrohealth Medical Center, Cleveland, Ohio 44109; Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes, Metabolism, and Nutrition (V.M.M.), Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota 55905; and Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism (H.L.), Santa Clara Valley Medical Center, San Jose, California 95128&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active form of vitamin D (calcitriol) cut in half the fractures following organ transplant – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/active-form-of-vitamin-d-calcitriol-cut-in-half-the-fractures-following-organ-tr-t-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/active-form-of-vitamin-d-calcitriol-cut-in-half-the-fractures-following-organ-tr-t-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>30 percent less chance of dying after hip fracture if take vitamin D and other drugs – 2011</title><link>/posts/30-percent-less-chance-of-dying-after-hip-fracture-if-take-vitamin-d-and-other-drugs-2011.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/30-percent-less-chance-of-dying-after-hip-fracture-if-take-vitamin-d-and-other-drugs-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="post-hip-fracture-use-of-prescribed-calcium-plus-vitamin-d-or-vitamin-d-supplements-and-anti-osteoporotic-drugs-are-associated-with-lower-mortality-a-nationwide-study-in-finland">Post-hip fracture use of prescribed calcium plus vitamin D or vitamin D supplements and anti-osteoporotic drugs are associated with lower mortality. A nationwide study in Finland†&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ilona Nurmi-Lüthje1,2,* &lt;a href="mailto:ilona.nurmi@pp.inet.fi">ilona.nurmi@pp.inet.fi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reijo Sund3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Merja Juntunen3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter Lüthje4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Center for Injury and Violence Prevention, Health Center of Kouvola, FI-45100 Kouvola, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Hjelt Institute, Department of Public Health, FI-00014 Helsinki University, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 National Institute for Health and Welfare, FI-00271 Helsinki, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 North Kymi Hospital, FI-45750 Kuusankoski, Finland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X more falls for senior men with less than 20ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/2x-more-falls-for-senior-men-with-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-falls-for-senior-men-with-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="relationships-between-serum-vitamin-d-levels-neuromuscular-and-neuropsychological-function-and-falls-in-older-men-and-women">Relationships between serum vitamin D levels, neuromuscular and neuropsychological function and falls in older men and women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Apr 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Menant JC, Close JC, Delbaere K, Sturnieks DL, Trollor J, Sachdev PS, Brodaty H, Lord SR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Falls and Balance Research Group, Neuroscience Research Australia, University of New South Wales, Barker Street, Randwick, NSW, 2031, Sydney, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among 463 community dwellers aged 70-90 years, those with vitamin D insufficiency showed reduced neuromuscular function, balance control and stepping ability and performed worse in tests of cognitive function. In men, vitamin D insufficiency was associated with an increased risk of falling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Role of the orthopaedic surgeon in fragility fractures</title><link>/posts/role-of-the-orthopaedic-surgeon-in-fragility-fractures.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/role-of-the-orthopaedic-surgeon-in-fragility-fractures.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="what-is-the-role-of-the-orthopaedic-surgeon-in-management-of-fragility-fractures">What is the role of the orthopaedic surgeon in management of fragility fractures?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Orthop Trauma. 2011 Jun;25 Suppl 1:S47-50.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sharif KM, Dimitriou R, Giannoudis PV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trauma &amp;amp; Orthopaedics, Manor Hospital, Walsall, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fragility fractures are the most prevalent trauma condition that orthopaedic surgeons face today. Osteoporosis and susceptibility to falls are the key predisposing factors. Despite evidence supporting the impact of treating osteoporosis on reducing the incidence of fragility fractures, it is often left untreated. Orthopaedic surgeons are often the first physicians to assess and treat the patient after a fragility fracture. Their role therefore does not end in the skillful fixation of the fractures, but they have a unique opportunity to ensure that preventive measures are implemented. This includes falls prevention, investigation of possible causes underlying osteoporosis, attention to diet, exercise, calcium, and vitamin D supplementation as well as prescription of anti-resorptive and anabolic medication. The need for a dedicated multidisciplinary team needs to be emphasized and therefore effective communication between the different parties is of paramount importance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Majority of animal bone fractures healed more quickly with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/majority-of-animal-bone-fractures-healed-more-quickly-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/majority-of-animal-bone-fractures-healed-more-quickly-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="is-supplementation-of-vitamin-d-beneficial-for-fracture-healing">Is Supplementation of Vitamin D Beneficial for Fracture Healing?&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-short-review-of-the-literature">A Short Review of the Literature&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Daniel Eschle, Dr. med. &lt;a href="mailto:d.eschle@rehaclinic.ch">d.eschle@rehaclinic.ch&lt;/a>; André G. Aeschlimann&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Geriatric Orthopaedic Surgery &amp;amp; Rehabilitation May 23, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been a surge of interest regarding the benefits of vitamin D supplementation to prevent fractures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But can it also make them heal more quickly once they have occurred—that is, is supplementation of vitamin D beneficial for fracture healing?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fracture patients had only 16 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hip-fracture-patients-had-only-16-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fracture-patients-had-only-16-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-in-hip-and-spine-fracture-patients-in-japan">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status in hip and spine-fracture patients in Japan.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Orthop Sci. 2011 May 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sakuma M, Endo N, Hagino H, Harada A, Matsui Y, Nakano T, Nakamura K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Medical Technology, Niigata University of Health and Welfare, Niigata, Japan, &lt;a href="mailto:m-sakuma@nuhw.ac.jp">m-sakuma@nuhw.ac.jp&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) is used as an index that reflects the level of vitamin D. We have previously reported, on the basis of a study in Sado in Niigata, that patients with hip fracture have lower serum 25(OH)D levels than non-hip-fracture cases. In this study, the serum 25(OH)D status in hip-fracture cases was examined in four regions in Japan. Although most hip-fracture patients have experienced past spine-compression fractures, the relationship of these fractures and 25(OH)D is unknown. Therefore, we also examined the 25(OH)D level in spine-compression fracture patients in the same locations and time periods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Most people with bone fractures still not getting vitamin D</title><link>/posts/most-people-with-bone-fractures-still-not-getting-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/most-people-with-bone-fractures-still-not-getting-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-deficiency-in-the-acute-inpatient-rehabilitation-population-and-its-effect-on-function">Prevalence of 25-hydroxyvitamin d deficiency in the acute inpatient rehabilitation population and its effect on function.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2011 May;92(5):705-11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pellicane AJ, Wysocki NM, Mallinson TR, Schnitzer TJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wayne State University, Rehabilitation Institute of Michigan, Detroit, MI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: To assess the prevalence of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) insufficiency and deficiency in the acute inpatient rehabilitation setting, identify risk factors associated with low serum 25(OH)D levels, and assess whether hypovitaminosis D affects the function of rehabilitation patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Having less than 25 ng of vitamin D was associated with severe hip fracture</title><link>/posts/having-less-than-25-ng-of-vitamin-d-was-associated-with-severe-hip-fracture.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/having-less-than-25-ng-of-vitamin-d-was-associated-with-severe-hip-fracture.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-as-a-risk-factor-of-hip-fracture-severity">Hypovitaminosis D as a risk factor of hip fracture severity.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Mar 11&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Larrosa M, Gomez A, Casado E, Moreno M, Vázquez I, Orellana C, Berlanga E, Ramon J, Gratacos J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatology Department, University Institute Parc Taulí (UAB), Parc Tauli s/n, 08208, Sabadell, Barcelona, Spain, &lt;a href="mailto:mlarrosa@tauli.cat">mlarrosa@tauli.cat&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a cross-sectional study including 324 patients older than 65 years admitted to our hospital for osteoporotic hip fracture, we found that those patients with a more severe vitamin D deficiency had more severe osteoporotic hip fractures (Garden grades III-IV and Kyle III-IV).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Vitamin D and Vitamin K: brittle bones and hardened arteries – LEF</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-brittle-bones-and-hardened-arteries-lef.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-and-vitamin-k-brittle-bones-and-hardened-arteries-lef.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fracture patients with bone diseases lacked vitamin D and calcium</title><link>/posts/fracture-patients-with-bone-diseases-lacked-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fracture-patients-with-bone-diseases-lacked-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="contributors-to-secondary-osteoporosis-and-metabolic-bone-diseases-in-patients-presenting-with-a-clinical-fracture">Contributors to Secondary Osteoporosis and Metabolic Bone Diseases in Patients Presenting with a Clinical Fracture.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Mar 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bours SP, van Geel TA, Geusens PP, Janssen MJ, Janzing HM, Hoffland GA, Willems PC, van den Bergh JP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine (S.P.G.B., J.P.W.v.d.B.), Laboratory of Clinical Chemistry and Haematology (M.J.W.J.), Department of Surgery (H.M.J.J.), Department of Radiology (G.A.H.), VieCuri Medisch Centrum Noord-Limburg, 5912 BL Venlo, The Netherlands; Department of Internal Medicine (S.P.G.B.), Subdivision Endocrinology, and Department of Orthopedic Surgery (P.C.W.), Maastricht University Medical Centre, 6202 AZ Maastricht, The Netherlands; Department of General Practice (T.A.C.M.v.G.), Department of Internal Medicine (P.P.M.M.G.), Subdivision Rheumatology, Maastricht University/CAPHRI School for Public Health and Primary Care, 6200 MD Maastricht, The Netherlands; Biomedical Research Centre (P.P.M.M.G.), University Hasselt, B-3590 Diepenbeek, Belgium; and Department of Internal Medicine (J.P.W.v.d.B.), Maastricht University Medical Centre/School for Nutrition, Toxicology, and Metabolism, 6200 MD Maastricht, The Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hip fractures worse if very low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hip-fractures-worse-if-very-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-fractures-worse-if-very-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-as-a-risk-factor-of-hip-fracture-severity">Hypovitaminosis D as a risk factor of hip fracture severity.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Mar 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Larrosa M, Gomez A, Casado E, Moreno M, Vázquez I, Orellana C, Berlanga E, Ramon J, Gratacos J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rheumatology Department, University Institute Parc Taulí (UAB), Parc Tauli s/n, 08208, Sabadell, Barcelona, Spain, &lt;a href="mailto:mlarrosa@tauli.cat">mlarrosa@tauli.cat&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a cross-sectional study including 324 patients older than 65 years admitted to our hospital for osteoporotic hip fracture, we found that those patients with a more severe vitamin D deficiency had more severe osteoporotic hip fractures (Garden grades III-IV and Kyle III-IV).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of non-bone effects of vitamin D on fall prevention</title><link>/posts/review-of-non-bone-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-fall-prevention.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-non-bone-effects-of-vitamin-d-on-fall-prevention.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="fall-prevention-and-vitamin-d-in-the-elderly-an-overview-of-the-key-role-of-the-non-bone-effects">Fall prevention and vitamin D in the elderly: an overview of the key role of the non-bone effects.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2010 Oct 11;7:50.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annweiler C, Montero-Odasso M, Schott AM, Berrut G, Fantino B, Beauchet O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine and Geriatrics, Angers University Hospital, Angers University Memory Center, UPRES EA 2646, University of Angers, UNAM, Angers, France. &lt;a href="mailto:ceannweiler@chu-angers.fr">ceannweiler@chu-angers.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Preventing falls and fall-related fractures in the elderly is an objective yet to be reached. There is increasing evidence that a supplementation of vitamin D and/or of calcium may reduce the fall and fracture rates. A vitamin D-calcium supplement appears to have a high potential due to its simple application and its low cost. However, published studies have shown conflicting results as some studies failed to show any effect, while others reported a significant decrease of falls and fractures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>75 percent of hip fractures associated with vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/75-percent-of-hip-fractures-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/75-percent-of-hip-fractures-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="three-fourths-of-hip-fractures-in-the-elderly-are-related-to-vitamin-d-deficiency-experts-say">Three-fourths of hip fractures in the elderly are related to vitamin D deficiency, experts say&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.endocrineweb.com/news/osteoporosis/3953-three-fourths-hip-fractures-elderly-are-related-vitamin-d-deficiency-experts">http://www.endocrineweb.com/news/osteoporosis/3953-three-fourths-hip-fractures-elderly-are-related-vitamin-d-deficiency-experts&lt;/a>–&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Researchers from India have found that three-quarters of osteoporosis-related hip fractures are related to vitamin D deficiency, according to statistics delivered at the First Asia-Pacific Regional Osteoporosis Meeting held in Singapore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a study of 90 hip-fracture patients and an equal number of unafflicted peers, scientists in New Delhi measured the levels of a number of vitamins and human hormones in blood donated by participants.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wrist fracture is also associated with vitamin D inadequacy</title><link>/posts/wrist-fracture-is-also-associated-with-vitamin-d-inadequacy.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wrist-fracture-is-also-associated-with-vitamin-d-inadequacy.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="two-items-on-this-page">two items on this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="44-percent-of-postmenopausal-wrist-fractures-had-low-vitamin-d--sept-2011">44 percent of postmenopausal wrist fractures had low vitamin D – Sept 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="from-american-society-for-bone-and-mineral-research-httpwwwasbmrorgitinerarypresentationdetailaspxidfcdadcdd-9898-4825-81be-b13d1e13aed020">From &lt;a href="http://www.asbmr.org/Itinerary/PresentationDetail.aspx?id=fcdadcdd-9898-4825-81be-b13d1e13aed0%20">American Society for Bone and Mineral Research &lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="hypovitaminosis-d-in-postmenopausal-women-with-a-distal-radius-fracture">Hypovitaminosis D in Postmenopausal Women with a Distal Radius Fracture&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Poster Sessions, Presentation Number: SU0377&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presenting Author(s): Hyun Sik Gong, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, ROK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>September 18, 2011 11:00 AM — 1:00 PM; San Diego Convention Center, Hall GH&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(later presented at presented at the 2012 Annual Meeting of the American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons (AAOS).)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Fractures and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-fractures-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-fractures-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/09/27/well/live/broken-bone-fracture-risk.html">&amp;quot;..only 9 percent of Medicare patients who sustained a hip or spinal fracture were tested for bone loss and offered treatment to head off a future fracture.&amp;quot;&lt;/a> NYT Sept 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Hip Fractures in Older Adults - JAMA 2019&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most estimates of risk of elderly fracture do not consider the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>    falls, cognitive impairment, urinary incontinence, neurological conditions, and medications&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Continues to recommend Vitamin D sufficiency (&amp;gt;30ng?)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/hip-fractures-in-older-adults-in-2019.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No reduction in Finish fractures with 800 IU Vitamin D3 and Calcium</title><link>/posts/no-reduction-in-finish-fractures-with-800-iu-vitamin-d3-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-reduction-in-finish-fractures-with-800-iu-vitamin-d3-and-calcium.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Overview Fractures and Falls and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-fractures-and-falls-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-fractures-and-falls-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="8-of-hospitalisations--for-falls-and-hip-fractures-in-australia-were-attributable-to-vitamin-d-deficiency-20-ng">8% of hospitalisations for falls and hip fractures in Australia were attributable to vitamin D deficiency (&amp;lt;20 ng)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hospitalisations for falls and hip fractures attributable to vitamin D deficiency in older Australians - Jan 2021&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0007114521000416">doi: 10.1017/S0007114521000416&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h5 id="it-has-been-known-since-year-2000-that-nerve-conduction-velocity-speeds-up-with-increased-vitamin-d---see-following-graph">It has been known since year 2000 that nerve conduction velocity speeds up with increased vitamin D - see following graph&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>{IMG(fileId=&amp;ldquo;420&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="juventhttpwwwjuventcomhealth-micro-impact-platform---3500---nov-2017">&lt;a href="http://www.juvent.com/health/">Juvent&lt;/a> Micro-Impact Platform - $3,500 - Nov 2017&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Computer and software find the resonant frequency of the user in a safe range of frequencies (32Hz-37Hz) and therefore is able to use a very small level of energy (.3g) to deliver a physiologically effective energy pulse.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D 2nd most recommended way to prevent next hip fracture</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-2nd-most-recommended-way-to-prevent-next-hip-fracture.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-2nd-most-recommended-way-to-prevent-next-hip-fracture.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="hip-fracture-prevention-strategies-in-long-term-care-a-survey-of-canadian-physicians-opinions">Hip fracture prevention strategies in long-term care: A survey of Canadian physicians’ opinions&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Canadian Family Physician&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol. 56, No. 11, November 2010, pp.e392 - e397&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anna M. Sawka, MD PhD FRCPC -Endocrinologist and clinician scientist at the University Health Network in Toronto, Ont, an Assistant Professor at the University of Toronto, and holds a Health Services Research Chair from Cancer Care Ontario&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nofisat Ismaila - Research analyst at the University Health Network at the time of submission&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 instead of 11 fractures with Parkinson disease when have enough sun</title><link>/posts/3-instead-of-11-fractures-with-parkinson-disease-when-have-enough-sun.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-instead-of-11-fractures-with-parkinson-disease-when-have-enough-sun.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>