<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer - Prostate on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer---prostate.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer - Prostate on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer---prostate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advanced Prostate Cancer 2X more likely if less than 20ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/advanced-prostate-cancer-2x-more-likely-if-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/advanced-prostate-cancer-2x-more-likely-if-less-than-20ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="associations-of-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-with-prostate-cancer-diagnosis-stage-and-grade">Associations of circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D with prostate cancer diagnosis, stage and grade.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int J Cancer. 2011 Oct 27. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ijc.27327.">doi: 10.1002/ijc.27327.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gilbert R, Metcalfe C, Fraser WD, Donovan J, Hamdy F, Neal DE, Athene Lane J, Martin RM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Social and Community Medicine, University of Bristol. &lt;a href="mailto:Becky.Gilbert@bristol.ac.uk">Becky.Gilbert@bristol.ac.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiological studies suggest that vitamin D protects against prostate cancer, although evidence is limited and inconsistent. We investigated associations of circulating total 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) with PSA-detected prostate cancer in a case-control study nested within the Prostate Testing for Cancer and Treatment (ProtecT) trial. Conditional logistic regression was used to estimate odds ratios (OR) and 95% confidence intervals (CI) quantifying the association between circulating total 25(OH)D and prostate cancer. In case-only analyses, we used unconditional logistic regression to quantify associations of total 25(OH)D with stage (advanced vs localized) and Gleason grade (high-grade (?7) vs low-grade (&amp;lt;7)). Pre-determined categories of total 25(OH)D were defined as: high: ?30ng/mL; adequate: 20-&amp;lt;30ng/mL; insufficient: 12-&amp;lt;20ng/mL; deficient: &amp;lt;12ng/mL. Fractional polynomials were used to investigate the existence of any U-shaped relationship. We included 1,447 prostate cancer cases (153 advanced, 469 high-grade) and 1,449 healthy controls.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unsure of association of vitamin D and prostate Cancer - 2011</title><link>/posts/unsure-of-association-of-vitamin-d-and-prostate-cancer-2011.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/unsure-of-association-of-vitamin-d-and-prostate-cancer-2011.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cancers and Vitamin D Council</title><link>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>More likely to develop Prostate Cancer if have high level of vitamin D in Finland</title><link>/posts/more-likely-to-develop-prostate-cancer-if-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d-in-finland.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-likely-to-develop-prostate-cancer-if-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d-in-finland.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-and-prostate-cancer-risk-in-a-large-nested-casecontrol-study">Serum 25-Hydroxy Vitamin D and Prostate Cancer Risk in a Large Nested Case–Control Study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Demetrius Albanes, Alison M. Mondul, Kai Yu, Dominick Parisi, Ronald L. Horst, Jarmo Virtamo, Stephanie J. Weinstein&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors&amp;rsquo; Affiliations: 1Nutritional Epidemiology Branch and 2 Biostatistics Branch, Division of Cancer Epidemiology and Genetics, National Cancer Institute, Bethesda; 3 Information Management Services, Silver Spring, Maryland; 4 Heartland Assays Inc., Ames, Iowa; and 5 Department of Chronic Disease Prevention, National Institute for Health and Welfare, Helsinki, Finland.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Undiagnosed osteoporosis is frequent in prostate cancer</title><link>/posts/undiagnosed-osteoporosis-is-frequent-in-prostate-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/undiagnosed-osteoporosis-is-frequent-in-prostate-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vertebral-fractures-and-the-misclassification-of-osteoporosis-in-men-with-prostate-cancer">Vertebral Fractures and the Misclassification of Osteoporosis in Men With Prostate Cancer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Densitometry doi:10.1016/j.jocd.2011.05.003&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah Sullivan1, Julie Wagner1, Neil M. Resnick1, Joel Nelson2, Subashan K. Perera1 and Susan L. Greenspan1, corressponding author&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Medicine, Department of Medicine, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 School of Urology, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 16 March 2011; revised 11 May 2011; accepted 11 May 2011; Available online 1 July 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prostate Cancer – Vitamin D – CYP27B1 – CYP24</title><link>/posts/prostate-cancer-vitamin-d-cyp27b1-cyp24.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prostate-cancer-vitamin-d-cyp27b1-cyp24.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-metabolism-and-action-in-the-prostate-implications-for-health-and-disease">Vitamin D metabolism and action in the prostate: Implications for health and disease.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-metabolism-and-action-in-the-prostate-implications-for-health-and-disease">Vitamin D metabolism and action in the prostate: Implications for health and disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2011 Jun 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Swami S, Krishnan AV, Feldman D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, CA 94305, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prostate cancer (PCa) is the second most common cancer in men worldwide. Epidemiological, molecular, and cellular studies have implicated vitamin D deficiency as a risk factor for the development and/or progression of PCa. Studies using cell culture systems and animal models suggest that vitamin D acts to reduce the growth of PCa through regulation of cellular proliferation and differentiation. However, although preclinical studies provide a strong indication for anti-cancer activity, proof of therapeutic benefits in men is still lacking. The anti-proliferative and pro-differentiating properties of vitamin D have been attributed to calcitriol &lt;span>[1,25(OH)(2)D(3)]&lt;/span>, the hormonally active form of vitamin D, acting through the vitamin D receptor (VDR). Metabolism of vitamin D in target tissues is mediated by two key enzymes: 1?-hydroxylase (CYP27B1), which catalyzes the synthesis of calcitriol from 25(OH)D and 24-hydroxylase (CYP24), which catalyzes the initial step in the conversion of calcitriol to less active metabolites. Many factors affect the balance of calcitriol synthesis and catabolism and several maneuvers, like combination therapy of calcitriol with other drugs, have been explored to treat PCa and reduce its risk. The current paper is an overview addressing some of the key factors that influence the biological actions of vitamin D and its metabolites in the treatment and/or prevention of PCa.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>59 percent more likely to die of Prostate Cancer if very low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/59-percent-more-likely-to-die-of-prostate-cancer-if-very-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/59-percent-more-likely-to-die-of-prostate-cancer-if-very-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Prediagnostic Plasma Vitamin D Metabolites and Mortality among Patients with Prostate Cancer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2011 Apr 6;6(4):e18625.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fang F, Kasperzyk JL, Shui I, Hendrickson W, Hollis BW, Fall K, Ma J, Gaziano JM, Stampfer MJ, Mucci LA, Giovannucci E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Channing Laboratory, Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, United States of America.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Laboratory evidence suggests that vitamin D might influence prostate cancer prognosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Risk of Prostate Cancer weakly associated with vitamin D - meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/risk-of-prostate-cancer-weakly-associated-with-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/risk-of-prostate-cancer-weakly-associated-with-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="associations-of-circulating-and-dietary-vitamin-d-with-prostate-cancer-risk-a-systematic-review-and-dose-response-meta-analysis">Associations of circulating and dietary vitamin D with prostate cancer risk: a systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2011 Mar;22(3):319-40. Epub 2011 Jan 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Associations of circulating and dietary vitamin D with prostate cancer risk: a systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gilbert R, Martin RM, Beynon R, Harris R, Savovic J, Zuccolo L, Bekkering GE, Fraser WD, Sterne JA, Metcalfe C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Social and Community Medicine, University of Bristol, Canynge Hall, 39 Whatley Road, Bristol BS8 2PS, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:Becky.Gilbert@Bristol.ac.uk">Becky.Gilbert@Bristol.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin A and risk of prostate cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-a-and-risk-of-prostate-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-a-and-risk-of-prostate-cancer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>16 percent less Prostate Cancer sometimes for each 10 ng vitamin D increase - meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/16-percent-less-prostate-cancer-sometimes-for-each-10-ng-vitamin-d-increase-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/16-percent-less-prostate-cancer-sometimes-for-each-10-ng-vitamin-d-increase-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="associations-of-circulating-and-dietary-vitamin-d-with-prostate-cancer-risk-a-systematic-review-and-dose-response-meta-analysis">Associations of circulating and dietary vitamin D with prostate cancer risk: a systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2011 Jan 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gilbert R, Martin RM, Beynon R, Harris R, Savovic J, Zuccolo L, Bekkering GE, Fraser WD, Sterne JA, Metcalfe C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Social and Community Medicine, University of Bristol, Canynge Hall, 39 Whatley Road, Bristol, BS8 2PS, UK, &lt;a href="mailto:Becky.Gilbert@Bristol.ac.uk">Becky.Gilbert@Bristol.ac.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: We systematically reviewed and meta-analyzed literature examining associations of vitamin D (dietary intake, circulating 25-hydroxy-vitamin-D (25(OH)D), and 1,25-dihydroxy-vitamin-D (1,25(OH)(2)D) concentrations) with prostate cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>8000 IU supplementation to people with various cancers</title><link>/posts/8000-iu-supplementation-to-people-with-various-cancers.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/8000-iu-supplementation-to-people-with-various-cancers.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="impact-of-oral-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-oncology">Impact of oral vitamin D supplementation on serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in oncology&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pankaj G Vashi email, Kristen Trukova email, Carolyn A Lammersfeld email, Donald P Braun email and Digant Gupta email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrition Journal 2010, 9:60doi:10.1186/1475-2891-9-60, 	23 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> is the major circulating form of vitamin D and a standard indicator of vitamin D status. Emerging evidence in the literature suggests a high prevalence of suboptimal vitamin D (as defined by serum 25(OH)D levels of &amp;lt;32 ng/ml) as well as an association between lower serum levels and higher mortality in cancer. We investigated the effect of oral vitamin D supplementation as a means for restoring suboptimal levels to optimal levels in cancer.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>