<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pancreatic Cancer on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/pancreatic-cancer.html</link><description>Recent content in Pancreatic Cancer on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/pancreatic-cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pancreatic Cancer causes include smoking and low vitamin D, adding vitamin D might help</title><link>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-causes-include-smoking-and-low-vitamin-d-adding-vitamin-d-might-help.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-causes-include-smoking-and-low-vitamin-d-adding-vitamin-d-might-help.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pancreatic Cancer Survival 40 percent more likely if had adequate vitamin D (30 ng)</title><link>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-survival-40-percent-more-likely-if-had-adequate-vitamin-d-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-survival-40-percent-more-likely-if-had-adequate-vitamin-d-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prediagnostic-plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-pancreatic-cancer-survival">Prediagnostic Plasma 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Pancreatic Cancer Survival.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Oncol. 2016 Jun 20. pii: JCO663005. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yuan C1, Qian ZR1, Babic A1, Morales-Oyarvide V1, Rubinson DA1, Kraft P1, Ng K1, Bao Y1, Giovannucci EL1, Ogino S1, Stampfer MJ1, Gaziano JM1, Sesso HD1, Buring JE1, Cochrane BB1, Chlebowski RT1, Snetselaar LG1, Manson JE1, Fuchs CS1, Wolpin BM2.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/pancreatic-cancer-30-percent-less-likely-in-australians-who-got-lots-of-uvb-vitamin-d">Pancreatic cancer 30 percent less likely in Australians who got lots of UVB (vitamin D) – Dec 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pancreatic Cancer treatment by calcipotriol (a synthetic vitamin D) improves outcome by 57 percent</title><link>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-treatment-by-calcipotriol-a-synthetic-vitamin-d-improves-outcome-by-57-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-treatment-by-calcipotriol-a-synthetic-vitamin-d-improves-outcome-by-57-percent.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pancreatic Cancer massively deregulates the local Vitamin D receptors and CPY24A1</title><link>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-massively-deregulates-the-local-vitamin-d-receptors-and-cpy24a1.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-massively-deregulates-the-local-vitamin-d-receptors-and-cpy24a1.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-vitamin-d-system-is-deregulated-in-pancreatic-diseases">The vitamin D system is deregulated in pancreatic diseases&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Journal of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, online 30 July 2014, DOI: 10.1016/j.jsbmb.2014.07.011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Doris Hummela, 1, Abhishek Aggarwala, 1, Katalin Borkab, Erika Bajnaa, Enikö Kállaya, , , Henrik Csaba Horvathc&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/pancreatic-cancer-f1.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;p>        shaded text and numbers in the chart were added by VitaminDWiki&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="highlights">Highlights&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>During PDAC development CYP24A1 levels are reduced in the endocrine islets.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>During malignant transformation pancreatic ducts accumulate CYP24A1 protein.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pancreatic cancer 30 percent less likely in Australians who got lots of UVB (vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-30-percent-less-likely-in-australians-who-got-lots-of-uvb-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-30-percent-less-likely-in-australians-who-got-lots-of-uvb-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-between-ultraviolet-radiation-skin-sun-sensitivity-and-risk-of-pancreatic-cancer">Association between ultraviolet radiation, skin sun sensitivity and risk of pancreatic cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiol. 2013 Dec;37(6):886-92. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.canep.2013.08.013.">doi: 10.1016/j.canep.2013.08.013.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Sep 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tran B1, Whiteman DC, Webb PM, Fritschi L, Fawcett J, Risch HA, Lucas R, Pandeya N, Schulte A, Neale RE; Queensland Pancreatic Cancer Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Population Health Division, QIMR Berghofer Medical Research Institute, Australia; Centre for Research Excellence in Sun and Health, Australia. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:b.tran@uws.edu.au">b.tran@uws.edu.au&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ecological studies showing an inverse association between pancreatic cancer incidence and mortality and levels of ultraviolet radiation (UVR), suggest that higher levels of sun exposure may reduce risks of pancreatic cancer but there has been only one individual-level study that examined this issue. We aimed to examine the association between pancreatic cancer and markers of exposure to solar UVR, namely skin type, treatment of skin lesions, ambient UVR and time outdoors on work days.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Molecular Link between Vitamin D and Cancer Prevention</title><link>/posts/molecular-link-between-vitamin-d-and-cancer-prevention.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/molecular-link-between-vitamin-d-and-cancer-prevention.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(10), 3993-4021; doi:10.3390/nu5103993&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meis Moukayed 1email and William B. Grant 2,* email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 School of Arts and Sciences, American University in Dubai, P. O. Box 28282, Dubai, UAE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, San Francisco, CA 94164-1603, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Author to whom correspondence should be addressed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Received: 7 August 2013; in revised form: 11 September 2013 / Accepted: 18 September 2013 / Published: 30 September 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(This article belongs to the Special Issue Vitamin D and Human Health)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Far fewer Pancreatic Cancer deaths at stage III and IV with more than 20 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/far-fewer-pancreatic-cancer-deaths-at-stage-iii-and-iv-with-more-than-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/far-fewer-pancreatic-cancer-deaths-at-stage-iii-and-iv-with-more-than-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-prognostics-among-patients-with-pancreatic-adenocarcinoma">Vitamin D deficiency and prognostics among patients with pancreatic adenocarcinoma.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Transl Med. 2013 Sep 8;11(1):206.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cho M, Peddi PF, Ding K, Chen L, Thomas D, Wang J, Lockhart AC, Tan B, Wang-Gillam A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency among patients with cancer has been previously reported. Because vitamin D is fat soluble, patients with pancreatic adenocarcinoma may have an especially high risk of vitamin D deficiency in association with ongoing and varying degrees of malabsorption. However, little is known about the correlation between vitamin D status and prognosis in these patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pancreatic Cancer association with PRKCA gene and the active form of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-association-with-prkca-gene-and-the-active-form-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-association-with-prkca-gene-and-the-active-form-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="genetic-pathways-related-to-vitamin-d-and-risk-of-pancreatic-cancer-abstract-61">Genetic pathways related to vitamin D and risk of pancreatic cancer. Abstract 61:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev November 2012 21; 61&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hannah Arem1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dennis Maeder1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kai Yu1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bill Wheeler2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emily Steplowski2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neal Freedman1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Susan T. Mayne3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harvey Risch3,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joshua Sampson1, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachael Z. Stolzenberg-Solomon1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 National Cancer Institute, Bethesda, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Information Management Systems, Rockville, MD,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Yale School of Public Health, New Haven, CT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Pancreatic cancer is a rapidly fatal disease with few well-established risk factors. Genome-wide association studies (GWAS) have identified four genes associated with pancreatic cancer risk, but the low statistical significance thresholds in GWAS preclude identification of many associations and genetic risk for disease may not be fully explained by single genes or single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs). Collections of genes grouped into pathways may have a collective effect not detected in GWAS or candidate gene approaches. Also, biologic plausibility can be taken into consideration in pathway-based analyses. Laboratory and animal studies suggest a role for vitamin D in inhibiting tumor cell differentiation and angiogenesis, while stimulating apoptosis. Additionally, ecologic studies suggest lower pancreatic cancer incidence with higher UV exposure. However, epidemiologic studies on the association between vitamin D status and pancreatic cancer risk provide conflicting evidence with some studies suggesting positive associations. Vitamin D-related genetic pathways have not been examined in relation to pancreatic cancer risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pancreatic cancer 80 percent more likely if person had diabetes for 2-8 years</title><link>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-80-percent-more-likely-if-person-had-diabetes-for-2-8-years.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-80-percent-more-likely-if-person-had-diabetes-for-2-8-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="diabetes-and-risk-of-pancreatic-cancer-a-pooled-analysis-from-the-pancreatic-cancer-cohort-consortium">Diabetes and risk of pancreatic cancer: a pooled analysis from the pancreatic cancer cohort consortium&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes &amp;amp; Control, January 2013, Volume 24, Issue 1, pp 13-25&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joanne W. Elena, Emily Steplowski, Kai Yu, Patricia Hartge, Geoffrey S. Tobias, Michelle J. Brotzman, Stephen J. Chanock, Rachael Z. Stolzenberg-Solomon, Alan A. Arslan, H. Bas Bueno-de-Mesquita, … show all 50&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetes is a suspected risk factor for pancreatic cancer, but questions remain about whether it is a risk factor or a result of the disease. This study prospectively examined the association between diabetes and the risk of pancreatic adenocarcinoma in pooled data from the NCI pancreatic cancer cohort consortium (PanScan).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Risk of Rarer Cancers</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-risk-of-rarer-cancers.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-risk-of-rarer-cancers.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="shedding-light-on-serum-vitamin-d-concentrations-and-the-risk-of-rarer-cancers">Shedding Light on Serum Vitamin D Concentrations and the Risk of Rarer Cancers&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.65-69 (5)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Kathy J. Helzlsouer, Lisa Gallicchio&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer is a broad term for many disparate diseases with different etiologies, commonly classified by affected organ site. This review summarizes the published evidence from prospective cohort studies examining the associations between vitamin D, measured as serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) concentrations, and the risk of rarer cancer sites including&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer - Pancreatic</title><link>/posts/cancer-pancreatic.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-pancreatic.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-receptor-and-cancer-81-studies">Vitamin D Receptor and Cancer (81+ studies)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pancreatic-cancer-cells-appear-to-have-learned-to-steal-electrons-from-healthy-cells---feb-2022">Pancreatic cancer cells appear to have learned to steal electrons from healthy cells - Feb 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#predict-pancreatic-cancer-3-years-before-diagnosis---may-2023">Predict Pancreatic Cancer 3 years before diagnosis - May 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-pancreatitis-and-vitamin-d---many-studiespostspancreatitis-and-vitamin-d-many-studies">See also: &lt;a href="/posts/pancreatitis-and-vitamin-d-many-studies">Pancreatitis and Vitamin D - many studies&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-and-cancer-81-studies">Vitamin D Receptor and Cancer (81+ studies)&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/the-role-of-resveratrol-in-cancer-therapy" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: The Role of Resveratrol in Cancer Therapy – Dec 2017">The Role of Resveratrol in Cancer Therapy – Dec 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>