<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mortality and D on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/mortality-and-d.html</link><description>Recent content in Mortality and D on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/mortality-and-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chance of dying within 1 month of entering hospital is 45 percent higher if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chance-of-dying-within-1-month-of-entering-hospital-is-45-percent-higher-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chance-of-dying-within-1-month-of-entering-hospital-is-45-percent-higher-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="pre-hospital-vitamin-d-concentration-mortality-and-bloodstream-infection-in-a-hospitalized-patient-population">Pre-hospital Vitamin D Concentration, Mortality, and Bloodstream Infection in a Hospitalized Patient Population&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The American Journal of Medicine; Volume 126, Issue 7, July 2013, Pages 640.e19–640.e27&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nancy Lange, MD, MPHa,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Augusto A. Litonjua, MD, MPHb,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fiona K. Gibbons, MDc,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Edward Giovannucci, MD, ScDd,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kenneth B. Christopher, MDe, &lt;a href="mailto:kbchristopher@partners.org">kbchristopher@partners.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Pulmonary Division, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Boston, Mass&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Channing Laboratory and Pulmonary and Critical Care Division, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Boston, Mass&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer survival 2X more likely if vitamin D sufficient – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-survival-2x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-sufficient-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-survival-2x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-sufficient-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-relationship-between-serum-vitamin-d-levels-and-breast-cancer-prognosis-a-meta-analysis">The relationship between serum vitamin D levels and breast cancer prognosis: A meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology, 2013 ASCO Annual Meeting Proceedings (Post-Meeting Edition).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol 31, No 15_suppl (May 20 Supplement), 2013: 1521&lt;/p>
&lt;p>April Ann Nicole Rose, Christine Elser and Pamela Jean Goodwin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Faculty of Medicine, McGill University, Montreal, QC, Canada; Princess Margaret Hospital, Toronto, ON, Canada; Samuel Lunenfeld Research Institute, Mount Sinai Hospital, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dermatologists view of UV radiation and the Skin</title><link>/posts/dermatologists-view-of-uv-radiation-and-the-skin.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dermatologists-view-of-uv-radiation-and-the-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="uv-radiation-and-the-skin">UV Radiation and the Skin&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2013, 14(6), 12222-12248; doi:10.3390/ijms140612222&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John D&amp;rsquo;Orazio 1,* email, Stuart Jarrett 2 email, Alexandra Amaro-Ortiz 3 email and Timothy Scott 3 email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Graduate Center for Toxicology and the Departments of Pediatrics, Biomedical and Molecular Pharmacology and Physiology, Markey Cancer Center, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA 2 Markey Cancer Center, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA 3 Graduate Center for Toxicology, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More sepsis deaths when active vitamin D (Calcitrol) was low</title><link>/posts/more-sepsis-deaths-when-active-vitamin-d-calcitrol-was-low.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-sepsis-deaths-when-active-vitamin-d-calcitrol-was-low.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-125-dihydroxyvitamin-d-an-outcome-prognosticator-in-human-sepsis">Serum 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D: An Outcome Prognosticator in Human Sepsis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(5): e64348. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0064348&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nguyen HB, Eshete B, Lau KHW, Sai A, Villarin M, Baylink D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In sepsis, the vitamin D active metabolite 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)2D) may play a crucial role by its action to produce cathelicidin and improve endothelial barrier function, such that a deficiency in 1,25(OH)2D is associated with poor outcome. To test our hypothesis, we performed analysis of stored plasma samples from a prospective observational study in 91 patients with sepsis, age of 59.1+/−2.0 years, 52.7% females, and 11.0% deaths at 30 days. Vitamin D status, including 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D), 1,25(OH)2D, 24,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (24,25(OH)2D), and parathyroid hormone (PTH), were measured daily over 3 days after hospital admission. At baseline, 1,25(OH)2D was significantly different between survivors vs. non-survivors. But there was no significant difference in 25(OH)D, 24,25(OH)2D, and PTH. In a multivariable binomial logistic regression model, age, total calcium and 1,25(OH)2D were significant predictors of 30-day mortality. Kaplan Meier analysis showed that patients with mean 1,25(OH)2D measured over 3 days of &amp;lt; = 13.6 pg/mL had 57.1% 30-day survival compared to 91.7% in patients with 1,25 (OH)2D level &amp;gt;13.6 pg/mL (p&amp;lt;0.01). From repeated measures regression analysis, there was significant increase in 1,25(OH)2D for increases in 25(OH)D in both survivors and non-survivors. However, compared to survivors, the low 25(OH)D in non-survivors was insufficient to account for the larger decrease in 1,25(OH)2D, indicating a dysfunctional 1α-hydroxylase. Additionally, there was a significant negative correlation between PTH and 1,25(OH)2D in both survivors and non-survivors, suggesting a severe impairment in the effect of PTH to increase renal 1α-hydroxylase activity. In conclusion, low 1,25(OH)2D levels are associated with increased 30-day mortality in sepsis patients, likely due to impaired 25(OH)D hydroxylation and PTH insensitivity. Our data also suggest that the active metabolite 1,25(OH)2D may be an important therapeutic target in the design of sepsis clinical trials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects against many types of health problems – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-effects-on-musculoskeletal-health-immunity-autoimmunity-cardiovascular-disease-cancer-fertility-pregnancy-dementia-and-mortality-a-review-of-recent-evidence">Vitamin D effects on musculoskeletal health, immunity, autoimmunity, cardiovascular disease, cancer, fertility, pregnancy, dementia and mortality-A review of recent evidence.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmun Rev. 2013 Mar 28. pii: S1568-9972(13)00040-2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.">doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pawel Pludowski a &lt;a href="mailto:p.pludowski@czd.pl">p.pludowski@czd.pl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael F. Holick b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Pilzc, d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carol L. Wagner e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce W. Hollis e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant f,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yehuda Shoenfeld g,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elisabeth Lerchbaum c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David J. Llewellyn h,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katharina Kienreich c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maya Soni h&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Biochemistry, Radioimmunology and Experimental Medicine, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Health Institute, Warsaw, Poland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D supplementation can cost 50 dollars a day (live longer)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-can-cost-50-dollars-a-day-live-longer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-supplementation-can-cost-50-dollars-a-day-live-longer.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Low Vitamin D associated with a variety of causes of death a decade later</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-a-variety-of-causes-of-death-a-decade-later.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-a-variety-of-causes-of-death-a-decade-later.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="strong-associations-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-with-all-cause-cardiovascular-cancer-and-respiratory-disease-mortality-in-a-large-cohort-study">Strong associations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations with all-cause, cardiovascular, cancer, and respiratory disease mortality in a large cohort study.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2013 Feb 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schöttker B, Haug U, Schomburg L, Köhrle J, Perna L, Müller H, Holleczek B, Brenner H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Divisions of Clinical Epidemiology and Aging Research and Preventive Oncology, German Cancer Research Center, Heidelberg, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentration has been linked to mortality in several studies, but appropriate cutoffs to define risk categories are under debate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Use of ICU in month before death has increased to almost 30 pcnt</title><link>/posts/off-topic-use-of-icu-in-month-before-death-has-increased-to-almost-30-pcnt.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-use-of-icu-in-month-before-death-has-increased-to-almost-30-pcnt.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="change-in-end-of-life-care-for-medicare-beneficiariessite-of-death-place-of-care-and-health-care-transitions-in-2000-2005-and-2009">Change in End-of-Life Care for Medicare BeneficiariesSite of Death, Place of Care, and Health Care Transitions in 2000, 2005, and 2009&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>JAMA. 2013;309(5):470-477. doi:10.1001/jama.2012.207624. February 6, 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joan M. Teno, MD, MS; Pedro L. Gozalo, PhD; Julie P. W. Bynum, MD, MPH; Natalie E. Leland, PhD; Susan C. Miller, PhD, MBA; Nancy E. Morden, MD, MPH; Thomas Scupp, BS; David C. Goodman, MD; Vincent Mor, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Importance A recent Centers for Disease Control and Prevention report found that more persons die at home. This has been cited as evidence that persons dying in the United States are using more supportive care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Almost 6X more likely to die after coronary bypass if vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/almost-6x-more-likely-to-die-after-coronary-bypass-if-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/almost-6x-more-likely-to-die-after-coronary-bypass-if-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="pre-hospital-serum-vitamin-d-levels-and-mortality-following-coronary-artery-bypass-grafting">Pre-Hospital Serum Vitamin D Levels and Mortality Following Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Critical Care Medicine: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/01.ccm.0000424294.93940.c5">doi: 10.1097/01.ccm.0000424294.93940.c5&lt;/a>, Oral Abstract Session&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moromizato, Takuhiro; Litonjua, Augusto; Braun, Andrea; Gibbons, Fiona; Giovannucci, Edward; Christopher, Kenneth&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Whether the degree of vitamin D deficiency affects survival following coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) is not clear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypothesis: We hypothesize that pre-hospital vitamin D deficiency is associated with mortality following CABG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: We performed a retrospective cohort study between 2001 and 2010 in two teaching hospitals in Boston, Massachusetts utilizing an institutional Research Patient Data Registry. We studied 322 patients, age = 18 years, in whom 25(OH)D was measured prior to hospitalization. The exposure of interest was pre-admission 25(OH)D categorized a priori as deficiency in 25(OH)D (=15ng/mL), insufficiency (15-30 ng/mL) and sufficiency (=30ng/mL). The primary outcome was all cause mortality 90 days following CABG. Vital status was obtained from the Social Security Administration Death Master File. Associations between vitamin D groups and mortality were estimated by bivariable and multivariable logistic regression models.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Predicted cardiac surgery death associated with low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/predicted-cardiac-surgery-death-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/predicted-cardiac-surgery-death-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-cross-sectional-study-of-the-association-between-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-predicted-operative-mortality-of-patients-with-cardiovascular-disease">A Cross-Sectional Study of the Association between Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels and Predicted Operative Mortality of Patients with Cardiovascular Disease.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Nutr Sci Vitaminol (Tokyo). 2012;58(5):327-32.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tsutsumi Y, Sanui M, Shimojima A, Ishioka H, Urashima M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Molecular Epidemiology, Jikei University School of Medicine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent studies have suggested that low levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) are associated with cardiovascular risks in medical patients. However, these associations have not been well documented in high risk surgical patients. We hypothesized that serum 25OHD, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25OHD) would be associated with the cardiac operative risk stratification score. The study was conducted with a cross-sectional design at a single academic medical center in Japan. Two hundred five adult patients scheduled for major cardiovascular surgery were included consecutively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D associated with respiratory, digestive, and other deaths</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-respiratory-digestive-and-other-deaths.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-respiratory-digestive-and-other-deaths.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Off topic: Special issue on Longevity in the Journal Nature - free text</title><link>/posts/off-topic-special-issue-on-longevity-in-the-journal-nature-free-text.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-special-issue-on-longevity-in-the-journal-nature-free-text.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="naturehttpwwwnaturecomnaturejournalv492n7427_suppindexhtml-06-december-2012">&lt;a href="http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v492/n7427_supp/index.html">Nature&lt;/a> (06 December 2012)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Brief, but nice&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ageing Michelle Grayson Nature 492, S1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Demography: To the limit Tony Scully Nature 492, S2–S3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cognition: The brain&amp;rsquo;s decline Alison Abbott Nature 492, S4–S5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Centenarians: Great expectations Michael Eisenstein Nature 492, S6–S8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Q&amp;amp;A Eva Kahana: Ageing proactively Rebecca Kessler Nature 492, S9&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Comparative biology: Looking for a master switch Sarah Deweerdt Nature 492, S10–S11&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stem cells: Repeat to fade Peter Wehrwein Nature 492, S12–S13&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Cancer Mortality – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-mortality-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-cancer-mortality-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-cancer-mortality-systematic-review-of-prospective-epidemiological-studies">Vitamin D and Cancer Mortality: Systematic Review of Prospective Epidemiological Studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1 pp.107-117 (11)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Pilz, Katharina Kienreich, Andreas Tomaschitz, Eberhard Ritz, Elisabeth Lerchbaum, Barbara Obermayer-Pietsch, Veronika Matzi, Joerg Lindenmann, Winfried Marz, Sara Gandini, Jacqueline M. Dekker&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accumulating evidence from experimental and epidemiological studies suggests that vitamin D deficiency might be a causal risk factor for cancer and therewith associated mortality. We performed a systematic review in Medline up to February 2012 to identify prospective studies on 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) and cancer mortality as well as on 25(OH)D and survival in cancer patients. Our search retrieved 13 studies on cancer-specific mortality and 20 studies on overall mortality in cancer patients. Data on 25(OH)D and cancer mortality were mainly derived from general populations. The results were inconsistent and yielded either no, inverse or positive associations. By contrast, the majority of studies in cancer patients showed that patients with higher 25(OH)D levels had a decreased risk of mortality. This relationship was particularly evident in cohorts of colorectal cancer patients. In contrast, there was no indication for increased mortality risk with higher vitamin D levels in any cancer cohort. In conclusion, the relationship of vitamin D status and cancer specific mortality is still unclear and warrants further studies. Our results provide a strong rationale to perform prospective randomized controlled studies to document a potential effect of vitamin D supplementation on survival in cancer patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 X increased chance of death if have asthma – study of 200,000 people over 10 years</title><link>/posts/3-x-increased-chance-of-death-if-have-asthma-study-of-200000-people-over-10-years.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3-x-increased-chance-of-death-if-have-asthma-study-of-200000-people-over-10-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="adult-asthma-and-risk-of-coronary-heart-disease-cerebrovascular-disease-and-heart-failure-a-prospective-study-of-2-matched-cohorts">Adult Asthma and Risk of Coronary Heart Disease, Cerebrovascular Disease, and Heart Failure: A Prospective Study of 2 Matched Cohorts&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American Journal of Epidemiology, (2012), &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/aje/kws181">doi: 10.1093/aje/kws181&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carlos Iribarren*, Irina V. Tolstykh, Mary K. Miller, Erica Sobel and Mark D. Eisner&lt;/p>
&lt;p>?*Correspondence to Dr. Carlos Iribarren, Division of Research, Kaiser Permanente Medical Care Program, 2000 Broadway, Oakland, CA 94612 (e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:cgi@dor.kaiser.org">cgi@dor.kaiser.org&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abbreviations: CHD, coronary heart disease; CVD, cardiovascular disease; ICD-9, International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision; KPNC, Kaiser Permanente Northern California.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If you have inherited longevity genes you can take 200 IU less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/if-you-have-inherited-longevity-genes-you-can-take-200-iu-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-you-have-inherited-longevity-genes-you-can-take-200-iu-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="leiden-longevity-studyhttpblogvitamindcouncilorg20121108study-links-low-vitamin-d-levels-to-longer-lifespan-did-we-hear-that-correctly-described-at-vitamin-d-council">&lt;a href="http://blog.vitamindcouncil.org/2012/11/08/study-links-low-vitamin-d-levels-to-longer-lifespan-did-we-hear-that-correctly/">Leiden Longevity Study&lt;/a> described at Vitamin D Council&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Looked at people &amp;gt;89 and their children and used their partners as controls&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the kids of the seniors who were 90+ and had&lt;/p>
&lt;p>64 nmol vs 69 nmol for controls (partners)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2X as many study as controls (why? Should be about equal)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Average age of kids: 59&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whites only&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Did not measure tanning bed nor sun&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking carefully: Kids who were offspring of the parents who were &amp;gt; 90 had 4 nmol lower vitamin D level than their spouses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Differences in black and non-black mortality and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/differences-in-black-and-non-black-mortality-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/differences-in-black-and-non-black-mortality-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Low levels of vitamin D associated with all cause mortality</title><link>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-all-cause-mortality.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-levels-of-vitamin-d-associated-with-all-cause-mortality.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="circulating-25ohd-dietary-vitamin-d-pth-and-calcium-associations-with-incident-cardiovascular-disease-and-mortality-the-midspan-family-study">Circulating 25OHD, Dietary Vitamin D, PTH, and Calcium Associations with Incident Cardiovascular Disease and Mortality: The MIDSPAN Family Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism October 15, 2012 jc.2012-2272&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paul Welsh, Orla Doolin, Alex McConnachie, Emma Boulton, Geraldine McNeil, Helen Macdonald, Antonia Hardcastle, Carole Hart, Mark Upton, Graham Watt and Naveed Sattar&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Institute of Cardiovascular and Medical Sciences (P.W., E.B., N.S.), Robertson Centre for Biostatistics (O.D., A.M.), Institute of Health and Wellbeing (C.H.), and General Practice and Primary Care (G.W.), University of Glasgow, Glasgow G12 8TA, United Kingdom; Public Health Nutrition Research Group (G.M., H.M., A.H.), University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen AB24 3FX, United Kingdom; and Woodlands Family Medical Centre (M.U.), Stockton-on-Tees TS18 1YE, United Kingdom&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seniors on mechanical ventilation having very low vitamin D died sooner</title><link>/posts/seniors-on-mechanical-ventilation-having-very-low-vitamin-d-died-sooner.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/seniors-on-mechanical-ventilation-having-very-low-vitamin-d-died-sooner.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-poor-outcomes-and-increased-mortality-in-severely-ill-patients">Vitamin D deficiency is associated with poor outcomes and increased mortality in severely ill patients.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>QJM. 2012 Jul;105(7):633-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/qjmed/hcs014.">doi: 10.1093/qjmed/hcs014.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Feb 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arnson Y, Gringauz I, Itzhaky D, Amital H. &lt;a href="mailto:hamital@netvision.net.il">hamital@netvision.net.il&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine B, Sheba Medical Center, Tel-Hashomer 52621, Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D plays a seminal role in many homeostatic mechanisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this study, we assessed the correlation between circulating vitamin D levels and mortality rates in critically ill patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More US deaths due to cancer than heart if dark skinned</title><link>/posts/more-us-deaths-due-to-cancer-than-heart-if-dark-skinned.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-us-deaths-due-to-cancer-than-heart-if-dark-skinned.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Correcting magnesium deficiencies may prolong life – Space Station</title><link>/posts/correcting-magnesium-deficiencies-may-prolong-life-space-station.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/correcting-magnesium-deficiencies-may-prolong-life-space-station.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Clin Interv Aging. 2012;7:51-4. Epub 2012 Feb 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rowe WJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical University of Ohio at Toledo, Ohio, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:rowerun@aol.com">rowerun@aol.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The International Space Station provides an extraordinary facility to study the accelerated aging process in microgravity, which could be triggered by significant reductions in magnesium (Mg) ion levels with, in turn, elevations of catecholamines and vicious cycles between the two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With space flight there are significant reductions of serum Mg (P &amp;lt; 0.0001) that have been shown in large studies of astronauts and cosmonauts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death in less than 2 years of Heart Failure associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/death-in-less-than-2-years-of-heart-failure-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-in-less-than-2-years-of-heart-failure-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-a-predictor-of-reduced-survival-in-patients-with-heart-failure">Vitamin D Deficiency is a Predictor of Reduced Survival in Patients With Heart Failure&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Israel Gotsman; Ayelet Shauer; Donna R. Zwas; Yaron Hellman; Andre Keren; Chaim Lotan; Dan Admon&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eur J Heart Fail. 2012;14(4):357-366. © 2012 Oxford University Press&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aims Vitamin D deficiency is a highly prevalent, global phenomenon. The prevalence in heart failure (HF) patients and its effect on outcome are less clear. We evaluated vitamin D levels and vitamin D supplementation in patients with HF and its effect on mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart Failure early death 2X more likely if less than 20 nanograms of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/heart-failure-early-death-2x-more-likely-if-less-than-20-nanograms-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-failure-early-death-2x-more-likely-if-less-than-20-nanograms-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-and-mortality-from-heart-failure-and-cardiovascular-disease-and-premature-mortality-from-all-cause-in-united-states-adults">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration and Mortality From Heart Failure and Cardiovascular Disease, and Premature Mortality from All-Cause in United States Adults&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Cardiol. 2012 Jun 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liu L, Chen M, Hankins SR, Nùñez AE, Watson RA, Weinstock PJ, Newschaffer CJ, Eisen HJ; Drexel Cardiovascular Health Collaborative Education, Research, and Evaluation Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Drexel University School of Public Health, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We aimed to examine associations between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) concentration and mortality from heart failure (HF) and cardiovascular disease (CVD) and premature death from all causes using data from the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, which included 13,131 participants (6,130 men, 7,001 women) =35 years old at baseline (1988 to 1994) and followed through December 2000.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death rate 2X higher at age 60 if low vitamin D - 180,000 in Israel</title><link>/posts/death-rate-2x-higher-at-age-60-if-low-vitamin-d-180000-in-israel.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-rate-2x-higher-at-age-60-if-low-vitamin-d-180000-in-israel.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-risk-of-all-cause-mortality-is-inversely-related-to-serum-25ohd-levels">The Risk of All-Cause Mortality Is Inversely Related to Serum 25(OH)D Levels.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012 May 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saliba W, Barnett O, Rennert HS, Rennert G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Community Medicine and Epidemiology (W.S., O.B., H.S.R., G.R.), Carmel Medical Center, Clalit Health Services, and Bruce Rappaport Faculty of Medicine (W.S., O.B., H.S.R., G.R.), Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa 34362, Israel; Department of Internal Medicine C (W.S.), Ha&amp;rsquo;emek Medical Center, Afula 18101, Israel; and Department of Epidemiology and Disease Prevention (G.R.), Office of the Chief Physician, Clalit Health Services Headquarters, Tel Aviv 62098, Israel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D with Calcium reduces mortality by 7 percent – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-with-calcium-reduces-mortality-by-7-percent-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-with-calcium-reduces-mortality-by-7-percent-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>All-cause mortality does not relate to vitamin D tests years earlier</title><link>/posts/all-cause-mortality-does-not-relate-to-vitamin-d-tests-years-earlier.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/all-cause-mortality-does-not-relate-to-vitamin-d-tests-years-earlier.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Death rate reduced 8 percent for 8 nanogram more vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/death-rate-reduced-8-percent-for-8-nanogram-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/death-rate-reduced-8-percent-for-8-nanogram-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Women very low on vitamin D were 56 percent more likely to die in nursing home</title><link>/posts/women-very-low-on-vitamin-d-were-56-percent-more-likely-to-die-in-nursing-home.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-very-low-on-vitamin-d-were-56-percent-more-likely-to-die-in-nursing-home.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-is-associated-with-increased-mortality-in-female-nursing-home-residents">Low 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Is Associated with Increased Mortality in Female Nursing Home Residents.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012 Feb 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pilz S, Dobnig H, Tomaschitz A, Kienreich K, Meinitzer A, Friedl C, Wagner D, Piswanger-Sölkner C, März W, Fahrleitner-Pammer A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine (S.P., H.D., A.T., K.K., C.P.-S., A.F.-P.), Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism; Clinical Institute of Medical and Chemical Laboratory Diagnostics (A.M., W.M.); Division for Transplantation (C.F.), Department of Surgery; and Department of Internal Medicine (D.W.), Division of Nephrology, Medical University of Graz, 8036 Graz, Austria; Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics and EMGO Institute for Health and Care Research (S.P.), VU University Medical Center, 1081 BT Amsterdam, The Netherlands; Synlab Academy (W.M.), Synlab services LLC, D-68165 Mannheim, Germany; and Mannheim Institute of Public Health (W.M.), Ruperto Carola University Heidelberg, Medical Faculty Mannheim, D-68167 Mannheim, Germany.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chance of death after heart failure reduced by 1000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/chance-of-death-after-heart-failure-reduced-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chance-of-death-after-heart-failure-reduced-by-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-a-predictor-of-reduced-survival-in-patients-with-heart-failure-vitamin-d-supplementation-improves-outcome">Vitamin D deficiency is a predictor of reduced survival in patients with heart failure; vitamin D supplementation improves outcome.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Eur J Heart Fail. 2012 Feb 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gotsman I, Shauer A, Zwas DR, Hellman Y, Keren A, Lotan C, Admon D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heart Institute, Hadassah University Hospital, POB 12000, Jerusalem, Israel IL-91120.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIMS: Vitamin D deficiency is a highly prevalent, global phenomenon. The prevalence in heart failure (HF) patients and its effect on outcome are less clear. We evaluated vitamin D levels and vitamin D supplementation in patients with HF and its effect on mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Omega 3 and Exercise are being used in controlled trial to support healthy ageing</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-omega-3-and-exercise-are-being-used-in-controlled-trial-to-support-healthy-ageing.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-omega-3-and-exercise-are-being-used-in-controlled-trial-to-support-healthy-ageing.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lack of solar UVB in US is associated with some Cancers - 2006</title><link>/posts/lack-of-solar-uvb-in-us-is-associated-with-some-cancers-2006.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lack-of-solar-uvb-in-us-is-associated-with-some-cancers-2006.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="solar-ultraviolet-b-exposure-and-cancer-incidence-and-mortality-in-the-united-states-1993-2002">Solar ultraviolet-B exposure and cancer incidence and mortality in the United States, 1993-2002.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>BMC Cancer. 2006 Nov 10;6:264.Boscoe FP, Schymura MJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, University at Albany, Rensselaer, NY 12144, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:fpb01@health.state.ny.us">fpb01@health.state.ny.us&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An inverse relationship between solar ultraviolet-B (UV-B) exposure and non-skin cancer mortality has long been reported. Vitamin D, acquired primarily through exposure to the sun via the skin, is believed to inhibit tumor development and growth and reduce mortality for certain cancers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer patients 64% less likely to die if have high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cancer-patients-64-percent-less-likely-to-die-if-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-patients-64-percent-less-likely-to-die-if-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-survival-in-norwegian-patients-with-cancer-of-breast-colon-lung-and-lymphoma-a-population-based-study">Serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D and survival in Norwegian patients with cancer of breast, colon, lung, and lymphoma: a population-based study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2011 Dec 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tretli S, Schwartz GG, Torjesen PA, Robsahm TE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cancer Registry of Norway, Institute of Population-based Cancer Research, PB 5313, Majorstuen, 0304, Oslo, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no">steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: We investigated the association between serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) and risk of death in Norwegian cancer patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D increased death rate 2X in Finland</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increased-death-rate-2x-in-finland.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-increased-death-rate-2x-in-finland.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-with-the-risk-of-death-in-a-general-older-population-in-finland">Association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D with the risk of death in a general older population in Finland.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Nutr. 2011 Aug;50(5):305-12. Epub 2010 Oct 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Virtanen JK, Nurmi T, Voutilainen S, Mursu J, Tuomainen TP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Eastern Finland, Kuopio Campus, Institute of Public Health and Clinical Nutrition, Finland. &lt;a href="mailto:jyrki.virtanen@uef.fi">jyrki.virtanen@uef.fi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: To investigate the association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentration, a marker of vitamin D status, and risk of all-cause and cardiovascular mortality in a general older population with relatively low average serum 25(OH)D concentrations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>40 ng Vitamin D perhaps optimal for reduced mortality – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/40-ng-vitamin-d-perhaps-optimal-for-reduced-mortality-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/40-ng-vitamin-d-perhaps-optimal-for-reduced-mortality-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-mortality-risk-in-the-general-population-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-cohort-studies">Vitamin D deficiency and mortality risk in the general population: a meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Dec 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zittermann A, Iodice S, Pilz S, &lt;strong>Grant WB&lt;/strong> , Bagnardi V, Gandini S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinic for Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery, Heart Centre North Rhine-Westphalia, Ruhr University Bochum, Bad Oeynhausen, Germany, San Francisco, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Low vitamin D status may increase mortality risk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: We used nonparametric (&amp;ldquo;highest compared with lowest&amp;rdquo; categories) and parametric (&amp;gt;2 categories) statistical models to evaluate associations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> serum concentrations and mortality in observational studies among general populations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D3 but not D2 reduces mortality – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d3-but-not-d2-reduces-mortality-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d3-but-not-d2-reduces-mortality-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Much higher death rate 10 years after TIA – Nov 2011 – vitamin D might help</title><link>/posts/much-higher-death-rate-10-years-after-tia-nov-2011-vitamin-d-might-help.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/much-higher-death-rate-10-years-after-tia-nov-2011-vitamin-d-might-help.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mini-strokes-temporary-episodes-shorten-liveshttpabcnewsgocomhealthlongevitytias-mini-strokes-shorten-livesstoryid14924889tr0r-pkofz0-abc-news">&lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Health/Longevity/tias-mini-strokes-shorten-lives/story?id=14924889#.Tr0r-PKOfZ0">Mini Strokes: Temporary Episodes Shorten Lives&lt;/a> ABC News&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>22,157 Australian adults hospitalized with a TIA from July 1, 2000, to June 30, 2007,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At 10 years after TIA the death rate was about 2X higher than those of same age, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-researchers-found-that-other-diagnoses-compounded-tia-survivors-risk-of-dying">The researchers found that other diagnoses compounded TIA survivors&amp;rsquo; risk of dying.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Congestive heart failure more than tripled it. = 6X&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prior hospitalization for stroke more than doubled it, = 4X&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Telomeres for a Longer, Healthier Life - book mentions vitamin D - 2010</title><link>/posts/telomeres-for-a-longer-healthier-life-book-mentions-vitamin-d-2010.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/telomeres-for-a-longer-healthier-life-book-mentions-vitamin-d-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-immortality-edge-realize-the-secrets-of-your-telomeres-for-a-longer-healthier-life">The Immortality Edge: Realize the Secrets of Your Telomeres for a Longer, Healthier Life&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Hardcover and Kindle versions Dec 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Immortality-Edge-Realize-Telomeres-Healthier/dp/0470873906/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1318519736&amp;amp;sr=8-1">Amazon&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking inside of the book finds 16 hits for &amp;ldquo;Vitamin D&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Can read first chapter for free on any Kindle reader - including PC, MAC&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;806&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/telomeres-improved-when-obese-blacks-took-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily">Telomeres improved when obese blacks took 2000 iu of vitamin D daily – Oct 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/lupus-in-blacks-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-short-telomeres">Lupus in blacks associated with low vitamin D AND short telomeres – May 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Telomeres improved when obese blacks took 2000 IU of vitamin D daily</title><link>/posts/telomeres-improved-when-obese-blacks-took-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/telomeres-improved-when-obese-blacks-took-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-daily.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cochrane – 800 IU vitamin D decreased mortality by 6 percent</title><link>/posts/cochrane-800-iu-vitamin-d-decreased-mortality-by-6-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cochrane-800-iu-vitamin-d-decreased-mortality-by-6-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-for-prevention-of-mortality-in-adults">Vitamin D supplementation for prevention of mortality in adults.&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>– – – – – – –&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="note-this-is-a-result-of-averaging-mortality-across-all-vitamin-d-trials--most-of-which-used-only-800-iu-of-vitamin-d">Note: this is a result of averaging mortality across all vitamin D trials – most of which used only 800 IU of vitamin D&lt;/h5>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011 Jul 6;7:CD007470.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bjelakovic G, Gluud LL, Nikolova D, Whitfield K, Wetterslev J, Simonetti RG, Bjelakovic M, Gluud C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine - Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Medical Faculty, University of Nis, Zorana Djindjica 81, Nis, Serbia, 18000.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dr. Grant on vitamin D and mortality in VitaminDWiki</title><link>/posts/dr-grant-on-vitamin-d-and-mortality-in-vitamindwiki.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dr-grant-on-vitamin-d-and-mortality-in-vitamindwiki.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostsvitamin-d-video-53-minutes-with-text-and-pdfs-grant-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-vitamin-d-video-53-minutes-with-text-and-pdfs--grant-oct-2017vitamin-d-video-53-minutes-with-text-and-pdfs--grant-oct-2017a">&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-video-53-minutes-with-text-and-pdfs-grant" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Vitamin D Video 53 minutes with text and PDFs – Grant Oct 2017">Vitamin D Video 53 minutes with text and PDFs – Grant Oct 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="presentation-by-dr-grant-dec-2014">Presentation by Dr. Grant Dec 2014&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/grant-dec-2014.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=91eDzM0qiJM">Video is on YouTube&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Some of the slides from the presentation&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/g9.jpg" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/g22-breast-cancer.jpg" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/g23-cancer.jpg" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/g34-deaths.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/g34-conclusions.jpg" alt="image" width="400"></description></item><item><title>In Defence of the Sun – reduce 400000 premature deaths – 2009</title><link>/posts/in-defence-of-the-sun-reduce-400000-premature-deaths-2009.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/in-defence-of-the-sun-reduce-400000-premature-deaths-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="in-defense-of-the-sun--an-estimate-of-changes-in-mortality-rates-in-the-united-states-if-mean-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-were-raised-to-45-ngml-by-solar-ultraviolet-b-irradiance">In defense of the sun -An estimate of changes in mortality rates in the United States if mean serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels were raised to 45 ng/mL by solar ultraviolet-B irradiance&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2009 Jul-Aug; 1(4): 207–214. PMCID: PMC2835876&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B Grant. Sunlight, Nutrition and Health Research Center (SUNARC); San Francisco, CA USA, &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Emerging scientific evidence strongly supports the beneficial role of vitamin D in reducing the risk of incidence and death from many chronic and infectious diseases. This study estimates increases in melanoma and nonmelanoma skin cancer mortality rates and decreases in chronic and infectious disease mortality rates in the US from the standpoint of approximately doubling population doses of solar UVB to increase mean serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels from 16 ng/mL for black Americans and 25 ng/mL for white Americans to 45 ng/mL. The primary benefits are expected to come from reductions in cancer and cardiovascular diseases. Although a few thousand excess deaths per year might occur from melanoma and skin cancer, the avoided premature death rate could be near 400,000/ year, with most of the avoided deaths coming late in life. While oral sources of vitamin D could be used instead of UVB or when UVB irradiance is not available, public health policies do not yet recommend the 3,000–4,000 IU/day required to raise serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels to the levels required for optimal health, which would be required before vitamin D fortification levels in food can be raised. Until then, moderate solar UVB irradiance remains an import source, and the health benefits greatly outweigh the risks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increase life expectancy by 2 years if double Vitamin D levels – Grant</title><link>/posts/increase-life-expectancy-by-2-years-if-double-vitamin-d-levels-grant.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increase-life-expectancy-by-2-years-if-double-vitamin-d-levels-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#an-estimate-of-the-global-reduction-in-mortality-rates-through-doubling-vitamin-d-levels">An estimate of the global reduction in mortality rates through doubling vitamin D levels.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#203-citations-of-this-study-as-of-dec-2023">203 citations of this study as of Dec 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="an-estimate-of-the-global-reduction-in-mortality-rates-through-doubling-vitamin-d-levels">An estimate of the global reduction in mortality rates through doubling vitamin D levels.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2011.68.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2011.68.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grant WB. Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, San Francisco, CA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Objectives:The goal of this work is to estimate the reduction in mortality rates for six geopolitical regions of the world under the assumption that serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) levels increase from 54 to 110?nmol/l.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mortality and vitamin D – great chart</title><link>/posts/mortality-and-vitamin-d-great-chart.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mortality-and-vitamin-d-great-chart.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="an-estimate-of-the-survival-benefit-of-improving-vitamin-d-status-in-the-adult-german-population">An estimate of the survival benefit of improving vitamin D status in the adult german population.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Zittermann A, von Helden R, Grant W, Kipshoven C, Ringe JD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2009 Nov;1(6):300-6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardio-Thoracic Surgery; Heart Center North Rhine-Westfalia; Ruhr University Bochum; Bad Oeynhausen, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Inadequate vitamin D status is a worldwide problem. Evidence is accumulating that individuals with low vitamin D status have excess mortality rates. We calculated to which extent annual mortality rates can be reduced in the German population by optimizing vitamin D status.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis – Mozart died from lack of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-mozart-died-from-lack-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-mozart-died-from-lack-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-contributed-to-mozarts-death">Vitamin D Deficiency Contributed to Mozart’s Death&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Med Probl Perform Art. 2011 Jun;26(2):117.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To the Editor—Dawson’s recent extensive bibliographic review1 of the cause of death of Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart found that there were a number of hypotheses including poisoning, infection, cardiovascular disease, and renal disease and its complications. It is difficult to pin down the exact cause, and likely a number of factors contributed to his early death.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overlooked in any of the papers hypothesizing about his death was a discussion of the likely role of very low serum 25- hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> level in contributing to his untimely death. Low serum 25(OH)D level is an important risk factor for several types of infection, including pneumonia and sepsis, cardiovascular disease, and renal disease.2-4&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mortality and Cancer varies with latitude in France too – 2010</title><link>/posts/mortality-and-cancer-varies-with-latitude-in-france-too-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mortality-and-cancer-varies-with-latitude-in-france-too-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="an-ecological-study-of-cancer-incidence-and-mortality-rates-in-france-with-respect-to-latitude-an-index-for-vitamin-d-production">An ecological study of cancer incidence and mortality rates in France with respect to latitude, an index for vitamin D production&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2010 Apr–Dec; 2(2): 62–67. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4161/derm.2.2.13624.">doi: 10.4161/derm.2.2.13624.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B Grant &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3081677&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2010 Landes Bioscience&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight, Nutrition and Health Research Center (SUNARC); San Francisco, CA USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received July 18, 2010; Revised September 7, 2010; Accepted September 8, 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>France has unexplained &lt;strong>large latitudinal variations in cancer incidence and mortality rates&lt;/strong> . Studies of cancer rate variations in several other countries, as well as in multicountry studies, have explained such variations primarily in terms of gradients in solar ultraviolet-B (UVB) doses and vitamin D production. To investigate this possibility in France, I obtained data on&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heart patients 10 percent more likely to die for every 4 ng less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/heart-patients-10-percent-more-likely-to-die-for-every-4-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/heart-patients-10-percent-more-likely-to-die-for-every-4-ng-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-and-outcomes-in-heart-failure-patients">Vitamin D status and outcomes in heart failure patients.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#219-studies-cited-this-one-as-of-oct-2022">219 studies cited this one as of Oct 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-and-outcomes-in-heart-failure-patients">Vitamin D status and outcomes in heart failure patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Heart Fail. 2011 May 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liu LC, Voors AA, van Veldhuisen DJ, van der Veer E, Belonje AM, Szymanski MK, Silljé HH, van Gilst WH, Jaarsma T, de Boer RA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cardiology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Hanzeplein 1, PO Box 30.001, 9700 RB Groningen, The Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D should Improve mortality in Nordic Countries</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-should-improve-mortality-in-nordic-countries.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-should-improve-mortality-in-nordic-countries.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="review-article-health-benefit-of-increased-serum-25ohd-levels-from-oral-intake-and-ultraviolet-b-irradiance-in-the-nordic-countries">Review Article: Health benefit of increased serum 25(OH)D levels from oral intake and ultraviolet-B irradiance in the Nordic countries.&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpostsclick-here-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-904click-herea">&lt;a href="/posts/click-here" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 904">CLICK HERE&lt;/a>&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D associated with all-cause mortality and frailty</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-all-cause-mortality-and-frailty.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-all-cause-mortality-and-frailty.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-aging-beyond-calcium-and-bone-metabolism">Vitamin D and aging: Beyond calcium and bone metabolism&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Faustino R. Pérez-López&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Universidad de Zaragoza, Facultad de Medicina, Hospital Clínico, Zaragoza 50009, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 4 February 2011; accepted 9 February 2011. published online 08 March 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maturitas; European Menopause Journal&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) levels are common and may be associated with morbidity and mortality (and indeed with frailty more generally). This association is not restricted to the links between vitamin D and calcium and bone metabolism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>US truckers die 16 years sooner (UVA-low Vitamin D, obesity, little exercise)</title><link>/posts/us-truckers-die-16-years-sooner-uva-low-vitamin-d-obesity-little-exercise.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/us-truckers-die-16-years-sooner-uva-low-vitamin-d-obesity-little-exercise.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#from-pegasis-wirehttpwwwpegasusnewscomnews2011feb10dallas-dr-ken-cooper-supplement-truckersrefscroll437-feb-2011">From &lt;a href="http://www.pegasusnews.com/news/2011/feb/10/dallas-dr-ken-cooper-supplement-truckers/?refscroll=437">Pegasis Wire&lt;/a> Feb 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#note-a-hrefpostsuva-coming-thru-windows-decrease-vitamin-d-blood-levels-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-2472uva-coming-thru-windows-decrease-vitamin-d-blood-levels--march-2012a">Note &lt;a href="/posts/uva-coming-thru-windows-decrease-vitamin-d-blood-levels" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2472">UVA coming thru windows decrease vitamin D blood levels – March 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#had-never-heard-that-truckers-live-on-average-to-only-age-61">Had never heard that truckers live on average to only age 61.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2004-findings-that-truckers-have-a-mortality-rate-11-times-higher">&amp;ldquo;2004 findings that truckers have a mortality rate 11 times higher&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#quick-glance-on-internet-for-shift-work-and-mortality-or-longevity">Quick glance on internet for &amp;ldquo;shift work&amp;rdquo; AND (mortality OR Longevity)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#search-of-clinical-trials-for-shift-workers-mortality-or-longevityhttpwwwncbinlmnihgovpubmedtermshift20workers2028mortality20or20longevity29itoolquerysuggestion-got-55-hits-oct-2023">&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed?term=shift%20workers%20%28mortality%20OR%20longevity%29&amp;amp;itool=QuerySuggestion">Search of Clinical Trials for &amp;ldquo;shift workers&amp;rdquo; (mortality OR longevity)&lt;/a> got 55 hits Oct 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cdc-nov-2007httpwwwcdcgovnioshblognsb111907_truckhtml-with-many-many-comments">&lt;a href="http://www.cdc.gov/niosh/blog/nsb111907_truck.html">CDC Nov 2007&lt;/a> with many, many comments&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hard-turn-better-health-on-the-highwayhttpwwwnytimescom20111122healtha-hard-turn-truck-drivers-try-steering-from-bad-dietshtml-new-york-times-nov-21-2011">&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/11/22/health/a-hard-turn-truck-drivers-try-steering-from-bad-diets.html">A Hard Turn: Better Health on the Highway&lt;/a> New York Times Nov 21, 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#truck-drivers-are-11x-more-likely-to-suffer-from-sleep-apnea-than-the-general-population---2020">Truck drivers are 11x more likely to suffer from sleep apnea than the general population - 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#trucking-joke-buffet--big-ugly-fat-fellows-eating-together">Trucking joke: Buffet = “Big Ugly Fat Fellows Eating Together.”&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="from-pegasis-wirehttpwwwpegasusnewscomnews2011feb10dallas-dr-ken-cooper-supplement-truckersrefscroll437-feb-2011">From &lt;a href="http://www.pegasusnews.com/news/2011/feb/10/dallas-dr-ken-cooper-supplement-truckers/?refscroll=437">Pegasis Wire&lt;/a> Feb 2011&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Does not discuss shorter life due to stress, vibration, living away from home, smoking, poor eating, obesity, diabetes, Exposure to Diesel Particle Matter, &amp;hellip;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You are 66 percent more likely to die if low vitamin D – CDC</title><link>/posts/you-are-66-percent-more-likely-to-die-if-low-vitamin-d-cdc.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/you-are-66-percent-more-likely-to-die-if-low-vitamin-d-cdc.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-all-cause-mortality-among-adults-in-usa-findings-from-the-national-health-and-nutrition-examination-survey-linked-mortality-study">Vitamin D and all-cause mortality among adults in USA: findings from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey Linked Mortality Study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Int. J. Epidemiol. (2011) &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ije/dyq264">doi: 10.1093/ije/dyq264&lt;/a> * Accepted December 9, 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Earl S Ford &lt;a href="mailto:eford@cdc.gov">eford@cdc.gov&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Guixiang Zhao,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>James Tsai and&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Chaoyang Li&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Division of Adult and Community Health, National Center for Chronic Disease Prevention and Health Promotion, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background Whether concentrations of vitamin D are related to mortality remains unresolved. Our objective was to examine the relationship between serum concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D and all-cause mortality in a national sample of US adults.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Critically ill 70 percent more likely to die if vitamin D less than 15ng</title><link>/posts/critically-ill-70-percent-more-likely-to-die-if-vitamin-d-less-than-15ng.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/critically-ill-70-percent-more-likely-to-die-if-vitamin-d-less-than-15ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Less than 30 ng vitamin D greatly increased hazard of dying and diabetes</title><link>/posts/less-than-30-ng-vitamin-d-greatly-increased-hazard-of-dying-and-diabetes.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-than-30-ng-vitamin-d-greatly-increased-hazard-of-dying-and-diabetes.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cardiovascular-disease-risk-factors-and-markers-session-title">Cardiovascular Disease Risk Factors and Markers (Session Title)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Cardiology Volume 122, Issue 21 Supplement; November 23, 2010 / Abstracts From Scientific Sessions 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Core 2. Epidemiology and Prevention of CV Disease: Physiology, Pharmacology and Lifestyle&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-supplementation-impact-on-cardiovascular-morbidity-and-overall-mortality">Vitamin D Deficiency and Supplementation: Impact on Cardiovascular Morbidity and Overall Mortality&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Abstract 12680:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Subba Reddy Vanga; Matthew Good; Dhanunjaya Lakkireddy; Patricia Howard; James L Vacek&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Univ of Kansas Med Cntr and the Univ of Kansas Hosp, Kansas City, KS; Univ of Kansas Med Cntr, Kansas City, KS; Univ of Kansas Med Cntr and the Univ of Kansas Hosp, Kansas City, KS&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Too much and too little Calcium both increase death after strokes</title><link>/posts/too-much-and-too-little-calcium-both-increase-death-after-strokes.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/too-much-and-too-little-calcium-both-increase-death-after-strokes.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-calcium-levels-and-long-term-mortality-in-patients-with-acute-stroke">Serum Calcium Levels and Long-Term Mortality in Patients with Acute Stroke&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Shmuel A. Appela, Noa Molshatzkia, Yvonne Schwammenthala, Oleg Merzeliaka, Maya Toashia, Ben-Ami Selab, c, David Tannea, c&lt;/p>
&lt;p>aStroke Center, Department of Neurology, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>bInstitute of Chemical Pathology, The Chaim Sheba Medical Center, Tel Hashomer, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>cSackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prof. David Tanne; Stroke Center, Department of Neurology; The Chaim Sheba Medical Center; &lt;a href="mailto:tanne@post.tau.ac.il">tanne@post.tau.ac.il&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cerebrovasc Dis 2011;31:93-99 (DOI: 10.1159/000321335)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>