<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bone Surgery on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/bone-surgery.html</link><description>Recent content in Bone Surgery on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/bone-surgery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hip surgery with multiple doses of 50,000 IU of vitamin D weekly both before and after – RCT 2023</title><link>/posts/hip-surgery-with-multiple-doses-of-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly-both-before-and-after-rct-2023.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hip-surgery-with-multiple-doses-of-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly-both-before-and-after-rct-2023.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-status-and-repletion-on-postoperative-total-joint-arthroplasty-complicationshttpsclinicaltrialsgovct2shownct04229368-clinical-trials-datatbase">&lt;a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04229368">Effect of Vitamin D Status and Repletion on Postoperative Total Joint Arthroplasty Complications&lt;/a> Clinical Trials datatbase&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Active Comparator: High Vitamin D3 Supplementation&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Subjects enrolled into Group 2 (high-dose Vitamin D3 supplementation) will receive 50,000 IU of oral Vitamin D3 (Cholecalciferol) twice per week for 1 weeks followed by 50,000 IU once per week for 3 weeks prior to surgery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After surgery they will receive 50,000 IU of oral Vitamin D3 once per week for 4 weeks followed by 800 IU daily for 8 weeks. Vitamin D3 supplementation will be given for a total of 4 months.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Orthopaedic surgeries need Vitamin D – many studies</title><link>/posts/orthopaedic-surgeries-need-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/orthopaedic-surgeries-need-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki">VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#infections-after-bone-surgery-are-associated-with-low-vitamin-d---review-sept-2021">Infections after bone surgery are associated with low vitamin D - Review Sept 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#current-concepts-in-vitamin-d-and-orthopaedic-surgery---april-2019">Current concepts in vitamin D and orthopaedic surgery - April 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamindwiki">VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-genes-may-be-more-important-than-25ohd-to-orthopedics-review">Vitamin D genes may be more important than (25(OH)D) to orthopedics – Review Dec 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/reduced-knee-osteoarthritis-if-consistently-supplement-with-vitamin-d-for-2-years">Reduced knee osteoarthritis if consistently supplement with vitamin D for 2 years – April 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/total-knee-arthroplasty-worse-outcome-if-low-vitamin-d-many-studies">Total knee arthroplasty – worse outcome if low vitamin D – many studies&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Total hip replacement: 14 times more likely to redo if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/total-hip-replacement-14-times-more-likely-to-redo-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/total-hip-replacement-14-times-more-likely-to-redo-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="influence-of-vitamin-d-levels-on-revision-and-complication-rates-following-total-joint-arthroplasty">INFLUENCE OF VITAMIN D LEVELS ON REVISION AND COMPLICATION RATES FOLLOWING TOTAL JOINT ARTHROPLASTY&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Orthopaedic Proceedings, vol. 99-B no. SUPP 5 88 1 March 2017&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J.F. Plate, T.M. Seyler, A.D. Wohler, M.K. Langfitt, J.E. Lang&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wake Forest School of Medicine - Winston-Salem, USA &lt;a href="mailto:jplate@wakehealth.edu">jplate@wakehealth.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:750px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Brief summary of many studies on hip fractures and vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1) Having a high level of vitamin D greatly reduces the risk of hip fractures&lt;br>
2) &lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-insufficiency-increased-after-hip-replacement-38-percent-before-68-percent-the-next-day">A hip fracture consumes vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;br>
3) Far fewer complications after hip fracture if add sun/uv or vitamin D&lt;br>
4) 14X more likely to need revision surgery within 3 years if Vitamin D remains &amp;lt; 30 ng (this study)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dental implants 10 percent better with topical vitamin D (in dogs)</title><link>/posts/dental-implants-10-percent-better-with-topical-vitamin-d-in-dogs.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dental-implants-10-percent-better-with-topical-vitamin-d-in-dogs.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="topical-applications-of-vitamin-d-on-implant-surface-for-bone-to-implant-contact-enhance-a-pilot-study-in-dogs-part-ii">Topical applications of vitamin D on implant surface for bone-to-implant contact enhance: a pilot study in dogs part II.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Oral Implants Res. 2015 Sep 30. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.12707">doi: 10.1111/clr.12707&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Salomó-Coll O1, Maté-Sánchez de Val JE2, Ramírez-Fernandez MP2, Hernández-Alfaro F1, Gargallo-Albiol J1, Calvo-Guirado JL2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery, International University of Catalonia, Barcelona, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2International Dentistry Research Cathedra, Universidad Católica San Antonio de Murcia (UCAM), Murcia, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study was to evaluate the effect of topical application of vitamin D over implant surface, placed immediately to the extraction, throughout histological and histomorphometric analysis of peri-implant tissue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Should stock-up on vitamin D if having surgery due to fragile bones</title><link>/posts/should-stock-up-on-vitamin-d-if-having-surgery-due-to-fragile-bones.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/should-stock-up-on-vitamin-d-if-having-surgery-due-to-fragile-bones.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="short-term-and-long-term-orthopaedic-issues-in-patients-with-fragility-fractures">Short-term and Long-term Orthopaedic Issues in Patients With Fragility Fractures.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2011 Jan 29.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bukata SV, Kates SL, O&amp;rsquo;Keefe RJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Orthopaedics, University of Rochester, 601 Elmwood Ave, Box 665, Rochester, NY, 14534, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:susan_bukata@urmc.rochester.edu">susan_bukata@urmc.rochester.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Patients with impaired bone quality who suffer a fragility fracture face substantial challenges in both their short- and long-term care. In addition to poor bone quality, many of these patients have multiple medical comorbidities that alter their surgical risk and affect their ultimate functional recovery. Some medical issues can contribute to the altered bone quality and must be addressed to prevent future fractures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium and vitamin D supplements after hip fracture reduced death rate by 25%</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-supplements-after-hip-fracture-reduced-death-rate-by-25-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-supplements-after-hip-fracture-reduced-death-rate-by-25-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="post-hip-fracture-use-of-prescribed-calcium-plus-vitamin-d-or-vitamin-d-supplements-and-anti-osteoporotic-drugs-are-associated-with-lower-mortality">Post-hip fracture use of prescribed calcium plus vitamin D or vitamin D supplements and anti-osteoporotic drugs are associated with lower mortality.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="a-nationwide-study-in-finland">A nationwide study in Finland.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2011 Feb 23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jbmr.375.">doi: 10.1002/jbmr.375.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nurmi-Lüthje I, Sund R, Juntunen M, Lüthje P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Injury and Violence Prevention, Health Center of Kouvola, FI-45100 Kouvola, Finland; Hjelt Institute, Department of Public Health, FI-00014 Helsinki University, Finland. &lt;a href="mailto:ilona.nurmi@pp.inet.fi">ilona.nurmi@pp.inet.fi&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We previously found a positive association between calcium plus vitamin D and anti-osteoporotic drugs and survival among hip fracture patients. Our aim was to verify this observation using a nationwide database. A retrospective cohort of home-discharged hip fracture patients aged ?50 years (n?=?23 615) was enrolled from the national database. Primary exposure was medical treatment for osteoporosis and the outcome was all-cause mortality. Cumulative mortalities were calculated by using the Kaplan-Meier estimator. The relationship between mortality and medication purchases was modeled using Cox&amp;rsquo;s proportional hazards regression with time-dependent covariates for medication use. One in four women and one in ten men with a hip fracture were treated for osteoporosis in Finland. Unadjusted &lt;strong>one-year mortality was lower among patients who purchased calcium plus vitamin D or vitamin D supplements and anti-osteoporotic drugs&lt;/strong> than among those who did not purchase these medications (HR 0.74; 95% CI 0.67-0.81).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D before orthopedic surgery – dark skin 5X more likely</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-before-orthopedic-surgery-dark-skin-5x-more-likely.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-before-orthopedic-surgery-dark-skin-5x-more-likely.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-rampant-in-patients-undergoing-orthopedic-surgery-damaging-patient-recovery">Vitamin D Deficiency Rampant In Patients Undergoing Orthopedic Surgery, Damaging Patient Recovery&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>From &lt;a href="http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/203758.php">Medical News Today&lt;/a> Article Date: 07 Oct 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Almost 50 percent of patients undergoing orthopedic surgery have vitamin D deficiency that should be corrected before surgery to improve patient outcomes, based on a study by researchers at Hospital for Special Surgery (HSS) in New York City. Vitamin D is essential for bone healing and muscle function and is critical for a patient&amp;rsquo;s recovery. The study appears in the October issue of The Journal of Bone and Joint Surgery (see below)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>