<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Diabetes on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/diabetes.html</link><description>Recent content in Diabetes on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/diabetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Type 1 diabetes is increasing, vitamin D deficiency may be one of the reasons</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-is-increasing-vitamin-d-deficiency-may-be-one-of-the-reasons.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-is-increasing-vitamin-d-deficiency-may-be-one-of-the-reasons.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-is-type-1-diabetes-increasing">Why is type 1 diabetes increasing?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>J Mol Endocrinol August 1, 2013 51 R1-R13&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Francesco Maria Egro &lt;a href="mailto:francescoegro@gmail.com">francescoegro@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Cellular and Molecular Medicine, University of Bristol, 53 Arley Hill, Bristol BS6 5PJ, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A series of studies have reported a constant global rise in the incidence of type 1 diabetes. Epidemiological and immunological studies have demonstrated that environmental factors may influence the pathogenesis, leading to a cell-mediated pancreatic β-cell destruction associated with humoral immunity. The search for the triggering factor(s) has been going on for the past century, and yet they are still unknown. This review provides an overview of some of the most well-known theories found in the literature: hygiene, viral, vitamin D deficiency, breast milk and cow&amp;rsquo;s milk hypotheses. Although the hygiene hypothesis appears to be the most promising, positive evidence from animal, human and epidemiological studies precludes us from completely discarding any of the other hypotheses. Moreover, due to contrasting evidence in the literature, a single factor is unlikely to cause an increase in the incidence of diabetes all over the world, which suggests that a multifactorial process might be involved. Although the immunological mechanisms are still unclear, there seems to be some overlap between the various hypotheses. It is thought that the emphasis should be shifted from a single to a multifactorial process and that perhaps the ‘balance shift’ model should be considered as a possible explanation for the rise in the incidence of type 1 diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Will 1600 IU vitamin D prevent gestational diabetes – no, not enough,</title><link>/posts/will-1600-iu-vitamin-d-prevent-gestational-diabetes-no-not-enough.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/will-1600-iu-vitamin-d-prevent-gestational-diabetes-no-not-enough.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dali-vitamin-d-and-lifestyle-intervention-for-gestational-diabetes-mellitus-gdm-prevention-an-european-multicentre-randomised-trial----study-protocol">DALI: Vitamin D and lifestyle intervention for gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) prevention: an European multicentre, randomised trial &amp;ndash; study protocol&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth 2013, 13:142 doi:10.1186/1471-2393-13-142&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 5 July 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Judith GM Jelsma, Mireille NM van Poppel, Sander Galjaard, Gernot Desoye, Rosa Corcoy, Roland Devlieger, Andre van Assche, Dirk Timmerman, Goele Jans, Jurgen Harreiter, Alexandra Kautzky-Willer, Peter Damm, Elisabeth R Mathiesen, Dorte M Jensen, Liselotte Andersen, Fidelma Dunne, Annunziata Lapolla, Graziano Di Cianni, Alessandra Bertolotto, Ewa Wender-Oegowska, Agnieszka Zawiejska, Kinga Blumska, David Hill, Pablo Rebollo, Frank J Snoek and David Simmons&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 1 diabetes associated with faulty Vitamin D receptor genes</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-associated-with-faulty-vitamin-d-receptor-genes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-associated-with-faulty-vitamin-d-receptor-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-receptor-vdr-gene-polymorphisms-and-age-onset-in-type-1-diabetes-mellitus">Vitamin D receptor (VDR) gene polymorphisms and age onset in type 1 diabetes mellitus&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Autoimmunity Posted online on May 30, 2013. (doi:10.3109/08916934.2013.795952)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jaqueline De Azevêdo Silva 1,2, Rafael Lima Guimarães 1,2, Lucas André Cavalcanti Brandão 2,3, Jacqueline Araujo 4, Ludovica Segat 5, Sergio Crovella 1,2, and Paula Sandrin-Garcia 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Genetics, Federal University of Pernambuco, Recife, Pernambuco, Brazil,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Laboratory of Immunopathology Keizo Asami (LIKA), Federal University of Pernambuco,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 2 diabetes 1.5X more likely if low vs high vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/type-2-diabetes-15x-more-likely-if-low-vs-high-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-2-diabetes-15x-more-likely-if-low-vs-high-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="low-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-risk-of-type-2-diabetes-a-prospective-cohort-study-and-metaanalysis">Low 25-hydroxyvitamin D and risk of type 2 diabetes: a prospective cohort study and metaanalysis.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clin Chem. 2013 Feb;59(2):381-91. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1373/clinchem.2012.193003.">doi: 10.1373/clinchem.2012.193003.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Afzal S, Bojesen SE, Nordestgaard BG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Herlev Hospital, Copenhagen University Hospital, Copenhagen, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D deficiency has been implicated in decreased insulin secretion and increased insulin resistance, hallmarks of type 2 diabetes mellitus. We tested the hypothesis that low plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> is associated with increased risk of type 2 diabetes in the general population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X increase Diabetes if low vitamin D AND Arsenic in urine</title><link>/posts/3x-increase-diabetes-if-low-vitamin-d-and-arsenic-in-urine.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-increase-diabetes-if-low-vitamin-d-and-arsenic-in-urine.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-of-diabetes-mellitus-with-a-combination-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-arsenic-exposure-in-the-korean-general-population-analysis-of-20082009-korean-national-health-and-nutrition-examination-survey-data">Association of Diabetes Mellitus with a Combination of Vitamin D Deficiency and Arsenic Exposure in the Korean General Population: Analysis of 2008–2009 Korean National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey Data&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Annals of Occupational and Environmental Medicine 2013, 25:7 doi:10.1186/2052-4374-25-7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Byung-Kook Lee1 and Yangho Kim2; &lt;a href="mailto:yanghokm@nuri.net">yanghokm@nuri.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1 Institute of Environmental &amp;amp; Occupational Medicine, Soonchunhyang University 646 Eupnae-ri, Shinchang-myun, Asan-si, Choongnam, 336-745, South Korea&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>2 Department of Occupational and Environmental Medicine, Ulsan University Hospital, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Ulsan, South Korea&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects against many types of health problems – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-effects-on-musculoskeletal-health-immunity-autoimmunity-cardiovascular-disease-cancer-fertility-pregnancy-dementia-and-mortality-a-review-of-recent-evidence">Vitamin D effects on musculoskeletal health, immunity, autoimmunity, cardiovascular disease, cancer, fertility, pregnancy, dementia and mortality-A review of recent evidence.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmun Rev. 2013 Mar 28. pii: S1568-9972(13)00040-2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.">doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pawel Pludowski a &lt;a href="mailto:p.pludowski@czd.pl">p.pludowski@czd.pl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael F. Holick b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Pilzc, d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carol L. Wagner e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce W. Hollis e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant f,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yehuda Shoenfeld g,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elisabeth Lerchbaum c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David J. Llewellyn h,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katharina Kienreich c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maya Soni h&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Biochemistry, Radioimmunology and Experimental Medicine, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Health Institute, Warsaw, Poland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Obesity causes vitamin D deficiency and type 2 diabetes - 2012</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-obesity-causes-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-type-2-diabetes-2012.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-obesity-causes-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-type-2-diabetes-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-a-new-risk-factor-for-type-2-diabetes">Vitamin D deficiency: a new risk factor for type 2 diabetes?.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ann Nutr Metab. 2012;61(4):337-48. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1159/000342771.">doi: 10.1159/000342771.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Dec 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mezza T, Muscogiuri G, Sorice GP, Prioletta A, Salomone E, Pontecorvi A, Giaccari A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinologia, Università Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Roma, Italia. &lt;a href="mailto:teresa.mezza@gmail.com">teresa.mezza@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent compelling evidence suggests a role of vitamin D deficiency in the pathogenesis of insulin resistance and insulin secretion derangements, with a consequent possible interference with type 2 diabetes mellitus. The mechanism of this link is incompletely understood. In fact, vitamin D deficiency is usually detected in obesity in which insulin resistance is also a common finding. The coexistence of insulin resistance and vitamin D deficiency has generated several hypotheses. Some cross-sectional and prospective studies have suggested that vitamin D deficiency may play a role in worsening insulin resistance; others have identified obesity as a risk factor predisposing individuals to exhibit both vitamin D deficiency and insulin resistance. The available data from intervention studies are largely confounded, and inadequate considerations of seasonal effects on 25(OH)D concentrations are also a common design flaw in many studies. On the contrary, there is strong evidence that obesity might cause both vitamin D deficiency and insulin resistance, leaving open the possibility that vitamin D and diabetes are not related at all. Although it might seem premature to draw firm conclusions on the role of vitamin D supplementation in reducing insulin resistance and preventing type 2 diabetes, this manuscript will review the circumstances leading to vitamin D deficiency and how such a deficiency can eventually independently affect insulin sensitivity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4 percent less type 2 diabetes for every 4 ng more vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/4-percent-less-type-2-diabetes-for-every-4-ng-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4-percent-less-type-2-diabetes-for-every-4-ng-more-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="blood-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-levels-and-incident-type-2-diabetes-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Blood 25-Hydroxy Vitamin D Levels and Incident Type 2 Diabetes: A meta-analysis of prospective studies.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care. 2013 May;36(5):1422-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2337/dc12-0962.">doi: 10.2337/dc12-0962.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Song Y, Wang L, Pittas AG, Del Gobbo LC, Zhang C, Manson JE, Hu FB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corresponding author: Yiqing Song, &lt;a href="mailto:ysong3@rics.bwh.harvard.edu">ysong3@rics.bwh.harvard.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE To quantitatively assess the strength and shape of the association between blood 25-hydroxy vitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and incident risk of type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS A systematic search of the MEDLINE and Embase databases and a hand search of references from original reports were conducted up to 31 October 2012. Prospective observational studies that assessed the association between blood levels of 25(OH)D and risk of incident type 2 diabetes were included for meta-analysis. DerSimonian and Laird&amp;rsquo;s random-effects model was used. A quadratic spline regression analysis was used to examine the shape of the association with a generalized least-squares trend test performed for the dose-response relation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>44 percent less Type 1 diabetes if high level of vitamin D – white skinned military</title><link>/posts/44-percent-less-type-1-diabetes-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d-white-skinned-military.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/44-percent-less-type-1-diabetes-if-high-level-of-vitamin-d-white-skinned-military.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="preclinical-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-risk-of-type-1-diabetes-in-a-cohort-of-us-military-personnel">Preclinical serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels and risk of type 1 diabetes in a cohort of US military personnel.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Epidemiol. 2013 Mar 1;177(5):411-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/aje/kws243.">doi: 10.1093/aje/kws243.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Feb 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Munger KL, Levin LI, Massa J, Horst R, Orban T, Ascherio A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutrition, Harvard School of Public Health, Harvard University, Boston, MA 02115, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:kgorham@hsph.harvard.edu">kgorham@hsph.harvard.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine whether serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) in young adults are associated with risk of type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1D), we conducted a prospective, nested case-control study among US active-duty military personnel with serum in the US Department of Defense Serum Repository, identifying 310 T1D cases diagnosed between 1997 and 2009 with at least 2 serum samples collected before disease onset and 613 controls matched to cases on age, sex, race/ethnicity, branch of military service, and dates of serum collection. Conditional logistic regression was used to estimate rate ratios and 95% confidence intervals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 1 diabetes strongly associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-role-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-the-incidence-progression-and-complications-of-type-1-diabetes-mellitus">The role of vitamin d deficiency in the incidence, progression, and complications of type 1 diabetes mellitus.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Int J Endocrinol. 2013;2013:148673. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1155/2013/148673.">doi: 10.1155/2013/148673.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Mar 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chakhtoura M, Azar ST.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, American University of Beirut-Medical Center, 3 Dag Hammarskjold Plaza, 8th floor, New York, NY 10017, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &amp;ldquo;nonclassic&amp;rdquo; role of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3) has been recently widely recognized. In type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1D), it plays an immunomodulatory role through the vitamin D receptor (VDR) present on pancreatic and immune cells. Specific VDR allelic variants have been associated with T1D in many countries. Furthermore, vitamin D deficiency has been prevalent in T1D, and the seasonal and latitude variability in the incidence of T1D can be partly explained by the related variability in vitamin D level. In fact, retrospective studies of vitamin D supplementation during pregnancy or infancy showed a lower incidence of T1D. We will review the different mechanisms of the vitamin D protective effect against insulitis and present the available data on the role of vitamin D deficiency in the control, progression, and complications of T1D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dr. Holick video on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dr-holick-video-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dr-holick-video-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="holick-video-on-youtubehttpwwwyoutubecomwatchvhigbvdcbfvkfeatureyoutube">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hiGBVDcbFVk&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be">Holick Video on YouTube&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-few-images-from-another-of-his-excellent-videos">A few images from another of his excellent videos&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="other-forms-of-vitamin-d-generated">Other forms of vitamin D generated&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-other-forms-of-vitamin-d-generated.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="c-section">C-section&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-c-section.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h2 id="iguana-with-little-vitamin-d">Iguana with little vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-iguana.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="uvb-white-skin-vs-black-skin">UVB White skin vs black skin&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/hollick-uvb-white-vs-black.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;h3 id="global-deficiency-of-vitamin-d">Global deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-global-deficiency.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="psorasis-placebo-vs-vitamin-d">Psorasis placebo vs vitamin d&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-psorasis-pacelbo-vs-vitamin-d.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="navy-indoors-8x-more-death-than-outdoors---1915">Navy indoors 8X more death than outdoors - 1915&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-navy-indoors-8x-more-death-than-outdoors---1915.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="type-1-diabetes-10x-less-at-equator">Type 1 diabetes 10X less at equator&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-type-1-diabetes-10x-less-at-equator.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="perhipheral-vascular-disease-decrease-80">Perhipheral Vascular Disease decrease 80%&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-pvd-decrease-80-.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="holick-and-his-family-take-3000-iu-vitamin-d-total-daily">Holick and his family take 3000 IU vitamin D total daily&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-3000-iu-vitamin-d-total.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="holick-recommendations-vs-age">Holick recommendations vs age&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-recommendations-vs-age.jpg" alt="image" width="400"></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D receptor gene associated with 50 percent more type 2 Diabetes – meta-analyses 2013, 2016</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-gene-associated-with-50-percent-more-type-2-diabetes-meta-analyses-2013-2016.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-gene-associated-with-50-percent-more-type-2-diabetes-meta-analyses-2013-2016.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#type-2-diabetes-in-chinese-is-50-percent-more-likely-if-have-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-problem--meta-analysis-2016">Type 2 Diabetes in Chinese is 50 percent more likely if have Vitamin D Receptor gene problem – meta-analysis 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-and-type-2-diabetes-a-meta-analysis--march-2013">Vitamin D Receptor Gene Polymorphisms and Type 2 Diabetes: A Meta-analysis.- March 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="type-2-diabetes-in-chinese-is-50-percent-more-likely-if-have-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-problem--meta-analysis-2016">Type 2 Diabetes in Chinese is 50 percent more likely if have Vitamin D Receptor gene problem – meta-analysis 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The genetic polymorphisms in vitamin D receptor and the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus: an updated meta-analysis.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Insulin improvement in obese teens with 4000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/insulin-improvement-in-obese-teens-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/insulin-improvement-in-obese-teens-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="correcting-vitamin-d-insufficiency-improves-insulin-sensitivity-in-obese-adolescents-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Correcting vitamin D insufficiency improves insulin sensitivity in obese adolescents: a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2013 Feb 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Belenchia AM, Tosh AK, Hillman LS, Peterson CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutrition and Exercise Physiology, University of Missouri, Columbia, MO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Obese adolescents are at a greater risk of vitamin D deficiency because vitamin D is thought to be sequestered by excess adipose tissue. Poor vitamin D status has been associated with a higher prevalence of the metabolic syndrome, type 2 diabetes, or both in adults and adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Insulin resistance helped with 50000 IU of vitamin D weekly</title><link>/posts/insulin-resistance-helped-with-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/insulin-resistance-helped-with-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-insulin-resistance-in-patients-with-type-2-diabetes">The effect of vitamin D on insulin resistance in patients with type 2 diabetes.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2013 Feb 26;5(1):8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1758-5996-5-8.">doi: 10.1186/1758-5996-5-8.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Talaei A, Mohamadi M, Adgi Z.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thyroid Disorders Research Center, Arak University of Medical Sciences, Arak, Iran. &lt;a href="mailto:talaei@arakmu.ac.ir">talaei@arakmu.ac.ir&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Over the past decade, numerous non-skeletal diseases have been reported to be associated with vitamin D deficiency including type2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). Different studies provide evidence that vitamin D may play a functional role in glucose tolerance through its effects on insulin secretion and insulin sensitivity. This study evaluates the effects of vitamin D supplementation on insulin resistance in T2DM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetics who were low on vitamin D were 2X more likely to become obese</title><link>/posts/diabetics-who-were-low-on-vitamin-d-were-2x-more-likely-to-become-obese.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetics-who-were-low-on-vitamin-d-were-2x-more-likely-to-become-obese.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hypovitaminosis-d-and-incidence-of-obesity-a-prospective-study">Hypovitaminosis D and incidence of obesity: a prospective study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2013 Feb 20. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2013.48.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2013.48.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>González-Molero I, Rojo-Martínez G, Morcillo S, Gutierrez C, Rubio E, Pérez-Valero V, Esteva I, Ruiz de Adana MS, Almaraz MC, Colomo N, Olveira G, Soriguer F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1] Servicio de Endocrinología y Nutrición, Hospital Regional Universitario Carlos Haya de Málaga, Málaga, Spain &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup> Ciber de Diabetes y Metabolismo (CIBERDEM), Barcelona, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study was to assess the relationship between obesity and vitamin D status cross-sectionally, the relationship between obesity and the incidence of hypovitaminosis D prospectively and inversely the relationship between vitamin D status and incidence of obesity in a population-based cohort study in Spain. At baseline (1996-1998), 1226 subjects were evaluated and follow-up assessments were performed in 2002-2004 and 2005-2007, participants undergoing an interview and clinical examination with an oral glucose tolerance test. At the second visit, 25-hydroxyvitamin D and intact parathyroid hormone concentrations were also measured. Prevalence of obesity at the three visits was 28.1, 36.2 and 39.5%, respectively. The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency (25-hydroxyvitamin D 20 ng/ml (50 nmol/l)) was 34.7%. Neither obesity at baseline (OR=0.98, 95% CI: 0.69-1.40, P=0.93) nor the development of obesity between baseline and the second evaluation (OR=0.80, 95% CI: 0.48-1.33, P=0.39) were significantly associated with vitamin D status. In subjects who were non-obese (BMI &amp;lt;30 kg/m(2)) at the second evaluation, 25-hydroxyvitamin D values 17 ng/ml (42.5 nmol/l) were significantly associated with an increased risk of developing obesity in the next 4 years (OR=2.35, 95% CI: 1.03-5.4, P=0.040 after diverse adjustments).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetic Neuropathy sometimes can be reversed by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetic-neuropathy-sometimes-can-be-reversed-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetic-neuropathy-sometimes-can-be-reversed-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="exercise--vitamin-d-400-iu--1-gram-calcium-carbonate-helpes-diabetic-neuropathy-in-many-ways---may-2017">Exercise + Vitamin D (400 IU + 1 gram Calcium Carbonate) helpes Diabetic Neuropathy in many ways - May 2017&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Comparison between Effects of 12 weeks Combined Training and Vitamin D Supplement on Improvement of Sensory-motor Neuropathy in type 2 Diabetic Women.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adv Biomed Res. 2017 May 2;6:55. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4103/2277-9175.205528.">doi: 10.4103/2277-9175.205528.&lt;/a> eCollection 2017.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nadi M1, Marandi SM1, Esfarjani F1, Saleki M2, Mohammadi M3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: vitamin D and probiotics will reduce type II diabetes</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-and-probiotics-will-reduce-type-ii-diabetes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-vitamin-d-and-probiotics-will-reduce-type-ii-diabetes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-prebiotics-may-benefit-the-intestinal-microbacteria-and-improve-glucose-homeostasis-in-prediabetes-and-type-2-diabetes">Vitamin D and Prebiotics May Benefit the Intestinal Microbacteria and Improve Glucose Homeostasis in Prediabetes and Type 2 Diabetes.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2013 Jan 21:1-40.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barengolts E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Section of Endocrinology, Department of Medicine, University of Illinois Medical Center and Jesse Brown VA Medical Center, Chicago, Illinois.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To review the role of human large bowel microbacteria (microbiota) in the glucose homeostasis, to address vitamin D (VD) and prebiotics interactions with microbiota, and to summarize recent randomized clinical trials (RCT) of VD and prebiotics supplementation in prediabetes and T2DM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Insulin sensitivity in obese adolescents greatly improved with 4000 IU of vitamin D - RCT</title><link>/posts/insulin-sensitivity-in-obese-adolescents-greatly-improved-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/insulin-sensitivity-in-obese-adolescents-greatly-improved-with-4000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="correcting-vitamin-d-insufficiency-improves-insulin-sensitivity-in-obese-adolescents-a-randomized-controlled-trial123">Correcting vitamin D insufficiency improves insulin sensitivity in obese adolescents: a randomized controlled trial1,2,3&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr April 2013 ajcn.050013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anthony M Belenchia,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aneesh K Tosh,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laura S Hillman, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Catherine A Peterson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1From the Department of Nutrition and Exercise Physiology (AMB and CAP), and the Department of Child Health, University of Missouri School of Medicine (AKT and LSH), University of Missouri, Columbia, MO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵2 Supported by a JR Albert Foundation grant (Naperville, IL).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Magnesium and type II diabetes</title><link>/posts/low-magnesium-and-type-ii-diabetes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-magnesium-and-type-ii-diabetes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="correlation-of-magnesium-intake-with-metabolic-parameters-depression-and-physical-activity-in-elderly-type-2-diabetes-patients-a-cross-sectional-study">Correlation of magnesium intake with metabolic parameters, depression and physical activity in elderly type 2 diabetes patients: a cross-sectional study.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nutr J. 2012 Jun 13;11:41. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1475-2891-11-41.">doi: 10.1186/1475-2891-11-41.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Huang JH, Lu YF, Cheng FC, Lee JN, Tsai LC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Graduate Institute of Ph.D. Program in Nutrition and Food Science, Fu-JenCatholic University, New Taipei City, Hsinchuang, Taiwan.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/magnesium-and-diabetes.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/type-ii-diabetes-might-be-prevented-and-treated-with-magnesium-review" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Type II Diabetes might be prevented and treated with Magnesium – Review Feb 2015">Type II Diabetes might be prevented and treated with Magnesium – Review Feb 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 1 Diabetes probability reduced by 2X if have more than 40 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-probability-reduced-by-2x-if-have-more-than-40-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-probability-reduced-by-2x-if-have-more-than-40-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="preclinical-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-risk-of-type-1-diabetes-in-a-cohort-of-us-military-personnel">Preclinical Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels and Risk of Type 1 Diabetes in a Cohort of US Military Personnel&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>American Journal of Epidemiology, 10.1093/aje/kws243&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kassandra L. Munger*, Lynn I. Levin, Jennifer Massa, Ronald Horst, Tihamer Orban and Alberto Ascherio&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵*Correspondence to Dr. Kassandra L. Munger, Harvard School of Public Health, 665 Huntington Avenue, Building 2, 3rd Floor, Boston, MA 02115 (e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:kgorham@hsph.harvard.edu">kgorham@hsph.harvard.edu&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abbreviations: CI, confidence interval; CLIA, chemiluminescence immunoassay; GAD, glutamic acid decarboxylase; 25(OH)D, 25-hydroxyvitamin D; RIA radioimmunoassay; RR, rate ratio; T1D, type 1 diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Decreasing Magnesium and increasing CaMg ratio are increasing health problems – 2012 - 2013</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-decreasing-magnesium-and-increasing-camg-ratio-are-increasing-health-problems-2012-2013.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-decreasing-magnesium-and-increasing-camg-ratio-are-increasing-health-problems-2012-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="2-items-by-a-rosanoff">2 items by A Rosanoff&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="suboptimal-magnesium-status-in-the-united-states-are-the-health-consequences-underestimated">Suboptimal magnesium status in the United States: are the health consequences underestimated?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr Rev. 2012 Mar;70(3):153-64. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1753-4887.2011.00465.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1753-4887.2011.00465.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Feb 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rosanoff A, Weaver CM, Rude RK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Magnesium Education &amp;amp; Research, 13-1255 Malama Street, Pahoa, HI 96778, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:ARosanoff@gmail.com">ARosanoff@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In comparison with calcium, magnesium is an &amp;ldquo;orphan nutrient&amp;rdquo; that has been studied considerably less heavily. Low magnesium intakes and blood levels have been associated with type 2 diabetes, metabolic syndrome, elevated C-reactive protein, hypertension, atherosclerotic vascular disease, sudden cardiac death, osteoporosis, migraine headache, asthma, and colon cancer. Almost half (48%) of the US population consumed less than the required amount of magnesium from food in 2005-2006, and the figure was down from 56% in 2001-2002. Surveys conducted over 30 years indicate rising calcium-to-magnesium food-intake ratios among adults and the elderly in the United States, excluding intake from supplements, which favor calcium over magnesium.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolic Syndrome 10% less likely for every 4 ng increase in Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-10-percent-less-likely-for-every-4-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-10-percent-less-likely-for-every-4-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-parathyroid-hormone-and-their-association-with-metabolic-syndrome-in-chinese">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D, parathyroid hormone, and their association with metabolic syndrome in Chinese.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocrine. 2013 Jan 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Li LH, Yin XY, Yao CY, Zhu XC, Wu XH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Dali University School of Clinical Medicine, Jiashibo Road 32, Dali, 671000, Yunnan, China, &lt;a href="mailto:lilihuayncn@gmail.com">lilihuayncn@gmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Increasing evidence suggests that 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> and parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels are associated with metabolic syndrome (MetS). In 2010, we explored the association of serum 25(OH)D and PTH levels with MetS in 1,390 Chinese participants, aged 20-83 years. Anthropometric phenotypes, blood pressure, and the incidence of MetS were evaluated. In addition, serum lipids, 25(OH)D, and PTH were measured. The median concentration of 25(OH)D and PTH were 55.3 nmol/l and 2.8 pmol/l, respectively. The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency (&amp;lt;50 nmol/l) was 39.9 %, with 34.5 % in men and 47.8 % in women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No association between diabetes level and vitamin D insufficiency in obese youth</title><link>/posts/no-association-between-diabetes-level-and-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-obese-youth.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-association-between-diabetes-level-and-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-obese-youth.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-obese-youth-across-the-spectrum-of-glucose-tolerance-from-normal-to-prediabetes-to-type-2-diabetes">25-Hydroxyvitamin D in Obese Youth Across the Spectrum of Glucose Tolerance From Normal to Prediabetes to Type 2 Diabetes.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care. 2013 Jan 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>de Las Heras J, Rajakumar K, Lee S, Bacha F, Holick MF, Arslanian SA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatric Metabolism, Hospital Universitario de Cruces, Barakaldo, Vizcaya, Spain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE To 1) determine if plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) concentrations differ among obese youth with normal glucose tolerance (NGT) versus prediabetes versus type 2 diabetes, and 2) assess the relationships between 25(OH)D and in vivo insulin sensitivity and β-cell function in this cohort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prediabetics not helped by 50,000 IU of vitamin D weekly and Calcium</title><link>/posts/prediabetics-not-helped-by-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prediabetics-not-helped-by-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-weekly-and-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-effects-of-oral-vitamin-d-on-insulin-resistance-in-pre-diabetic-patients">The effects of oral vitamin D on insulin resistance in pre-diabetic patients&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Research in Medical Sciences, Vol 18, No 1 (2013)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seyed A Hoseini, Ashraf Aminorroaya, Bijan Iraj, Massoud Amini&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Seyed A Hoseini: Department of Internal Medicine and Endocrinology, Isfahan Endocrine and Metabolism Research Center, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ashraf Aminorroaya: Department of Internal Medicine and Endocrinology, Isfahan Endocrine and Metabolism Research Center, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>African-Americans at high risk of obesity and diabetes - 2011</title><link>/posts/african-americans-at-high-risk-of-obesity-and-diabetes-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/african-americans-at-high-risk-of-obesity-and-diabetes-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-type-2-diabetes-in-african-americans-the-common-denominators">Vitamin D Deficiency and Type 2 Diabetes in African Americans: The Common Denominators&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Shani V. Davis, MSN, ANP-BC, CDE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetic Spectrum&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metabolic Syndrome in children is associated with low vitamin D – review</title><link>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-in-children-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/metabolic-syndrome-in-children-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-association-between-vitamin-d-and-cardiometabolic-risk-factors-in-children---a-systematic-review">The Association Between Vitamin D and Cardiometabolic Risk Factors in Children - A Systematic Review&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>CLIN PEDIATR January 8, 2013 0009922812470742&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diana H. Dolinsky, MD, MPH&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah Armstrong, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Caren Mangarelli, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alex R. Kemper, MD, MPH, MS&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Duke University Medical Center, Durham, NC, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah Armstrong, Department of Pediatrics, Duke University Medical Center, 4020 North Roxboro Street, Durham, NC 27704, USA Email: &lt;a href="mailto:sarah.c.armstrong@dm.duke.edu">sarah.c.armstrong@dm.duke.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this systematic review was to evaluate the association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) and cardiometabolic risk in children and the effect of vitamin D supplementation on risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type II Diabetes not reduced by 3 months of 5000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/type-ii-diabetes-not-reduced-by-3-months-of-5000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-ii-diabetes-not-reduced-by-3-months-of-5000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="randomized-controlled-trial-of-vitamin-d-supplement-on-endothelial-function-in-patients-with-type-2-diabetes">Randomized controlled trial of vitamin D supplement on endothelial function in patients with type 2 diabetes&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Atherosclerosis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yuen-Fung Yiu, Kai-Hang Yiu, Chung-Wah Siu, Yap-Hang Chan, Sheung-Wai Li, Lai-Yung Wong, Stephen W.L. Lee, Sidney Tam, Eric W.K. Wong, Chu-Pak Lau, Bernard M.Y. Cheung &lt;a href="mailto:bernardmycheung@gmail.com">bernardmycheung@gmail.com&lt;/a>, Hung-Fat Tse&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 29 July 2012; received in revised form 2 December 2012; accepted 16 December 2012. published online 07 January 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suboptimal vitamin D status is associated with endothelial dysfunction and an increased risk of cardiovascular diseases but it is unclear whether vitamin D supplementation is beneficial. The aim was to investigate the effect of vitamin D supplementation on endothelial function in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (DM).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pancreatic cancer 80 percent more likely if person had diabetes for 2-8 years</title><link>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-80-percent-more-likely-if-person-had-diabetes-for-2-8-years.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pancreatic-cancer-80-percent-more-likely-if-person-had-diabetes-for-2-8-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="diabetes-and-risk-of-pancreatic-cancer-a-pooled-analysis-from-the-pancreatic-cancer-cohort-consortium">Diabetes and risk of pancreatic cancer: a pooled analysis from the pancreatic cancer cohort consortium&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes &amp;amp; Control, January 2013, Volume 24, Issue 1, pp 13-25&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joanne W. Elena, Emily Steplowski, Kai Yu, Patricia Hartge, Geoffrey S. Tobias, Michelle J. Brotzman, Stephen J. Chanock, Rachael Z. Stolzenberg-Solomon, Alan A. Arslan, H. Bas Bueno-de-Mesquita, … show all 50&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetes is a suspected risk factor for pancreatic cancer, but questions remain about whether it is a risk factor or a result of the disease. This study prospectively examined the association between diabetes and the risk of pancreatic adenocarcinoma in pooled data from the NCI pancreatic cancer cohort consortium (PanScan).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU of vitamin D helped Type 2 diabetic women, but was not enough</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-helped-type-2-diabetic-women-but-was-not-enough.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-helped-type-2-diabetic-women-but-was-not-enough.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-as-an-adjuvant-therapy-for-patients-with-t2dm">Vitamin D supplementation as an adjuvant therapy for patients with T2DM:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="an-18-month-prospective-interventional-study">an 18-month prospective interventional study.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2012 Jul 18;11(1):85. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1475-2840-11-85.">doi: 10.1186/1475-2840-11-85.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Al-Daghri NM, Alkharfy KM, Al-Othman A, El-Kholie E, Moharram O, Alokail MS, Al-Saleh Y, Sabico S, Kumar S, Chrousos GP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Biomarkers Research Program, Biochemistry Department, College of Science, King Saud University, PO Box, 2455, Riyadh, 11451, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. &lt;a href="mailto:aldaghri2011@gmail.com">aldaghri2011@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with impaired human insulin action, suggesting a role in the pathogenesis of diabetes mellitus type 2 (T2DM). In this prospective interventional study we investigated the effects of vitamin D3 supplementation on the metabolic profiles of Saudi T2DM subjects pre- and post-vitamin D supplementation over an 18-month period.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scientific explanation of vitamin D relationship to insulin resistance</title><link>/posts/scientific-explanation-of-vitamin-d-relationship-to-insulin-resistance.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/scientific-explanation-of-vitamin-d-relationship-to-insulin-resistance.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-up-regulates-glucose-transporter-4-glut4-translocation-and-glucose-utilization-mediated-by-cystathionine-γ-lyase-cse-activation-and-h2s-formation-in-3t3l1-adipocytes">Vitamin D Up-regulates Glucose Transporter 4 (GLUT4) Translocation and Glucose Utilization Mediated by Cystathionine-γ-lyase (CSE) Activation and H2S Formation in 3T3L1 Adipocytes*&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>December 7, 2012 The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 287, 42324-42332.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prasenjit Manna and Sushil K. Jain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Department of Pediatrics, Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center, Shreveport, Louisiana 71103&lt;/p>
&lt;p>↵1 To whom correspondence should be addressed: Dept. of Pediatrics, LSU Health Sciences Center, 1501 Kings Hwy., Shreveport, LA 71103. Tel.: 1-318-675-6086; Fax: 1-318-675-6059; E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:sjain@lsuhsc.edu">sjain@lsuhsc.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 1 Diabetes associated with low vitamin D, especially in dark skinned youths</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-especially-in-dark-skinned-youths.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-especially-in-dark-skinned-youths.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hyperglycemia in black veterans is associated with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hyperglycemia-in-black-veterans-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hyperglycemia-in-black-veterans-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="relationship-between-hbaic-and-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-in-african-american-and-caucasian-american-men">Relationship Between Hbaic and Circulating 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration in African American and Caucasian American Men.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2012 Nov 27:1-22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manickam B, Neagu V, Kukreja S, Barengolts E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Section of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Medicine, Jesse Brown VA and Section of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Medicine, University of Illinois Medical Centers, Chicago, IL 60612.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To examine whether (1) serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> is a risk factor for hyperglycemia, as assessed by HbA1c, in African American men (AAM) and (2) 25(OH)D is a predictor of HbA1c in AAM and Caucasian American men (CAM).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of Autoimmune diseases, solar radiation and vitamin D – Schwalfenberg 2012</title><link>/posts/review-of-autoimmune-diseases-solar-radiation-and-vitamin-d-schwalfenberg-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-autoimmune-diseases-solar-radiation-and-vitamin-d-schwalfenberg-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="solar-radiation-and-vitamin-d-mitigating-environmental-factors-in-autoimmune-disease">Solar Radiation and Vitamin D: Mitigating Environmental Factors in Autoimmune Disease&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal of Environmental and Public Health, Volume 2012 (2012), Article ID 619381, 9 pages, Review Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gerry K. Schwalfenberg&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Family Medicine, University of Alberta, Suite No. 301, 9509-156 Street, Edmonton, AB, Canada T6G 2M7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 3 July 2011; Revised 29 November 2011; Accepted 13 December 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This paper looks at the environmental role of vitamin D and solar radiation as risk reduction factors in autoimmune disease. Five diseases are considered: multiple sclerosis, type 1 diabetes, rheumatoid arthritis, autoimmune disease of the thyroid, and inflammatory bowel disease. Clinical relevant studies and factors that may indicate evidence that autoimmune disease is a vitamin D-sensitive disease are presented. Studies that have resulted in prevention or amelioration of some autoimmune disease are discussed. An example of the utility of supplementing vitamin D in an unusual autoimmune disease, idiopathic thrombocytic purpura, is presented.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Timeline of Heart Disease, Diabetes, fats, lard, HFCS, and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/timeline-of-heart-disease-diabetes-fats-lard-hfcs-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/timeline-of-heart-disease-diabetes-fats-lard-hfcs-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#subset-of--illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015httpdietheartnewscom201208illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-201520-diet-heart-news-aug-2012">Subset of &lt;a href="http://dietheartnews.com/2012/08/illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015/%20">Illustrated History of Heart Disease 1825-2015&lt;/a> Diet Heart News Aug 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-trans-fats">See also trans-fats&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#more-cholesterol-is-associated-with-fewer-deaths---around-the-entire-world">MORE cholesterol is associated with FEWER deaths - around the entire world&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsoverview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-889overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-da-has-the-following-chart">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 889">Overview Deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/a> has the following chart&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="subset-of--illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015httpdietheartnewscom201208illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-201520-diet-heart-news-aug-2012">Subset of &lt;a href="http://dietheartnews.com/2012/08/illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015/%20">Illustrated History of Heart Disease 1825-2015&lt;/a> Diet Heart News Aug 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Note: &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">lard&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">butter&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> used to have lots of vitamin D and &lt;a href="/posts/omega-3" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 3467">Omega-3&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prevent half of T1 Diabetes with vitamin D levels of 50 ng</title><link>/posts/prevent-half-of-t1-diabetes-with-vitamin-d-levels-of-50-ng.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prevent-half-of-t1-diabetes-with-vitamin-d-levels-of-50-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="lower-prediagnostic-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-is-associated-with-higher-risk-of-insulin-requiring-diabetes-a-nested-casecontrol-study">Lower prediagnostic serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration is associated with higher risk of insulin-requiring diabetes: a nested case–control study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>E. D. Gorham, C. F. Garland, A. A. Burgi, S. B. Mohr and K. Zeng, et al.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetologia, 2012, Volume 55, Number 12, Pages 3224-3227&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aims/hypothesis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentration may increase risk of insulin-requiring diabetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A nested case–control study was performed using serum collected during 2002–2008 from military service members. &lt;strong>One thousand subjects subsequently developed insulin-requiring diabetes&lt;/strong> . A healthy control was individually matched to each case on blood-draw date (±2 days), age (±3 months), length of service (±30 days) and sex.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>T1 Diabetes increased about 15 percent per decade in Eastern Canada</title><link>/posts/t1-diabetes-increased-about-15-percent-per-decade-in-eastern-canada.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/t1-diabetes-increased-about-15-percent-per-decade-in-eastern-canada.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="recent-incidence-of-type-1-diabetes-mellitus-in-children-0--14-years-in-newfoundland-and-labrador-canada-climbs-to-over-45100000--a-retrospective-time-trend-study">Recent incidence of type 1 diabetes mellitus in children 0&amp;ndash;14 years in Newfoundland and Labrador, Canada climbs to over 45/100,000: a retrospective time trend study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Res Notes. 2012 Nov 12;5(1):628.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Newhook LA, Penney S, Fiander J, Dowden J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: To study and update the provincial incidence of type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM) in Newfoundland and Labrador (NL), a province of Canada with a very high incidence previously reported in 2006, and one of the highest incidences reported worldwide. This is a retrospective time trend study of the incidence of T1DM, in children aged 0 -14 years from 1987 -2010 inclusive.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D level higher than 30 ng reduces diabetic blood clotting</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-level-higher-than-30-ng-reduces-diabetic-blood-clotting.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-level-higher-than-30-ng-reduces-diabetic-blood-clotting.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Worse diabetic vision is associated with low vitamin D or high PTH</title><link>/posts/worse-diabetic-vision-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-or-high-pth.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/worse-diabetic-vision-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-or-high-pth.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="diabetic-retinopathy-severity-serum-vitamin-d-and-parathormone-pth-concentrations-as-predictors-of-the-development-and-severity-of-diabetic-retinopathy">Diabetic Retinopathy severity Serum vitamin D and parathormone (PTH) concentrations as predictors of the development and severity of diabetic retinopathy&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="alexandria-journal-of-medicine--nov-2012httpwwwajmeorgarticles2090-50681200079-6abstract">&lt;a href="http://www.ajme.org/article/S2090-5068(12)00079-6/abstract">Alexandria Journal of Medicine Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Rania Naguib Abdel Mouteleb Abdel Reheem &lt;a href="mailto:ranianaguib2000@yahoo.com">ranianaguib2000@yahoo.com&lt;/a>, Maaly Abdel Halim Mohamed Abdel Fattah &lt;a href="mailto:mola_73@hotmail.com">mola_73@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 14 April 2012; accepted 24 August 2012. published online 08 October 2012.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D is suggested to be an inhibitor of angiogenesis. The degree of severity of diabetic retinopathy (DR) may be related to serum vitamin D concentration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: CVD: the primary cause of death in senior women, is increasing</title><link>/posts/off-topic-cvd-the-primary-cause-of-death-in-senior-women-is-increasing.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-cvd-the-primary-cause-of-death-in-senior-women-is-increasing.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="changing-long-held-beliefs-is-never-easy">Changing Long-Held Beliefs is Never Easy:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-proposal-for-multimodal-approaches-in-female-healthcare---an-integrative-view">A Proposal for Multimodal Approaches in Female Healthcare - An Integrative View&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The EPMA Journal 2012, 3:14 &lt;a href="http://www.epmajournal.eom/content/3/14">http://www.epmajournal.eom/content/3/14&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olga Golubnitschaja, Secretary-General of EPMA, and Vincenzo Costigliola, President of EPMA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>   {EPMA = European Association for Predictive, Preventive and Personalised Medicine.}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="worldwide-cardiovascular-disease-cvd-is-the-leading-cause-of-mortality-in-women-cardiovascular-health-in-females-is-not-improving-as-fast-as-that-of-males">Worldwide cardiovascular disease (CVD) is the leading cause of mortality in women: cardiovascular health in females is not improving as fast as that of males&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Worldwide a third of all deaths of women and &lt;strong>half of all deaths of women over 50 years old in developing countries are caused by CVD&lt;/strong> &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. Several studies have been recently dedicated to the question of CVD-related death with particular focus on gender-dependent aspects. Although CVD is traditionally considered as the major health burden of male subpopulations surprising statistics have been collected for worsening the situation in females. New trends obviously demonstrate a shifting of the problem into healthcare of female populations: from 25 countries selected by World Health Organisation in the years 1990-2000, more than a half (15 countries, 60%) currently demonstrate either increase in CVD-related death in females or, even if the rates are decreased then less compared to men &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vertebral fracture 7X more likely in diabetic men who were vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/vertebral-fracture-7x-more-likely-in-diabetic-men-who-were-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vertebral-fracture-7x-more-likely-in-diabetic-men-who-were-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-association-of-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-vertebral-fractures-in-patients-with-type-2-diabetes">The association of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and vertebral fractures in patients with type 2 diabetes.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocr J. 2012 Oct 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kim YJ, Park SO, Kim TH, Lee JH, Kim SH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kwandong University College of Medicine, Myongji Hospital, Koyang, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is an important regulator of bone health. Previous studies examining the association between vitamin D deficiency and osteoporotic fractures have reported conflicting results. The relationship between vitamin D status and risk of vertebral fractures in diabetic patients is unknown. The objective of this study was to examine whether low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels were associated with vertebral fractures in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. This cross-sectional study was conducted among 161 postmenopausal women and 180 men with type 2 diabetes. Serum concentrations of 25(OH)D were measured and the presence of vertebral fracture was assessed using lateral plain radiographs of the thoracolumbar spine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It appears that Vitamin D reduces diabetes by reducing monocyte stress</title><link>/posts/it-appears-that-vitamin-d-reduces-diabetes-by-reducing-monocyte-stress.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/it-appears-that-vitamin-d-reduces-diabetes-by-reducing-monocyte-stress.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-suppression-of-endoplasmic-reticulum-stress-promotes-an-anti-atherogenic">Vitamin D Suppression of Endoplasmic Reticulum Stress Promotes an Anti-Atherogenic&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Monocyte/Macrophage Phenotype in Type 2 Diabetic Patients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J Biol Chem. 2012 Sep 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Riek AE, Oh J, Sprague JE, Timpson A, de Las Fuentes L, Bernal-Mizrachi L, Schechtman KB, Bernal-Mizrachi C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Washington University School of Medicine, United States;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular disease (CVD) is the leading cause of morbidity/mortality in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM), but there is a lack of knowledge about the mechanism(s) of increased atherosclerosis in these patients. In patients with T2DM, the prevalence of 25-hydroxy vitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> deficiency is almost twice that for non-diabetics and doubles the relative risk of developing CVD compared to diabetic patients with normal 25(OH)D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Role of vitamin D in insulin resistance</title><link>/posts/role-of-vitamin-d-in-insulin-resistance.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/role-of-vitamin-d-in-insulin-resistance.html</guid><description>&lt;p>J Biomed Biotechnol. 2012;2012:634195. Epub 2012 Sep 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sung CC, Liao MT, Lu KC, Wu CC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, Tri-Service General Hospital, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei 114, Taiwan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is characterized as a regulator of homeostasis of bone and mineral metabolism, but it can also provide nonskeletal actions because vitamin D receptors have been found in various tissues including the brain, prostate, breast, colon, pancreas, and immune cells.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes 3.5X less likely if more than 25 ng Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetes-35x-less-likely-if-more-than-25-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-35x-less-likely-if-more-than-25-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="lower-prediagnostic-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentration-is-associated-with-higher-risk-of-insulin-requiring-diabetes-a-nested-case-control-study">Lower prediagnostic serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration is associated with higher risk of insulin-requiring diabetes: a nested case-control study.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Diabetologia. 2012 Sep 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gorham ED, Garland CF, Burgi AA, Mohr SB, Zeng K, Hofflich H, Kim JJ, Ricordi C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Naval Health Research Center, 140 Sylvester Road, San Diego, CA, 92106-3521, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:Edward.Gorham@med.navy.mil">Edward.Gorham@med.navy.mil&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIMS/HYPOTHESIS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentration may increase risk of insulin-requiring diabetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A nested case-control study was performed using serum collected during 2002-2008 from military service members. One thousand subjects subsequently developed insulin-requiring diabetes. A healthy control was individually matched to each case on blood-draw date (±2 days), age (±3 months), length of service (±30 days) and sex. The median elapsed time between serum collection and first diagnosis of diabetes was 1 year (range 1 month to 10 years). Statistical analysis used matched pairs and conditional logistic regression.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>8 weeks of 7000 IU vitamin D was not enough for seniors to improve insulin resistance</title><link>/posts/8-weeks-of-7000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-for-seniors-to-improve-insulin-resistance.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/8-weeks-of-7000-iu-vitamin-d-was-not-enough-for-seniors-to-improve-insulin-resistance.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-on-insulin-resistance-in-nursing-home-residents-an-interventional-study">Effects of vitamin D on insulin resistance in nursing home residents: an interventional study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Kaviani M, Abdollahian M, Almasi V, Amini M, Yamini AA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endokrynol Pol. 2012;63(3):191-5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Insulin resistance is defined as reduction of insulin-stimulated glucose uptake in skeletal muscles and inadequate suppression of the production of endogenous glucose. The aim of this study was to assess the effect of vitamin D intake on insulin resistance in aged patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Probability of Type I diabetes reduced 29 percent with vitamin D – systematic review</title><link>/posts/probability-of-type-i-diabetes-reduced-29-percent-with-vitamin-d-systematic-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/probability-of-type-i-diabetes-reduced-29-percent-with-vitamin-d-systematic-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="can-supplementation-with-vitamin-d-reduce-the-risk-or-modify-the-course-of-autoimmune-diseases-a-systematic-review-of-the-literature">Can supplementation with vitamin D reduce the risk or modify the course of autoimmune diseases? A systematic review of the literature.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Autoimmun Rev. 2012 Jul 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antico A, Tampoia M, Tozzoli R, Bizzaro N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laboratorio di Patologia Clinica, Ospedale Civile, Cittadella, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate whether vitamin D levels are related to the risk of developing autoimmune diseases and whether supplementation with vitamin D can modify the course of the diseases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes 6X more likely for those abdominal obese who have insufficient vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetes-6x-more-likely-for-those-abdominal-obese-who-have-insufficient-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-6x-more-likely-for-those-abdominal-obese-who-have-insufficient-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.mdedge.com/endocrinology/article/236356/obesity/obesity-pegged-diabetes-cause-almost-half-us-cases?ecd=wnl_evn_210224_mdedge_8pm&amp;amp;uac=138704MX&amp;amp;utm_source=News_MDedge_eNL_022421_F&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=Loss+of+smell+lingers+post+COVID-19&amp;amp;sso=true">Obesity pegged as diabetes cause in almost half of U.S. cases&lt;/a> Feb 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Note it appears else where that the connection might be obesity==&amp;gt; reduced vitamin D ==&amp;gt; diabetes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Diabetes in Saudi women improved with just 2,000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetes-in-saudi-women-improved-with-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-in-saudi-women-improved-with-just-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-as-an-adjuvant-therapy-for-patients-with-t2dm-an-18-month-prospective-interventional-study">Vitamin D supplementation as an adjuvant therapy for patients with T2DM: an 18-month prospective interventional study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nasser M Al-Daghri, Khalid M Alkharfy, Abdulaziz Al-Othman, Emad El-Kholie, Osama Moharram, Majed S Alokail, Yousef Al-Saleh, Shaun Sabico, Sudhesh Kumar and George Chrousos&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardiovascular Diabetology 2012, 11:85 doi:10.1186/1475-2840-11-85; Published: 18 July 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with impaired human insulin action, suggesting a role in the pathogenesis of diabetes mellitus type 2 (T2DM). In this prospective interventional study we investigated the effects of vitamin D3 supplementation on the metabolic profiles of Saudi T2DM subjects pre- and post-vitamin D supplementation over an 18-month period.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>27 percent less likely to develop diabetes if prediabetic and have adequate vitamin D</title><link>/posts/27-percent-less-likely-to-develop-diabetes-if-prediabetic-and-have-adequate-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/27-percent-less-likely-to-develop-diabetes-if-prediabetic-and-have-adequate-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="plasma-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-progression-to-diabetes-in-patients-at-risk-for-diabetes-an-ancillary-analysis-in-the-diabetes-prevention-program">Plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D and progression to diabetes in patients at risk for diabetes: an ancillary analysis in the Diabetes Prevention Program.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care. 2012 Mar;35(3):565-73. Epub 2012 Feb 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pittas AG, Nelson J, Mitri J, Hillmann W, Garganta C, Nathan DM, Hu FB, Dawson-Hughes B; Diabetes Prevention Program Research Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes, and Metabolism, Tufts Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:apittas@tuftsmedicalcenter.org">apittas@tuftsmedicalcenter.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the association between vitamin D status, assessed by plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D, and risk of incident diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review was not happy with 1000 papers on hyperglycaemia and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/review-was-not-happy-with-1000-papers-on-hyperglycaemia-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-was-not-happy-with-1000-papers-on-hyperglycaemia-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hyperglycaemia-and-vitamin-d-a-systematic-overview">Hyperglycaemia and vitamin D: a systematic overview.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Diabetes Rev. 2012 Jan;8(1):18-31.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thomas GN, Scragg R, Jiang CQ, Chan W, Marz W, Pilz S, Kim HC, Tomlinson B, Bosch J, Lam TH, Cheung BM, Cheng KK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Public Health, Epidemiology and Biostatistics, College of Medical and Dental Sciences, University of Birmingham, Edgbaston, Birmingham, B15 2TT, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:gneilthomas@yahoo.co.uk">gneilthomas@yahoo.co.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D plays a role in a range of functions that may impact on glycaemic control. In this study we systematically report on clinical studies evaluating the impact of vitamin D on aspects of hyperglycaemia in non-pregnant adults. A total of 1,294 articles, of which 417 were reviews, were identified.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gestational diabetes 2.2X more likely below 10 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/gestational-diabetes-22x-more-likely-below-10-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gestational-diabetes-22x-more-likely-below-10-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-pregnancy-and-gestational-diabetes-mellitus">Vitamin D deficiency in pregnancy and gestational diabetes mellitus.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2012 Jun 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burris HH, Rifas-Shiman SL, Kleinman K, Litonjua AA, Huh SY, Rich-Edwards JW, Camargo CA Jr, Gillman MW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Neonatology, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Boston, MA; Division of Newborn Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Boston, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We examined the association of second-trimester maternal plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) during pregnancy with gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes reduces vitamin D levels which reduces cognition</title><link>/posts/diabetes-reduces-vitamin-d-levels-which-reduces-cognition.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-reduces-vitamin-d-levels-which-reduces-cognition.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="diabetes-linked-to-memory-problems-in-older-adultshttpwellblogsnytimescom20120619diabetes-linked-to-memory-problems-in-older-adults20-ny-times-june-2012">&lt;a href="http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/06/19/diabetes-linked-to-memory-problems-in-older-adults/%20">Diabetes Linked to Memory Problems in Older Adults&lt;/a> NY Times June 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By ANAHAD O&amp;rsquo;CONNOR&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="snips">Snips&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“What we’ve shown is a clear association with diabetes and cognitive aging in terms of the slope and the rate of decline on these cognitive tests,” said Dr. Kristine Yaffe, a professor of psychiatry and neurology at the University of California, San Francisco. “That’s very powerful.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous studies have shown that Type 2 diabetes correlates with a higher risk of Alzheimer’s disease and dementia later in life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Patients having both Diabetes and TB treated by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/patients-having-both-diabetes-and-tb-treated-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/patients-having-both-diabetes-and-tb-treated-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-type-2-diabetes-patients-with-pulmonary-tuberculosis">Response to Vitamin D Supplementation in Type 2 Diabetes Patients with Pulmonary Tuberculosis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Rev, Vol. 33 (03_MeetingAbstracts): SAT-168&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2012 by The Endocrine Society ENDO 2012: June 23-26, 2012, Houston, Texas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunil K Kota, MD1, Siva K Kota, MD, DNB2, Svs Krishna, MD1, Lalit K Meher, MD3 and Kirtikumar D Modi, DM, DNB1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Endocrinology, Medwin Hospital Hyderabad, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Anesthesia, Central Security Hospital Riyadh, Saudi Arabia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Medicine, MKCG Medical College Berhampur, India&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetes-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25ohd-and-type-2-diabetes-association-in-a-general-population-a-prospective-study">Serum 25(OH)D and Type 2 Diabetes Association in a General Population: A prospective study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care. 2012 Jun 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Husemoen LL, Thuesen BH, Fenger M, Jørgensen T, Glümer C, Svensson J, Ovesen L, Witte DR, Linneberg A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Research Centre for Prevention and Health, Glostrup Hospital, Glostrup, Denmark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE This study aimed to examine vitamin D status as a determinant for development of type 2 diabetes and deterioration of glucose homeostasis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>12700 IU daily vitamin D3 did not stop prediabetic minorities from becoming diabetic</title><link>/posts/12700-iu-daily-vitamin-d3-did-not-stop-prediabetic-minorities-from-becoming-diabetic.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/12700-iu-daily-vitamin-d3-did-not-stop-prediabetic-minorities-from-becoming-diabetic.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-fails-diabetes-testhttpblogsnaturecomnews201206vitamin-d-fails-diabetes-testhtml--june-10-2012-nature-news-blog">&lt;a href="http://blogs.nature.com/news/2012/06/vitamin-d-fails-diabetes-test.html">Vitamin D fails diabetes test&lt;/a> June 10, 2012, NATURE NEWS BLOG&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="highlights-of-a-clinical-trial">Highlights of a clinical trial&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>reported at the American Diabetes Association meeting&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Mayer Davidson, a diabetes researcher at Charles R, Drew University&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>88,865 IU D3 weekly for a year&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>70ng/mL.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>100 participants all were either Latinos or African Americans diagnosed with ‘pre-diabetes’&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>no change in rate of becoming diabetic by taking the Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>– – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – –&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetics with darker skin were more vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/diabetics-with-darker-skin-were-more-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetics-with-darker-skin-were-more-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-vitamin-d-insufficiency-and-diabetes-status-in-three-ethnic-minority-groups">Serum Vitamin D Insufficiency and Diabetes Status in Three Ethnic Minority Groups.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Immigr Minor Health. 2012 May 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shaban LH, Zarini GG, Exebio JC, Sukhram SD, Huffman FG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dietetics and Nutrition, Florida International University, 11200 SW, 8th ST, AHC-1 430, Miami, FL, 33199, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this study was to investigate the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels and diabetes status in three ethnicities. This cross sectional study included Cuban Americans (n = 199), Haitian Americans (n = 253) and African Americans (n = 248) with and without type 2 diabetes (T2D) from Florida, U.S. Recruitment of participants was through mailing lists (Cuban Americans and African Americans) and community based sources (Haitian Americans).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Like their diabetic mothers, infants had low vitamin D and were slightly diabetic</title><link>/posts/like-their-diabetic-mothers-infants-had-low-vitamin-d-and-were-slightly-diabetic.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/like-their-diabetic-mothers-infants-had-low-vitamin-d-and-were-slightly-diabetic.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Low 25-hydroxyvitamin D level and adiponectin is associated with insulin sensitivity in large gestational age infants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cytokine. 2012 May 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cekmez F, Aydemir G, Aydinoz S, Pirgon O, Genc FA, Tunc T, Sarici SU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Division of Neonatology, GATA Medical Faculty, 34090 Istanbul, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the relationship between adipokines (visfatin, adiponectin) and 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D), and markers of insulin sensitivity in &lt;strong>large for gestational age (LGA) infants&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4000 IU vitamin D not enough to treat diabetes in overweight blacks in 3 months</title><link>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-treat-diabetes-in-overweight-blacks-in-3-months.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-treat-diabetes-in-overweight-blacks-in-3-months.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-randomized-placebo-controlled-trial-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-to-improve-glycemia-in-overweight-and-obese-african-americans">A Randomized, Placebo Controlled Trial of Vitamin D Supplementation to Improve Glycemia in Overweight and Obese African Americans&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Susan S. Harris D.Sc.1,*, Anastassios G. Pittas M.D., M.S.1,2, Nancy J. Palermo B.S.1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Jean Mayer USDA Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging at Tufts University&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes &amp;amp; Metabolism, Tufts Medical Center&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dr. Susan Harris Jean Mayer USDA Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging at Tufts University 711 Washington St., Boston, MA 02111 617-556-3265 (voice) 617-556-3305 (fax) &lt;a href="mailto:susan.harris@tufts.edu">susan.harris@tufts.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Aims. Vitamin D deficiency may increase the risk for type 2 diabetes. African Americans tend to have poor vitamin D status and increased risk of diabetes, but effects of vitamin D supplementation on components of diabetes risk have not been tested in this group. This study was conducted to determine whether vitamin D supplementation improves insulin secretion, insulin sensitivity and glycemia in African Americans with prediabetes or early diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fructose reduces blood levels of active vitamin D</title><link>/posts/fructose-reduces-blood-levels-of-active-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fructose-reduces-blood-levels-of-active-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#chronic-high-fructose-intake-reduces-serum-125-oh2d3-levels-in-calcium-sufficient-rodents---2014">Chronic high fructose intake reduces serum 1,25 (OH)2D3 levels in calcium-sufficient rodents - 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="chronic-high-fructose-intake-reduces-serum-125-oh2d3-levels-in-calcium-sufficient-rodents---2014">Chronic high fructose intake reduces serum 1,25 (OH)2D3 levels in calcium-sufficient rodents - 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2014 Apr 9;9(4):e93611. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0093611">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0093611&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Douard V1, Patel C1, Lee J1, Tharabenjasin P1, Williams E2, Fritton JC3, Sabbagh Y4, Ferraris RP1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/fructose-2014a.jpg" alt="image" width="300">&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/fructose-2014b.jpg" alt="image" width="100">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Excessive fructose consumption inhibits adaptive increases in intestinal Ca2+ transport in lactating and weanling rats with increased Ca2+ requirements by preventing the increase in serum levels of 1,25(OH)2D3. Here we tested the hypothesis that chronic fructose intake decreases 1,25(OH)2D3 levels independent of increases in Ca2+ requirements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type II diabetes and vitamin D – review</title><link>/posts/type-ii-diabetes-and-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-ii-diabetes-and-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="focus-on-vitamin-d-inflammation-and-type-2-diabetes">Focus on Vitamin D, Inflammation and Type 2 Diabetes&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2012, 4(1), 52-67; doi:10.3390/nu4010052, Review&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carlos Eduardo Andrade Chagas 1 , Maria Carolina Borges 2 , Lígia Araújo Martini 2 and Marcelo Macedo Rogero 2, Author to whom correspondence should be addressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Center for Nutrition Practice and Research, Department of Education, Institute of Biosciences, São Paulo State University, Botucatu, SP 18618-970, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Nutrition, School of Public Health, University of Sao Paulo, Sao Paulo 01246-904, Brazil&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>140,000 IU vitamin D monthly reduced probability of diabetes</title><link>/posts/140000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly-reduced-probability-of-diabetes.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/140000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly-reduced-probability-of-diabetes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-peripheral-regulatory-t-cells-and--cell-function-in-healthy-humans-a-randomized-controlled-trial">The effect of vitamin D supplementation on peripheral regulatory T cells and ? cell function in healthy humans: a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2011 Nov;27(8):942-5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/dmrr.1276.">doi: 10.1002/dmrr.1276.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bock G, Prietl B, Mader JK, Höller E, Wolf M, Pilz S, Graninger WB, Obermayer-Pietsch BM, Pieber TR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria. &lt;a href="mailto:gerlies.bock@medunigraz.at">gerlies.bock@medunigraz.at&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Increasing evidence supports the role of vitamin D (vitD) in modifying the risk to develop type 1 diabetes (T1D) and other autoimmune diseases. VitD3 might stimulate regulatory T cells (Tregs), a central player in the maintenance of self-tolerance. In addition, direct effects of vitD on ?-cell function are postulated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetics helped with food fortified with 1000 IU vitamin D and Calcium</title><link>/posts/diabetics-helped-with-food-fortified-with-1000-iu-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetics-helped-with-food-fortified-with-1000-iu-vitamin-d-and-calcium.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="improvement-of-vitamin-d-status-via-daily-intake-of-fortified-yogurt-drink-either-with-or-without-extra-calcium-ameliorates-systemic-inflammatory-biomarkers-including-adipokines-in-the-subjects-with-type-2-diabetes">Improvement of Vitamin D Status via Daily Intake of Fortified Yogurt Drink Either with or without Extra Calcium Ameliorates Systemic Inflammatory Biomarkers, including Adipokines, in the Subjects with Type 2 Diabetes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism March 22, 2012 jc.2011-3465&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tirang R. Neyestani, Bahareh Nikooyeh, Hamid Alavi-Majd, Nastaran Shariatzadeh, Ali Kalayi, Nima Tayebinejad, Soudabeh Heravifard, Shabnam Salekzamani and Malihe Zahedirad&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laboratory of Nutrition Research, National Nutrition and Food Technology Research Institute and Faculty of Nutrition and Food Technology (T.R.N., B.N., N.S., A.K., N.T., S.H., S.S., M.Z.), and Department of Biostatistics (H.A.-M.), Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, 1981619573 Tehran, Iran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prediabetes progression to diabetes 25 percent less for every 4 ng increase in vitamin D</title><link>/posts/prediabetes-progression-to-diabetes-25-percent-less-for-every-4-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prediabetes-progression-to-diabetes-25-percent-less-for-every-4-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-level-predicts-progression-to-type-2-diabetes-in-individuals-with-prediabetes-but-not-with-normal-glucose-tolerance">Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level predicts progression to type 2 diabetes in individuals with prediabetes but not with normal glucose tolerance&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Diabetologia. European Association for the Study of Diabetes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. Deleskog, A. Hilding, K. Brismar, A. Hamsten, S. Efendic and C.-G. Östenson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aims/hypothesis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency may increase the risk of type 2 diabetes. We therefore investigated whether serum concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> would predict the development of prediabetes (impaired fasting glucose, impaired glucose tolerance or the two combined) and type 2 diabetes, either on their own or when combined with serum concentrations of IGF-1 or IGF-binding protein-1 (IGFBP-1), which may interact with 25(OH)D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gestational diabetes 60 percent more likely below 20 ng of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/gestational-diabetes-60-percent-more-likely-below-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gestational-diabetes-60-percent-more-likely-below-20-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-gestational-diabetes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D and gestational diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#maternal-vitamin-d-status-as-a-critical-determinant-in-gestational-diabetes">Maternal vitamin d status as a critical determinant in gestational diabetes.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-gestational-diabetes-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D and gestational diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>European Journal of Internal Medicine, online 20 February 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Y.H.M. Poel a, Corresponding author contact information, E-mail the corresponding author,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P. Hummel b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P. Lips c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>F. Stam a,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>T. van der Ploeg d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. Simseka c&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Internal Medicine, Gynaecology and Reproductive Medicine, Medical Centre Alkmaar, Alkmaar, The Netherlands&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D associated with obesity-related diseases for ethnic minorities</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-obesity-related-diseases-for-ethnic-minorities.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-associated-with-obesity-related-diseases-for-ethnic-minorities.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-obesity-and-obesity-related-chronic-disease-among-ethnic-minorities-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D, obesity, and obesity-related chronic disease among ethnic minorities: a systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrition. 2011 Sep;27(9):868-79. Epub 2011 Jun 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renzaho AM, Halliday JA, Nowson C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WHO Collaborating Centre for Obesity Prevention, Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria, Australia. &lt;a href="mailto:andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au">andre.renzaho@deakin.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="for-ethnic-minorities-this-study-has-found-that-span-stylecolor00flow-vitamin-d-diabetes-etcspan">For ethnic minorities this study has found that &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">low vitamin D==&amp;gt; diabetes etc&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="rather-than-the-conventional-hypothesis-span-stylecolor00flow-vitamin-d--obesity--diabetes-etcspan">rather than the conventional hypothesis: &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">low vitamin D ==&amp;gt; obesity ==&amp;gt; diabetes etc&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To assess the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) status and obesity, cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), the metabolic syndrome, and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in ethnic minorities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type I diabetes 2X more likely if mother had low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-i-diabetes-2x-more-likely-if-mother-had-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-i-diabetes-2x-more-likely-if-mother-had-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="maternal-serum-levels-of-25-hydroxy-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-risk-of-type-1-diabetes-in-the-offspring">Maternal serum levels of 25-hydroxy-vitamin D during pregnancy and risk of type 1 diabetes in the offspring.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Diabetes. 2012 Jan;61(1):175-8. Epub 2011 Nov 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sørensen IM, Joner G, Jenum PA, Eskild A, Torjesen PA, Stene LC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Oslo University Hospital Ullevål, Oslo, Norway. &lt;a href="mailto:i.m.sorensen@medisin.uio.no">i.m.sorensen@medisin.uio.no&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous studies indicate reduced risk of type 1 diabetes after intake of vitamin D supplements during pregnancy or early childhood. We aimed to test whether lower maternal serum concentrations of 25-hydroxy-vitamin D (25-OH D) during pregnancy were associated with an increased risk of childhood-onset type 1 diabetes. In this case-control study nested within a cohort of 29,072 women in Norway, 25-OH D levels were measured using a radioimmunoassay on samples from late pregnancy in 109 women delivering a child who developed type 1 diabetes before 15 years of age (case subjects) and from 219 control women. Dividing the levels of maternal 25-OH D into quartiles, there was a trend toward a higher risk of type 1 diabetes with lower levels of vitamin D during pregnancy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency might cause diabetes and cardiovascular diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-might-cause-diabetes-and-cardiovascular-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-might-cause-diabetes-and-cardiovascular-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="can-vitamin-d-deficiency-cause-diabetes-and-cardiovascular-diseases">Can vitamin D deficiency cause diabetes and cardiovascular diseases?&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="present-evidence-and-future-perspectives">Present evidence and future perspectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>G. Muscogiuria, &lt;a href="mailto:giovanna.muscogiuri@edu.rm.unicatt.it">giovanna.muscogiuri@edu.rm.unicatt.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G.P. Soricea,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R. Ajjanb,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>T. Mezzaa,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S. Pilzc,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. Priolettaa,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R. Scraggd,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S.L. Volpee,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M.D. Withamf,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. Giaccaria&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Endocrinologia e Malattie del Metabolismo, Università Cattolica, Rome, Italy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Division of Cardiovascular and Diabetes Research, University of Leeds, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes increases probability of bone fracture</title><link>/posts/diabetes-increases-probability-of-bone-fracture.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-increases-probability-of-bone-fracture.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="several-articles-on-this-page">Several articles on this page&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="got-the-suggestion-from-a-hrefpoststhe-complete-book-of-bone-health-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-2312the-complete-book-of-bone-healtha---diane-schneider---2011">Got the suggestion from: &lt;a href="/posts/the-complete-book-of-bone-health" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2312">The Complete Book of Bone Health&lt;/a> - Diane Schneider - 2011&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>– – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – –&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="bone-metabolism-and-fracture-risk-in-type-2-diabetes-mellitus-spanreviewspan">Bone metabolism and fracture risk in type 2 diabetes mellitus &lt;span>[Review]&lt;/span>.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endocr J. 2011;58(8):613-24. Epub 2011 Jul 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yamaguchi T, Sugimoto T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Internal Medicine 1, Shimane University Faculty of Medicine, Japan. &lt;a href="mailto:yamaguch@med.shimane-u.ac.jp">yamaguch@med.shimane-u.ac.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Statin use increased probability of diabetes in women by 48 percent – perhaps via vitamin D</title><link>/posts/statin-use-increased-probability-of-diabetes-in-women-by-48-percent-perhaps-via-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/statin-use-increased-probability-of-diabetes-in-women-by-48-percent-perhaps-via-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact:&lt;/strong> Many statins reduce vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fact:&lt;/strong> Low &lt;a href="/posts/levels-of-vitamin-d-increase-probability-of-diabetes" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1660">levels of vitamin D increase probability of diabetes&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="/posts/overview" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 339">Overview&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="statin-use-and-risk-of-diabetes-mellitus-in-postmenopausal-women-in-the-womens-health-initiative">Statin Use and Risk of Diabetes Mellitus in Postmenopausal Women in the Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Initiative&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Annie L. Culver, BPharm; Ira S. Ockene, MD; Raji Balasubramanian, ScD; Barbara C. Olendzki, RD, MPH; Deidre M. Sepavich, MBA; Jean Wactawski-Wende, PhD; JoAnn E. Manson, MD, DrPH; Yongxia Qiao, MD; Simin Liu, MD, ScD; Philip A. Merriam, MSPH; Catherine Rahilly-Tierny, MD, MPH; Fridtjof Thomas, PhD; Jeffrey S. Berger, MD, MS; Judith K. Ockene, PhD, MEd, MA; J. David Curb, MD; Yunsheng Ma, MD, PhD&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No diabetes if more than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/no-diabetes-if-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-diabetes-if-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-incidence-of-diabetes-a-prospective-cohort-study-vitamin-d-and-diabetes-incidence">Vitamin D and incidence of diabetes: A prospective cohort study: Vitamin D and diabetes incidence&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Inmaculada González-Moleroa, b, &lt;a href="mailto:inmagonzalezmolero@hotmail.com">inmagonzalezmolero@hotmail.com&lt;/a> , Gemma Rojo-Martínezb, Sonsoles Morcillob, Carolina Gutiérrez-Repisob, Elehazara Rubio-Martínb, Maria Cruz Almaraza, b, Gabriel Olveiraa, b, Federico Soriguera, b&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a	Servicio de Endocrinología y Nutrición, Hospital Universitario Carlos Haya, Málaga, Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b	Ciber de Diabetes y Metabolismo (CIBERDEM), Spain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical Nutrition; Received 5 October 2011; Accepted 8 December 2011. Available online 26 December 2011.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity lowers vitamin D which increases probability of diabetes in children</title><link>/posts/obesity-lowers-vitamin-d-which-increases-probability-of-diabetes-in-children.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-lowers-vitamin-d-which-increases-probability-of-diabetes-in-children.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-obese-children-and-its-relationship-to-glucose-homeostasis">Vitamin D Deficiency in Obese Children and Its Relationship to Glucose Homeostasis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Nov 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olson ML, Maalouf NM, Oden JD, White PC, Hutchison MR. &lt;a href="mailto:michele.hutchison@utsouthwestern.edu">michele.hutchison@utsouthwestern.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Departments of Pediatrics (M.L.O., J.D.O., P.C.W., M.R.H.) and Internal Medicine (N.M.M.), University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives:The aim of the study was to compare the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in obese and non-overweight children in North Texas, to examine relationships between dietary habits and 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> level in obese children, and to examine the relationship between 25(OH)D level and markers of abnormal glucose metabolism and blood pressure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hyperglycemia 2.5X more likely when vitamin D less than 10 ng</title><link>/posts/hyperglycemia-25x-more-likely-when-vitamin-d-less-than-10-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hyperglycemia-25x-more-likely-when-vitamin-d-less-than-10-ng.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>97 percent of Native American children have less than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/97-percent-of-native-american-children-have-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/97-percent-of-native-american-children-have-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-is-associated-with-diabetes-risk-in-native-american-children">Vitamin D Insufficiency Is Associated With Diabetes Risk in Native American Children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2011 Oct 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nsiah-Kumi PA, Erickson JM, Beals JL, Ogle EA, Whiting M, Brushbreaker C, Borgeson CD, Qui F, Yu F, Larsen JL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha, NE, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aims/Hypothesis. Vitamin D insufficiency has not been well studied in Native American (NA) children, who are at risk for obesity and diabetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The authors examined vitamin D insufficiency and its association with body mass index (BMI) and insulin resistance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obesity and diabetes reduced when move to better neighborhood – or better UV</title><link>/posts/obesity-and-diabetes-reduced-when-move-to-better-neighborhood-or-better-uv.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/obesity-and-diabetes-reduced-when-move-to-better-neighborhood-or-better-uv.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="neighborhoods-obesity-and-diabetes--a-randomized-social-experiment">Neighborhoods, Obesity, and Diabetes — A Randomized Social Experiment&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Jens Ludwig, Ph.D. &lt;a href="mailto:jludwig@uchicago.ed">jludwig@uchicago.ed&lt;/a>, Lisa Sanbonmatsu, Ph.D., Lisa Gennetian, Ph.D., Emma Adam, Ph.D., Greg J. Duncan, Ph.D., Lawrence F. Katz, Ph.D., Ronald C. Kessler, Ph.D., Jeffrey R. Kling, Ph.D., Stacy Tessler Lindau, M.D., Robert C. Whitaker, M.D., M.P.H., and Thomas W. McDade, Ph.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N Engl J Med 2011; 365:1509-1519October 20, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND The question of whether neighborhood environment contributes directly to the development of obesity and diabetes remains unresolved. The study reported on here uses data from a social experiment to assess the association of randomly assigned variation in neighborhood conditions with obesity and diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300,000 IU injection loading dose of vitamin D3 stopped gestational diabetes in RCT</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-injection-loading-dose-of-vitamin-d3-stopped-gestational-diabetes-in-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-injection-loading-dose-of-vitamin-d3-stopped-gestational-diabetes-in-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-a-single-span-stylecolorf00post-partumspan-injection-of-a-high-dose-of-vitamin-d-on-glucose-tolerance-and-insulin-resistance-in-mothers-with-first-time-gestational-diabetes-mellitus">Effects of a single &lt;span style="color:#F00;">post-partum&lt;/span> injection of a high dose of vitamin D on glucose tolerance and insulin resistance in mothers with first-time gestational diabetes mellitus&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>H. Mozaffari-Khosravi1, M. Hosseinzadeh-Shamsi-Anar1, M.-A. Salami2, H. Hadinedoushan3, M. R. Mozayan4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetic Medicine Vol. 28 Issue 10&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aim? This study was performed to determine the effect of a single, large, intramuscular injection of vitamin D post-partum on glucose tolerance and insulin resistance in women with gestational diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D relationship with HDL and LDL is uncertain</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-relationship-with-hdl-and-ldl-is-uncertain.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-relationship-with-hdl-and-ldl-is-uncertain.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-metabolic-health-with-special-reference-to-the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-serum-lipids">Vitamin D and metabolic health with special reference to the effect of vitamin D on serum lipids.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Prog Lipid Res. 2011 Oct;50(4):303-12. Epub 2011 May 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorde R, Grimnes G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinology Research Group, Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, and Medical Clinic, University Hospital of North Norway, 9038 Tromsø, Norway; University of Queensland at Princess Alexandra Hospital, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Considering that the vitamin D receptor as well as the 1-?-hydroxylase enzyme that converts 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) to its active form 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D have been found in tissues throughout the body, it is likely that vitamin D is important for more than the calcium balance. Accordingly, low serum levels of 25(OH)D have been associated with mortality, cardiovascular disease, type 2 diabetes, hypertension and obesity. Low serum levels of 25(OH)D have also been associated with an unfavourable lipid profile, which could possible explain the relation with cardiovascular disease and mortality. However, the relation between vitamin D and lipids have so far received little attention and is therefore the main focus of the present review.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetics have more retina problems as they have less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetics-have-more-retina-problems-as-they-have-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetics-have-more-retina-problems-as-they-have-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-diabetic-retinopathy--sept-2011">Vitamin D Insufficiency in Diabetic Retinopathy – Sept 2011&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2011 Sep 22:1-18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Payne JF, Ray R, Watson DG, Delille C, Rimler E, Cleveland J, Lynn MJ, Tangpricha V, Srivastava SK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Vitreoretinal Surgery and Disease, Emory University, Atlanta, GA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To assess the relationship between vitamin D status and diabetic retinopathy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: A clinic-based, cross-sectional study was conducted at Emory University. A total of 221 subjects were classified into five groups based on diabetes status and retinopathy findings:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Link between diabetes and Alzheimers is probably low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/link-between-diabetes-and-alzheimers-is-probably-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/link-between-diabetes-and-alzheimers-is-probably-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.whec.com/news/stories/S2291815.shtml?cat=566">Study: Adults with diabetes more prone to dementia&lt;/a> Sept 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For 11 years, Japanese researchers followed more than 1,000 people, ages 60 and older.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They found that those with diabetes at the outset were 35 percent more likely to develop Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Those with the most severe diabetes had more than triple the risk.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deficiency-of-vitamin-dcategoriesdeficiency-of-vitamin-d-has-the-following-graph">&lt;a href="/categories/deficiency-of-vitamin-d">Deficiency of Vitamin D&lt;/a> has the following graph&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h2 id="diabetes-is-in-a-vicious-circle-with-vitamin-d">Diabetes is in a vicious circle with vitamin D.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="low-vitamin-d-increases-diabetes-and-diabetes-decreased-vitamin-d-even-more">Low vitamin D increases diabetes, and diabetes decreased vitamin D even more.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-spirals-lower-and-lower">Vitamin D spirals lower and lower&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpostsoverview-cognition-and-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-584overview-cognition-and-vitamin-da">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-cognition-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 584">Overview Cognition and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cognitive decline, dementia, and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Disease are all associated with low vitamin D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes not TREATED statistically with 5700 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetes-not-treated-statistically-with-5700-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-not-treated-statistically-with-5700-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-insulin-secretion-sensitivity-and-lipids-results-from-a-case-control-study-and-a-randomized-controlled-trial-using-hyperglycemic-clamp-technique">Vitamin D, Insulin Secretion, Sensitivity, and Lipids: Results From a Case-Control Study and a Randomized Controlled Trial Using Hyperglycemic Clamp Technique.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Diabetes. 2011 Sep 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grimnes G, Figenschau Y, Almås B, Jorde R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tromsø Endocrine Research Group, Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, Tromsø, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE Vitamin D deficiency is associated with an unfavorable metabolic profile in observational studies. The intention was to compare insulin sensitivity (the primary end point) and secretion and lipids in subjects with low and high serum 25(OH)D (25-hydroxyvitamin D) levels and to assess the effect of vitamin D supplementation on the same outcomes among the participants with low serum 25(OH)D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Japanese men eating small fish were 32 percent less likely to get diabetes</title><link>/posts/japanese-men-eating-small-fish-were-32-percent-less-likely-to-get-diabetes.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/japanese-men-eating-small-fish-were-32-percent-less-likely-to-get-diabetes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="fish-intake-and-type-2-diabetes-in-japanese-men-and-women-the-japan-public-health-centerbased-prospective-study123">Fish intake and type 2 diabetes in Japanese men and women: the Japan Public Health Center–based Prospective Study1,2,3&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr September 2011 vol. 94 no. 3 884-891&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Akiko Nanri, Tetsuya Mizoue, Mitsuhiko Noda, Yoshihiko Takahashi, Yumi Matsushita, Kalpana Poudel-Tandukar, Masayuki Kato, Shino Oba, Manami Inoue,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shoichiro Tsugane, and for the Japan Public Health Center–based Prospective Study Group&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1From the Department of Epidemiology and Prevention, International Clinical Research Center, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan (AN, TM, YM, and KP-T); the Department of Diabetes and Metabolic Medicine, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan (MN and YT); the Japan Foundation for the Promotion of International Medical Research Cooperation, Tokyo, Japan (MK); the Department of Health Promotion, National Institute of Public Health, Wako, Japan (SO); and the Epidemiology and Prevention Division, Research Center for Cancer Prevention and Screening, National Cancer Center, Tokyo, Japan (MI and ST).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 1 diabetes epidemic not correlated with vitamin D in womb</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-epidemic-not-correlated-with-vitamin-d-in-womb.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-epidemic-not-correlated-with-vitamin-d-in-womb.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-epidemic-of-type-1-diabetes-what-is-it-telling-us">The epidemic of type 1 diabetes: what is it telling us?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes. 2011 Aug;18(4):248-51.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forlenza GP, Rewers M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Department of Pediatrics bBarbara Davis Center, University of Colorado, Aurora, Colorado, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE OF REVIEW: Type 1 diabetes (T1D) is an autoimmune disorder which affects millions around the world. The incidence of T1D in children is increasing worldwide at a rate that cannot be explained by genetics alone. This review explores the recent research regarding possible causes of this epidemic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency and diabetes – rheumatoid arthritis – lupus</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-and-diabetes-rheumatoid-arthritis-lupus.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-and-diabetes-rheumatoid-arthritis-lupus.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="disease-specific-definitions-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-need-to-be-established-in-autoimmune-and-non-autoimmune-chronic-diseases-a-retrospective-comparison-of-three-chronic-diseases">Disease-specific definitions of vitamin D deficiency need to be established in autoimmune and non-autoimmune chronic diseases: a retrospective comparison of three chronic diseases&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arthritis Res Ther. 2010; 12(5): R191. 10.1186/ar3161&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anna R Broder, corresponding author1 Jonathan N Tobin,2,3 and Chaim Putterman1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Division of Rheumatology, Albert Einstein College of Medicine/Montefiore Medical Center, 1300 Morris Park Avenue, Bronx, NY 10461, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Epidemiology and Population Health, Albert Einstein College of Medicine, 1300 Morris Park Avenue, Bronx, NY 10461, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes and gene clinical trial with 1000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetes-and-gene-clinical-trial-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-and-gene-clinical-trial-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="efficacy-of-vitamin-d3-fortified-yogurt-drink-on-anthropometric-metabolic-inflammatory-and-oxidative-stress-biomarkers-according-to-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-in-type-2-diabetic-patients-a-study-protocol-for-a-randomized-controlled-clinical-trial">Efficacy of vitamin D3-fortified-yogurt drink on anthropometric, metabolic, inflammatory and oxidative stress biomarkers according to vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms in type 2 diabetic patients: a study protocol for a randomized controlled clinical trial&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>BMC Endocr Disord. 2011; 11: 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2011 June 22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1472-6823-11-12">doi: 10.1186/1472-6823-11-12&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sakineh Shab-Bidar,1 Tirang R Neyestani,corresponding author2 and Abolghassem Djazayerycorresponding author1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Nutrition and Biochemistry, School of Public Health, Tehran University of Medical Sciences (TUMS), Tehran, Iran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes down 13 percent if more than 500 IU of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/diabetes-down-13-percent-if-more-than-500-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-down-13-percent-if-more-than-500-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-type-2-diabetes-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D and type 2 diabetes: a systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2011.118.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2011.118.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mitri J, Muraru MD, Pittas AG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes and Metabolism, Tufts Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Objectives:Vitamin D may modify the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus. The aim of this review was to examine the association between vitamin D status and incident type 2 diabetes, and the effect of vitamin D supplementation on glycemic outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>25 ng Vitamin D reduced chance of diabetes by 43 percent -review</title><link>/posts/25-ng-vitamin-d-reduced-chance-of-diabetes-by-43-percent-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/25-ng-vitamin-d-reduced-chance-of-diabetes-by-43-percent-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-type-2-diabetes-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D and type 2 diabetes: a systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Nutr. 2011 Jul 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2011.118.">doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2011.118.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mitri J, Muraru MD, Pittas AG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes and Metabolism, Tufts Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Objectives:Vitamin D may modify the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus. The aim of this review was to examine the association between vitamin D status and incident type 2 diabetes, and the effect of vitamin D supplementation on glycemic outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetic neuropathy and low vitamin D, especially in blacks</title><link>/posts/diabetic-neuropathy-and-low-vitamin-d-especially-in-blacks.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetic-neuropathy-and-low-vitamin-d-especially-in-blacks.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="association-between-vitamin-d-and-diabetic-neuropathy-in-a-nationally-representative-sample-results-from-20012004-nhanes">Association between vitamin D and diabetic neuropathy in a nationally representative sample: results from 2001–2004 NHANES&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>L. H. Soderstrom1, S. P. Johnson2, V. A. Diaz2, A. G. Mainous III2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1111/j.1464-5491.2011.03379.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal compilation © 2011 Diabetes UK, Vol. 28 Issue 7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aims:? To evaluate the association between vitamin D insufficiency and peripheral neuropathy in a nationally representative sample of adults with diagnosed diabetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods:? Vitamin D concentrations, medical examination variables and questionnaire results from the 2001–2004 National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey were analysed for adults ? 40 years old with diagnosed diabetes (unweighted n = 591, weighted n = 8.82 million). Neuropathy was defined as self report of peripheral neuropathy symptoms of painful sensation, tingling, numbness or loss of feeling in hands or feet. Additionally, Semmes–Weinstein monofilament test results were used as an indicator of neuropathy. Insufficient vitamin D was characterized as &lt;strong>&amp;lt; 30 ng/ml.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D patent for treating immune system diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wo2008039409httpwwwwipointpatentscopesearchenwo2008039409-world-wide-patent---2008">&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/WO2008039409">(WO2008039409)&lt;/a> World-Wide patent - 2008&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="treatment-and-prevention-of-diseases-or-conditions-of-the--immune-system-or-infectious-diseases">TREATMENT AND PREVENTION OF DISEASES OR CONDITIONS OF THE &lt;strong>IMMUNE SYSTEM OR INFECTIOUS DISEASES&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>allergic rhinitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eczema,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>psoriasis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>food allergy,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>type-1 diabetes,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>ulcerative colitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>rheumatoid arthritis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>multiple sclerosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>lupus,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>tuberculosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>parasitic infection, etc,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Studies linked low vitamin D and dark skin to Obesity, Diabetes, and heart</title><link>/posts/studies-linked-low-vitamin-d-and-dark-skin-to-obesity-diabetes-and-heart.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/studies-linked-low-vitamin-d-and-dark-skin-to-obesity-diabetes-and-heart.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-obesity-and-obesity-related-chronic-disease-among-ethnic-minorities-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D, obesity, and obesity-related chronic disease among ethnic minorities: A systematic review.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrition. 2011 Jun 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Renzaho AM, Halliday JA, Nowson C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WHO Collaborating Centre for Obesity Prevention, Deakin University, Burwood , Victoria, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To assess the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) status and obesity, cardiovascular diseases (CVDs), the metabolic syndrome, and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in ethnic minorities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Databases searched were CINHAL with full text, Global Health, MEDLINE with full text, and PsycINFO from 1980 through 2010 (February). Studies were included if they 1) targeted immigrants from low- to high-income countries or ethnic minorities, 2) focused primarily on 25(OH)D and its relation to obesity, T2DM, and/or CVDs, and 3) were published in peer-reviewed journals. The influences of key confounders such as age, gender, and ethnicity on any observed relations were also assessed. Due to the heterogeneity of study characteristics, only a narrative synthesis was undertaken.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>25 percent reduction in diabetes risk if vitamin D great than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/25-percent-reduction-in-diabetes-risk-if-vitamin-d-great-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/25-percent-reduction-in-diabetes-risk-if-vitamin-d-great-than-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-medscapehttpwwwmedscapecomviewarticle745335">from &lt;a href="http://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/745335">Medscape&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="also-reported-in-reutershttpwwwreuterscomarticle20110708us-vitamin-d-pancreas-idustre7676qg20110708">also reported in &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/07/08/us-vitamin-d-pancreas-idUSTRE7676QG20110708">Reuters&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Based on American Diabetes Association (ADA) 71st Scientific Sessions: Abstract 0117-OR. Presented June 25, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>by Dr. Pittas and Dr. Rosen&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolorf0054--reduction-in-diabetes-risk--when--50-ngmlspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">54 % reduction in Diabetes risk when &amp;gt; 50 ng/ml&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-supplementation-on-pancreatic--cell-function-insulin-sensitivity-and-glycemia-in-adults-at-high-risk-of-diabetes-the-calcium-and-vitamin-d-for-diabetes-mellitus-caddm-randomized-controlled-trial1234">Effects of vitamin D and calcium supplementation on pancreatic ? cell function, insulin sensitivity, and glycemia in adults at high risk of diabetes: the Calcium and Vitamin D for Diabetes Mellitus (CaDDM) randomized controlled trial1,2,3,4&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Joanna Mitri, Bess Dawson-Hughes, Frank B Hu, and Anastassios G Pittas&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes rising quickly in areas with recent air conditioning</title><link>/posts/diabetes-rising-quickly-in-areas-with-recent-air-conditioning.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-rising-quickly-in-areas-with-recent-air-conditioning.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="reported-by-medicalxpresshttpmedicalxpresscomnews2011-06-million-adults-diabetes-reveals-scalehtml">&lt;a href="http://medicalxpress.com/news/2011-06-million-adults-diabetes-reveals-scale.html">reported by MedicalXpress&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="prevalence-of-diabetes-has-risen-or-at-best-remained-unchanged-in-virtually-every-part-of-the-world-over-the-last-three-decades">Prevalence of diabetes has risen or at best remained unchanged in virtually every part of the world over the last three decades&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>had been 8.3 per cent of men, 9.8 per cent of men = 350 million in 2008&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>biggest rise appears to be those equatorial areas which have gotten air conditioning since the study began (1980)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Diabetes has taken off most dramatically in Pacific Island nations, which now have the highest diabetes levels in the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis non-severe depression and diabetes related by low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-non-severe-depression-and-diabetes-related-by-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-non-severe-depression-and-diabetes-related-by-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="depression-and-type-2-diabetes-mellitus-a-call-to-explore-the-common-cause-hypothesis">Depression and Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: A Call to Explore the Common Cause Hypothesis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Briana Mezuk, PhD, Department of Epidemiology and Community Health, Virginia Commonwealth University School of Medicine, Richmond, VA (&lt;a href="mailto:bmezuk@vcu.edu">bmezuk@vcu.edu&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Archives of Internal Medicine	Vol. 171 No. 11, June 13, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Short item with just the first 150 words of the full text)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read the recent article by Pan and colleagues1 with great interest. Their findings using the Short-Form 36 Health Status Survey suggest that even mood disturbances that do not require clinical intervention are predictive of diabetes. This interpretation, combined with the counterintuitive finding that nonsevere depression was similarly, and potentially more strongly, associated with diabetes risk than severe depression reported in another recent article,2 begs the question(s):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>70 year-olds got T2 Diabetes 2X more often when less than 20 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/70-year-olds-got-t2-diabetes-2x-more-often-when-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/70-year-olds-got-t2-diabetes-2x-more-often-when-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-in-relation-to-glucose-metabolism-and-type-2-diabetes-in-septuagenarians">Vitamin D Status in Relation to Glucose Metabolism and Type 2 Diabetes in Septuagenarians&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Christine Dalgård, PHD1 – &lt;a href="mailto:cdalgaard@health.sdu.dk">cdalgaard@health.sdu.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maria Skaalum Petersen, PHD2,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pal Weihe, MD1,2 and Philippe Grandjean, DMSC1,3 Diabetes Care&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Institute of Public Health, Department of Environmental Medicine, University of Southern Denmark, JB Winslowsvej, Odense C, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Occupational Medicine and Public Health, Faroese Hospital System, Tórshavn, Faroe Islands, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Department of Environmental Health, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, Massachusetts&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 1 diabetes, genes and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-genes-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-genes-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="two-abstracts-on-this-page">two abstracts on this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolor00fhypothesis--three-genes-show-why-type-1-diabetes-patients-need-more-vitamin-d--mar-2011span">&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Hypothesis – Three genes show why type 1 diabetes patients need more vitamin D – Mar 2011&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="inherited-variation-in-vitamin-d-genes-is-associated-with-predisposition-to-autoimmune-disease-type-1-diabetes">Inherited Variation in Vitamin D Genes Is Associated With Predisposition to Autoimmune Disease Type 1 Diabetes.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Diabetes. 2011 Mar 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cooper JD, Smyth DJ, Walker NM, Stevens H, Burren OS, Wallace C, Greissl C, Ramos-Lopez E, Hypponen E, Dunger DB, Spector TD, Ouwehand WH, Wang TJ, Badenhoop K, Todd JA. &lt;a href="mailto:john.todd@cimr.cam.ac.uk">john.todd@cimr.cam.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes risk reduced 24 percent for every 10 ng increase in vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetes-risk-reduced-24-percent-for-every-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-risk-reduced-24-percent-for-every-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-calcium-intake-and-risk-of-type-2-diabetes-after-5-years-results-from-a-national-population-based-prospective-study-the-australian-diabetes-obesity-and-lifestyle-study">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D, Calcium Intake, and Risk of Type 2 Diabetes After 5 Years: Results from a national, population-based prospective study (The Australian Diabetes, Obesity and Lifestyle Study).&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care. 2011 Mar 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gagnon C, Lu ZX, Magliano DJ, Dunstan DW, Shaw JE, Zimmet PZ, Sikaris K, Grantham N, Ebeling PR, Daly RM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, NorthWest Academic Centre, The University of Melbourne, Western Hospital, Melbourne, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE To examine whether serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) and dietary calcium predict incident type 2 diabetes and insulin sensitivity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Synergism between vitamin A and vitamin D – Masterjohn</title><link>/posts/synergism-between-vitamin-a-and-vitamin-d-masterjohn.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/synergism-between-vitamin-a-and-vitamin-d-masterjohn.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Not yet certain that vitamin D reduces cardiovascular and diabetes in blacks</title><link>/posts/not-yet-certain-that-vitamin-d-reduces-cardiovascular-and-diabetes-in-blacks.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/not-yet-certain-that-vitamin-d-reduces-cardiovascular-and-diabetes-in-blacks.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="does-vitamin-d-deficiency-contribute-to-increased-rates-of-cardiovascular-disease-and-type-2-diabetes-in-african-americans">Does vitamin D deficiency contribute to increased rates of cardiovascular disease and type 2 diabetes in African Americans?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Mar 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harris SS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jean Mayer US Department of Agriculture Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging at Tufts University, Boston, MA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>African Americans have higher rates of type 2 diabetes (T2D) and some forms of cardiovascular disease (CVD) than do European Americans. African Americans also have much higher rates of vitamin D deficiency. There is emerging evidence that vitamin D deficiency may be a risk factor for hypertension, T2D, and CVD, but the extent to which racial disparities in disease rates are explained by racial differences in vitamin D status is uncertain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wonder which political party afflication would believe in vitamin D</title><link>/posts/wonder-which-political-party-afflication-would-believe-in-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wonder-which-political-party-afflication-would-believe-in-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="clipped-from-how-cognitive-biases-affect-our-interpretation-of-political-messages">Clipped from: How cognitive biases affect our interpretation of political messages&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>^Overview:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Different causes for diabetes were given to people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which cause of diabetes was believed was strongly determined by their political party.^&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.bmj.com/content/340/bmj.c2276.full">http://www.bmj.com/content/340/bmj.c2276.full&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMJ 2010; 340:c2276 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.c2276">doi: 10.1136/bmj.c2276&lt;/a> (Published 27 April 2010)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A recent study from the United States randomly allocated one of four versions of an authoritative news story about &lt;strong>diabetes to people who had declared different political allegiances.3&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to become diabetic in 5 easy steps</title><link>/posts/how-to-become-diabetic-in-5-easy-steps.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-become-diabetic-in-5-easy-steps.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sarcasm-by-dr-william-davis-jan-14-2010httpheartscanblogblogspotcom201101how-to-become-diabetic-in-5-easy-stepshtmlutm_sourcefeedburnerutm_mediumfeedutm_campaignfeed3ablogspot2ftpzx28theheartscanblog29utm_contentgooglereader">Sarcasm by &lt;a href="http://heartscanblog.blogspot.com/2011/01/how-to-become-diabetic-in-5-easy-steps.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+blogspot%2Ftpzx+%28The+Heart+Scan+Blog%29&amp;amp;utm_content=Google+Reader">Dr. William Davis Jan 14, 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you would like to become diabetic in as short a time as possible, or if you have someone you don&amp;rsquo;t like - ex-spouse, nasty neighbor, cranky mother-in-law - whose health you&amp;rsquo;d like to booby trap, then here&amp;rsquo;s an easy-to-follow 5-step plan to make you or your target diabetic.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cut your fat and eat healthy, whole grains&amp;ndash;Yes, reduce satiety-inducing foods and replace the calories with appetite-increasing foods, such as whole grain bread, that skyrocket blood sugar higher than a candy bar.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Confirmed - need more than 400 IU vitamin D to prevent diabetes – 2008</title><link>/posts/confirmed-need-more-than-400-iu-vitamin-d-to-prevent-diabetes-2008.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/confirmed-need-more-than-400-iu-vitamin-d-to-prevent-diabetes-2008.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="calcium-plus-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-the-risk-of-incident-diabetes-in-the-womens-health-initiative">Calcium Plus Vitamin D Supplementation and the Risk of Incident Diabetes in the Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Initiative&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care. Author manuscript; available in PMC 2011 February 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care. 2008 April; 31(4): 701–707.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2008 January 30. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2337/dc07-1829.">doi: 10.2337/dc07-1829.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3046029&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NIHMSID: NIHMS267497&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright notice and Disclaimer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ian H. de Boer, MD, MS,1 Lesley F. Tinker, PHD, RD,2 Stephanie Connelly, MD, MPH,3 J. David Curb, MD, MPH,4 Barbara V. Howard, MD, PHD,5 Bryan Kestenbaum, MD, MS,1 Joseph C. Larson, MS,2 JoAnn E. Manson, MD, DRPH,6 Karen L. Margolis, MD, MPH,7 David S. Siscovick, MD, MPH,1 and Noel S. Weiss, MD, DRPH1, For the Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Initiative Investigators*&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 2 diabetes treated by 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-2-diabetes-treated-by-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-2-diabetes-treated-by-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-type-2-diabetes-mellitus-where-do-we-stand-review">Vitamin D and type 2 diabetes mellitus: Where do we stand? Review&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Diabetes &amp;amp; Metabolism; doi:10.1016/j.diabet.2011.01.001 |&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Copyright © 2011 Elsevier Masson SAS All rights reserved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E. Cavaliera, &lt;a href="mailto:Etienne.cavalier@chu.ulg.ac.be">Etienne.cavalier@chu.ulg.ac.be&lt;/a>, P. Delanayeb, J.-C. Souberbiellec and R.-P. Radermeckerd&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Clinical Chemistry, University of Liege, CHU Sart-Tilman, 4000 Liège, Belgium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b Department of Nephrology, Dialysis and Hypertension, University of Liege, CHU Sart-Tilman, 4000 Liège, Belgium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c Laboratoire d’explorations fonctionnelles, hôpital Necker–Enfants-Malades, 75743 Paris, France&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D with or without Calcium helped glycemic status</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-with-or-without-calcium-helped-glycemic-status.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-with-or-without-calcium-helped-glycemic-status.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="daily-consumption-of-vitamin-d--or-vitamin-d--calcium-fortified-yogurt-drink-improved-glycemic-control-in-patients-with-type-2-diabetes-a-randomized-clinical-trial">Daily consumption of vitamin D- or vitamin D + calcium-fortified yogurt drink improved glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomized clinical trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Feb 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nikooyeh B, Neyestani TR, Farvid M, Alavi-Majd H, Houshiarrad A, Kalayi A, Shariatzadeh N, Gharavi A, Heravifard S, Tayebinejad N, Salekzamani S, Zahedirad M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laboratory of Nutrition Research, National Research Institute and Faculty of Nutrition and Food Technology, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran, and the Department of Biostatistics, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pre-diabetes and hypertension 2.4X more common when less than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/pre-diabetes-and-hypertension-24x-more-common-when-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pre-diabetes-and-hypertension-24x-more-common-when-less-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>CDC confirms association between more vitamin D and less insulin</title><link>/posts/cdc-confirms-association-between-more-vitamin-d-and-less-insulin.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cdc-confirms-association-between-more-vitamin-d-and-less-insulin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="associations-between-concentrations-of-vitamin-d-and-concentrations-of-insulin-glucose-and-hba1c-among-adolescents-in-the-united-states">Associations Between Concentrations of Vitamin D and Concentrations of Insulin, Glucose, and HbA1c Among Adolescents in the United States.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Diabetes Care. 2011 Jan 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ford ES, Zhao G, Tsai J, Li C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Adult and Community Health, National Center for Chronic Disease Prevention and Health Promotion, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, Georgia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE Our objective was to examine the associations between concentrations of vitamin D and concentrations of insulin, glucose, and HbA(1c) in a nationally representative sample of adolescents in the U.S.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficient Type 1 diabetics 3X more likely to have calcification problems</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficient-type-1-diabetics-3x-more-likely-to-have-calcification-problems.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficient-type-1-diabetics-3x-more-likely-to-have-calcification-problems.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-coronary-artery-calcification-in-subjects-with-type-1-diabetes">Vitamin D Deficiency and Coronary Artery Calcification in Subjects With Type 1 Diabetes&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kendra A. Young, MSPH1,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Janet K. Snell-Bergeon, PHD2, &lt;a href="mailto:janet.snell-bergeon@ucdenver.edu">janet.snell-bergeon@ucdenver.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ramachandra G. Naik, MD3,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>John E. Hokanson, PHD1,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>David Tarullo, BS2,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Peter A. Gottlieb, MD2,4,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Satish K. Garg, MD2,4 and&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Marian Rewers, MD2&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>1.Colorado School of Public Health, University of Colorado, Denver, Colorado&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Barbara Davis Center for Childhood Diabetes, University of Colorado, Denver, Colorado&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Novartis Pharmaceuticals Corporation, East Hanover, New Jersey&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less muscle and insulin resistance for children of vitamin D deficient mothers</title><link>/posts/less-muscle-and-insulin-resistance-for-children-of-vitamin-d-deficient-mothers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-muscle-and-insulin-resistance-for-children-of-vitamin-d-deficient-mothers.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-status-during-pregnancy-and-body-composition-and-cardiovascular-risk-markers-in-indian-children-the-mysore-parthenon-study">Maternal vitamin D status during pregnancy and body composition and cardiovascular risk markers in Indian children: the Mysore Parthenon Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>AM J CLIN NUTR () (2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ghattu V Krishnaveni, Sargoor R Veena, Nicola R Winder, Jacqueline C Hill, Kate Noonan, Barbara J Boucher, Samuel C Karat and Caroline Hd Fall&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epidemiology Research Unit, CSI Holdsworth Memorial Hospital, Mysore, India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Metabolic consequences of vitamin D deficiency have become a recent research focus. Maternal vitamin D status is thought to influence musculoskeletal health in children, but its relation with offspring metabolic risk is not known.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview of Vitamin D and Insulin – 2010</title><link>/posts/overview-of-vitamin-d-and-insulin-2010.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-of-vitamin-d-and-insulin-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-insulin-action-and-secretion-an-overview-of-current-understanding-and-future-perspectives">Vitamin D and Insulin Action and Secretion –An Overview of Current Understanding and Future Perspectives&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Birkeland Kare I, Gulseth Hanne L, Wium Cecilie&lt;/p>
&lt;p>European Endocrinology, 2010;6(2):13–8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Impaired vitamin D status has been linked to the development of type 2 diabetes. This review summarises the current knowledge of the effects of vitamin D on insulin action and secretion. Animal and in vitro studies suggest an effect of vitamin D on insulin action and secretion. The effects of vitamin D status in humans are not as clear, however, and cross-sectional data on insulin sensitivity and secretion are inconclusive. Intervention studies are few and often suffer from inadequate design including short duration, low sample power, low dose of vitamin D or use of indirect measures of insulin sensitivity and secretion. Despite some plausible biological mechanisms for an effect of vitamin D on both insulin secretion and action, more evidence is needed to decide whether vitamin D plays an important role in the pathophysiology of type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetes not TREATED by a single 200000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetes-not-treated-by-a-single-200000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetes-not-treated-by-a-single-200000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-effect-of-different-doses-of-vitamin-d3-on-markers-of-vascular-health-in-patients-with-type-2-diabetes-a-randomised-controlled-trial">The effect of different doses of vitamin D(3) on markers of vascular health in patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomised controlled trial.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Diabetologia. 2010 Oct;53(10):2112-9. Epub 2010 Jul 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Witham MD, Dove FJ, Dryburgh M, Sugden JA, Morris AD, Struthers AD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ageing and Health, Ninewells Hospital, Dundee DD1 9SY, UK. &lt;a href="mailto:m.witham@dundee.ac.uk">m.witham@dundee.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIMS/HYPOTHESIS: Low 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels predict future cardiovascular events and are common in patients with type 2 diabetes. We compared the effect of 100,000 and 200,000 IU doses of vitamin D(3) on endothelial function, blood pressure and markers of glycaemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Can Vitamin D treat Diabetes - many articles</title><link>/posts/can-vitamin-d-treat-diabetes-many-articles.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/can-vitamin-d-treat-diabetes-many-articles.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Type 1 diabetes patients may be pissing away vitamin D</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-patients-may-be-pissing-away-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-patients-may-be-pissing-away-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="enhanced-excretion-of-vitamin-d-binding-protein-in-type-1-diabetes-a-role-in-vitamin-d-deficiency">Enhanced Excretion of Vitamin D Binding Protein in Type 1 Diabetes: A Role in Vitamin D Deficiency?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism Vol. 96, No. 1 142-149&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kathryn M. Thrailkill, Chan-Hee Jo, Gael E. Cockrell, Cynthia S. Moreau and John L. Fowlkes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences and Arkansas Children’s Hospital Research Institute, Little Rock Arkansas 72205&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Address all correspondence and requests for reprints to: Kathryn M. Thrailkill, M.D., Arkansas Children’s Hospital, 1 Children’s Way, Slot 512-6, Little Rock, Arkansas 72202 E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:thrailkillkathrynm@uams.edu">thrailkillkathrynm@uams.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less than 30 ng vitamin D greatly increased hazard of dying and diabetes</title><link>/posts/less-than-30-ng-vitamin-d-greatly-increased-hazard-of-dying-and-diabetes.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-than-30-ng-vitamin-d-greatly-increased-hazard-of-dying-and-diabetes.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cardiovascular-disease-risk-factors-and-markers-session-title">Cardiovascular Disease Risk Factors and Markers (Session Title)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Cardiology Volume 122, Issue 21 Supplement; November 23, 2010 / Abstracts From Scientific Sessions 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Core 2. Epidemiology and Prevention of CV Disease: Physiology, Pharmacology and Lifestyle&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-and-supplementation-impact-on-cardiovascular-morbidity-and-overall-mortality">Vitamin D Deficiency and Supplementation: Impact on Cardiovascular Morbidity and Overall Mortality&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Abstract 12680:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Subba Reddy Vanga; Matthew Good; Dhanunjaya Lakkireddy; Patricia Howard; James L Vacek&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Univ of Kansas Med Cntr and the Univ of Kansas Hosp, Kansas City, KS; Univ of Kansas Med Cntr, Kansas City, KS; Univ of Kansas Med Cntr and the Univ of Kansas Hosp, Kansas City, KS&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4000 IU vitamin D improved glycemic control for type 1 diabetes</title><link>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-improved-glycemic-control-for-type-1-diabetes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/4000-iu-vitamin-d-improved-glycemic-control-for-type-1-diabetes.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="glycemic-changes-after-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-patients-with-type-1-diabetes-mellitus-and-vitamin-d-deficiency">Glycemic changes after vitamin D supplementation in patients with type 1 diabetes mellitus and vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ann Saudi Med. 2010 Nov-Dec;30(6):454-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aljabri KS, Bokhari SA, Khan MJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology, Department of Medicine, King Fahad Armed Forces Hospital, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background : A prospective, nonblinded and nonrandomized controlled trial was conducted to test the hypothesis that vitamin D supplementation would improve glycemic control in patients with type 1 diabetes mellitus who have vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>