<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Middle East on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/middle-east.html</link><description>Recent content in Middle East on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/middle-east/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Osteoporosis increasing and vitamin D decreasing in Middle East</title><link>/posts/osteoporosis-increasing-and-vitamin-d-decreasing-in-middle-east.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/osteoporosis-increasing-and-vitamin-d-decreasing-in-middle-east.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="news-release-of-conferencehttpwwweurekalertorgpub_releases2011-10iof-boo102111php">&lt;a href="http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2011-10/iof-boo102111.php">News Release of Conference&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h1 id="bone-density-decreases-with-age">Bone Density decreases with age&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;834&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;835&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="prevalence-in-children">Prevalence in CHILDREN&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;841&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;837&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="increasing-number-of-hip-replacements-in-a-decade">Increasing number of hip replacements in a decade&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;838&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="standard-osteo-treatments-do-not-yet-include-vitamin-d">Standard Osteo treatments do not yet include vitamin D&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;839&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="2x-more-osteoporosis-than-in-ancient-eqypt">2X more Osteoporosis than in ancient Eqypt&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;840&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="see-pdf-attached-at-bottom-of-this-page">See PDF attached at bottom of this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-osteoporosis-and-vitamin-d">Overview Osteoporosis and vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=49&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">All items in category Bone - Osteoporosis&lt;/a> 89 items Oct 2011&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Excessive clothes and being indoors results in very low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/excessive-clothes-and-being-indoors-results-in-very-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/excessive-clothes-and-being-indoors-results-in-very-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Review of Vitamin D Deficiencies in developing countries</title><link>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-deficiencies-in-developing-countries.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-deficiencies-in-developing-countries.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D in blood is higher in winter than summer – in Middle-East</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-in-blood-is-higher-in-winter-than-summer-in-middle-east.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-in-blood-is-higher-in-winter-than-summer-in-middle-east.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="increased-vitamin-d-supplementation-recommended-during-summer-season-in-the-gulf-region">Increased Vitamin D Supplementation Recommended during Summer Season in the Gulf Region:&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="a-counterintuitive-seasonal-effect-in-vitamin-d-levels-in-adult-overweight-and-obese-middle-eastern-residents">A Counterintuitive Seasonal Effect in Vitamin D Levels in Adult, Overweight and Obese Middle-eastern Residents&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Al-Daghri NM, Al-Attas OS, Alokail MS, Alkharfy KM, El-Kholie E, Yousef M, Al-Othman A, Al-Saleh Y, Sabico S, Kumar S, Chrousos GP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Biomarkers Research Program, Biochemistry Department, College of Science, King Saud University, Riyadh 11451, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (KSA)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center of Excellence in Biotechnology Research Center, King Saud University, Riyadh 11451, Saudi Arabaia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Military in hot climates and vitamin D deficiency - 2010</title><link>/posts/military-in-hot-climates-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2010.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/military-in-hot-climates-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-2010.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jordanian women vitamin D – 16 ng if Western clothing – 12 ng otherwise</title><link>/posts/jordanian-women-vitamin-d-16-ng-if-western-clothing-12-ng-otherwise.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/jordanian-women-vitamin-d-16-ng-if-western-clothing-12-ng-otherwise.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="plasma-concentrations-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-among-jordanians--effect-of-biological-and-habitual-factors-on-vitamin-d-status">Plasma concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D among Jordanians: Effect of biological and habitual factors on vitamin D status&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Clinical Pathology 2011, 11:8doi:10.1186/1472-6890-11-8. Published: 	4 August 2011, Abstract (provisional)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eyad M Mallah, Mohammad F Hamad, Mays A ElManaseer, Nidal A Qinna, Nasir M Idkaidek, Tawfiq A Arafat and Khalid Z Matalka&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D is cutaneously synthesized following sun exposure (vitamin D3) as well as it is derived from dietary intake (vitamin D3 and D2). Vitamin D2 and D3 are metabolized in the liver to 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D). This metabolite is considered the functional indicator of vitamin D stores in humans. Since Jordan latitude is 31oN, cutaneous synthesis of vitamin D3 should be sufficient all year round. However, many indications reveal that it is not the case. Thus, this study was conducted to determine the 25(OH)D status among Jordanians.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MS new cases increased 2.5X in 2 years in Isfahan Iran</title><link>/posts/ms-new-cases-increased-25x-in-2-years-in-isfahan-iran.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ms-new-cases-increased-25x-in-2-years-in-isfahan-iran.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="sharp-increase-in-the-incidence-and-prevalence-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-isfahan-iran">Sharp increase in the incidence and prevalence of multiple sclerosis in Isfahan, Iran&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Masoud Etemadifar1,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amir-Hadi Maghzi1,2? &lt;a href="mailto:Maghzi@edc.mui.ac.ir">Maghzi@edc.mui.ac.ir&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Medical School, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Blizard Institute of Cell and Molecular Science, Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, London, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Neurology, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amir-Hadi Maghzi, Isfahan Research Committee of Multiple Sclerosis (IRCOMS), Multiple Sclerosis Clinic, Al-Zahra Hospital, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Soffeh Street, Isfahan 81744, Iran&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>400 IU vitamin D appeared to prevent infant rickets in Turkey</title><link>/posts/400-iu-vitamin-d-appeared-to-prevent-infant-rickets-in-turkey.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/400-iu-vitamin-d-appeared-to-prevent-infant-rickets-in-turkey.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prevention-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-infancy-daily-400-iu-vitamin-d-is-sufficient">Prevention of Vitamin D deficiency in infancy: Daily 400 IU vitamin D is sufficient.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Gul Y Yesiltepe Mutlu, Yusuf Kusdal, Elif Ozsu, Filiz M Cizmecioglu and Sukru Hatun&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International Journal of Pediatric Endocrinology 2011, 2011:4 doi:10.1186/1687-9856-2011-4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 28 June 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aim, Objective:Vitamin D deficiency and rickets in developing countries continues to be a major health problem. Additionally, the increase of cases of rickets in children of some ethnic groups in the United States and European countries has provided this issue to be updated. Obviously, powerful strategies are necessary to prevent vitamin D deficiency nation-wide.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iranian vitamin D levels 13 ng summer, 12 ng winter</title><link>/posts/iranian-vitamin-d-levels-13-ng-summer-12-ng-winter.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/iranian-vitamin-d-levels-13-ng-summer-12-ng-winter.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-prevalence-in-summer-compared-to-winter-in-a-city-with-high-humidity-and-a-sultry-climate">Vitamin D deficiency prevalence in summer compared to winter in a city with high humidity and a sultry climate.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Endokrynol Pol. 2011;62(3):249-251.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kashi Z, Saeedian FS, Akha1 O, Gorgi MA, Emadi SF, Zakeri H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency is high in winter because of reduced exposure to sunlight. It seems that in places with high humidity and a sultry climate, exposure to sunlight in summer can be low too. This study was designed to determine the vitamin D deficiency prevalence in Sari, a city with a high humidity climate at the end of summer, and compare it to winter. Material and methods: This cross-sectional study was carried out on men and women aged 10 to 70. Clustered blood samples were received from 351 subjects who participated in this study toward the end of summer, and in winter. The levels of serum vitamin D, calcium, phosphorus, alkaline phosphatase and PTH were measured. T test and X2 were used for data analysis. Results: 351subjects (66.4% women, 33.6% men) aged 11 to 69 (mean age ± SD 37.11 ± 12.6) participated in the study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Middle East and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-middle-east-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-middle-east-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-ahem-joy-of-summer-in-dubaihttpmideastpostscom20110623the-ahem-joy-of-summer-in-dubai">&lt;a href="http://mideastposts.com/2011/06/23/the-ahem-joy-of-summer-in-dubai/">The, ahem, ‘Joy’ of Summer in Dubai&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Written by thehedonista (2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upon awakening this morning, I could not see out my windows. Lion asked me if it had been raining – the condensation was thick and punctuated with large rivulets that revealed the jungle our garden has become. But if I look out the windows on the second storey, I can see nothing but beige. The light is dull, the sun shrouded in mother earth’s pollution – dust and humidity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Parkinson disease increased in Israel by 50 percent in 7 years</title><link>/posts/parkinson-disease-increased-in-israel-by-50-percent-in-7-years.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/parkinson-disease-increased-in-israel-by-50-percent-in-7-years.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="new-method-for-measuring-parkinsons-disease-prevalence-reveals-sharp-increase-in-israel">New method for measuring Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease prevalence reveals sharp increase in Israel&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://medicalxpress.com/news/2011-06-method-parkinson-disease-prevalence-reveals.html%20">June 9, 2011 Medical Xpress&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a new study published today in the inaugural issue of the Journal of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease, Israeli researchers report that by tracking pharmacy purchases of anti-Parkinson drugs they could estimate the number of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease (PD) cases in a large population. The study identified a sharp rise in PD prevalence from 170/100,000 in 2000 to 256/100,000 in 2007 in Israel, which warrants further investigation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turkey gave 400 IU vitamin D to all infants and reduced Rickets by 60X - 2011</title><link>/posts/turkey-gave-400-iu-vitamin-d-to-all-infants-and-reduced-rickets-by-60x-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/turkey-gave-400-iu-vitamin-d-to-all-infants-and-reduced-rickets-by-60x-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="free-vitamin-d-supplementation-for-every-infant-in-turkey">Free vitamin D supplementation for every infant in Turkey&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Arch Dis Child. 2007 April; 92(4): 373–374.; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/adc.2006.113829.">doi: 10.1136/adc.2006.113829.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC2083692&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sükrü Hatun, Abdullah Bereket, Behzat Özkan, Turgay Çoþkun, Rýfat Köse, and Ali Süha Çalýkoðlu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence to: S Hatun &lt;a href="mailto:sukruhatun@gmail.com">sukruhatun@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We read with interest the article by Zipitis et al 1 concerning primary care trusts providing funds for vitamin D supplementation of Asian children for at least the first 2?years of life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutritional rickets remains prevalent in developing regions of the world such as Africa, the Indian subcontinent, Asia and the Middle East, and ranks among the five most common diseases in children.2,3,4 The prevalence of nutritional rickets in developed countries also seems to be rising.5,6,7,8,9,10,11&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yet again – vitamin D levels very low in sunny Saudia Arabia</title><link>/posts/yet-again-vitamin-d-levels-very-low-in-sunny-saudia-arabia.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yet-again-vitamin-d-levels-very-low-in-sunny-saudia-arabia.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>33 percent of pregnant women in Turkey had undetectable vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/33-percent-of-pregnant-women-in-turkey-had-undetectable-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/33-percent-of-pregnant-women-in-turkey-had-undetectable-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="bone-turnover-and-maternal-25oh-vitamin-d3-levels-during-pregnancy-and-the-postpartum-period-should-routine-vitamin-d-supplementation-be-increased-in-pregnant-women">Bone turnover and maternal 25(OH) vitamin D3 levels during pregnancy and the postpartum period: should routine vitamin D supplementation be increased in pregnant women?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Haliloglu B, Ilter E, Aksungar FB, Celik A, Coksuer H, Gunduz T, Yucel E, Ozekici U.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maltepe University, Faculty of Medicine, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Istanbul, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2011 May 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the relationship between 25(OH) vitamin D3 levels and maternal bone turnover during pregnancy and lactation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels in Israel vs skin type and age</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-in-israel-vs-skin-type-and-age.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-in-israel-vs-skin-type-and-age.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-25ohd-concentrations-in-sunny-israel">Serum 25(OH)D concentrations in sunny Israel.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2011 Mar 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saliba W, Rennert HS, Kershenbaum A, Rennert G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Community Medicine and Epidemiology, Carmel Medical Center, Clalit Health Services, and Bruce Rappaport Faculty of Medicine, Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, 7 Michal St., Haifa, 34362, Israel, &lt;a href="mailto:saliba_wa@clalit.org.il">saliba_wa@clalit.org.il&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study assesses vitamin D status in Israel. Serum 25(OH)D levels &amp;lt;25 and &amp;lt;50 nmol/L are common in Israel with noted differences between Arabs and Jews, Arab females were particularly at high risk. These findings may require public health intervention at the population level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Alert – one in three pre-teens in Tehran had less than 5 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/red-alert-one-in-three-pre-teens-in-tehran-had-less-than-5-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/red-alert-one-in-three-pre-teens-in-tehran-had-less-than-5-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="high-prevalence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-school-age-children-in-tehran-2008-a-red-alert">High prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in school-age children in Tehran, 2008: a red alert.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Public Health Nutr. 2011 Feb 28:1-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neyestani TR, Hajifaraji M, Omidvar N, Eshraghian MR, Shariatzadeh N, Kalayi A, Gharavi A, Khalaji N, Haidari H, Zowghi T, Nikooyeh B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Laboratory of Nutrition Research, National Research Institute, Faculty of Nutritional Science and Food Technology, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, PO Box 19395-4741, Tehran, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To assess the vitamin D status of 9-12-year-old primary-school children in Tehran during autumn and winter 2007-2008.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>23 ng of vitamin D in sunny Israel</title><link>/posts/23-ng-of-vitamin-d-in-sunny-israel.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/23-ng-of-vitamin-d-in-sunny-israel.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Concealing clothing resulted in only 8 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/concealing-clothing-resulted-in-only-8-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/concealing-clothing-resulted-in-only-8-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="risk-factors-for-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-women-aged-20-50-years-consulting-in-general-practice-a-cross-sectional-study">Risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in women aged 20-50 years consulting in general practice: a cross-sectional study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Gen Pract. 2011 Feb 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Le Goaziou MF, Contardo G, Dupraz C, Martin A, Laville M, Schott-Pethelaz AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of General Practice, University Claude Bernard, Lyon 1, &lt;strong>France.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: Vitamin D deficiency is often unidentified, although treatment is simple and inexpensive. Our objective was to estimate the influence of concealing clothes and other risk factors for vitamin D deficiency in women aged 20 to 50 years consulting general practitioners.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Only 19 percent of Turkish mothers had normal levels of vitamin D – 2009</title><link>/posts/only-19-percent-of-turkish-mothers-had-normal-levels-of-vitamin-d-2009.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/only-19-percent-of-turkish-mothers-had-normal-levels-of-vitamin-d-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-turkish-mothers-and-their-neonates-and-in-women-of-reproductive-age">Vitamin D Deficiency in Turkish Mothers and Their Neonates and in Women of Reproductive Age&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Clin Res Pediatr Endocrinol. 2009 December; 1(6): 266–269.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2009 November 3. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4274/jcrpe.v1i6.266.">doi: 10.4274/jcrpe.v1i6.266.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ayça Törel Ergür,corresponding author1 Merih Berbero?lu,1 Begüm Atasay,2 Zeynep ??klar,1 Pelin Bilir,1 Saadet Arsan,2 Feride Söylemez,3 and Gönül Öcal1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Ankara University, School of Medicine, Departments of Pediatric Endocrinology, Ankara, Turkey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Ankara University, School of Medicine, Departments of Neonatology, Ankara, Turkey&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultra-orthodox Jews also suffer from 10 ng vitamin D levels (cloth)</title><link>/posts/ultra-orthodox-jews-also-suffer-from-10-ng-vitamin-d-levels-cloth.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ultra-orthodox-jews-also-suffer-from-10-ng-vitamin-d-levels-cloth.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effect-of-different-dress-style-on-vitamin-d-level-in-healthy-young-orthodox-and-ultra-orthodox-students-in-israel">Effect of different dress style on vitamin D level in healthy young Orthodox and ultra-Orthodox students in Israel.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-at-vitamindwiki">See also at VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="effect-of-different-dress-style-on-vitamin-d-level-in-healthy-young-orthodox-and-ultra-orthodox-students-in-israel">Effect of different dress style on vitamin D level in healthy young Orthodox and ultra-Orthodox students in Israel.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int () (2010)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tsur&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetes and Endocrinology, Clalit Health Services, Jerusalem, Israel, &lt;a href="mailto:tsuranat@netvision.net.il">tsuranat@netvision.net.il&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultra-orthodox Jewish lifestyle, which encourages modest dress and indoor scholarly activity, represents a risk factor for vitamin-D deficiency. Our study in healthy young males from higher education religious institutions located in the same geographical area showed frequent and severe vitamin D deficiency, strongly correlated with the degree of sun exposure. However, PTH level was usually normal.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>