<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Overview for Doctors on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/overview-for-doctors.html</link><description>Recent content in Overview for Doctors on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/overview-for-doctors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consultation to medical professionals on Vitamin D Testing</title><link>/posts/consultation-to-medical-professionals-on-vitamin-d-testing.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/consultation-to-medical-professionals-on-vitamin-d-testing.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="pathology-consultation-on-vitamin-d-testing">Pathology Consultation on Vitamin D Testing&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Matthew D. Krasowski, MD, PhD Pathology Consultation / Special Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Key Words: Calcitriol; Calcium metabolism disorders; Osteoporosis; Reference standards; Reference values; Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1309/AJCPB50USETUOQDZ&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=24&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">All items in category Test for D&lt;/a> 40 items as of Oct 2011&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Many on variation between tests: different days, different testing methods&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/one-vitamin-d-blood-test-said-toxic-the-other-said-normal" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 902">One vitamin D blood test said toxic the other said normal – Aug 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Graphs of diseases vs vitamin D levels - and D3 vs D2</title><link>/posts/graphs-of-diseases-vs-vitamin-d-levels-and-d3-vs-d2.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/graphs-of-diseases-vs-vitamin-d-levels-and-d3-vs-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="graphs-from-a-presentation-by-dr-grimes-in-london">Graphs from a presentation by Dr. Grimes in London&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PDF of the presentation is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindassociation.org/7th-april-2011-vitamin-d---experts-forum.html">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for audio and video versions on the web (Clinical Experiences)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="can-see-that-the-patients-with-east-asian-names-have-significantly-lower-vitamin-d-levels-than-those-with-british-names">Can see that the patients with East Asian Names have significantly lower vitamin D levels than those with British Names&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;735,734&amp;rdquo; max =&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="median-east-asian--9-ng--nbsp-nbspmedian-british--19-ng">Median East Asian = 9 ng    Median British = 19 ng&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="notepatients-with-the-lowest-level-of-vitamin-d-in-their-blood-are-on-the-right">Note:patients with the lowest level of vitamin D in their blood are on the right&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="graphs-showing-the-vitamin-d-levels-for-each-disease">Graphs showing the vitamin D levels for each disease.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;736,737,738,739,740,741,742,743,744,745&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;250&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Panel Discussion on Vitamin D and Tests - 2011</title><link>/posts/panel-discussion-on-vitamin-d-and-tests-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/panel-discussion-on-vitamin-d-and-tests-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="clinical-applications-for-vitamin-d-assays-what-is-known-and-what-is-wished-forhttpwwwclinchemorgcgicontentshort5791227rss1">&lt;a href="http://www.clinchem.org/cgi/content/short/57/9/1227?rss=1">Clinical Applications for Vitamin D Assays: What Is Known and What Is Wished for&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Clinical Chemistry April 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael Kleerekoper, Moderator1, &lt;a href="mailto:mkleerekoper@med.wayne.edu">mkleerekoper@med.wayne.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rosemary L. Schleicher2, John Eisman3,4,5, Roger Bouillon6, Ravinder J. Singh7 and Michael F. Holick, Experts8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Wayne State University, St. John River District Hospital, East China, MI;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Nutritional Biomarkers Laboratory, Division of Laboratory Sciences, National Center for Environmental Health, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mini-review of vitamin D roles</title><link>/posts/mini-review-of-vitamin-d-roles.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mini-review-of-vitamin-d-roles.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-multiple-roles-of-vitamin-d-in-human-health-a-mini-review">The Multiple Roles of Vitamin D in Human Health. A Mini-Review&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J. Boucher, Barbara&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Immunology, Endocrine &amp;amp; Metabolic Agents - Medicinal Chemistry (Formerly, Volume 11, Number 3, September 2011 , pp. 220-227(8)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a hormone precursor, originally provided by ultraviolet light-induced skin synthesis of cholecalciferol but, with modern lifestyles, humans depend on dietary intake &lt;span>[mainly as ergocalciferol]&lt;/span>; adequate intakes are essential for musculo-skeletal health, the `classical&amp;rsquo; benefits of this vitamin, modulated by the activated hormonal metabolite, calcitriol. Most other tissues also contain vitamin D receptors and it&amp;rsquo;s activating enzyme.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D insufficiency - NEJM</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-insufficiency-nejm.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-insufficiency-nejm.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="pdf-is-at-bottom-of-this-page">PDF is at bottom of this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="rough-text-follows---for-translation-to-other-languages">Rough text follows - for translation to other languages&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1 id="clifford-j-rosen-md-who-was-a-consultant-to-the-iom">Clifford J. Rosen, M.D. (who was a consultant to the IoM)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This Journal feature begins with a case vignette highlighting a common clinical problem. Evidence supporting various strategies is then presented, followed by a review of formal guidelines, when they exist. The article ends with the author’s clinical recommendations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A healthy 61-year-old white woman is concerned about a low vitamin D level detected during an assessment of her skeletal health. Her menopause began at 54 years of age. She has no history of falls, and there is no family history of hip fracture. She takes no medications or supplements. Her height is 157.5 cm (5 ft 2 in.), and her weight 59.1 kg (130 lb). The results of a physical examination are unremarkable, and the f indings on laboratory studies are normal. The T score for bone mineral density at the hip is âˆ’1.5, and the serum level of 25-hydroxyvitamin D is 21 ng per milliliter (53 nmol per liter). What do you advise?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paradigm Shift of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/paradigm-shift-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/paradigm-shift-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-human-health-a-paradigm-shift">The Role of Vitamin D in Human Health: A Paradigm Shift&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Joan M. Lappe, PhD, RN, FAAN&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creighton University, Omaha, NE, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:jmlappe@creighton.edu">jmlappe@creighton.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Journal of Evidence-Based Complementary &amp;amp; Alternative Medicine January 2011 vol. 16 no. 1 58-72&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is pandemic, spanning many continents and including all ages, genders and racial/ethnic groups. Currently, world-wide attention is focused on the importance of vitamin D in optimizing health and preventing disease. This focus is largely the result of the scientific discovery that vitamin D receptors are present in nearly every tissue and cell in the body and that adequate vitamin D status is essential for optimal functioning of these tissues and cells. An impressive body of research has accumulated over the past two decades providing new information about the role of vitamin D in prevention of a broad range of diseases. The purpose of this paper is to provide a review of this new information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D overview by Grant</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-overview-by-grant.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-overview-by-grant.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="requirements-for-vitamin-d-across-the-life-span">Requirements for Vitamin D Across the Life Span&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>William B. Grant and Barbara J. Boucher&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Biological Research For Nursing, Biol Res Nurs published online 17 January 2011, DOI: 10.1177/1099800410391243&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant, PhD1, and Barbara J. Boucher, MD, FRCP2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center (SUNARC), San Francisco, CA, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Centre for Diabetes, Bart&amp;rsquo;s and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, Blizard Institute of Cell and Molecular Science, London, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mayo Clinic still wants stronger evidence of benefits of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mayo-clinic-still-wants-stronger-evidence-of-benefits-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mayo-clinic-still-wants-stronger-evidence-of-benefits-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency">Vitamin d insufficiency.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Mayo Clin Proc. 2011 Jan;86(1):50-60.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thacher TD, Clarke BL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Family Medicine, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St SW, Rochester, MN 55905. &lt;a href="mailto:thacher.thomas@mayo.edu">thacher.thomas@mayo.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency, which classically manifests as bone disease (either rickets or osteomalacia), is characterized by impaired bone mineralization. More recently, the term vitamin D insufficiency has been used to describe low levels of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D that may be associated with other disease outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>75 trials and 11 systematic reviews published every day</title><link>/posts/75-trials-and-11-systematic-reviews-published-every-day.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/75-trials-and-11-systematic-reviews-published-every-day.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="seventy-five-trials-and-eleven-systematic-reviews-a-day">Seventy-Five Trials and Eleven Systematic Reviews a Day:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How Will We Ever Keep Up?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolorf00it-is-impossible-for-the-doctors-to-keep-up-with-all-of-the-medical-advancesspan">&lt;span style="color:#F00;">(It is impossible for the doctors to keep up with all of the medical advances)&lt;/span>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hilda Bastian1*, Paul Glasziou2, Iain Chalmers3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 German Institute for Quality and Efficiency in Health Care (IQWiG), Cologne, Germany, 2 Centre for Research in Evidence-Based Practice, Faculty of Health Sciences, Bond University, Gold Coast, Australia, 3 James Lind Library, James Lind Initiative, Oxford, United Kingdom&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Evaluating the vitamin D evidence - Heaney</title><link>/posts/evaluating-the-vitamin-d-evidence-heaney.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/evaluating-the-vitamin-d-evidence-heaney.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-few-images-from-a-presentation-given-in-london">A few images from a Presentation given in London&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="spantiki-download_filephpfileid1628span-to-see-entire-pdf-file">&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1628]&lt;/span> to see entire PDF file&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;367,368,369,370,371,372,373,374,375&amp;rdquo; max=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-index.php">Home page&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=86&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">All items Strength of Evidence for D&lt;/a> 7 items as of Sept 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Consensus Vitamin D position statement – UK</title><link>/posts/consensus-vitamin-d-position-statement-uk.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/consensus-vitamin-d-position-statement-uk.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="this-page-includes-comments-by-span-stylecolorf33vitamindwiki-embededspan-and-followed-by-natural-news">This page includes comments by &lt;span style="color:#F33;">VitaminDWiki (embeded)&lt;/span> and followed by Natural News&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="this-consensus-statement-represents-the-unified-views-of-the">This consensus statement represents the unified views of the&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>British Association of Dermatologists,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cancer Research UK,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Diabetes UK,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Multiple Sclerosis Society,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>National Heart Forum,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>National Osteoporosis Society and&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Primary Care Dermatology Society.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is essential for good bone health and for most people sunlight is the most important source of vitamin D. The time required to make sufficient vitamin D varies according to a number of environmental, physical and personal factors, but is typically short and less than the amount of time needed for skin to redden and burn. Enjoying the sun safely, while taking care not to burn, can help to provide the benefits of vitamin D without unduly raising the risk of skin cancer. Vitamin D supplements and specific foods can help to maintain sufficient levels of vitamin D, particularly in people at risk of deficiency. However, there is still a lot of uncertainty around what levels qualify as “optimal” or “sufficient”, how much sunlight different people need to achieve a given level of vitamin D, whether vitamin D protects against chronic diseases such as cancer, heart disease and diabetes, and the benefits and risks of widespread supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>25 experts recommend vitamin D level of min 30 ng</title><link>/posts/25-experts-recommend-vitamin-d-level-of-min-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/25-experts-recommend-vitamin-d-level-of-min-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="publication-of-the-nov-2009-meeting-was-sept-2010">Publication of the Nov 2009 meeting was Sept 2010&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="minimum-recommended-vitamin-d-by-25-experts-was-higher-than-the-20-ngml-proclamation-of-the-institute-of-medicine">MINIMUM recommended vitamin D by 25 experts was higher than the 20 ng/ml proclamation of the Institute of Medicine&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;355&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-musculoskeletal-health-cardiovascular-disease-autoimmunity-and-cancer-recommendations-for-clinical-practice">Vitamin D and musculoskeletal health, cardiovascular disease, autoimmunity and cancer: Recommendations for clinical practice&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmunity Reviews&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volume 9, Issue 11, September 2010, Pages 709-715; doi:10.1016/j.autrev.2010.06.009&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="spantiki-download_filephpfileid1615span">&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1615]&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Jean-Claude Souberbielle a, Jean-Jacques Body b, Joan M. Lappe c, Mario Plebani d, Yehuda Shoenfeld e, Thomas J. Wang f, Heike A. Bischoff-Ferrari g, Etienne Cavalier h, Peter R. Ebeling i, Patrice Fardellone j, Sara Gandini k, Damien Gruson l, Alain P. Guérin m, Lene Heickendorff n, Bruce W. Hollis o, Sofia Ish-Shalom p, Guillaume Jean q, Philipp von Landenberg r, Alvaro Largura s, Tomas Olsson t, Charles Pierrot-Deseilligny u, Stefan Pilz v, Angela Tincani w, Andre Valcour x and Armin Zittermann y&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Holick</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-holick.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-holick.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-evolutionary-physiological-and-health-perspectives">Vitamin D: evolutionary, physiological and health perspectives.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Curr Drug Targets. 2011 Jan 1;12(1):4-18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Holick MF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Section of Endocrinology, Nutrition, and Diabetes, Vitamin D, Skin and Bone Research Laboratory, Boston University Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:mfholick@bu.edu">mfholick@bu.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D, the sunshine vitamin, has been important not only for the evolution of a healthy calcified vertebrate skeleton but it also evolved into a hormone that has a wide diversity of biologic effects. During exposure to sunlight the ultraviolet B radiation converts 7-dehydrocholesterol to previtamin D(3) which in turn rapidly isomerizes to vitamin D(3).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Report on Vitamin D – 35 pages</title><link>/posts/report-on-vitamin-d-35-pages.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/report-on-vitamin-d-35-pages.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-in-health-and-disease-current-perspectives">Vitamin D in health and disease: Current perspectives&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ran Zhang and Declan P Naughton&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrition Journal 2010, 9:65doi:10.1186/1475-2891-9-65&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 	8 December 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite the numerous reports of the association of vitamin D with a spectrum of development, disease treatment and health maintenance, vitamin D deficiency is common. Originating in part from the diet but with a key source resulting from transformation by exposure to sunshine, a great deal of the population suffers from vitamin D deficiency especially during winter months. It is linked to the treatment and pathogenesis and/or progression of several disorders including cancer, hypertension, multiple sclerosis, rheumatoid arthritis, osteoporosis, muscle weakness and diabetes. This widespread deficiency of Vitamin D merits consideration of widespread policies including increasing awareness among the public and healthcare professionals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D trials, studies, and meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-trials-studies-and-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-trials-studies-and-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="on-dec-5-2010">On Dec 5, 2010&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="searched-pubmedhttpwwwncbinlmnihgovpubmed-with-vitamin-d-in-titleabstract-and-found">Searched &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/">PubMed&lt;/a> with &amp;ldquo;Vitamin D&amp;rdquo; in title/abstract and found&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="141-meta-analysis--overview-of-many-random-controlled-trials">141 Meta-Analysis = overview of many Random Controlled Trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="4784-reviews">4784 Reviews&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="998-random-controlled-trials">998 Random Controlled Trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="1668-clinical-trials">1668 Clinical Trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="38-practice-guidelines">38 Practice Guidelines&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="more-pubmed-articles-every-year-with-vitamin-d-in-title-or-abstract">More PubMed articles every year with vitamin D in title or abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="year-ending-2010----2429--ending-2009----1783--ending-2008----1541">year ending 2010 - &lt;strong>2429&lt;/strong> ; ending 2009 - &lt;strong>1783&lt;/strong> ; ending 2008 - &lt;strong>1541&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h5 id="whereas-vitamin-a-was-mentioned-only-2389-times-in-the-past-5-years">whereas, &amp;ldquo;vitamin A&amp;rdquo; was mentioned only 2389 times in the past 5 years&lt;/h5>
&lt;h2 id="searched-us-clinical-trials-databasehttpclinicaltrialsgovct2resultsterm22vitamind22t-for-vitamin-d">Searched &lt;a href="http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/results?term=%22vitamin+d%22T">US Clinical Trials database&lt;/a> for Vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="720-clinical-trials">720 clinical trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="421-clinical-trials-updated-since-jan-1-2010">421 clinical trials updated since Jan 1, 2010&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;333&amp;quot;max=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Survey of patient and doctor vitamin D knowledge</title><link>/posts/survey-of-patient-and-doctor-vitamin-d-knowledge.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/survey-of-patient-and-doctor-vitamin-d-knowledge.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="survey-of-health-professionalshttprnzcgporgnzvitamin-d-survey">&lt;a href="http://rnzcgp.org.nz/vitamin-d-survey/">Survey of Health Professionals&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>How do you as a GP advise patients about vitamin D sufficiency and sun exposure? Does your advice vary depending on the time of year? Which patient attributes or health histories may alter the advice you give? University of Otago researchers are interested in knowing how New Zealand GP’s respond to these issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="spantiki-download_filephpfileid1585span">&lt;span>[tiki-download_file.php?fileId=1585]&lt;/span>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="concurrent-survey-of-non-professionals">Concurrent Survey of non-professionals&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="full-results-here-later">Full results here later&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The survey showed over 70 per cent of mothers thought the skin cancer messages made it difficult to understand messages about vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rediscovering vitamin D</title><link>/posts/rediscovering-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rediscovering-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="nasr-anaizi-department-of-pharmacology-and-physiology-university-of-rochester-school-of-medicine-and-dentistry-ny-usa">Nasr Anaizi, Department of Pharmacology and Physiology, University of Rochester School of Medicine and Dentistry, NY, USA&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Over the past 2 years there has been a radical change in standard clinical practice with respect to vitamin D.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a result of a growing body of knowledgeable physicians are assessing the vitamin D nutritional status of their patients and prescribing aggressive repletion regimens of a vitamin D supplement. The present paper summarizes some basic information about this essential nutrient and reviews some of the more recent data implicating vitamin D deficiency in disease etiology with an emphasis on cardiovascular disease and cancer. Finally a rational approach to the dosing of vitamin D in different patient populations is provided.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of vitamin D and bone health studies – with tables</title><link>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-and-bone-health-studies-with-tables.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-vitamin-d-and-bone-health-studies-with-tables.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bone-health-nutrition-issues-in-aging">Bone Health Nutrition Issues in Aging&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2010, 2(11), 1086-1105; doi:10.3390/nu2111086&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Review&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karen Plawecki &lt;a href="mailto:plawecki@illinois.edu">plawecki@illinois.edu&lt;/a> and Karen Chapman-Novakofski&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Nutritional Sciences, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Urbana, IL 61801, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received: 19 September 2010; in revised form: 29 October 2010 / Accepted: 2 November 2010 / Published: 8 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(This article belongs to the Special Issue Nutrition and Aging)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abstract: Bone health is an important issue in aging. Calcium and vitamin D currently have the most focus in published research on nutrition and bone health in aging, although evidence from published research is not conclusive. A systematic review was conducted to determine the impact of dietary and supplemental interventions focused on calcium and vitamin D over the past 10 years. Using key words to search, and search limits (aging population, English), 62 papers were found related to diet, nutrition, and bone; and 157 were found related to calcium and bone. Our review found a positive effect on bone health for supplements; food-based interventions; and educational strategies. Although there may be a publishing bias related to non-significant findings not being published, our results suggest the effectiveness of food based and educational interventions with less economic impact to the individual, as well as less risk of physiological side effects occurring.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>