<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Autism on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/autism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Autism on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/autism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autism treated by an activator of the Vitamin D Receptor: supforaphane</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-treated-by-an-activator-of-the-vitamin-d-receptor-supforaphane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-treated-by-an-activator-of-the-vitamin-d-receptor-supforaphane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;new-study-shows-promise-for-natural-support-of-autism-symptoms---march-2024&#34;&gt;New Study Shows Promise for Natural Support of Autism Symptoms - March 2024&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://greenmedinfo.com/content/new-study-shows-promise-natural-support-autism-symptoms&#34;&gt;GreenMedInfo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A new double-blind, placebo-controlled study published in Psychiatry and Clinical Neurosciences shows exciting potential for sulforaphane, a compound found in broccoli sprouts, to help ease symptoms of irritability and hyperactivity in children with autism spectrum disorder (ASD).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;After 10 weeks, the sulforaphane group showed significantly greater improvements in irritability scores and hyperactivity/noncompliance scores compared to placebo. However, no differences were seen between groups in other symptom areas like lethargy, stereotypic behavior, or inappropriate speech.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot; A study published in Psychiatry and Clinical Neurosciences found that when used as an adjunctive treatment alongside  &lt;strong&gt;risperidone&lt;/strong&gt; , sulforaphane significantly improved symptoms of irritability and hyperactivity in children with ASD compared to placebo.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autism risky if low vitamin D during pregnancy and early life (mice, fecal transplant reversed it)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-risky-if-low-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-early-life-mice-fecal-transplant-reversed-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-risky-if-low-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-early-life-mice-fecal-transplant-reversed-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;induction-of-autism-related-behavior-in-male-mice-by-early-life-vitamin-d-deficiency-association-with-disruption-of-the-gut-microbial-composition-and-homeostasis&#34;&gt;Induction of autism-related behavior in male mice by early-life vitamin D deficiency: association with disruption of the gut microbial composition and homeostasis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Food Funct . 2024 Mar 27. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1039/d4fo00279b&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1039/d4fo00279b&lt;/a&gt; PDF behind paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jingjing Cui 1 2 3, Shumin Wang 3 4, Zidan Zhai 1 2, Xiaoyue Song 5, Ting Qiu 2, Leilei Yu 3 4, Qixiao Zhai 3 4, Heng Zhang 2 5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D deficiency (VDD) during early life emerges as a potential risk factor for autism spectrum disorder (ASD). Individuals with autism commonly exhibit lower vitamin D (VD) levels compared to the general population, and VD deficiency is prevalent during pregnancy and lactation. Moreover, gastrointestinal comorbidity, prevalent in ASD patients, correlates closely with disruptions in the gut microbiota and altered intestinal permeability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24% lower risk of Autism for every 4 ng higher level of vitamin D during pregnancy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/24-percent-lower-risk-of-autism-for-every-4-ng-higher-level-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/24-percent-lower-risk-of-autism-for-every-4-ng-higher-level-of-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;high-dose-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-pregnancy-and-risk-of-neurodevelopmental-disorders-in-the-children-at-age-10-a-randomized-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;High-dose vitamin D3 supplementation in pregnancy and risk of neurodevelopmental disorders in the children at age 10: A randomized clinical trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition Vol 119, Issue 2, February 2024, Pages 362-370 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajcnut.2023.12.002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajcnut.2023.12.002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kristina Aagaard 1, Jens Richardt Møllegaard Jepsen 2 3, Astrid Sevelsted 1, David Horner 1, Rebecca Vinding 1, Julie Bøjstrup Rosenberg 1 3, Nicklas Brustad 1, Anders Eliasen 1 4, Parisa Mohammadzadeh 1 3, Nilofar Følsgaard 1, María Hernández-Lorca 1, Birgitte Fagerlund 2 3 5, Birte Y. Glenthøj 3 6, Morten Arendt Rasmussen 1 7, Niels Bilenberg 8 9, Jakob Stokholm 1 7, Klaus Bønnelykke 1 6, Bjørn H. Ebdrup 3 6 †, Bo Chawes 1 6 †&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autism risk if toxins, heavy metals, microplastics, etc during pregnancy (unless add Vitamin D)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-risk-if-toxins-heavy-metals-microplastics-etc-during-pregnancy-unless-add-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-risk-if-toxins-heavy-metals-microplastics-etc-during-pregnancy-unless-add-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-autism-spectrum-disorder-and-its-possible-origins-in-pregnancy&#34;&gt;The Autism Spectrum Disorder and Its Possible Origins in Pregnancy&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 2024, 21(3), 244; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph21030244&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph21030244&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rayane M. Botelho ORCID,Ana Lúcia M. Silva ORCID and Alexandre U. Borbely *ORCID&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cell Biology Laboratory, Institute of Biological and Health Sciences, Federal University of Alagoas, Maceio 57072-970, Brazil&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) belongs to the group of neurodevelopmental disorders, and has a high prevalence, affecting 1 in 100 children according to data from the World Health Organization (WHO). To be diagnosed with ASD, the child must have persistent deficits in communication and social interactions, and restricted and repetitive patterns of behavior, interests, or activities. Despite its prevalence, the etiology of ASD is still uncertain, with multifactorial characteristics, including those associated with the gestational period, where maternal exposure to biological, chemical, or physical hazards occurs, some of which have already been proposed as causes of ASD outcomes. Since pregnancy requires a balance between the maternal–fetal binomial, the breakdown of this balance caused by such environmental hazards can lead to altered fetal neurodevelopment, including ASD. With this firmly in mind, this review aims to compile the most recent data on the gestational causes that may be associated with the development of ASD to help health professionals identify risk factors and act for the prevention and management of ASD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autism reduced 24% for each 4 ng more Vitamin D while pregnant ( ADHD 12%)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-reduced-24-percent-for-each-4-ng-more-vitamin-d-while-pregnant-adhd-12-percent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-reduced-24-percent-for-each-4-ng-more-vitamin-d-while-pregnant-adhd-12-percent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;high-dose-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-pregnancy-and-risk-of-neurodevelopmental-disorders-in-the-children-at-age-10-a-randomized-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;High-dose vitamin D3 supplementation in pregnancy and risk of neurodevelopmental disorders in the children at age 10: A randomized clinical trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Am J Clin Nutr . 2024 Feb;119(2):362-370. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajcnut.2023.12.002&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.ajcnut.2023.12.002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kristina Aagaard 1, Jens Richardt Møllegaard Jepsen 2, Astrid Sevelsted 1, David Horner 1, Rebecca Vinding 1, Julie Bøjstrup Rosenberg 3, Nicklas Brustad 1, Anders Eliasen 4, Parisa Mohammadzadeh 3, Nilofar Følsgaard 1, María Hernández-Lorca 1, Birgitte Fagerlund 5, Birte Y Glenthøj 6, Morten Arendt Rasmussen 7, Niels Bilenberg 8, Jakob Stokholm 7, Klaus Bønnelykke 9, Bjørn H Ebdrup 6, Bo Chawes 10&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fewer neurons in males born from COVID-19 vaccinated mothers (rats)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fewer-neurons-in-males-born-from-covid-19-vaccinated-mothers-rats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fewer-neurons-in-males-born-from-covid-19-vaccinated-mothers-rats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;will-covid-19-shots-drive-an-epidemic-of-autism&#34;&gt;Will COVID-19 Shots Drive an Epidemic of Autism?&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://viralimmunologist.substack.com/p/will-covid-19-shots-drive-an-epidemic?utm_source=cross-post&amp;amp;publication_id=592214&amp;amp;post_id=140854321&amp;amp;utm_campaign=1119676&amp;amp;isFreemail=false&amp;amp;r=ofo3r&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&#34;&gt;Brindle substack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Male rats were the ones in which biochemical changes translated into an obvious manifestation of autism-like behaviours. Note that this was “pronounced”. Interestingly, this correlates with the human condition, in which boys are diagnosed with autism more often than girls. Of particular concern is the loss of neurons in the brain. Depending on the location of the brain, there were 24-38% fewer neurons in males born from dams (mothers) that had received the COVID-19 shot.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Down syndrome people have even lower D levels if have additional Vitamin D diseases</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/down-syndrome-people-have-even-lower-d-levels-if-have-additional-vitamin-d-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/down-syndrome-people-have-even-lower-d-levels-if-have-additional-vitamin-d-diseases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;hypovitaminosis-d-in-persons-with-down-syndrome-and-autism-spectrum-disorder&#34;&gt;Hypovitaminosis D in persons with Down syndrome and autism spectrum disorder&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J Neurodev Disord . 2023 Oct 25;15(1):35. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s11689-023-09503-y.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1186/s11689-023-09503-y.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Natalie K Boyd 1, Julia Nguyen 2, Mellad M Khoshnood 1, Timothy Jiang 1, Lina Nguyen 1, Lorena Mendez 1, Noemi A Spinazzi 3, Melanie A Manning 4, Michael S Rafii 5 6, Jonathan D Santoro 7 8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Plasma levels of vitamin D have been reported to be low in persons with Down syndrome (DS) and existing data is limited to small and homogenous cohorts. This is of particular importance in persons with DS given the high rates of autoimmune disease in this population and the known relationship between vitamin D and immune function. This study sought to investigate vitamin D status in a multi-center cohort of individuals with DS and compare them to individuals with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) and neurotypical (NT) controls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aspartame while pregnant increased risk by 3.4 X that male infant will be Autistic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aspartame-while-pregnant-increased-risk-by-34-x-that-male-infant-will-be-autistic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aspartame-while-pregnant-increased-risk-by-34-x-that-male-infant-will-be-autistic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;daily-early-life-exposures-to-diet-soda-and-aspartame-are-associated-with-autism-in-males-a-case-control-study&#34;&gt;Daily Early-Life Exposures to Diet Soda and Aspartame Are Associated with Autism in Males: A Case-Control Study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2023, 15(17), 3772; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15173772&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15173772&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Sharon Parten Fowler 1,*,David Gimeno Ruiz de Porras 2,3,4ORCID,Michael D. Swartz 5,Paula Stigler Granados 6ORCID,Lynne Parsons Heilbrun 7 and Raymond F. Palmer 8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since its introduction, aspartame—the leading sweetener in U.S. diet sodas (DS)—has been reported to cause neurological problems in some users. In prospective studies, the offspring of mothers who consumed diet sodas/beverages (DSB) daily during pregnancy experienced increased health problems. We hypothesized that gestational/early-life exposure to ≥1 DS/day (DSearly) or equivalent aspartame (ASPearly: ≥177 mg/day) increases autism risk. The case-control Autism Tooth Fairy Study obtained retrospective dietary recalls for DSB and aspartame consumption during pregnancy/breastfeeding from the mothers of 235 offspring with autism spectrum disorder (ASD: cases) and 121 neurotypically developing offspring (controls). The exposure odds ratios (ORs) for DSearly and ASPearly were computed for autism, ASD, and the non-regressive conditions of each.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infants getting an additional 800 IU of vitamin D for 2 years had 60% fewer psychiatric symptoms at age 7 – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/infants-getting-an-additional-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-2-years-had-60-percent-few-ms-at-age-7-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/infants-getting-an-additional-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-2-years-had-60-percent-few-ms-at-age-7-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;~~#00F:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reduced: Autism, ADHD, Depression. etc&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finland was supplementing milk with Vitamin D during the study, so both groups got more D&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefit if it had increased vitamin D dose with increased body weight&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Infant body weight triples in 24 months - so probably need 3600 IU at 24 months&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefit if it had adjusted vitamin D dose with BMI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Obese needs &amp;gt;2X more vitamin D&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefits if supplementation had started before birth&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefits with non-daily supplementation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study found a 79% reduction in problems if 1200 IU  when mothers had Vitamin D levels &amp;lt;30 ng&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preemies need even more vitamin D – no comment in study about preemies~~&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-the-first-2-years-of-life-on-psychiatric-symptoms-at-ages-6-to-8-years-a-randomized-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;Effect of Vitamin D3 Supplementation in the First 2 Years of Life on Psychiatric Symptoms at Ages 6 to 8 Years: A Randomized Clinical Trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JAMA Netw Open. 2023 May 1;6(5):e2314319. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.14319.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.14319.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transgender associated with autism, low vitamin D, low BMD, etc. - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/transgender-associated-with-autism-low-vitamin-d-low-bmd-etc-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/transgender-associated-with-autism-low-vitamin-d-low-bmd-etc-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vitamindwiki.com/tiki-index.php?page_id=10189&#34;&gt;Vitamin D levels have been crashing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has been a big increase in &lt;a href=&#34;https://vitamindwiki.com/tiki-index.php?page_id=605&#34;&gt;Autism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D has been proven to both prevent and treat Autism&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has been a big increase in Transgender etc. individuals&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps low vitamin D before and/or after birth increases gender confusion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People preparing for transgender therapy had lower Vitamin D levels&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Speculation: Increased vitamin D levels sometime after conception will decrease gender confusion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc  Title=&#34;20+ items&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;people-preparing-for-transgender-therapy-had-lower-vitamin-d-levels---july-2023&#34;&gt;People preparing for transgender therapy had lower Vitamin D levels - July 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bone health and body composition in transgender adults before gender-affirming hormonal therapy: data from the COMET study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
