<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Spinal Cord on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/spinal-cord.html</link><description>Recent content in Spinal Cord on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/spinal-cord/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spinal Surgery patients – almost all have low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/spinal-surgery-patients-almost-all-have-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-surgery-patients-almost-all-have-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-needed-for-spinal-fusion--sept-2017">&amp;gt; 30 ng of Vitamin D needed for spinal fusion – Sept 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="-30-ng-of-vitamin-d-needed-for-spinal-fusion--sept-2017">&amp;gt; 30 ng of Vitamin D needed for spinal fusion – Sept 2017&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D: Should we be checking levels before spine fusion?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seminars in Spine Surgery. online 12 September 2017, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1053/j.semss.2017.09.003">https://doi.org/10.1053/j.semss.2017.09.003&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Owoicho Adogwa, M.D., M.P.H, Jacob M. Buchowski, M.D., M.S.,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a prohormone that regulates calcium absorption from the gastrointestinal tract. It plays an important role in calcium homeostasis and Calcium has several important roles in transmission of nerve impulses, muscle contraction and proper mineralization of bone. An alarmingly high prevalence of vitamin D deficiency has been described in numerous segments of the U.S population, with recent studies estimating a prevalence rate of approximately 70%.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Both Spinal cord injury and stroke with one side disabled have similar low levels of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/both-spinal-cord-injury-and-stroke-with-one-side-disabled-have-similar-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/both-spinal-cord-injury-and-stroke-with-one-side-disabled-have-similar-low-levels-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-profile-of-patients-with-spinal-cord-injury-and-post-stroke-hemiplegia-all-in-the-same-boat">Vitamin D profile of patients with spinal cord injury and post-stroke hemiplegia: All in the same boat.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2016 Apr 27;29(2):205-210.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coskun Benlidayi I1, Basaran S1, Seydaoglu G2, Guzel R1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Medicine, Cukurova University, Adana, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Biostatistics, Faculty of Medicine, Cukurova University, Adana, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-repaired-nerve-in-rat-50000-iu-daily-dose-equivalent-for-human">Vitamin D repaired nerve in rat (50,000 IU daily dose equivalent for human) – June 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinal cord injury in rats was reduced if vitamin D is given soon after the injury</title><link>/posts/spinal-cord-injury-in-rats-was-reduced-if-vitamin-d-is-given-soon-after-the-injury.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-cord-injury-in-rats-was-reduced-if-vitamin-d-is-given-soon-after-the-injury.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="repairing-the-spinal-cord-with-vitamin-d-a-promising-strategy">Repairing the spinal cord with vitamin D: a promising strategy&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Biol Aujourdhui. 2014;208(1):69-75. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1051/jbio/2014008.">doi: 10.1051/jbio/2014008.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Jun 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[Article in French]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Féron F1, Marqueste T2, Bianco J1, Gueye Y1, Chabas JF1, Decherchi P2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2014, a phase II randomised, double blind clinical trial assessing the efficacy of cholecalciferol (vitamin D3) in patients with a cervical trauma will be set up. This trial stems from previous studies showing that vitamin D supplementation improves functional recovery in rat models of peripheral or central nerve injury. In a first series of experiments, we used a rat model of peripheral nerve trauma to demonstrate the therapeutic efficiency of vitamin D. We first demonstrated that ergocalciferol (vitamin D2) increases the number and the diameter of newly formed axons and improves the response of metabosensitive fibers from tibialis muscle, in a model of transected peroneal nerve. Then, we compared vitamin D2 and vitamin D3 and observed that the latter is more efficient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinal Cord</title><link>/posts/spinal-cord.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-cord.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Endocrinological and inflammatory markers in individuals with spinal cord injury: A systematic review and meta-analysis - Aug 2022   &lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/sci-meta.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> Vitamin D is one of several SCI concerns&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.greenmedinfo.com/blog/turmeric-heals-spinal-cord-injuries-better-drugssurgery-review-suggests">Turmeric Heals Spinal Cord Injuries Better Than Drugs/Surgery, Review Suggests&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Greenmedinfo June 2016, which has 200 Tumeric studies&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/the-potential-of-curcumin-in-treatment-of-spinal-cord-injury.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.pmrjournal.org/article/S1934-1482(16)30307-0/abstract">The Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation on Pain, Mood, Depression, and Strength in Patients with Spinal Cord Injury&lt;/a> Sept 2016&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinal cord problems more likely if TBI if little Omega-3 in diet</title><link>/posts/spinal-cord-problems-more-likely-if-tbi-if-little-omega-3-in-diet.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-cord-problems-more-likely-if-tbi-if-little-omega-3-in-diet.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="dietary-omega-3-deficiency-from-gestation-increases-spinal-cord-vulnerability-to-traumatic-brain-injury-induced-damage">Dietary omega-3 deficiency from gestation increases spinal cord vulnerability to traumatic brain injury-induced damage.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(12):e52998. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0052998.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0052998.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Dec 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ying Z, Feng C, Agrawal R, Zhuang Y, Gomez-Pinilla F.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Integrative Biology &amp;amp; Physiology, University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although traumatic brain injury (TBI) is often associated with gait deficits, the effects of TBI on spinal cord centers are poorly understood. We seek to determine the influence of TBI on the spinal cord and the potential of dietary omega-3 (n-3) fatty acids to counteract these effects. Male rodents exposed to diets containing adequate or deficient levels of n-3 since gestation received a moderate fluid percussion injury when becoming 14 weeks old. TBI reduced levels of molecular systems important for synaptic plasticity (BDNF, TrkB, and CREB) and plasma membrane homeostasis (4-HNE, iPLA2, syntaxin-3) in the lumbar spinal cord. These effects of TBI were more dramatic in the animals exposed to the n-3 deficient diet. Results emphasize the comprehensive action of TBI across the neuroaxis, and the critical role of dietary n-3 as a means to build resistance against the effects of TBI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D repaired nerve in rat (50,000 IU daily dose equivalent for human)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-repaired-nerve-in-rat-50000-iu-daily-dose-equivalent-for-human.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-repaired-nerve-in-rat-50000-iu-daily-dose-equivalent-for-human.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="cholecalciferol-vitamin-d3-improves-myelination-and-recovery-after-nerve-injury">Cholecalciferol (Vitamin D3) Improves Myelination and Recovery after Nerve Injury&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PLoS-ONE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jean-Francois Chabas, Delphine Stephan, Tanguy Marqueste, Stephane Garcia, Marie-Noelle Lavaut, Catherine Nguyen, Regis Legre, Michel Khrestchatisky, Patrick Decherchi equal contributor mail, Francois Feron equal contributor mail&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previously, we demonstrated i) that ergocalciferol (vitamin D2) increases axon diameter and potentiates nerve regeneration in a rat model of transected peripheral nerve and ii) that cholecalciferol (vitamin D3) improves breathing and hyper-reflexia in a rat model of paraplegia. However, before bringing this molecule to the clinic, it was of prime importance i) to assess which form – ergocalciferol versus cholecalciferol – and which dose were the most efficient and ii) to identify the molecular pathways activated by this pleiotropic molecule.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>