<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Loading Dose for Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/loading-dose-for-vitamin-d.html</link><description>Recent content in Loading Dose for Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/loading-dose-for-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D injections of a total of 1,800,000 IU reduced shinbone tenderness</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-injections-of-a-total-of-1800000-iu-reduced-shinbone-tenderness.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-injections-of-a-total-of-1800000-iu-reduced-shinbone-tenderness.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="tibial-tenderness-identifies-secondary-hyperparathyroidism-responding-to-high-dose-vitamin-d-in-pakistani-women">Tibial Tenderness Identifies Secondary Hyperparathyroidism Responding to High Dose Vitamin D in Pakistani Women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2013 Feb 20:1-20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ali B, Butt A, Fatima A, McDonnell ME, Masud F.; Department of Medicine, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: To assess the utility of &lt;strong>anterior tibial tenderness&lt;/strong> (ATT) measured by visual analogue score (VAS) as a clinical diagnostic tool for vitamin D deficiency in a high-risk population of Pakistani women&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: ATT using a VAS was assessed in 75 premenopausal women, ages 17-56 (mean 41.3) with generalized aches and pains and calcium of less than 11.0mg/dl (normal: 8-11) at a tertiary care center in Lahore, Pakistan. This was followed by administration of &lt;strong>1.8 million units of vitamin D3&lt;/strong> in divided doses. ATT, vitamin D and parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels were checked before and after the injections. Correlation between ATT, vitamin D and PTH as well as change in ATT, vitamin D and (PTH) following supplementation was determined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guideline following hip fracture – 50000 IU vitamin D daily for 7 days</title><link>/posts/guideline-following-hip-fracture-50000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-for-7-days.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/guideline-following-hip-fracture-50000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-for-7-days.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-levels-in-hip-fractures-rationale-and-guidelines-for-rapid-substitution-therapy">Vitamin D levels in hip fractures: rationale and guidelines for rapid substitution therapy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bone Joint J 2013 vol. 95-B no. SUPP 1 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A de Jong, K Woods, M Suresh and M Porteous; Bury St. Edmunds, United Kingdom&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction Assessment for and treatment of osteoporosis is recommended following hip fracture. All forms of osteoporosis treatment require an adequate calcium intake and normal vitamin D levels. This study assesses vitamin D levels in patients with hip fractures and describes guidelines on how to manage low vitamin D levels with high dose oral vitamin D3 (cholecalciferol).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rickets cured for 3 months with 10,000 IU per kg vitamin D (600,000 IU max)</title><link>/posts/rickets-cured-for-3-months-with-10000-iu-per-kg-vitamin-d-600000-iu-max.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rickets-cured-for-3-months-with-10000-iu-per-kg-vitamin-d-600000-iu-max.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="clinical-biochemical-and-radiological-manifestations-of-severe-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-adolescents-versus-children-response-to-therapy">Clinical, biochemical and radiological manifestations of severe vitamin d deficiency in adolescents versus children: response to therapy.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Georgian Med News. 2012 Sep;(210):58-64.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span>[Article in English, Georgian]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soliman A, De Sanctis V, Adel A, El Awwa A, Bedair S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics and Radiology, Hamad Medical Center, Doha, Qatar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objectives: to compare clinical, biochemical and radiological manifestations of severe vitamin D deficiency (VDD - serum 25 OH - vitamin D level &amp;lt;10 ng/ml) in adolescents and children and to investigate the effects of an intramuscular injection (IM) of vitamin D3 megadose.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lupus flares totally eliminated by loading dose then 100000 IU of vitamin D each month</title><link>/posts/lupus-flares-totally-eliminated-by-loading-dose-then-100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-each-month.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lupus-flares-totally-eliminated-by-loading-dose-then-100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-each-month.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="restoration-of-regulatory-and-effector-t-cell-balance-and-b-cell-homeostasis-in-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-patients-through-vitamin-d-supplementation">Restoration of regulatory and effector T cell balance and B cell homeostasis in systemic lupus erythematosus patients through vitamin D supplementation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Benjamin Terrier, Nicolas Derian, Yoland Schoindre, Wahiba Chaara, Guillaume Geri, Noel Zahr, Kuberaka Mariampillai, Michelle Rosenzwajg, Wassila Carpentier, Lucile Musset, Jean-Charles Piette, Adrien Six, David Klatzmann, David Saadoun, Patrice Cacoub and Nathalie Costedoat-Chalumeau&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arthritis Research &amp;amp; Therapy 2012, 14:R221 doi:10.1186/ar4060&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published: 17 October 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a T and B cell-dependent autoimmune disease characterized by the appearance of autoantibodies, a global regulatory T cells (Tregs) depletion and an increase in Th17 cells. Recent studies have shown the multifaceted immunomodulatory effects of vitamin D, notably the expansion of Tregs and the decrease of Th1 and Th17 cells. A significant correlation between higher disease activity and lower serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> was also shown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency somewhat treated with weekly 50000 IU Vitamin D2</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-somewhat-treated-with-weekly-50000-iu-vitamin-d2.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-somewhat-treated-with-weekly-50000-iu-vitamin-d2.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-within-a-large-integrated-health-care-delivery-system">Treatment of vitamin d deficiency within a large integrated health care delivery system.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Manag Care Pharm. 2012 Sep;18(7):497-505.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stratton-Loeffler MJ, Lo JC, Hui RL, Coates A, Minkoff JR, Budayr A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kaiser Permanente Division of Research, 2000 Broadway, Oakland, CA, 94612. USA. &lt;a href="mailto:Joan.C.Lo@kp.org">Joan.C.Lo@kp.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: In the past decade, increasing attention has focused on identification and treatment of vitamin D deficiency although repletion ?outcomes of pharmacologic vitamin D therapy have not been examined at ?a population level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recurrence of child pneumonia delayed by 100000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/recurrence-of-child-pneumonia-delayed-by-100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/recurrence-of-child-pneumonia-delayed-by-100000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-to-children-diagnosed-with-pneumonia-in-kabul-a-randomised-controlled-trial">Effects of vitamin D supplementation to children diagnosed with pneumonia in Kabul: a randomised controlled trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trop Med Int Health. 2010 Oct;15(10):1148-55. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-3156.2010.02578.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-3156.2010.02578.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2010 Aug 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manaseki-Holland S, Qader G, Isaq Masher M, Bruce J, Zulf Mughal M, Chandramohan D, Walraven G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kabul Medical University, Kabul, Afghanistan. Aga Khan Health Services, Kabul, Afghanistan&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To determine whether (i) supplementation of oral 100,000 iu of vitamin D(3) (cholecalciferol) along with antibiotics will reduce the duration of illness in children with pneumonia; (ii) supplementation will reduce the risk of repeat episodes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>600,000 IU vitamin D normalized virtually all seniors in 3 months (Injection better than oral)</title><link>/posts/600000-iu-vitamin-d-normalized-virtually-all-seniors-in-3-months-injection-better-than-oral.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/600000-iu-vitamin-d-normalized-virtually-all-seniors-in-3-months-injection-better-than-oral.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="efficacy-and-safety-of-high-dose-intramuscular-or-oral-cholecalciferol-in-vitamin-d-deficientinsufficient-elderly">Efficacy and safety of high dose intramuscular or oral cholecalciferol in vitamin D deficient/insufficient elderly.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Maturitas. 2012 May 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tellioglu A, Basaran S, Guzel R, Seydaoglu G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Faculty of Medicine, Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Cukurova University, Adana 01330, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: To evaluate and compare the effects and safety of high dose intramuscular (IM) or oral cholecalciferol on 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels, muscle strength and physical performance in vitamin D deficient/insufficient elderly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Huge gap between vitamin D advice and actual prescriptions</title><link>/posts/huge-gap-between-vitamin-d-advice-and-actual-prescriptions.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/huge-gap-between-vitamin-d-advice-and-actual-prescriptions.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="treatment-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-divergence-between-clinical-practice-and-expert-advice">Treatment of vitamin D deficiency: divergence between clinical practice and expert advice&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Postgrad Med J 2012;88:255-260 doi:10.1136/postgradmedj-2011-130243&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mark Findlay 1, Julia Anderson 2, Susan Roberts 3, Alison Almond 4, Chris Isles 1 &lt;a href="mailto:chris.isles@nhs.net">chris.isles@nhs.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Medicine, Dumfries and Galloway Royal Infirmary, Dumfriesshire, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Biochemistry, Dumfries and Galloway Royal Infirmary, Dumfriesshire, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Pharmacy Department, Dumfries and Galloway Royal Infirmary, Dumfriesshire, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Renal Unit, Dumfries and Galloway Royal Infirmary, Dumfriesshire, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>600,000 IU of vitamin D2 every 4 months for decades in East Germany – 1987</title><link>/posts/600000-iu-of-vitamin-d2-every-4-months-for-decades-in-east-germany-1987.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/600000-iu-of-vitamin-d2-every-4-months-for-decades-in-east-germany-1987.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="intermittent-high-dose-vitamin-d-prophylaxis-during-infancy-effect-on-vitamin-d-metabolites-calcium-and-phosphorus">Intermittent high-dose vitamin D prophylaxis during infancy: effect on vitamin D metabolites, calcium, and phosphorus.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Am J Clin Nutr. 1987 Oct;46(4):652-8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Markestad T, Hesse V, Siebenhuner M, Jahreis G, Aksnes L, Plenert W, Aarskog D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, University of Bergen, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In infants receiving intermittent high dose vitamin D prophylaxis (600,000 IU ergocalciferol per dose orally) every 3-5 mo, the serum concentrations of vitamin D metabolites, calcium (Ca), and phosphorus (P) were determined before and 2 wk after each dose. The 25-hydroxyvitamin D (OHD) concentrations increased to well above normal but the values returned to the normal range before each subsequent dose. The 24,25- and 25,26-dihydroxyvitamin D (&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>2D) levels followed a pattern similar to that of 25-OHD, and both were closely related to the latter (r = 0.85, p less than 0.005, and r = 0.84, p less than 0.005, respectively). The 1,25-(OH)2D concentrations did not vary in a consistent pattern and remained largely within the normal range. All infants had normal Ca levels before the first dose but 14 infants (34%) later had one or both Ca values above the upper normal limit of 2.80 mmol/L (2.81-3.32 mmol/L), indicating that the vitamin D doses were excessive despite the lack of accumulative increases in serum vitamin D concentrations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300,000 IU every 3 months helped raise vitamin D levels in half of RA patients</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-every-3-months-helped-raise-vitamin-d-levels-in-half-of-ra-patients.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-every-3-months-helped-raise-vitamin-d-levels-in-half-of-ra-patients.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="can-one-or-two-high-doses-of-oral-vitamin-d3-correct-insufficiency-in-a-non-supplemented-rheumatologic-population">Can one or two high doses of oral vitamin D3 correct insufficiency in a non-supplemented rheumatologic population?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>D. Stoll, J. Dudler, O. Lamy, D. Hans, M. A. Krieg and B. Aubry-Rozier&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis International, April 2012, DOI: 10.1007/s00198-012-1962-5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summary: We evaluated the effectiveness of supplementation with high dose of oral vitamin D3 to correct vitamin D insufficiency. We have shown that one or two oral bolus of 300,000 IU of vitamin D3 can correct vitamin D insufficiency in 50% of patients and that the patients who benefited more from supplementation were those with the lowest baseline levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Replentishment (Loading doses are not toxic)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-replentishment-loading-doses-are-not-toxic.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-replentishment-loading-doses-are-not-toxic.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>100,000 IU single dose of vitamin D - 2010</title><link>/posts/100000-iu-single-dose-of-vitamin-d-2010.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/100000-iu-single-dose-of-vitamin-d-2010.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="pharmacokinetics-of-a-single-large-dose-of-cholecalciferol">Pharmacokinetics of a single, large dose of cholecalciferol&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Marium Ilahi, Laura AG Armas, and Robert P Heaney&lt;/p>
&lt;p>.Am J Clin Nutr 2008;87:688-91. Printed in USA. © 2008 American Society for Nutrition&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/100000-iu-vitamin-d-lasts-60-days.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: There is much interest in dosing vitamin D intermittently for patient convenience and long-term adherence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: The objective was to characterize the time course and response of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (calcidiol) to a large oral dose of cholecalciferol.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loading dose of 300,000 IU vitamin D every 6 months</title><link>/posts/loading-dose-of-300000-iu-vitamin-d-every-6-months.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/loading-dose-of-300000-iu-vitamin-d-every-6-months.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>France attempts to restock vitamin D levels with 7000 or 14000 IU daily</title><link>/posts/france-attempts-to-restock-vitamin-d-levels-with-7000-or-14000-iu-daily.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/france-attempts-to-restock-vitamin-d-levels-with-7000-or-14000-iu-daily.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>300,000 IU injection loading dose of vitamin D3 stopped gestational diabetes in RCT</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-injection-loading-dose-of-vitamin-d3-stopped-gestational-diabetes-in-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-injection-loading-dose-of-vitamin-d3-stopped-gestational-diabetes-in-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effects-of-a-single-span-stylecolorf00post-partumspan-injection-of-a-high-dose-of-vitamin-d-on-glucose-tolerance-and-insulin-resistance-in-mothers-with-first-time-gestational-diabetes-mellitus">Effects of a single &lt;span style="color:#F00;">post-partum&lt;/span> injection of a high dose of vitamin D on glucose tolerance and insulin resistance in mothers with first-time gestational diabetes mellitus&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>H. Mozaffari-Khosravi1, M. Hosseinzadeh-Shamsi-Anar1, M.-A. Salami2, H. Hadinedoushan3, M. R. Mozayan4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diabetic Medicine Vol. 28 Issue 10&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aim? This study was performed to determine the effect of a single, large, intramuscular injection of vitamin D post-partum on glucose tolerance and insulin resistance in women with gestational diabetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 loading doses did not increase, and may have decreased blood levels</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-loading-doses-did-not-increase-and-may-have-decreased-blood-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-loading-doses-did-not-increase-and-may-have-decreased-blood-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-randomized-controlled-trial-of-vitamin-d-dosing-strategies-after-acute-hip-fracture-no-advantage-of-loading-doses-over-daily-supplementation">A randomized controlled trial of vitamin D dosing strategies after acute hip fracture: no advantage of loading doses over daily supplementation.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2011 Jun 20;12:135.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Papaioannou A, Kennedy CC, Giangregorio L, Ioannidis G, Pritchard J, Hanley DA, Farrauto L, DeBeer J, Adachi JD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>McMaster University, HHSC, St. Peter&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Juravinski Research Centre, 88 Maplewood Avenue Hamilton, ON L8M 1W9, Canada. &lt;a href="mailto:papaioannou@hhsc.ca">papaioannou@hhsc.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There remains uncertainty regarding the appropriate therapeutic management of hip fracture patients. The primary aim of our study was to examine whether large loading doses in addition to daily vitamin D offered any advantage over a simple daily low-dose vitamin D regimen for increasing vitamin D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Variety of vitamin D loading dose recommendations in the UK - 2011</title><link>/posts/variety-of-vitamin-d-loading-dose-recommendations-in-the-uk-2011.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/variety-of-vitamin-d-loading-dose-recommendations-in-the-uk-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;p>East &amp;amp; South East England Specialist Pharmacy Services (August 2011)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>East of England, London, South Central &amp;amp; South East Coast&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="summary-of-variety-in-uk-2011-adults">Summary of variety in UK 2011: Adults&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>{SPLIT(colsize=250|250|200|500)}&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="different-definitions">Different definitions&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="of-deficient">of Deficient&lt;/h4>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Less than&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>1. groups&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>8 nanograms/ml&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>1&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>10 nanograms/ml&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>9&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>12 nanograms/ml&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>1&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>14 nanograms/ml&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>2&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>20 nanograms/ml&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>2&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-oral-to-restock-deficiency">Vitamin D3 oral to restock deficiency&lt;/h4>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Frequency&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Total dose&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>1. groups&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Daily&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>200,000 IU&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>1&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Daily&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>280,000 IU&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>3&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Daily&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>300,000 IU&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>1&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Monthly&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>240,000 IU&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>1&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Monthly&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>600,000 IU&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Monthly&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>720,000 IU&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>2&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Once&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>300,000 IU&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>1&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d2-to-restock">Vitamin D2 to restock&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>did not make a table&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Half of the seniors needed more than 1700 IU vitamin D3 (50000 monthly)</title><link>/posts/half-of-the-seniors-needed-more-than-1700-iu-vitamin-d3-50000-monthly.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/half-of-the-seniors-needed-more-than-1700-iu-vitamin-d3-50000-monthly.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>300,000 IU vitamin D helped seniors in many ways</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-vitamin-d-helped-seniors-in-many-ways.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-vitamin-d-helped-seniors-in-many-ways.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-effect-of-oral-and-parenteral-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-the-elderly-a-prospective-double-blinded-randomized-placebo-controlled-study">The effect of oral and parenteral vitamin D supplementation in the elderly: a prospective, double-blinded, randomized, placebo-controlled study&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Rheumatology International DOI: 10.1007/s00296-011-1943-6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hakan Sakalli, Didem Arslan and Ahmet Eftal Yucel&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypovitaminosis D in the elderly causes falls and fractures as a result of impaired neuromuscular functions and also may be a reason for nonspecific musculosceletal pain. The aim of this study is to investigate the benefits of a single dose per os or parenterally administrated vitamin D on increasing the quality of life and functional mobility and decreasing the pain in the elderly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300000 IU vitamin D monthly may treat MS</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly-may-treat-ms.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-vitamin-d-monthly-may-treat-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="therapeutic-effect-of-vitamin-d3-in-multiple-sclerosis-patients">Therapeutic Effect of Vitamin D3 in Multiple Sclerosis Patients.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Immunol Invest. 2011 May 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mosayebi G, Ghazavi A, Ghasami K, Jand Y, Kokhaei P.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Molecular and Medicine Research Center, Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Arak University of Medical Sciences, Arak, I.R. Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiple sclerosis (MS) is an inflammatory disease in which the myelin sheaths around the axons of the central nervous system are damaged. The damage leads to demyelination and scarring as well as a broad spectrum of signs and symptoms. The epidemiological data suggest a possible influence of vitamin D as an immunomodulatory agent on multiple sclerosis susceptibility as well as on clinical course of the disease. We investigated the effects of short-term vitamin D3 therapy on Iranian patients with MS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>540000 IU before ICU raised vitamin D by 25 ng in 2 days</title><link>/posts/540000-iu-before-icu-raised-vitamin-d-by-25-ng-in-2-days.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/540000-iu-before-icu-raised-vitamin-d-by-25-ng-in-2-days.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-7th-space-interactivehttp7thspacecomheadlines377128short_term_effects_of_high_dose_oral_vitamin_d3_in_critically_ill_vitamin_d_deficient_patients_a_randomized_double_blind_placebo_controlled_pilot_studyhtml--reporting-on-critical-care-2011-15r104">From &lt;a href="http://7thspace.com/headlines/377128/short_term_effects_of_high_dose_oral_vitamin_d3_in_critically_ill_vitamin_d_deficient_patients_a_randomized_double_blind_placebo_controlled_pilot_study.html">7th Space interactive&lt;/a> reporting on Critical Care 2011, 15:R104]&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="short-term-effects-of-high-dose-oral-vitamin-d3-in-critically-ill-vitamin-d-deficient-patients-a-randomized-double-blind-placebo-controlled-pilot-study">Short-term effects of high-dose oral vitamin D3 in critically ill vitamin D deficient patients: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled pilot study&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>IntroductionVitamin D deficiency is encountered frequently in critically ill patients and might be harmful. Current nutrition guidelines recommend very low vitamin D doses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this trial was to evaluate the safety and efficacy of a single oral high-dose vitamin D3 supplementation in an intensive care setting over a one-week observation period.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>300000 IU injection of vitamin D3</title><link>/posts/300000-iu-injection-of-vitamin-d3.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/300000-iu-injection-of-vitamin-d3.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-effect-of-intramuscular-vitamin-d-cholecalciferol-on-serum-25oh-vitamin-d-levels-in-older-female-acute-hospital-admissions">The effect of intramuscular vitamin D (cholecalciferol) on serum 25OH vitamin D levels in older female acute hospital admissions.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ir J Med Sci. 2010 Mar;179(1):57-61. Epub 2009 Aug 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nugent C, Roche K, Wilson S, Fitzgibbon M, Griffin D, Nichaidhin N, Mulkerrin E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine for the Elderly, University College Hospital Galway, Galway, Ireland. &lt;a href="mailto:cathalnugent@gmail.com">cathalnugent@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Many studies have demonstrated the prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency in the older population.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>