<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vision on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/vision.html</link><description>Recent content in Vision on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Macular degeneration 4X more likely if low vitamin D and a particular gene</title><link>/posts/macular-degeneration-4x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-and-a-particular-gene.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/macular-degeneration-4x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-and-a-particular-gene.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="genetics-factor-in-vitamin-d-amd-link">Genetics factor in vitamin D, AMD link&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://ophthalmologytimes.modernmedicine.com/node/369696%20">Ophthalmology Times Staff Reports&lt;/a> MAY 05, 2013&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seattle—Adequate levels of vitamin D can decrease the risk of age-related macular degeneration (AMD), but most markedly in individuals with two risk alleles for the CFH Y402H genotype, said Amy Millen, PhD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Specifically, the association between serum &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> and AMD is modified by the presence of the CFH Y402H polymorphism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Previous studies have shown a relationship between vitamin D and AMD,” said Dr. Millen, assistant professor, Department of Social and Preventive Medicine at the University at Buffalo, New York. “We looked to see if it was modified by the genetic risk of AMD.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Dyslexia and low vitamin D - early 2013</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-dyslexia-and-low-vitamin-d-early-2013.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-dyslexia-and-low-vitamin-d-early-2013.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#could-a-vitamin-d-deficiency-cause-dyslexiahttpwwwontrackreadingcomdyslexia-puzzlevitamin-d3-and-dyslexia-spring-2013">&lt;a href="http://www.ontrackreading.com/dyslexia-puzzle/vitamin-d3-and-dyslexia">Could a Vitamin D Deficiency Cause Dyslexia?&lt;/a> Spring 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#children-with-dyslexia-are-also-usually-deficient-in-zinc-magnesium-vitamin-b12-and-vitamin-d">Children with dyslexia are also usually deficient in Zinc, Magnesium, Vitamin B12 and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="could-a-vitamin-d-deficiency-cause-dyslexiahttpwwwontrackreadingcomdyslexia-puzzlevitamin-d3-and-dyslexia-spring-2013">&lt;a href="http://www.ontrackreading.com/dyslexia-puzzle/vitamin-d3-and-dyslexia">Could a Vitamin D Deficiency Cause Dyslexia?&lt;/a> Spring 2013&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dyslexia is similar to autism&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Dyslexia tends to run in families, as does autism.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Dyslexic children often exhibit developmental delays in motor skills as do autistic children.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Many of the symptoms of dyslexia overlap the symptoms of ADHD, Asperger&amp;rsquo;s and autism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetic Neuropathy sometimes can be reversed by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetic-neuropathy-sometimes-can-be-reversed-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetic-neuropathy-sometimes-can-be-reversed-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="exercise--vitamin-d-400-iu--1-gram-calcium-carbonate-helpes-diabetic-neuropathy-in-many-ways---may-2017">Exercise + Vitamin D (400 IU + 1 gram Calcium Carbonate) helpes Diabetic Neuropathy in many ways - May 2017&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Comparison between Effects of 12 weeks Combined Training and Vitamin D Supplement on Improvement of Sensory-motor Neuropathy in type 2 Diabetic Women.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adv Biomed Res. 2017 May 2;6:55. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4103/2277-9175.205528.">doi: 10.4103/2277-9175.205528.&lt;/a> eCollection 2017.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nadi M1, Marandi SM1, Esfarjani F1, Saleki M2, Mohammadi M3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off Topic: Cataracts can be dissolved away in 6 months</title><link>/posts/off-topic-cataracts-can-be-dissolved-away-in-6-months.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-cataracts-can-be-dissolved-away-in-6-months.html</guid><description>&lt;p>(There does not appear to be any need for vitamin D in the following)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>50% of people get cataracts which impare or totally stop vision by age 80&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those individuals or societies which can afford it cataract surgery has become the standard solution&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately the surgery, while very common, has complications&lt;/p>
&lt;p>about 30% have to be done a second time&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A non-surgical solution was developed in Russia in the 1990&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB has some association with cataracts</title><link>/posts/uvb-has-some-association-with-cataracts.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-has-some-association-with-cataracts.html</guid><description>&lt;p>UVB Is primarily absorbed in front part of your eye (the cornea and the lens)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See also &lt;a href="/posts/cataracts-and-vitamin-d-many-studies" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Cataracts and Vitamin D - many studies">Cataracts and Vitamin D - many studies&lt;/a> 12 as of April 2023&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="world-health-organizationhttpwwwwhointmediacentrefactsheetsfs305enindexhtml20">&lt;a href="http://www.who.int/mediacentre/factsheets/fs305/en/index.html%20">World Health Organization&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Worldwide approximately 18 million people are blind as a result of cataracts,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>of these &lt;strong>5%&lt;/strong> of all cataract related disease burden is directly attributable to &lt;strong>UV radiation&lt;/strong> exposure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Worse diabetic vision is associated with low vitamin D or high PTH</title><link>/posts/worse-diabetic-vision-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-or-high-pth.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/worse-diabetic-vision-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-or-high-pth.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="diabetic-retinopathy-severity-serum-vitamin-d-and-parathormone-pth-concentrations-as-predictors-of-the-development-and-severity-of-diabetic-retinopathy">Diabetic Retinopathy severity Serum vitamin D and parathormone (PTH) concentrations as predictors of the development and severity of diabetic retinopathy&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="alexandria-journal-of-medicine--nov-2012httpwwwajmeorgarticles2090-50681200079-6abstract">&lt;a href="http://www.ajme.org/article/S2090-5068(12)00079-6/abstract">Alexandria Journal of Medicine Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Rania Naguib Abdel Mouteleb Abdel Reheem &lt;a href="mailto:ranianaguib2000@yahoo.com">ranianaguib2000@yahoo.com&lt;/a>, Maaly Abdel Halim Mohamed Abdel Fattah &lt;a href="mailto:mola_73@hotmail.com">mola_73@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 14 April 2012; accepted 24 August 2012. published online 08 October 2012.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D is suggested to be an inhibitor of angiogenesis. The degree of severity of diabetic retinopathy (DR) may be related to serum vitamin D concentration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D might be generated in the eye by UVB</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-might-be-generated-in-the-eye-by-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-might-be-generated-in-the-eye-by-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="enhancement-of-vitamin-d-metabolites-in-the-eye-following-vitamin-d3-supplementation-and-uv-b-irradiation">Enhancement of Vitamin D Metabolites in the Eye Following Vitamin D3 Supplementation and UV-B Irradiation.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Curr Eye Res. 2012 May 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lin Y, Ubels JL, Schotanus MP, Yin Z, Pintea V, Hammock BD, Watsky MA. &lt;a href="mailto:mwatsky@uthsc.edu">mwatsky@uthsc.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Entomology &amp;amp; Cancer Center, University of California , Davis, CA , USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose: This study was designed to measure vitamin D metabolites in the aqueous and vitreous humor and in tear fluid, and to determine if dietary vitamin D3 supplementation affects these levels. We also determined if the corneal epithelium can synthesize vitamin D following UV-B exposure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Macular Degeneration decreased with UV and perhaps Vitamin D genetics</title><link>/posts/macular-degeneration-decreased-with-uv-and-perhaps-vitamin-d-genetics.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/macular-degeneration-decreased-with-uv-and-perhaps-vitamin-d-genetics.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="systems-biology-based-analysis-implicates-a-novel-role-for-vitamin-d-metabolism-in-the-pathogenesis-of-age-related-macular-degeneration">Systems biology-based analysis implicates a novel role for vitamin D metabolism in the pathogenesis of age-related macular degeneration.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Hum Genomics. 2011 Oct;5(6):538-68.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morrison MA, Silveira AC, Huynh N, Jun G, Smith SE, Zacharaki F, Sato H, Loomis S, Andreoli MT, Adams SM, Radeke MJ, Jelcick AS, Yuan Y, Tsiloulis AN, Chatzoulis DZ, Silvestri G, Kotoula MG, Tsironi EE, Hollis BW, Chen R, Haider NB, Miller JW, Farrer LA, Hageman GS, Kim IK, Schaumberg DA, DeAngelis MM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diabetics have more retina problems as they have less vitamin D</title><link>/posts/diabetics-have-more-retina-problems-as-they-have-less-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/diabetics-have-more-retina-problems-as-they-have-less-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-diabetic-retinopathy--sept-2011">Vitamin D Insufficiency in Diabetic Retinopathy – Sept 2011&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocr Pract. 2011 Sep 22:1-18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Payne JF, Ray R, Watson DG, Delille C, Rimler E, Cleveland J, Lynn MJ, Tangpricha V, Srivastava SK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Vitreoretinal Surgery and Disease, Emory University, Atlanta, GA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective: To assess the relationship between vitamin D status and diabetic retinopathy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methods: A clinic-based, cross-sectional study was conducted at Emory University. A total of 221 subjects were classified into five groups based on diabetes status and retinopathy findings:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Macular Degeneration increases risk of hemorrhagic stroke by 6X</title><link>/posts/macular-degeneration-increases-risk-of-hemorrhagic-stroke-by-6x.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/macular-degeneration-increases-risk-of-hemorrhagic-stroke-by-6x.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#age-related-macular-degeneration-and-the-risk-of-stroke--the-rotterdam-study">Age-Related Macular Degeneration and the Risk of Stroke – The Rotterdam Study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#notice-that-both-amd-and-strokecategoriesstroke-are-independently-associated-with-low-vitamin-d">Notice that both AMD and &lt;a href="/categories/stroke">stroke&lt;/a> are independently associated with low vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#wonder-if-lack-of-vitamin-d-might-be-a-common-cause">Wonder if lack of vitamin D might be a common cause&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="age-related-macular-degeneration-and-the-risk-of-stroke--the-rotterdam-study">Age-Related Macular Degeneration and the Risk of Stroke – The Rotterdam Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Renske G. Wieberdink, MD;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lintje Ho, MD;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. Kamran Ikram, MD, PhD;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter J. Koudstaal, MD, PhD;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Albert Hofman, MD, PhD;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paulus T.V.M. de Jong, MD, PhD;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sun exposure reduces Myopia</title><link>/posts/sun-exposure-reduces-myopia.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sun-exposure-reduces-myopia.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="seeing-the-light-why-sun-exposure-may-be-good-for-your-eyeshttpwwwmarksdailyapplecomsunlight-myopia-june-2011-marks-daily-apple">&lt;a href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/sunlight-myopia/">Seeing the Light: Why Sun Exposure May Be Good for Your Eyes&lt;/a> June 2011 Marks Daily Apple&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Huge amount of information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author wants to keep most of the information at his site&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, here are just a few items&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sunlight and circadian rhythm - (do not have bright light at night)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kathryn Rose, points to the weak or inconsistent epidemiology that attempts to link time&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>spent on the computer,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>watching television,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV and macular degeneration</title><link>/posts/uv-and-macular-degeneration.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-and-macular-degeneration.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="two-articles-on-this-page">Two articles on this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="good-2011-review-of-uv-and-blue-light-and-macular-degeneration">Good 2011 review of UV and blue light and macular degeneration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Abstract: Age-related macular degeneration (AMD) is a leading cause of blindness in the western world. The retina is highly susceptible to photo- chemical damage from continuous exposure of light and oxygen. The cornea and the lens block a major portion of the ultraviolet (UV) radiation from reaching the retina (,295 nm). The relationship between UV light exposure and AMD is unclear, although short wavelength radiation and the blue light induce significant oxidative stress to the retinal pigment epithelium. Epi- demiologic evidence indicates a trend toward association between severity of light exposure and AMD. In this review, we discuss type 1 and type 2 photochemical damage that occurs in response to UV exposure. We ex- amine the impact of different doses of exposure to UV radiation and the subsequent production of oxidative stress in AMD. Local and systemic protective mechanisms of the retina including antioxidant enzymes and macular pigments are reviewed. This article provides a review of possible cellular and molecular effects of UV radiation exposure in AMD and potential therapies that may prevent blindness resulting from this disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultraviolet Radiation and the Anterior Eye</title><link>/posts/ultraviolet-radiation-and-the-anterior-eye.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ultraviolet-radiation-and-the-anterior-eye.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eye Contact Lens. 2011 Jun 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coroneo M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Department of Ophthalmology, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The eye is on the one hand dependent on visible light energy and on the other hand can be damaged by these and the contiguous ultraviolet (UV) and infrared wavelengths.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diseases of the eye in which sunlight has been implicated have been termed the ophthalmohelioses, and these conditions pose a significant problem to the eye health of many communities. The ophthalmohelioses have a tremendous impact on patients&amp;rsquo; quality of life and have significant implications on the cost of health care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wear glasses when getting vitamin D from the sun</title><link>/posts/wear-glasses-when-getting-vitamin-d-from-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wear-glasses-when-getting-vitamin-d-from-the-sun.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Macular Degeneration Twin Study – Vitamin D reduced, smoking increased (by 13X in later study)</title><link>/posts/macular-degeneration-twin-study-vitamin-d-reduced-smoking-increased-by-13x-in-later-study.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/macular-degeneration-twin-study-vitamin-d-reduced-smoking-increased-by-13x-in-later-study.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="smoking-dietary-betaine-methionine-and-vitamin-d-in-monozygotic-twins-with-discordant-macular-degeneration-epigenetic-implications">Smoking, Dietary Betaine, Methionine, and Vitamin D in Monozygotic Twins with Discordant Macular Degeneration: Epigenetic Implications.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ophthalmology. 2011 May 25. DOI: 10.1016/j.ophtha.2010.12.020&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seddon JM, Reynolds R, Shah HR, Rosner B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ophthalmic Epidemiology and Genetics Service, New England Eye Center, Tufts Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts; Department of Ophthalmology, Tufts Medical Center, and Tufts University School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: We evaluated monozygotic twin pairs with discordant age-related macular degeneration (AMD) phenotypes to assess differences in behavioral and nutritional factors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D may help prevent macular degeneration in women younger than 75</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-may-help-prevent-macular-degeneration-in-women-younger-than-75.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-may-help-prevent-macular-degeneration-in-women-younger-than-75.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-status-and-early-age-related-macular-degeneration-in-postmenopausal-women">Vitamin D Status and Early Age-Related Macular Degeneration in Postmenopausal Women.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Arch Ophthalmol. 2011 Apr;129(4):481-489.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Millen AE, Voland R, Sondel SA, Parekh N, Horst RL, Wallace RB, Hageman GS, Chappell R, Blodi BA, Klein ML, Gehrs KM, Sarto GE, Mares JA; for the CAREDS Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Social and Preventive Medicine, University at Buffalo, Ferber Hall 240, Buffalo, NY 14214. &lt;a href="mailto:aemillen@buffal.edu">aemillen@buffal.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D) concentrations (nmol/L) and the prevalence of early age-related macular degeneration (AMD) was investigated in participants of the Carotenoids in Age-Related Eye Disease Study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Probable relationship between myopia and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/probable-relationship-between-myopia-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/probable-relationship-between-myopia-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-vdr-and-group-specific-component-gc-vitamin-d-binding-protein-polymorphisms-in-myopia">Vitamin D Receptor (VDR) and Group-specific Component (GC, Vitamin D Binding Protein) Polymorphisms in Myopia.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2011 Feb 25&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mutti DO, Cooper ME, Dragan E, Jones-Jordan LA, Bailey MD, Marazita ML, Murray JC, Zadnik K; the CLEERE Study Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Ohio State University, College of Optometry, Columbus, OH 43210;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose. Epidemiologic evidence indicates that time outdoors reduces the risk of myopia onset, suggesting a possible role for vitamin D. We conducted a case-control study to determine whether single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) within VDR at 12q13.11 and GC at 4q12-13 were associated with myopia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Myopia may be related to low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/myopia-may-be-related-to-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/myopia-may-be-related-to-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Many studies have found Myopia associated with Vitamin D and some of its cofactors - Mg and Zinc&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Possibly: Less vitamin D ( or cofactors which increase Vitamin D getting to cells)&lt;br>
    ==&amp;gt; less muscle tone ==&amp;gt; eye muscle not as strong&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The rest of this page are studies of Vitamin D/Sun and Myopia&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#myopia-2x-more-likely-if-both-parents-had-myopia-genetics">Myopia 2X more likely if both parents had myopia (genetics?)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#google-search-of-myopia--vitamin-d-4800-hits-june-2022---3-examples">Google Search of Myopia &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Vitamin D&amp;rdquo; 4,800 hits June 2022 - 3 examples&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#myopia-3-percent-less-likely-per-extra-1-ng-vitamin-d--may-2018">Myopia 3 percent less likely per extra 1 ng vitamin D – May 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#myopia-2x-more-likely-if-have-less-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d--june-2014">Myopia 2X more likely if have less than 20 ng of vitamin D – June 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#myopia-in-chickens-reduced-by-flashing-light-myopia-may-not-be-due-to-low-vitamin-d">Myopia (in chickens) reduced by flashing light (myopia may not be due to low vitamin D)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#high-myopia-strongly-associated-with-lowest-vitamin-d-level---april-2014">High myopia strongly associated with lowest vitamin D level - April 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#blood-levels-of-vitamin-d-in-teens-and-young-adults-with-myopia">Blood levels of vitamin D in teens and young adults with myopia.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vdr-problems-associated-with-2x-increase-risk-of-myopia---2011">VDR problems associated with 2X increase risk of Myopia - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#myopia-a-world-tourhttpjplagaceodwordpresscomcategorymyopia-2">&lt;a href="http://jplagaceod.wordpress.com/category/myopia-2/">Myopia: a world tour&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#extra-40-minutes-outdoors-daily-30-incidence-of-myopia-vs-40-if-not-outdoors---rct-2015">Extra 40 minutes outdoors daily: 30% incidence of myopia vs 40% if not outdoors - RCT 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="myopia-2x-more-likely-if-both-parents-had-myopia-genetics">Myopia 2X more likely if both parents had myopia (genetics?)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.appelbaumvision.com/myopia-control">Myopia Control Program&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>