<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forms of Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/forms-of-vitamin-d/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forms of Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/forms-of-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D can be inside of a “trojan horse” nanoball made of folate, Cancer cells attrack folate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-can-be-inside-of-a-trojan-horse-nanoball-made-of-folate-cancer-cells-attrack-folate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-can-be-inside-of-a-trojan-horse-nanoball-made-of-folate-cancer-cells-attrack-folate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;smart-drug-delivery-strategies-for-vitamin-d3-to-cancercells&#34;&gt;Smart Drug Delivery Strategies for Vitamin D3 to Cancer Cells&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IntechOpen DOI: 10.5772/intechopen.114083&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ricky Madison&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Revolutionizing cancer treatment and improving patient outcomes could be achieved through the development of smart drug delivery strategies for Vitamin D3 in cancer cells. Smart drug delivery strategies are crucial in administering Vitamin D3 to cancer cells with high specificity, efficacy, and minimal side effects. One unconventional method for smart drug delivery of Vitamin D3 in cancer cells is gene therapy - a cutting-edge technology that could alter the course of cancer treatment. Vitamin D3 is renowned for its anti-cancer properties, and its targeted delivery to cancer cells is paramount for successful treatment. In conclusion, smart drug delivery strategies have demonstrated significant potential in transporting Vitamin D3 to cancer cells with high specificity, efficacy, and minimal side effects. Nanocarriers such as liposomes, nanoparticles, and dendrimers possess unique characteristics that make them ideal for Vitamin D3 delivery. These carriers can precisely target cancer cells, discharge Vitamin D3 solely in the cancerous environment, and reduce the harmful effects on healthy cells. Gene therapy is a potential alternative to conventional drug delivery methods, paving the way for a brighter future in cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fat-soluble Vitamins go thru the slow lymph system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fat-soluble-vitamins-go-thru-the-slow-lymph-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fat-soluble-vitamins-go-thru-the-slow-lymph-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;some-vitamin-d-in-gut-goes-thru-the-lymph-system-radioactive-tracing---may-1984&#34;&gt;Some Vitamin D in gut goes thru the lymph system (radioactive tracing) - May 1984&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lymphatic absorption and transport of retinol and vitamin D-3 from rat intestine. Evidence for different pathways&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biochim Biophys Acta. 1984 May 16;772(2):109-16. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/0005-2736&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/0005-2736&lt;/a&gt;(84)90033-6.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;R Blomhoff, P Helgerud, S Dueland, T Berg, J I Pedersen, K R Norum, C A Drevon&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lymphatic absorption and transport of retinol and vitamin D-3 from rat intestine has been studied. When rats were cannulated in the intestinal lymph duct and given an intraduodenal bolus of &lt;span&gt;[3H]&lt;/span&gt;retinol and 14C-labelled vitamin D-3, 14C-labeled vitamin D-3 appeared later in the intestinal lymph than &lt;span&gt;[3H]&lt;/span&gt;retinol and the rate of absorption of vitamin D-3 was still maximal at a time when that of retinol had declined. Both vitamins were absorbed via the lymphatic route in association with  &lt;strong&gt;chylomicrons&lt;/strong&gt; . Almost all the retinol was esterified, while vitamin D-3 appeared in the chylomicrons as free vitamin D-3. In vitro incubations and in vivo studies using hepatectomized and normal rats showed that the retinyl ester was a relatively nonexchangeable component of the chylomicrons and their remnants. Hence, all the vitamin A followed the remnants in their clearance from plasma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microencapsulated Vitamin D better than oil-based in 6 ways</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/microencapsulated-vitamin-d-better-than-oil-based-in-6-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/microencapsulated-vitamin-d-better-than-oil-based-in-6-ways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;benefits-of-using-a-microencapsulated-vitamin-d-delivery-system-in-women-with-polycystic-ovary-syndrome---sept-2023&#34;&gt;Benefits of using a microencapsulated vitamin D delivery system in women with polycystic ovary syndrome - Sept 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eur J Hosp Pharm. 2023 Sep;30(5):284-287. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1136/ejhpharm-2021-002967&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1136/ejhpharm-2021-002967&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;   PDF behind paywall until Sept 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vesselina Yanachkova 1, Radiana Staynova 2, Svetoslav Stoev 3, Emilia Naseva 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objective: To compare and assess the efficacy of two vitamin D delivery systems (oil-based and microencapsulated) on 25-hydroxy-vitamin D (25(OH)D) levels, body mass index (BMI) and insulin resistance (IR) in women with established polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) and vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sucrosomia Vitamin D appears to be 2 X more bio-available– RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sucrosomia-vitamin-d-appears-to-be-2-x-more-bio-available-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sucrosomia-vitamin-d-appears-to-be-2-x-more-bio-available-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: Horizontal axis IS NOT linear&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-comparative-absorption-study-of-sucrosomial-orodispersible-vitamin-d3-supplementation-vs-a-reference-chewable-tablet-and-soft-gel-capsule-vitamin-d3-in-improving-circulatory-25ohd-levels-in-healthy-adults-with-vitamin-d-deficiencyresults-from-a-prospective-randomized-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;A comparative absorption study of sucrosomial® orodispersible vitamin D3 supplementation vs. a reference chewable tablet and soft gel capsule vitamin D3 in improving circulatory 25(OH)D levels in healthy adults with vitamin D deficiency—Results from a prospective randomized clinical trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front. Nutr., 17 August 2023 Volume 10 - 2023 | &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2023.1221685&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2023.1221685&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aasiya Bano1† Saida Abrar2† Elisa Brilli3 Germano Tarantino3 Ali Akbar Bugti4 Marco Fabbrini5 Gabriele Conti5 Silvia Turroni5 Mahroo Bugti6 Fauzia Afridi7 Shah Mureed8 Hakeem Zada9 Ikram Din Ujjan10 Saadia Ashraf11 Aamir Ghafoor12 Saeed Khan13 Amjad Khan14,15*&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D: liposomal and nanoemulsion forms - Chat-GPT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-liposomal-and-nanoemulsion-forms-chat-gpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-liposomal-and-nanoemulsion-forms-chat-gpt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;comparing-liposomal-and-nanoemulsion-forms-of-vitamin-d-involves-looking-at-their-absorption-efficacy-and-overallbenefits---chat-gpt&#34;&gt;Comparing liposomal and nanoemulsion forms of Vitamin D involves looking at their absorption, efficacy, and overall benefits - Chat-GPT&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Absorption and Bioavailability&lt;/strong&gt; :&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liposomal Vitamin D&lt;/strong&gt; : Liposomes are tiny vesicles that can encapsulate nutrients, improving their stability and absorption. The liposomal form of Vitamin D is designed to bypass the digestive system, allowing for direct absorption into the bloodstream. This may enhance the bioavailability of Vitamin D, making it more effective at raising blood levels of the vitamin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Olive oil problem with Vitamin D (again)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/olive-oil-problem-with-vitamin-d-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/olive-oil-problem-with-vitamin-d-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-response-to-vitamin-d-supplementation-using-different-lipid-delivery-systems-in-middle-aged-and-older-adults-a-randomised-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D response to vitamin D supplementation using different lipid delivery systems in middle-aged and older adults: a randomised controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Br J Nutr . 2023 Nov 14;130(9):1548-1557. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0007114523000636&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1017/S0007114523000636&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aislinn F McCourt 1, Steven L Mulrooney 1, Graham J O&amp;rsquo;Neill 2, E Dolores O&amp;rsquo;Riordan 1, Aifric M O&amp;rsquo;Sullivan 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;olive-not-as-good-as-coconut-if-already-have-sufficient-vitamin-d&#34;&gt;Olive not as good as coconut if already have sufficient Vitamin D&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Food fortification improves vitamin D intakes but is not yet mandated in many countries. Combining vitamin D with different dietary lipids altered vitamin D absorption in in vitro and postprandial studies. This randomised, placebo-controlled trial examined the effect of the lipid composition of a vitamin D-fortified dairy drink on change in 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentrations. Sixty-three healthy adults aged 50+ years were randomised to one of the following for 4 weeks: vitamin D-fortified olive oil dairy drink, vitamin D-fortified coconut oil dairy drink, vitamin D supplement or placebo control dairy drink. All vitamin D groups received 20 µg of vitamin D3 daily. Serum was collected at baseline and post-intervention to measure 25(OH)D concentrations and biomarkers of metabolic health. Repeated-measures general linear model ANCOVA (RM GLM ANCOVA) compared changes over time. There was a significant time × treatment interaction effect on 25(OH)D concentrations for those classified as vitamin D-insufficient (P &amp;lt; 0·001) and -sufficient at baseline (P = 0·004). 25(OH)D concentrations increased significantly for all insufficient participants receiving vitamin D3 in any form. However, for vitamin D-sufficient participants at baseline, 25(OH)D concentrations only increased significantly with the coconut oil dairy drink and supplement. There was no effect of vitamin D on biomarkers of metabolic health. Vitamin D fortification of lipid-containing foods may be used in lieu of supplementation when supplement adherence is low or for individuals with dysphagia. These results are important given the recent recommendation to increase vitamin D intakes to 15-20 µg for older adults in Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D which dissolves in mouth for those having poor response due to poor guts, HSCT etc.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-which-dissolves-in-mouth-for-those-having-poor-response-due-to-poor-guts-hsct-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-which-dissolves-in-mouth-for-those-having-poor-response-due-to-poor-guts-hsct-etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;optimized-vitamin-d-repletion-in-refractory-patients-undergoing-stem-cell-transplant-with-oral-thin-film-cholecalciferol&#34;&gt;Optimized Vitamin D Repletion in Refractory Patients Undergoing Stem Cell Transplant with Oral Thin Film Cholecalciferol&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blood Adv. 2023 Jun 7;bloodadvances.2023009855. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1182/bloodadvances.2023009855&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1182/bloodadvances.2023009855&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Allison L Bartlett &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Allison.bartlett@cchmc.org&#34;&gt;Allison.bartlett@cchmc.org&lt;/a&gt; 1, Grace Zhang 2, Gregory Wallace 3, Stacie McLean 3, Kasiani C Myers 1, Ashley Teusink-Cross 3, Cynthia Taggart 4, Bhaumik Patel 5, Robert Davidson 5, Stella M Davies 1, Sonata Jodele 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1Division of Bone Marrow Transplantation and Immune Deficiency, Cincinnati Children’s Hospital Medical Center, Cincinnati, OH&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People allergic to Lanolin should not be allergic to vegan Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/people-allergic-to-lanolin-should-not-be-allergic-to-vegan-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/people-allergic-to-lanolin-should-not-be-allergic-to-vegan-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;lanolin-gets-nod-for-allergen-of-the-year&#34;&gt;Lanolin gets nod for Allergen of the Year&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdedge.com/dermatology/article/261868/contact-dermatitis/lanolin-gets-nod-allergen-year?ecd=WNL_EVE_230320_mdedge&#34;&gt;MDedge March 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;“From my perspective, this was a timely year to think about lanolin, as there is significant ongoing controversy about whether it is allergenic,” Dr. Jenkins said in an interview. “Numerous companies market lanolin-containing topicals as safe and effective emollients,” she said.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Notably, modern wool textiles do not contain lanolin, and lanolin-allergic patients need not avoid wool, Dr. Belsito added.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
