<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>High-Dose on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/high-dose.html</link><description>Recent content in High-Dose on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/high-dose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Many hints that vitamin D megadoses cure some diseases</title><link>/posts/many-hints-that-vitamin-d-megadoses-cure-some-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-hints-that-vitamin-d-megadoses-cure-some-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Unaware of any studies of meg-doses of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="there-have-been-several-indications-that-getting-lots-of-vitamin-d--20000-iu-daily-can-cure-some-diseases">There have been several indications that getting lots of vitamin D (&amp;gt; 20,000 IU daily) can cure some diseases&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/appears-that-vitamin-d-can-induce-remission-in-recent-multiple-sclerosis">Appears that Vitamin D can induce remission in recent Multiple Sclerosis&lt;/a> 1,000 patients 20,000 IU to 140,000 IU daily&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/dr-cannell-on-autism-spring-2013">Dr. Cannell on Autism – Spring 2013&lt;/a> 3 moms accidentally gave 60,000 IU daily - rapid recovery from Autism&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://pandemicsurvivor.com/2009/06/28/a-tale-of-two-women/">ovarian cancer had metastasized, give only months to live, internal bleeding&lt;/a> 50,000 IU daily for 3 months&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>70 percent of people with IBS had symptoms relieved with high dose vitamin D – 2012</title><link>/posts/70-percent-of-people-with-ibs-had-symptoms-relieved-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-2012.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/70-percent-of-people-with-ibs-had-symptoms-relieved-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-as-a-novel-treatment-for-irritable-bowel-syndrome-single-case-leads-to-critical-analysis-of-patient-centred-data">Vitamin D3 as a novel treatment for irritable bowel syndrome: single case leads to critical analysis of patient-centred data&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMJ Case Reports 2012; doi:10.1136/bcr-2012-007223&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eleanor F Sprake,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vicky A Grant,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bernard M Corfe &lt;a href="mailto:b.m.corfe@sheffield.ac.uk">b.m.corfe@sheffield.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Molecular Gastroenterology Research Group, Academic Unit of Surgical Oncology, Department of Oncology, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is a chronic and debilitating functional disorder of the gastrointestinal tract with serious and detrimental impacts on quality of life. Its aetiology is largely unknown and the identification of effective management strategies remains far from complete. This paper first reports, a case of a 41-year-old woman IBS sufferer who reported significant symptom improvements with high-dose vitamin D3 supplementation. The sufferer identified a &lt;strong>substantial body of patient data surrounding this potential therapy on social media sites&lt;/strong> , and this paper, therefore, also reports the findings from a systematic analysis of patient-centred, internet-based data surrounding this phenomenon. Data from 37 IBS sufferers commenting on the effect of vitamin D supplementation on their condition were located; approximately &lt;strong>70% of these reported that high-dose supplementation improved their IBS symptoms.&lt;/strong> A randomised controlled trial into the effect of vitamin D supplementation on IBS symptomatology to test this association scientifically is merited.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>