<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>High-Dose on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/high-dose.html</link><description>Recent content in High-Dose on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/high-dose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hospital ICU added high dose vitamin D - malpractice lawsuit costs dropped from 26 million dollars to ZERO</title><link>/posts/hospital-icu-added-high-dose-vitamin-d-malpractice-lawsuit-costs-dropped-from-26-dollars-to-zero.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hospital-icu-added-high-dose-vitamin-d-malpractice-lawsuit-costs-dropped-from-26-dollars-to-zero.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-short-essay-high-dose-vitamin-d-supplementation-reduces-medical-malpractice-lawsuits-in-critically-ill-trauma-patients">A Short Essay: High Dose Vitamin D Supplementation Reduces Medical Malpractice Lawsuits in Critically ILL Trauma Patients&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Medical Research Archives, Vol. 4, Issue 7, November 2016 &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.18103/mra.v4i7.868">http://dx.doi.org/10.18103/mra.v4i7.868&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>L. Ray Matthews&lt;/strong> , M.D., FACS 1, Yusuf Ahmed, M.D. 2, Keren Bashan-Gilzenrat, M.D. 1, Jonathan Nguyen, M.D.1, Adatee Okonkwo, M.D. 1, Diane Dennis-Griggs, NP 1, Nekeisha Prayor, NP 1, Kenneth Wilson, M.D., FACS 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morehouse School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA 1;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sidra Medical and Research Center, Doha, Saudi Arabia 2;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High dose vitamin D (20,000 IU per kg of feed) safe for pigs</title><link>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-d-20000-iu-per-kg-of-feed-safe-for-pigs.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-d-20000-iu-per-kg-of-feed-safe-for-pigs.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="tolerance-evaluation-of-overdosed-dietary-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-in-growing-piglets">Tolerance evaluation of overdosed dietary levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 in growing piglets.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr (Berl). 2015 Aug 6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/jpn.12355">doi: 10.1111/jpn.12355&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>von Rosenberg SJ1, Weber GM2, Erhardt A1, Höller U2, Wehr UA1, Rambeck WA1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forty-eight, cross-bred (GL × LW × P) piglets were used in a 42-day tolerance trial to assess the effects of feeding diets supplemented with vitamin D or increasing levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25-OH-D3 ). Six-week-old piglets (24 castrate males, 24 females) were used. Two replicate groups of 6 piglets were randomized by weight and allocated to four dietary treatments. The control group (T1) was supplemented with 50 μg vitamin D3 /kg feed. The experimental groups received 25-OH-D3 at the recommended dose (T2: 50 μg/kg = 1x), at 250 μg/kg (T3: 5x) or at 500 μg/kg (T4: 10x) respectively. Feed intake and daily weight gain were measured weekly, and the animals were examined by a veterinarian daily. After 42 days, body mass, blood, urine, bone and tissue samples were analysed and a pathology examination conducted. Dietary treatments had no significant effect on final body mass or daily weight gain. The 25-OH-D3 plasma concentration in T1 was 17 ± 3 ng/ml (mean ± SD) while the respective values of the experimental groups were significantly increased in T2, T3 and T4. Tissue concentrations of 25-OH-D3 were higher in liver and muscle for T3 and T4 and in skin for T4 than in T1. However, neither gross pathology nor histology, nor blood and urine characteristics, nor bone parameters were affected by dietary treatments. Weight of organs as well as dry matter, ash and calcium content of kidneys remained unaffected by dietary 25-OH-D3 intake. Furthermore, no changes were observed for general indicators of health. The results of this study demonstrated that feeding piglets with 25-OH-D3 at 5 or 10 times the recommended level had no adverse effects on any of the biological parameters measured. It was concluded that 25-OH-D3 can be regarded as a supplement with a very high safety margin when used at the recommended level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High dose vitamin reduced pain of fibromyalgia, osteoarthritis, and rheumatoid arthritis</title><link>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-reduced-pain-of-fibromyalgia-osteoarthritis-and-rheumatoid-arthritis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-reduced-pain-of-fibromyalgia-osteoarthritis-and-rheumatoid-arthritis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gene activation by high dose vitamin D - both quick and long term</title><link>/posts/gene-activation-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-both-quick-and-long-term.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gene-activation-by-high-dose-vitamin-d-both-quick-and-long-term.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kidney disease helped by active or high dose Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/kidney-disease-helped-by-active-or-high-dose-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kidney-disease-helped-by-active-or-high-dose-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-beneficial-impact-of-vitamin-d-treatment-in-ckd-patients-whats-next---editorial-comment">The beneficial impact of vitamin D treatment in CKD patients: what&amp;rsquo;s next? - Editorial Comment&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Clin Kidney J (2015) 8:38-40 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ckj/sfu135">doi: 10.1093/ckj/sfu135&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) have markedly higher rates of severe vitamin D deficiency and reduced ability to convert 25-(OH)vitamin D into the active form, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. In the setting of CKD, secondary hyperparathyroidism develops as a consequence of reduced renal production of active vitamin D and phosphate retention resulting in hypocalcaemia and hyperpho- sphataemia. This is a process that is dangerously linked with metabolic bone disease, arterial calcifications and cardiovascular mortality &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>. Therefore, the conventional rationale for vitamin D treatment in CKD is to slow the progression of secondary hyperparathyroidism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Can get 50,000 IU Vitamin D anywhere on the globe</title><link>/posts/can-get-50000-iu-vitamin-d-anywhere-on-the-globe.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/can-get-50000-iu-vitamin-d-anywhere-on-the-globe.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#international-shipping-from-the-us-of-vitamin-d-include">International Shipping from the US of vitamin D include:&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#amazon--often-does-not-ship-health-products-out-of-the-country">Amazon often does not ship health products out of the country.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#many-amazon-products-can-be-sent-to-many-countries-unsure-about-health-products">Many Amazon products can be sent to many countries (unsure about health products)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#amazon-and-non-amazon-can-be-forwarded-to-many-countries">Amazon AND non-Amazon can be forwarded to many countries&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="international-shipping-from-the-us-of-vitamin-d-include">International Shipping from the US of vitamin D include:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.biotechpharmacal.com/catalog/category/vitamin-d/">Bio-Tech Pharmacal&lt;/a> my trusted favorite for vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.swansonvitamins.com/q?kw=%22vitamin+d%22%20">Swanson’s Vitamins&lt;/a> I often used them&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://search.puritan.com/search?view=grid&amp;amp;w=%22vitamin+d%22&amp;amp;x=0&amp;amp;y=0">Puritan Vitamin&lt;/a> often sells vitamin D at a loss, &lt;a href="http://www.puritan.com/house/helpcenter.asp?icid=ros-_-footer-_-IntlShipping#InternationalShipments">International Shipping information&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cluster headaches virtually eliminated in 7,000 people with high-dose vitamin D and cofactors</title><link>/posts/cluster-headaches-virtually-eliminated-in-7000-people-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-and-cofactors.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cluster-headaches-virtually-eliminated-in-7000-people-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-and-cofactors.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="fda-approved-cluster-headache-drug-in-spring-2019">FDA approved Cluster Headache drug in Spring 2019&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>$550/mo only slightly better than placebo, major side effects, &lt;a href="https://dgalerts.docguide.com/first-treatment-approved-fda-episodic-cluster-headache?nl_ref=newsletter&amp;amp;pk_campaign=newsletter&amp;amp;nl_eventid=29908%20">News Release&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Emgality experienced 8.7 fewer weekly cluster headache attacks than they did at baseline, compared to 5.2 fewer attacks for patients on placebo. &amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Emgality is given by patient self-injection. It was first approved by the FDA in September 2018 for the preventive treatment of migraine in adults. The FDA granted the approval of Emgality to Eli Lilly. &amp;quot;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many hints that vitamin D megadoses cure some diseases</title><link>/posts/many-hints-that-vitamin-d-megadoses-cure-some-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-hints-that-vitamin-d-megadoses-cure-some-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Unaware of any studies of meg-doses of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="there-have-been-several-indications-that-getting-lots-of-vitamin-d--20000-iu-daily-can-cure-some-diseases">There have been several indications that getting lots of vitamin D (&amp;gt; 20,000 IU daily) can cure some diseases&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/appears-that-vitamin-d-can-induce-remission-in-recent-multiple-sclerosis">Appears that Vitamin D can induce remission in recent Multiple Sclerosis&lt;/a> 1,000 patients 20,000 IU to 140,000 IU daily&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/dr-cannell-on-autism-spring-2013">Dr. Cannell on Autism – Spring 2013&lt;/a> 3 moms accidentally gave 60,000 IU daily - rapid recovery from Autism&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://pandemicsurvivor.com/2009/06/28/a-tale-of-two-women/">ovarian cancer had metastasized, give only months to live, internal bleeding&lt;/a> 50,000 IU daily for 3 months&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>70 percent of people with IBS had symptoms relieved with high dose vitamin D – 2012</title><link>/posts/70-percent-of-people-with-ibs-had-symptoms-relieved-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-2012.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/70-percent-of-people-with-ibs-had-symptoms-relieved-with-high-dose-vitamin-d-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-as-a-novel-treatment-for-irritable-bowel-syndrome-single-case-leads-to-critical-analysis-of-patient-centred-data">Vitamin D3 as a novel treatment for irritable bowel syndrome: single case leads to critical analysis of patient-centred data&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMJ Case Reports 2012; doi:10.1136/bcr-2012-007223&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eleanor F Sprake,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vicky A Grant,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bernard M Corfe &lt;a href="mailto:b.m.corfe@sheffield.ac.uk">b.m.corfe@sheffield.ac.uk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Molecular Gastroenterology Research Group, Academic Unit of Surgical Oncology, Department of Oncology, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is a chronic and debilitating functional disorder of the gastrointestinal tract with serious and detrimental impacts on quality of life. Its aetiology is largely unknown and the identification of effective management strategies remains far from complete. This paper first reports, a case of a 41-year-old woman IBS sufferer who reported significant symptom improvements with high-dose vitamin D3 supplementation. The sufferer identified a &lt;strong>substantial body of patient data surrounding this potential therapy on social media sites&lt;/strong> , and this paper, therefore, also reports the findings from a systematic analysis of patient-centred, internet-based data surrounding this phenomenon. Data from 37 IBS sufferers commenting on the effect of vitamin D supplementation on their condition were located; approximately &lt;strong>70% of these reported that high-dose supplementation improved their IBS symptoms.&lt;/strong> A randomised controlled trial into the effect of vitamin D supplementation on IBS symptomatology to test this association scientifically is merited.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>