<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer - After Diagnosis on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer---after-diagnosis.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer - After Diagnosis on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer---after-diagnosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cancer Chemotherapy and vitamin D – Review</title><link>/posts/cancer-chemotherapy-and-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-chemotherapy-and-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-pharmacokinetics-and-safety-when-used-in-conjunction-with-the-pharmaceutical-drugs-used-in-cancer-patients-a-systematic-review">Vitamin D: Pharmacokinetics and Safety When Used in Conjunction with the Pharmaceutical Drugs Used in Cancer Patients: A Systematic Review&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancers 2013, 5(1), 255-280; doi:10.3390/cancers5010255&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deborah A. Kennedy 1 , Kieran Cooley 1 , Becky Skidmore 1 Heidi Fritz 1 , Tara Campbell 1 email and Dugald Seely 1,2, &lt;a href="mailto:dseely@ccnm.edu">dseely@ccnm.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Canadian College of Naturopathic Medicine, 1255 Sheppard Avenue East, Toronto, Ontario, M2K 1E2, Canada 2 Ottawa Integrative Cancer Centre, 29 Bayswater Avenue, Ottawa, Ontario, K1Y 2E5, Canada&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer with bisphosphonates was not helped by 200 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cancer-with-bisphosphonates-was-not-helped-by-200-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-with-bisphosphonates-was-not-helped-by-200-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-oncology-patients--an-ignored-condition">Vitamin D deficiency in oncology patients&amp;ndash;an ignored condition:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="impact-on-hypocalcemia-and-quality-of-life">impact on hypocalcemia and quality of life.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Isr Med Assoc J. 2012 Oct;14(10):607-12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency in oncology patients&amp;ndash;an ignored condition: impact on hypocalcemia and quality of life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Segal E, Felder S, Haim N, Yoffe-Sheinman H, Peer A, Wollner M, Shen-Or Z, Ish-Shalom S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Metabolic Bone Diseases Unit, Rambam Health Care Campus, Haifa, Israel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D status is not evaluated routinely in cancer patients with bone metastasis who are treated with bisphosphonates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer - After diagnosis</title><link>/posts/cancer-after-diagnosis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-after-diagnosis.html</guid><description>&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>                  &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">click on chart for details&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="40-less-cancer-recurrence-after-breast-cancer-surgery-if-no-radiation-treatment---dec-2023">40% less Cancer recurrence after Breast Cancer surgery if NO radiation treatment - Dec 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.mdedge.com/hematology-oncology/article/266920/breast-cancer/compelling-case-skipping-rt-some-early-breast?ecd=WNL_EVE_231207_mdedge">Compelling case for skipping RT in some early breast cancers - MD Edge&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Recurrence rate: 1% in 5 years if no radiation therapy vs 1.7% if radiation therapy&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Omitting radiation therapy led to better health-related quality of life and functional and cosmetic outcomes, and the women viewed not having radiation as highly acceptable and appropriate treatment, not undertreatment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer medicine pain reduced with 4300 IU vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-medicine-pain-reduced-with-4300-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-medicine-pain-reduced-with-4300-iu-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="highlight-from-vitamin-d-may-help-breast-cancer-survivors-stay-on-track-httpwwwmedscapecomviewarticle76627320medscape-medical-news">Highlight from &lt;a href="http://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/766273%20">Vitamin D May Help Breast Cancer Survivors Stay on Track &lt;/a>Medscape Medical News&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>2012 Annual Meeting of the American Society of Clinical Oncology®&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>aromatase inhibitors&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>half of the women have severe musculoskeletal pain from these agents, and 18% to 30% report fatigue, &lt;span>[resulting in]&lt;/span> a discontinuation rate of about 10% each year,&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>30,000 IU of oral vitamin D3 weekly on starting letrozole therapy achieved significant benefits in terms of fatigue, joint pain, and disability from joint pain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2000 IU of vitamin D reduced fatigue of advanced cancer – RCT</title><link>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-fatigue-of-advanced-cancer-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-reduced-fatigue-of-advanced-cancer-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-supplementation-to-improve-fatigue-in-patients-with-advanced-cancer">Vitamin D3 supplementation to improve fatigue in patients with advanced cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology, 2012 ASCO Annual Meeting Proceedings (Post-Meeting Edition).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol 30, No 15_suppl (May 20 Supplement), 2012: 9097&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2012 American Society of Clinical Oncology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dragan Trivanovic, Stjepko Plestina, Renata Dobrilla-Dintinjana, Lorena Honovic, Lems Jerin and Irena Hrstic&lt;/p>
&lt;p>General Hospital Pula, Pula, Croatia; University Hospital Centre Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia; Internal Clinic, Rijeka, Croatia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Fatigue is one of the most common symptoms of patients diagnosed with cancer. Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with an increased risk of mortality in oncology patients. We conducted a prospective vitamin D (cholecalciferol) supplementation study to analyse the response to oral D3 supplementation on fatigue in this population of chemo-naïve patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels dropped 3 ng during cancer chemotherapy</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-dropped-3-ng-during-cancer-chemotherapy.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-dropped-3-ng-during-cancer-chemotherapy.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="variations-in-serum-vitamin-d-status-during-cancer-chemotherapy">Variations in serum vitamin D status during cancer chemotherapy.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Clinical Oncology, 2012 ASCO Annual Meeting Proceedings (Post-Meeting Edition).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol 30, No 15_suppl (May 20 Supplement), 2012: e19550&lt;/p>
&lt;p>© 2012 American Society of Clinical Oncology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bogda Koczwara, Richard John Woodman, Laisa Vicki Teleni, Michael Kimlin, Euan Thomas Walpole, Kunal Jain, Christos Stelios Karapetis, Emma-Louise Smith, Wendy Louise Davidson, Maree Ferguson, Shawgi Sukumaran, Ganessan Kichenadasse and Elizabeth Isenring&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Flinders University of South Australia and Flinders Medical Centre, Bedford Park, Australia; Flinders University, Adelaide, Australia;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>85 percent less risk of death from Breast Cancer when vitamin D levels higher than 30 ng</title><link>/posts/85-percent-less-risk-of-death-from-breast-cancer-when-vitamin-d-levels-higher-than-30-ng.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/85-percent-less-risk-of-death-from-breast-cancer-when-vitamin-d-levels-higher-than-30-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-status-at-breast-cancer-diagnosis-correlation-with-tumor-characteristics-disease-outcome-and-genetic-determinants-of-vitamin-d-insufficiency">Vitamin D status at breast cancer diagnosis: correlation with tumor characteristics, disease outcome and genetic determinants of vitamin D insufficiency&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Carcinogenesis (2012), &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/carcin/bgs187">doi: 10.1093/carcin/bgs187&lt;/a>; Received November 29, 2011; First published online: May 23, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sigrid Hatse*,1, Diether Lambrechts2, Annemieke Verstuyf3, Ann Smeets4, Barbara Brouwers1, Thijs Vandorpe4, Olivier Brouckaert4, Gilian Peuteman2, Annouschka Laenen5, Lieve Verlinden3, Carsten Kriebitzsch3, Anne-Sophie Dieudonné4, Robert Paridaens4, Patrick Neven4, Marie-Rose Christiaens4, Roger Bouillon3 and Hans Wildiers1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Catholic University Leuven and University Hospitals, Laboratory of Experimental Oncology and Department of General Medical Oncology, Leuven, Belgium&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D after breast cancer diagnosis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-after-breast-cancer-diagnosis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-after-breast-cancer-diagnosis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#how-important-is-vitamin-d-before-and-after-breast-cancer-diagnosishttpfoodforbreastcancercomarticleshow-important-is-vitamin-d-before-and-after-breast-cancer-diagnosis3f">&lt;a href="http://foodforbreastcancer.com/articles/how-important-is-vitamin-d-before-and-after-breast-cancer-diagnosis%3F">How important is Vitamin D before and after breast cancer diagnosis?&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="how-important-is-vitamin-d-before-and-after-breast-cancer-diagnosishttpfoodforbreastcancercomarticleshow-important-is-vitamin-d-before-and-after-breast-cancer-diagnosis3f">&lt;a href="http://foodforbreastcancer.com/articles/how-important-is-vitamin-d-before-and-after-breast-cancer-diagnosis%3F">How important is Vitamin D before and after breast cancer diagnosis?&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>From Food For Breast Cancer - unknown date: sometime before May 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following text copy does not contain the hyperlinks&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D regulates the flow of calcium into the bloodstream and is crucial for normal bone development. Vitamin D also has a role in regulating parathyroid, neuromuscular, immune, and insulin functions. Vitamin D has been found to be associated with lower risks of cardiovascular disease and age-related cognitive impairment, as well as Hodgkin’s and non-Hodgkin’s lymphoma and esophageal, lung, pancreatic, renal, colorectal, endometrial, prostate and ovarian cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If vitamin D levels were not changed, toxicity to chemotherapy did not vary with levels</title><link>/posts/if-vitamin-d-levels-were-not-changed-toxicity-to-chemotherapy-did-not-vary-with-levels.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/if-vitamin-d-levels-were-not-changed-toxicity-to-chemotherapy-did-not-vary-with-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-relationship-between-vitamin-d-and-chemotherapy-induced-toxicity---a-pilot-study">The relationship between vitamin D and chemotherapy-induced toxicity - a pilot study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Br J Cancer. 2012 May 15. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/bjc.2012.194.">doi: 10.1038/bjc.2012.194.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kitchen D, Hughes B, Gill I, O&amp;rsquo;Brien M, Rumbles S, Ellis P, Harper P, Stebbing J, Rohatgi N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1] Leaders in Oncology Care (LOC), 95 Harley Street, London W1G 6AF, UK &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup> Barts and The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Garrod Building, Turner Street, London E1 2AD, UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:There are anecdotal data that lower levels of vitamin D may be associated with increased levels of toxicity in individuals receiving chemotherapy; we therefore wished to investigate this further.Methods:From a cohort of over 11?000 individuals, we included those who had vitamin D levels (serum 1,25(OH)(2)D3) measured before and during chemotherapy. They were analysed for side effects correlating Chemotherapy Toxicity Criteria with vitamin D levels, normalising data for general markers of patient health including C-reactive protein and albumin.Results:A total of 241 (2% of the total cohort) individuals entered the toxicity analysis. We found no overall difference in toxicity effects experienced by patients depending on whether they were vitamin D depleted or had sufficient levels (P=0.78).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breast Cancer Chemotherapy initially decreases vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-initially-decreases-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-chemotherapy-initially-decreases-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>two articles on this page, both published May 2012&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="changes-of-serum-vitamin-d-according-to-the-breast-cancer-treatment">CHANGES OF SERUM VITAMIN D ACCORDING TO THE BREAST CANCER TREATMENT&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>H.J. Kim? and S.H. Ahn&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ann Oncol (2012) 23 (suppl 2): ii46-ii50.; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/annonc/mds046">doi: 10.1093/annonc/mds046&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article appears in: IMPAKT Breast Cancer Conference, 3-5 May 2012, Brussels, Belgium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Surgery, Asan Medical Center, Seoul, KOREA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background Vitamin D deficiency is associated with increased breast cancer risk and decreased breast cancer survival. The purpose of this study was to determine the effect of breast cancer adjuvant treatment to the vitamin D status, as measured by the serum hydroxyvitamin D (25OHD) in breast cancer patients&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aromatase inhibitor chemotherapy after breast cancer not associated with vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/aromatase-inhibitor-chemotherapy-after-breast-cancer-not-associated-with-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/aromatase-inhibitor-chemotherapy-after-breast-cancer-not-associated-with-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-baseline-serum-vitamin-d-levels-on-aromatase-inhibitors-induced-musculoskeletal-symptoms-results-from-the-ibis-ii-chemoprevention-study-using-anastrozole">Effect of baseline serum vitamin D levels on aromatase inhibitors induced musculoskeletal symptoms: results from the IBIS-II, chemoprevention study using anastrozole&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Breast Cancer Research and Treatment&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1007/s10549-011-1911-6&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical trial&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shalini Singh, Jack Cuzick, David Mesher, Bill Richmond and Anthony Howell&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Severe deficiency of vitamin D in adults can cause musculoskeletal pain, stiffness, and joint discomfort. Musculoskeletal symptoms similar to those associated with vitamin D deficiency are frequently seen in breast cancer patients receiving adjuvant aromatase inhibitors (AIs). This is presumably due to oestrogen deficiency caused by Ais.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer patients 64% less likely to die if have high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cancer-patients-64-percent-less-likely-to-die-if-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-patients-64-percent-less-likely-to-die-if-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-survival-in-norwegian-patients-with-cancer-of-breast-colon-lung-and-lymphoma-a-population-based-study">Serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D and survival in Norwegian patients with cancer of breast, colon, lung, and lymphoma: a population-based study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2011 Dec 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tretli S, Schwartz GG, Torjesen PA, Robsahm TE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cancer Registry of Norway, Institute of Population-based Cancer Research, PB 5313, Majorstuen, 0304, Oslo, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no">steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: We investigated the association between serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) and risk of death in Norwegian cancer patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children surviving blood cancer and vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/children-surviving-blood-cancer-and-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/children-surviving-blood-cancer-and-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D2 patent granted to prevent hair loss during chemotherapy – 2002</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d2-patent-granted-to-prevent-hair-loss-during-chemotherapy-2002.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d2-patent-granted-to-prevent-hair-loss-during-chemotherapy-2002.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wo2002030430-use-of-vitamin-d2-compounds-for-alopeciahttpwwwwipointpatentscopesearchendetailjsfdocidwo2002030430recnum1maxrecofficeprevfiltersortoptionquerystringtabpctbiblio20">&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/detail.jsf?docId=WO2002030430&amp;amp;recNum=1&amp;amp;maxRec=&amp;amp;office=&amp;amp;prevFilter=&amp;amp;sortOption=&amp;amp;queryString=&amp;amp;tab=PCT+Biblio%20">(WO2002030430) USE OF VITAMIN D2 COMPOUNDS FOR ALOPECIA&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Owner of patent =	ABBOTT LABORATORIES&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D reduces hair loss - many studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-hair-loss-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-reduces-hair-loss-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> Vitamins, such as vitamin D, are needed to reduce hair loss&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FACT:&lt;/strong> Chemotherapy reduces vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>OBSERVATION:&lt;/strong> Vitamin D reduces hair loss due to chemotherapy: reasons include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D can reduce the amount of chemo needed, so less hair is killed off&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fewer chemo results in less reduction in Vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D can keep the hair healthy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/#hl=en&amp;amp;pwst=1&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=bv-VTe3EBsfiiAL744T0CA&amp;amp;ved=0CBgQvwUoAQ&amp;amp;q=%22hair%20loss%22%20chemotherapy%20%22vitamin%20d%22&amp;amp;spell=1&amp;amp;fp=cc8e06da34e9bc37">Google search &amp;ldquo;hair loss&amp;rdquo; chemotherapy &amp;ldquo;vitamin d&amp;rdquo; &lt;/a> 3,60,000 hits Nov2019&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#89700-hair-and-vitamin-d-results-in-google-scholar---feb-2025">89,700 Hair and Vitamin D results in Google Scholar - Feb 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#evaluation-of-the-safety-and-effectiveness-of-nutritional-supplements-for-treating-hair-loss---nov2022">Evaluation of the Safety and Effectiveness of Nutritional Supplements for Treating Hair Loss - Nov 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#role-of-vitamin-d-in-hair-loss-a-short-review-2021">Role of vitamin D in hair loss: A short review – 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hair-and-the-founder-of-vitamindwiki">Hair and the founder of VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#noticed-more-hair-growth-after-added-gluathione-protein-and-weekly-omega-3--may-2025">Noticed more hair growth after added Gluathione, Protein, and weekly Omega-3 May 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#great-hair-regrowth-june-2012-henry-lahore-admin-ofvitamindwiki">Great hair regrowth June 2012: Henry Lahore, admin of VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#observation--vitamin-d3--cofactors--massage--has-worked-extremely-well-forme">Observation: &lt;strong>Vitamin D3 + cofactors + massage&lt;/strong> has worked extremely well for me.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#my-beard-growth-perhaps-aided-by-vitamin-d-andzinc">My beard growth, perhaps aided by Vitamin D and Zinc&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-level-laser-therapy-helps-hairgrowth---2019-note-lllt-known-to-increase-vitamin-dlevels">Low-Level Laser Therapy helps hair growth - 2019 (note LLLT known to increase Vitamin D levels)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#great-hair-regrowth-june-2012-henry-lahore-admin-ofvitamindwiki-1">Great hair regrowth June 2012: Henry Lahore, admin of VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#observation--vitamin-d3--cofactors--massage--has-worked-extremely-well-forme-1">Observation: &lt;strong>Vitamin D3 + cofactors + massage&lt;/strong> has worked extremely well for me.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-hair-cycle-and-vitamin-d-receptor--2011">The Hair Cycle and Vitamin D Receptor - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#female-hair">Female hair&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#female-pattern-hair-loss-treatment-augmented-by-vitamin-d--jan2022">Female pattern hair loss treatment augmented by Vitamin D – Jan 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#serum-ferritin-and-vitamin-d-in-female-hair-loss-do-they-play-a-role--2013">Serum ferritin and vitamin D in female hair loss: do they play a role? - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#serum-vitamin-d-in-patients-with-alopecia-areata-sept2016">Serum Vitamin D in Patients with alopecia areata Sept 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#female-pattern-hair-loss-treatment-augmented-by-vitamin-d--jan2022-1">Female pattern hair loss treatment augmented by Vitamin D – Jan 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#google-scholar-18000-hits-for-alopecia-and-vitamin-d-as-of-march2022">Google Scholar 18,000 hits for alopecia and &amp;ldquo;Vitamin D&amp;rdquo; as of March 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsovitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsoweb">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web---graying-hair-is-related-to-several-vitamin-d-deficientdiseases">See also web - graying hair is related to several vitamin D deficient diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dr-greger-low-zinc-too-much-mercury-or-smoking-causes-hairloss">Dr. Greger: Low Zinc, too much Mercury, or smoking causes hair loss&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-helps-minoxidil-rogaine-re-growhair">Vitamin D helps minoxidil (rogaine) re-grow hair&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#role-of-vitamin-d-in-hair-loss-a-short-review-2021-1">Role of vitamin D in hair loss: A short review – 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#feb-2010-meta-analysishttpdermatologycdliborg1602reviewsvitamindrashidhtml-of-vitamin-d-and-hairloss">&lt;a href="http://dermatology.cdlib.org/1602/reviews/vitamind/rashid.html">Feb 2010 Meta-analysis&lt;/a> of Vitamin D and Hair Loss&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-hair-cycle-and-vitamin-d-receptor--2011-1">The Hair Cycle and Vitamin D Receptor - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#serum-ferritin-and-vitamin-d-in-female-hair-loss-do-they-play-a-rolehttpwwwncbinlmnihgovpubmedterm23428658--2013">&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=23428658">Serum ferritin and vitamin d in female hair loss: do they play a role?&lt;/a> - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#serum-vitamin-d-in-patients-with-alopecia-areata-sept2016-1">Serum Vitamin D in Patients with alopecia areata Sept 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#female-pattern-hair-loss-vitd-135-ng-vs-controlsno-fp-hair-loss-172-ng-2016">Female pattern hair loss VitD: 13.5 ng vs controls(no FP hair loss): 17.2 ng -2016&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsovitamindwiki-1">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#google-scholar-18000-hits-for-alopecia-and-vitamin-d-as-of-march2022-1">Google Scholar 18,000 hits for alopecia and &amp;ldquo;Vitamin D&amp;rdquo; as of March 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsoweb-1">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web---graying-hair-is-related-to-several-vitamin-d-deficientdiseases-1">See also web - graying hair is related to several vitamin D deficient diseases&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#low-level-laser-therapy-helps-hairgrowth">Low-Level Laser Therapy helps hair growth&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#my-beard-growth-perhaps-aided-by-vitamin-d-andzinc-1">My beard growth, perhaps aided by Vitamin D and Zinc&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dr-greger-low-zinc-too-much-mercury-or-smoking-causes-hairloss-1">Dr. Greger: Low Zinc, too much Mercury, or smoking causes hair loss&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-helps-minoxidil-rogaine-re-growhair-1">Vitamin D helps minoxidil (rogaine) re-grow hair&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="89700-hair-and-vitamin-d-results-in-google-scholar---feb-2025">89,700 Hair and Vitamin D results in Google Scholar - Feb 2025&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?q=hair%20%22vitamin%20d%22&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0,48">Google Scholar here are some of them&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D appears to both prevent and treat various cancers</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-appears-to-both-prevent-and-treat-various-cancers.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-appears-to-both-prevent-and-treat-various-cancers.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-as-a-promising-anticancer-agent">Vitamin D as a promising anticancer agent&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Indian Journal of Pharmacology, 2011 | Volume : 43 | Issue : 2 | Page : 113-120&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chandra Kanti Chakraborti&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Microbiology, Kanak Manjari Institute of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Rourkela, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Date of Submission	25-Feb-2010; Date of Decision	07-Sep-2010; Date of Acceptance	31-Dec-2010; Date of Web Publication	6-Mar-2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.4103/0253-7613.77335&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presence of vitamin D receptors in noncalcemic tissues and subsequent identification of its involvement in growth factor(s)-mediated cellular function suggested its probable beneficial role in genesis, progression and survival of cancerous growths. Data collected from both in vitro and in vivo studies are &lt;strong>highly optimistic regarding its potential in prevention and regression of colorectal, prostate and breast cancers&lt;/strong> . The vitamin has been found to interfere with the transduction pathways of various growth factor(s)-activated receptors (receptor tyrosine kinases) thereby modulating transcription and alteration of genomic functions resulting in inhibition of cell proliferation and angiogenesis and facilitation of cell differentiation and apoptosis. It also increases the level of an endogenous protein - cystatin D, which possesses antitumor and antimetastatic property, by facilitation of the expression of the gene coding for it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>