<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intervention on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/intervention/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intervention on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/intervention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>COVID and Vitamin D: 2X more likely to die if low, 2X more likely to survive if supplement – umbrella meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-and-vitamin-d-2x-more-likely-to-die-if-low-2x-more-likely-to-survive-if-su-a-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-and-vitamin-d-2x-more-likely-to-die-if-low-2x-more-likely-to-survive-if-su-a-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-outcomes-of-critical-care-in-covid-19-patients-evidence-from-an-umbrella-meta-analysis-of-interventional-and-observational-studies&#34;&gt;The role of vitamin D in outcomes of critical care in COVID-19 patients: Evidence from an umbrella meta-analysis of interventional and observational studies&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Public Health Nutrition  . 2024 Apr 24:1-25.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S1368980024000934.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1017/S1368980024000934.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objectives: Several meta-analyses have suggested the beneficial effect of vitamin D on patients infected with SARS-CoV-2. This umbrella meta-analysis aims to evaluate influence of vitamin D supplementation on clinical outcomes and the mortality rate of COVID-19 patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TB treatment helped by the addition of Vitamin D (100,000 IU bi-weekly) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tb-treatment-helped-by-the-addition-of-vitamin-d-100000-iu-bi-weekly-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tb-treatment-helped-by-the-addition-of-vitamin-d-100000-iu-bi-weekly-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-adjunct-vitamin-d-treatment-in-vitamin-d-deficient-pulmonary-tuberculosis-patients-a-randomized-double-blind-active-controlled-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;Effect of adjunct Vitamin D treatment in vitamin D deficient pulmonary tuberculosis patients: A randomized, double blind, active controlled clinical trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indian J Tuberc. 2024 Apr;71(2):170-178. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijtb.2023.04.026.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.ijtb.2023.04.026.&lt;/a&gt; Epub 2023 Apr 29.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Harish Chandra 1, Adil Rahman 2, Prashant Yadav 3, Geeta Maurya 4, Sushil Kumar Shukla 5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Since, Vitamin D &lt;span&gt;[1α,25(OH)2D)]&lt;/span&gt; enhances antimicrobial activity of Innate immunity and modulate Adaptive immune responses, simultaneously, so it play a potential role for balanced immune activity against Mycobacterium tuberculosis and restricting tissue injuries within the TB patients.(Chun et al., 2011) 9 We aimed to determine the role of adjunct Vitamin D treatment on the outcome of pulmonary tuberculosis patients and evaluated the effect of Vitamin D administration on Differential Leucocyte Count, Erythrocyte Sedimentation Rate, serum Adenosine deaminase, serum C- reactive protein, Oxygen saturation (SpO2) and Body Weight in Vitamin D deficient pulmonary tuberculosis patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID fought by Vitamin D: 2.3X less likely to die of COVID if supplemented, 1.9 X less likely to become infected – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-fought-by-vitamin-d-23x-less-likely-to-die-of-covid-if-supplemented-19-x-l-d-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-fought-by-vitamin-d-23x-less-likely-to-die-of-covid-if-supplemented-19-x-l-d-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-covid-19-survival-and-prevention-a-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;The Role of Vitamin D in COVID-19 Survival and Prevention: A Meta-analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sudan Journal of Medical Sciences (SJMS) / Sudan JMS: Volume 19 (2024), Issue No. 1 / Pages 72–83&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: COVID-19 is still ongoing with frequently discovered new strains, although vaccines are highly effective for prevention. Literature on vitamin D supplementation in COVID-19 prevention and its effect on survival is scarce. This meta-analysis assessed the role of vitamin D supplementation in COVID-19 prevention and survival.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Randomized Controlled Trials and Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/randomized-controlled-trials-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/randomized-controlled-trials-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;see-also-a-hrefpostsintervention-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-intervention---vitamin-dintervention---vitamin-da&#34;&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/intervention-vitamin-d&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Intervention - Vitamin D&#34;&gt;Intervention - Vitamin D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange837span-vitamindwiki-pages-have-rct-in-the-title-includes-some-omega-3&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;837+&lt;/span&gt; VitaminDWiki pages have RCT in the title (includes some Omega-3)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{list max=&amp;ldquo;1000&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;RCT&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;NOT Omega-6&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;NOT handgrip&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;NOT NO&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;NOT D2&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;NOT magnesium&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; shownbitems=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 X less COVID infection of health care workers who took lots of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/5-x-less-covid-infection-of-health-care-workers-who-took-lots-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/5-x-less-covid-infection-of-health-care-workers-who-took-lots-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;850&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;preventive-vitamin-d-supplementation-and-risk-for-covid-19-infection-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;Preventive Vitamin D Supplementation and Risk for COVID-19 Infection: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2024, 16(5), 679; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu16050679&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu16050679&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Marina Sartini  1,2,&lt;em&gt;,†ORCID,Filippo Del Puente 3,&lt;/em&gt;,†,Martino Oliva 1,Alessio Carbone 1,Nicoletta Bobbio 3,Elisa Schinca 1,2,Luana Giribone 1 and Maria Luisa Cristina 1,2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Department of Health Sciences, University of Genoa, 16132 Genoa, Italy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Operating Unit Hospital Hygiene, Galliera Hospital, 16128 Genoa, Italy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 Department of Infectious Diseases, Galliera Hospital, 16128 Genoa, Italy&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID deaths cut in half by a single dose of 600,000 IU of Vitamin D - RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-deaths-cut-in-half-by-a-single-dose-of-600000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-deaths-cut-in-half-by-a-single-dose-of-600000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;therapeutic-high-dose-vitamin-d-for-vitamin-d-deficient-severe-covid-19-disease-randomized-double-blind-placebo-controlled-study-shade-s&#34;&gt;Therapeutic high-dose vitamin D for vitamin D-deficient severe COVID-19 disease: randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study (SHADE-S)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J Public Health (Oxf)  2024 Jan 30:fdae007. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/pubmed/fdae007&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1093/pubmed/fdae007&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind a $55 paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ajay Singh 1, Ashu Rastogi 2, Goverdhan Dutt Puri 1, Venkata Ganesh 1, Naveen Bal Naik 1, Kamal Kajal 1, Shubhkarman Kahlon 1, Shiv Lal Soni 1, Narender Kaloria 1, Kulbhushan Saini 1, Amarjyoti Hazarika 1, Varun Mahajan 1, Karan Singla 1, Sanjay Bhadada 2, Vaishali Soni 3 (India)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PMS reduced by 50,000 IU every two weeks - RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pms-reduced-by-50000-iu-every-two-weeks-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pms-reduced-by-50000-iu-every-two-weeks-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-symptoms-severity-in-vitamin-d-insufficient-women-with-premenstrual-syndrome-a-randomized-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;Effect of vitamin D supplementation on symptoms severity in vitamin D insufficient women with premenstrual syndrome: A randomized controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2024 Feb:59:241-248. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnesp.2023.11.014&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.clnesp.2023.11.014&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hajar Heidari 1, Khadijeh Abbasi 2, Awat Feizi 3, Shahnaz Kohan 4, Reza Amani 5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Premenstrual syndrome (PMS) is one of the most prevalent disorders among reproductive women worldwide that negatively impact women&amp;rsquo;s quality of life. This study aimed to investigate the effect of vitamin D supplementation on the severity of PMS symptoms in vitamin D insufficient women with PMS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D loading dose of 30,000 IU twice a week is safe and effective – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-loading-dose-of-30000-iu-twice-a-week-is-safe-and-effective-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-loading-dose-of-30000-iu-twice-a-week-is-safe-and-effective-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;controlled-randomized-open-label-clinical-study-comparing-the-safety-and-efficacy-of-loading-schedules-in-vitamin-d-deficient-patients&#34;&gt;Controlled randomized open label clinical study comparing the safety and efficacy of loading schedules in vitamin D deficient patients&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The J/ of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology Vol 231, July 2023,  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2023.106330&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2023.106330&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Istvan Takacs a, Bence Bakos a, Zsuzsanna Nemeth a, Bela E. Toth b, Balazs Szili a, Peter Lakatos a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rapidly restoring vitamin D levels to normal might be desirable in certain clinical situations. Larger doses of supplementation, have been shown to increase bone loss and the risk of falls. The optimal way to perform vitamin D loading safely and effectively is still not well elucidated. Our study was aimed to assess the safety and efficacy of two oral vitamin D loading protocols. Sixty-nine subjects with vitamin D deficiency (25OH-vitamin D (25(OH)D) &amp;lt; 20 ng/ml) were included. Thirty-five participants received 30 000 IU of vitamin D3 per week for 10 weeks (group Slower Loading Dose (SLD)) and thirty-four received 30 000 IU twice weekly for 5 weeks (group Moderate Loading Dose (MLD)) resulting in a loading dose of 300 000 IU for all subjects. Following this initial loading phase, both groups received 30 000 IU biweekly for 4 weeks to test whether the recommended daily vitamin D supplementation in range of 2000 IU dose-equivalent could maintain the achieved levels. Seventy-nine percent of those subjects treated in group SLD and everyone in group MLD achieved a 25(OH)D level of 30 ng/ml, which is the lower limit of the recommended normal range in Hungary. The mean increase in 25(OH)D was significantly higher in group MLD than in group SLD (38.6 ± 1.80 ng/ml vs 46,6 ± 1.80 ng/ml). No significant decrease was observed with the administration of the maintenance dose. There were no clinically significant changes in serum or urine calcium, and bone biomarkers in either group. Both protocols were found to be safe and effective, but the five-week dosing caused a significantly greater increase in 25(OH)D. A maintenance dose applied for four weeks after the loading protocol did not raise 25(OH)D levels further but maintained the achieved increase. The administration of 30 000 IU of vitamin D3 twice weekly for five weeks is a rapid, effective and safe way to treat vitamin D deficiency in vitamin D deficient patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Individualized – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/individualized-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/individualized-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effects-of-an-individualized-vs-standardized-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-the-25ohd-level-in-athletes&#34;&gt;Effects of an Individualized vs. Standardized Vitamin D Supplementation on the 25(OH)D Level in Athletes&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2023, 15(22), 4747; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15224747&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15224747&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Chiara Tuma 1,2,*ORCID, Arne Schick 1,Nele Pommerening 1,Hans Braun 1,2 and Mario Thevis 1,3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Institute of Biochemistry/Center of Preventive Doping Research, German Sport University Cologne, 50933 Cologne, Germany&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 German Research Centre of Elite Sports (Momentum), German Sport University Cologne, 50933 Cologne, Germany&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 European Monitoring Center for Emerging Doping Agents, 50933 Cologne, Germany&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monthly vitamin D dosing better for children than daily (again)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/monthly-vitamin-d-dosing-better-for-children-than-daily-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/monthly-vitamin-d-dosing-better-for-children-than-daily-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;monthly-versus-daily-administration-of-vitamin-d3-in-children-a-retrospective-propensity-score-matched-study&#34;&gt;Monthly versus daily administration of vitamin D3 in children: a retrospective propensity score-matched study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2023 Oct 24:14:1265943. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2023.1265943&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3389/fendo.2023.1265943&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jinjoo Choi # 1, Yunsoo Choe # 2, Seung Yang 1 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objectives: We aimed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of monthly vitamin D3 administration compared to a daily dosing regimen in healthy children with vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Methods: This retrospective study included vitamin D deficient (serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span&gt;[25(OH)D]&lt;/span&gt; &amp;lt; 20 ng/mL) children with precocious puberty who received gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist every 4 weeks between December 2019 and November 2022. We used propensity scores to 1:1 match daily (1,000 IU daily) and monthly (25,000 IU per 4 weeks) administration of vitamin D3 based on age, sex, body mass index Z-scores, season of blood collection, and baseline serum 25(OH)D concentrations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D 100,000 IU loading dose and stem cell transplants – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-100000-iu-loading-dose-and-stem-cell-transplants-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-100000-iu-loading-dose-and-stem-cell-transplants-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;loading-dose-vitamin-d3-improves-vitamin-d-insufficiency-in-adults-undergoing-hematopoietic-stem-cell-transplantation-a-randomized-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;Loading dose vitamin D3 improves vitamin D insufficiency in adults undergoing hematopoietic stem cell transplantation: A randomized controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PLoS One. 2023 Oct 26;18(10):e0284644. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0284644.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0284644.&lt;/a&gt; eCollection 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ni Bai 1, Karen Lee 1, Wasithep Limvorapitak 2, Emily Liu 1, David Kendler 3, Raewyn Broady 1, Jennifer White 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplant (aHSCT) patients are well known to be at high risk of vitamin D (vit D) deficiency. This study assessed whether a loading dose (100,000 IU) of vitamin D3 pre-aHSCT could effectively achieve and maintain sufficient post-transplant vit D levels (serum total 25 hydroxy vitamin D (25(OH)D) ≥ 75nmol/L). Dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) was also conducted for bone health evaluation. 74 patients were enrolled and randomly assigned, in a 1:1 ratio, either to the high vit D group (single loading dose (100,000 IU) plus 2,000 IU vit D3 daily) or the control group (2,000 IU vit D3 daily). Vit D levels were measured at three time points (baseline, day 30 and day 100 post-aHSCT). At baseline, fewer than 50% patients had a sufficient 25(OH)D (control: 42.9%; high vit D: 43.6%). The proportion of patients with sufficient 25(OH)D (nmol/L) was increased at day 30 and day 100, with a trend of higher proportion in the high vit D group at day 30 (high vit D vs. control: 89.7% vs. 74.3%, p = 0.08). The increased 25(OH)D was significantly higher in the high vit D group at day 30 (high vit D vs. control: 29±25.2 vs. 14 ±21.9, p = 0.01). Insufficient vit D level before transplant (baseline) was an independent risk factor for vit D insufficiency (serum 25(OH)D &amp;lt; 75nmol/L) post-aHSCT (OR = 4.16, p = 0.03). DXA suggested significant bone loss for total hip in both groups, and in the femoral neck for the control group only.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4,000 IU of daily Vitamin D during pregnancy is good (Mongolia this time) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/4000-iu-of-daily-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-is-good-mongolia-this-time-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/4000-iu-of-daily-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-is-good-mongolia-this-time-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;maternal-vitamin-d-intakes-during-pregnancy-and-child-health-outcome&#34;&gt;Maternal vitamin D intakes during pregnancy and child health outcome&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J. of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology  October 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2023.106411&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2023.106411&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Erdenebileg Nasantogtokh a b, Davaasambuu Ganma a c d, Shirchinjav Altantuya a b, Bayarsaikhan Amgalan b, Davaasambuu Enkhmaa а&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We conducted a follow up of the children in Mongolia whose mothers received one of the three doses of vitamin D  &lt;strong&gt;(600, 2000, or 4000 IU daily)&lt;/strong&gt; during pregnancy as part of the randomized, double-blind, clinical trial of vitamin D supplementation to determine their impact on child health to two years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5000 IU Vitamin D daily resulted in lower health care costs - RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/5000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-resulted-in-lower-health-care-costs-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/5000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-resulted-in-lower-health-care-costs-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;healthcare-costs-and-healthcare-utilization-outcomes-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation-at-5000-iu-daily-during-a-109-month-observation-period-within-a-pragmatic-randomized-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;Healthcare Costs and Healthcare Utilization Outcomes of Vitamin D3 Supplementation at 5000 IU Daily During a 10.9 month Observation Period within a Pragmatic Randomized Clinical Trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2023, 15(20), 4435; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15204435&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15204435&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patrick J. LaRiccia,   Teresa Cafaro,   Dibato John,   Noud van Helmond,   Ludmil V. Mitrev,   Brigid Bandomer,   Tracy L. Brobyn,   Krystal Hunter,   Satyajeet Roy,   Kevin Q. Ng, Helen Goldstein,   Alan Tsai, Denise Thwing, Mary Ann Maag,   Myung K. Chung&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muscles improved in women with 50,000 IU vitamin D weekly (8 weeks) plus daily Magnesium – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/muscles-improved-in-women-with-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-8-weeks-plus-daily-magnesium-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/muscles-improved-in-women-with-50000-iu-vitamin-d-weekly-8-weeks-plus-daily-magnesium-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;randomized-study-of-the-effects-of-vitamin-d-and-magnesium-co-supplementation-on-muscle-strength-and-function-body-composition-and-inflammation-in-vitamin-d-deficient-middle-aged-women----sept-2020&#34;&gt;Randomized Study of the Effects of Vitamin D and Magnesium Co-Supplementation on Muscle Strength and Function, Body Composition, and Inflammation in Vitamin D-Deficient Middle-Aged Women  - Sept 2020&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biological Trace Element Research volume 199, pages 2523–2534 (2021&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fatemeh Kheyruri, Javad Sarrafzadeh, Agha Fatemeh Hosseini, Behnaz Abiri &amp;amp; Mohammadreza Vafa&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;700&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study aimed to investigate the effects of vitamin D and magnesium co-supplementation on muscle strength and function, body composition, and inflammation in vitamin D-deficient middle-aged women. In this study, 83 healthy middle-aged women (40–55 years) with vitamin D deficiency were randomly assigned into two groups: (1) intervention: receiving a 50,000-IU vitamin D soft gel (weekly) plus a 250-mg magnesium tablet (daily); (2) control: receiving a vitamin D placebo (weekly) plus a magnesium placebo (daily), for 8 weeks. Before and after the intervention, anthropometric indices, muscle strength, muscle function, and some inflammatory markers were measured. After 8 weeks of supplementation, significant difference was observed in handgrip strength and time for Time Get Up and Go (TGUG) test between the intervention and placebo groups (P &amp;lt; 0.05). Regarding percentage of fat mass (FM%) and fat free mass (FFM%), and knee extension strength, there was no significant difference between the two groups at the end of intervention (P &amp;gt; .05). Serum 25(OH)-D levels increased significantly (P &amp;lt; 0.001) and its change was significantly different between the two groups, at the end of the intervention (P &amp;lt; 0.001). Serum level of hs-CRP decreased significantly in the intervention group compared to baseline (P &amp;lt; 0.001), and the change in hs-CRP was significant between the two groups at the end of the intervention (P &amp;lt; 0.01). Furthermore, serum level of TNF-α declined significantly in the intervention group compared to baseline (P &amp;lt; 0.001) but, no significant differences were seen between the two groups in regard of serum levels of TNF-α and IL-6 after the intervention (P &amp;gt; 0.05).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fibromyalgia pain, fatigue, etc. reduced by 50,000 IU of Vitamin D for 12 weeks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fibromyalgia-pain-fatigue-etc-reduced-by-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-12-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fibromyalgia-pain-fatigue-etc-reduced-by-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-12-weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-effect-of-vitamin-d-treatment-on-quality-of-life-in-patients-with-fibromyalgia&#34;&gt;The effect of vitamin D treatment on quality of life in patients with fibromyalgia&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Irish Journal of Medical Science (1971 -) &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11845-023-03521-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11845-023-03521-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sedef Ersoy, Fatma Nur Kesiktas, Busra Sirin, Derya Bugdayci &amp;amp; Nurdan Paker (Turkey)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;FIQ consists of 10 questions that inquire about the level of impact on daily activities, fatigue, pain level, morning discomfort, and mood over the past week. The maximum score is 80, and the minimum score is 0&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pesticides 8 X less likely to result in female infertility if take vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pesticides-8-x-less-likely-to-result-in-female-infertility-if-take-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pesticides-8-x-less-likely-to-result-in-female-infertility-if-take-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-intake-attenuated-the-association-between-pesticides-exposure-and-female-infertility&#34;&gt;Vitamin D Intake Attenuated the Association between Pesticides Exposure and Female Infertility&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clin Lab. 2023 Sep 1;69(9). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7754/Clin.Lab.2023.230201.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.7754/Clin.Lab.2023.230201.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chunxiu Wu, Xiaoqin Xin, Jianlan Chen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Only a few epidemiological studies have illuminated the association between pesticide exposure and female infertility. However, evidence of the available data is restricted and also controversial. Vitamin D supplement was considered as having a beneficial effect on fertility. So, the purpose of our study is to assess the effect of dietary vitamin D consumption on the relationship between pesticide exposure in home and female infertility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Senior cognition improved in 4 ways by Vitamin D (50,000 IU weekly for 8 weeks)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/senior-cognition-improved-in-4-ways-by-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly-for-8-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/senior-cognition-improved-in-4-ways-by-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly-for-8-weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-neurocognitive-functions-in-older-vitamin-d-deficient-adults-a-pilot-longitudinal-interventional-study&#34;&gt;The effect of vitamin D on neurocognitive functions in older vitamin D deficient adults: a pilot longitudinal interventional study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psychogeriatrics. 2023 Sep;23(5):781-788. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/psyg.12997&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1111/psyg.12997&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Banu Ozulu Turkmen 1, Busra Can 2, Seda Buker 3, Birsu Beser 3, Deniz Büyükgök 3, Bahar Dernek 4, Sevilay Bovatekin 1, Pınar Kucukdagli 1, Birkan Ilhan 1, Şükriye Akça Kalem 3, Nilgun Erten 1, Mehmet Akif Karan 1, Gulistan Bahat 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: The relationship between vitamin D and cognitive status remains controversial. We aimed to evaluate the effect of vitamin D replacement on cognitive functions in healthy and cognitively intact vitamin D deficient older females.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Periodontitis reduced by Vitamin D (60,000 IU weekly for 8 weeks) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-periodontitis-reduced-by-vitamin-d-60000-iu-weekly-for-8-weeks-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-periodontitis-reduced-by-vitamin-d-60000-iu-weekly-for-8-weeks-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessment-of-outcome-of-oral-supplementation-of-vitamin-d3-as-an-adjunct-to-scaling-and-root-planing-in-chronic-periodontitis-patients-with-type-ii-diabetes-mellitus--a-randomized-controlled-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;Assessment of Outcome of Oral Supplementation of Vitamin D3 as an Adjunct to Scaling and Root Planing in Chronic Periodontitis Patients with Type II Diabetes Mellitus – A Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J. of Pharmacy and Bioallied Sciences 15(Suppl 1):p S346-S349, July 2023. DOI: 10.4103/jpbs.jpbs_543_22&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ramaprabha, G1; Khan, Nubesh S.2; Kunusoth, Ramesh3; Kakati, Indrajit4; Hussain Qadri, Syed Shah5; Seshadri, Pavithra Rangarajan6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both diabetes and periodontitis affect millions of people worldwide and Vitamin D insufficiency may create a conducive environment for the progression of diabetes and periodontal disease. The aim of the study was to assess the outcome of oral supplementation of Vitamin D3 in patients with Type 2Diabetes Mellitus with generalized chronic periodontitis, as an adjuvant toscaling and root planing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Less morphine recall if preceded by twice a week Vitamin D (400 IU per kg in rats, human weights 80 kg)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/less-morphine-recall-if-preceded-by-twice-a-week-vitamin-d-400-iu-per-kg-in-rats-human-weights-80-kg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/less-morphine-recall-if-preceded-by-twice-a-week-vitamin-d-400-iu-per-kg-in-rats-human-weights-80-kg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;attenuation-of-morphine-conditioned-place-preference-and-reinstatement-by-vitamin-d&#34;&gt;Attenuation of morphine conditioned place preference and reinstatement by vitamin D&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Behav Pharmacol. 2023 Aug 15. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1097/FBP.0000000000000747&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1097/FBP.0000000000000747&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mahdieh Akbari 1, Houman Parsaei 2, Katayoun Sedaghat 1, Fatemeh Mousavi 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Research Center of Physiology, Semnan University of Medical Sciences, Semnan and.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Department of Anatomy, School of Medicine, Iran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opioid&lt;/strong&gt;  action in the brain involves the dopamine-reward system as well as non-dopamine pathways. Since vitamin D also modulates the brain&amp;rsquo;s dopamine system, the question of this study was how vitamin D might affect the  &lt;strong&gt;opioid&lt;/strong&gt;  influences on the reward system. Therefore, the objective of this study was to investigate the possible effect of vitamin D on the conditioned place preference (CPP) induced by  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt; , as a valuable model of assessment of the reinforcing properties of  &lt;strong&gt;opioids&lt;/strong&gt;  by associating the context to the rewarding properties of the addictive drugs. Male Wistar rats were randomly divided into two main groups that either received saline ( &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  vehicle) or  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  (5 mg/kg, intraperitoneally) for CPP. Each of the main groups was divided into three vitamin D treatment subgroups: vitamin D vehicle and vitamin D (5 and 10 μg/kg, intraperitoneally). Vitamin D injections were started 1 week ahead of the experiment (two injections) or immediately after post-conditioning and in both cases, it was continued twice weekly throughout the CPP. Administration of vitamin D (10 μg/kg) before conditioning in CPP markedly attenuated  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  expression in the post-conditioning test. Receiving vitamin D (5 or 10 μg/kg) before or after conditioning significantly attenuated  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  reinstatement. Administration of vitamin D after  &lt;strong&gt;opioid&lt;/strong&gt;  conditioning facilitated  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  memory extinction and attenuated  &lt;strong&gt;morphine&lt;/strong&gt;  reinstatement. Vitamin D is probably a valuable addition to be considered as a part of the treatment for prevention or minimizing the dependency or relapse to  &lt;strong&gt;opioids&lt;/strong&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breast Cancer survival: 44% with just 10,000 IU of vitamin D per week, 33% with placebo – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/breast-cancer-survival-44-percent-with-just-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-week-33-pe-ith-placebo-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/breast-cancer-survival-44-percent-with-just-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-week-33-pe-ith-placebo-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;efficacy-of-nutritional-intervention-in-breast-cancer-patients-a-randomized-clinical-case-control-trial&#34;&gt;Efficacy of nutritional intervention in breast cancer patients: a randomized clinical case control trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF FOOD PROPERTIES 2023, VOL. 26, NO. 1, 2146-2159 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/10942912.2023.2244686&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/10942912.2023.2244686&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aneela Qureshia, Farzana Siddiquea, Muhammad Arshadb, Waseem Khalidc, Shahid Bashirec&amp;rsquo;d, Ammar Ahmad Khanc, Syeda Mahvish Zahrae, Turky Omar Asarf, and Mayada Ahmad Al-Sameen9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;aInstitute of Food Science and Nutrition, University of Sargodha, Sargodha, Pakistan; bDepartment of Zoology, University of Sargodha, Sargodha, Pakistan; cUniversity Institute of Food Science and Technology, The University of Lahore, Lahore, Pakistan; dFaculty of Allied Health and Biological Sciences, Ibadat International University Islamabad, Islamabad, Pakistan; department of Environmental Design, Health and Nutritional Sciences, Allama Iqbal Open University, Islamabad, Pakistan; department of Biology, College of Science and Arts at Alkamil, University of Jeddah, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia; department of Horticulture Science, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Damascus, Damascus, Syria&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D response independent of dosing interval – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-response-independent-of-dosing-interval-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-response-independent-of-dosing-interval-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;efficacy-of-intermittent-versus-daily-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-improving-circulating-25ohd-concentration-a-bayesian-network-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials&#34;&gt;Efficacy of intermittent versus daily vitamin D supplementation on improving circulating 25(OH)D concentration: A Bayesian network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front. Nutr.Sec. Nutritional Epidemiology Volume 10 - 2023 | &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2023.1168115&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3389/fnut.2023.1168115&lt;/a&gt;   PDF not available initially&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hui Liu1, 2* Haibo Zhou1 Zhicheng Peng1 Haoyue Cheng1  Peihan Chi1 Xing Xin1 Wenliang Luo1 Shuting Si1  Minjia Mo1  Danqing Chen1  Yunxian Yu1*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Zhejiang University, China&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Sir Run run shaw hospital, China&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pain not reduced by 60,000 IU monthly vitamin D (need 50,000 IU weekly) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pain-not-reduced-by-60000-iu-monthly-vitamin-d-need-50000-iu-weekly-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pain-not-reduced-by-60000-iu-monthly-vitamin-d-need-50000-iu-weekly-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-pain-an-analysis-of-data-from-the-d-health-randomised-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;The effect of vitamin D supplementation on pain: an analysis of data from the D-Health randomised controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trial Br J Nutr. 2023 Aug 28;130(4):633-640. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S000711452200356&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1017/S000711452200356&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aninda Rahman 1, Mary Waterhouse 2, Catherine Baxter 2, Briony Duarte Romero 2, Donald S A McLeod 2 3, Bruce K Armstrong 4, Peter R Ebeling 5, Dallas R English 6 7, Gunter Hartel 2, Michael G Kimlin 8, Rachel O&amp;rsquo;Connell 9, Jolieke C van der Pols 10, Alison J Venn 11, Penelope M Webb 2 12, David C Whiteman 2 12, Rachel E Neale 2 12&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cardiovascular events – need more than monthly 60,000 IU vitamin D to prevent other than infarction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cardiovascular-events-need-more-than-monthly-60000-iu-vitamin-d-to-prevent-other-than-infarction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cardiovascular-events-need-more-than-monthly-60000-iu-vitamin-d-to-prevent-other-than-infarction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-supplementation-and-major-cardiovascular-events-d-health-randomised-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;Vitamin D supplementation and major cardiovascular events: D-Health randomised controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BMJ 2023; 381 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/https&#34;&gt;doi: https&lt;/a&gt;://doi.org/10.1136/bmj-2023-075230 (Published 28 June 2023)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bridie Thompson, research officer1,  Mary Waterhouse, statistician epidemiologist1,  Dallas R English, professor2,  Donald S McLeod, senior research officer1,  Bruce K Armstrong, professor3,  Catherine Baxter, project manager1,  Briony Duarte Romero, research assistant1,  Peter R Ebeling, professor4,  Gunter Hartel, head of statistics5,  Michael G Kimlin, professor6,  Sabbir T Rahman, research officer1,  Jolieke C van der Pols, associate professor7,  Alison J Venn, professor8,  Penelope M Webb, professor1,  David C Whiteman, professor1,  Rachel E Neale, professor1  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:rachel.neale@qimrberghofer.edu.au&#34;&gt;rachel.neale@qimrberghofer.edu.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID in hospital stopped by Vitamin D Receptor activators (curcumin, quercetin) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-in-hospital-stopped-by-vitamin-d-receptor-activators-curcumin-quercetin-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-in-hospital-stopped-by-vitamin-d-receptor-activators-curcumin-quercetin-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;nasafytol-supplementation-in-adults-hospitalized-with-covid-19-infection-results-from-an-exploratory-open-label-randomized-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;NASAFYTOL® supplementation in adults hospitalized with COVID-19 infection: results from an exploratory open-label randomized controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front. Nutr. 10:1137407. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2023.1137407&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3389/fnut.2023.1137407&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jean Gérain1, Melanie Uebelhoer2*, Bérénice Costes2, Julie Herman2, Sandra Pietri2, Anne-Françoise Donneau3, Justine Monseur3 and Yves Henrotin2   Belgium&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange25-people-got-curcumin-42-mg-quercetin-65-mg-vitamin-d-90-iu-dailyspan&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;25 people got Curcumin (42 mg), Quercetin (65 mg), Vitamin D (90 IU) daily&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objectives: The effect and safety of Nasafytol®, a food supplement combining curcumin, quercetin, and Vitamin D, on hospitalized COVID-19-positive patients as support to standard of care were to be assessed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Sclerosis treated equally by UVB and weekly 50,000 IU of Vitamin D – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-treated-equally-by-uvb-and-weekly-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-treated-equally-by-uvb-and-weekly-50000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;efficacy-of-ultraviolet-b-radiation-versus-vitamin-d3-on-postural-control-and-cognitive-functions-in-relapsing-remitting-multiple-sclerosis-a-randomized-controlled-study&#34;&gt;Efficacy of ultraviolet B radiation versus vitamin D3 on postural control and cognitive functions in relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis: A randomized controlled study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2023 Jul;35:49-56. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbmt.2023.04.069&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.jbmt.2023.04.069&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shimaa Abdelalim Essa 1, Ahmed Elokda 2, Dalia Mosaad 3, Wael Shendy 4, Maged Abdel-Nasser 5, Asmaa Mohamed Ebraheim 6, Hadeel Mohammad 7, Alaa Elmazny 8, Eman Magdy 9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: The relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis (RRMS) is the most common type of MS with prevalence rate 20-60 patients/100.000 individuals in Egypt. Poor postural control and cognitive dysfunctions are well-established complications of RRMS without potent remedy yet. The latest evidence highlighted the potential and independent immune-modulating effects of vitamin D3 and ultraviolet radiation in the management of RRMS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bone fractures of children not reduced if given little vitamin D, no Calcium etc. – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bone-fractures-of-children-not-reduced-if-given-little-vitamin-d-no-calcium-etc-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bone-fractures-of-children-not-reduced-if-given-little-vitamin-d-no-calcium-etc-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gave 14,000 IU vitamin D weekly – independent of body weight (age 6-13)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Average vitamin D level achieved was only 30 ng after 3 years (in summer?)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fracture prevention also needs Magnesium, Vitamin K2, and Omega-3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;influence-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-fracture-risk-bone-mineral-density-and-bone-biochemistry-in-mongolian-schoolchildren-multicenter-double-blind-randomized-placebo-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;Influence of vitamin D supplementation on fracture risk, bone mineral density and bone biochemistry in Mongolian schoolchildren: multicenter double-blind randomized placebo-controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1101/2023.05.18.23290181.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1101/2023.05.18.23290181.&lt;/a&gt; Preprint&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Davaasambuu Ganmaa, Polyna Khudyakov, Uyanga Buyanjargal, Enkhtsetseg Tserenkhuu, Sumiya Erdenenbaatar, Chuluun-Erdene Achtai, Narankhuu Yansan, Baigal Delgererekh, Munkhzaya Ankhbat, Enkhjargal Tsendjav, Batbayar Ochirbat, Badamtsetseg Jargalsaikhan, Enkhmaa Davaasambuu, Adrian R Martineau&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D-disease associations vary with the type of study – RCT, Observational, MR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-disease-associations-vary-with-the-type-of-study-rct-observational-mr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-disease-associations-vary-with-the-type-of-study-rct-observational-mr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-and-multiple-health-outcomes-an-umbrella-review-of-observational-studies-randomized-controlled-trials-and-mendelian-randomization-studies&#34;&gt;Vitamin D and Multiple Health Outcomes: An Umbrella Review of Observational Studies, Randomized Controlled Trials, and Mendelian Randomization Studies&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Advances in Nutrition, Vol 13, #4, July 2022, Pages 1044–1062, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/advances/nmab142&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/advances/nmab142&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Di Liu, Xiaoni Meng, Qiuyue Tian, Weijie Cao, Xin Fan, Lijuan Wu, Manshu Song, Qun Meng, Wei Wang, Youxin Wang&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Observational studies, randomized controlled trials (RCTs), and Mendelian randomization (MR) studies have yielded inconsistent results on the associations of vitamin D concentrations with multiple health outcomes. In the present umbrella review we aimed to evaluate the effects of low vitamin D concentrations and vitamin D supplementation on multiple health outcomes. We summarized current evidence obtained from meta-analyses of observational studies that examined associations between vitamin D concentrations and multiple health outcomes, meta-analyses of RCTs that investigated the effect of vitamin D supplementation on multiple health outcomes, and MR studies that explored the causal associations of vitamin D concentrations with various diseases (international prospective register of systematic reviews PROSPERO registration number CRD42018091434).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuberculosis not prevented by a tiny amount of vitamin D (equiv to 1,400 IU daily) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tuberculosis-not-prevented-by-a-tiny-amount-of-vitamin-d-equiv-to-1400-iu-daily-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tuberculosis-not-prevented-by-a-tiny-amount-of-vitamin-d-equiv-to-1400-iu-daily-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-supplementation-to-prevent-tuberculosis-infection-in-south-african-schoolchildren-multicentre-phase-3-double-blind-randomised-placebo-controlled-trial-vidikids&#34;&gt;Vitamin D supplementation to prevent tuberculosis infection in South African schoolchildren: multicentre phase 3 double-blind randomised placebo-controlled trial (ViDiKids)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Int J Infect Dis. 2023 May 19;S1201-9712(23)00562-3. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2023.05.010&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2023.05.010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keren Middelkoop 1, Justine Stewart 1, Neil Walker 2, Carmen Delport 3, David A Jolliffe 4, Anna K Coussens 5, James Nuttall 6, Jonathan C Y Tang 7, William D Fraser 7, Christopher J Griffiths 2, Geeta Trilok Kumar 8, Suzanne Filteau 9, Richard L Hooper 2, Robert J Wilkinson 10, Linda-Gail Bekker 3, Adrian R Martineau 11&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chronic tonsillitis virtually eliminated in children by Vitamin D (50,000 IU weekly) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-tonsillitis-virtually-eliminated-in-children-by-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chronic-tonsillitis-virtually-eliminated-in-children-by-vitamin-d-50000-iu-weekly-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;impact-of-vitamin-d-in-children-with-chronic-tonsillitis-immunohistochemical-study-of-cd68-polarisation-and-proinflammatory-cytokines-estimation&#34;&gt;Impact of vitamin D in children with chronic tonsillitis (immunohistochemical study of CD68 polarisation and proinflammatory cytokines estimation)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sci Rep . 2023 May 17;13(1):8014. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-33970-x.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-33970-x.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ayat Abu-Elnasr Awwad 1, Rehab A Hasan 2, Mohamed Ghazy Attia Hablas 3, Osama Mohammad Mohammad Abdelhay 4, Yahia Mohmmed Ahmed Dawood 5, Bothina Ahmed Mohamed 1, Khadiga Abdallah Abd Rabou 1, Taghreed Mahmoud Mohamed Salem 1, Marwa Elhady 6, Gehad Nabil Abd El-Aal 6, Ahmed Helal Elsayed Ahmed 7, Ahmed Ibrahim Mostafa Hasan 7, Asmaa Abd Elsalam Elmadbouly 8, Mohamed Basiouny Yahia 9, Walaa Mohamed Omar Ashry 10, Said S M M El Sayed 4, Ashraf M M Algendy 4, Ahmad M F Alkot 4, Mohamed F Farag 11, Ashraf Abdel Aty El Shenawy Emara 4, Fayez Mohammed Abd Elfattah Elbayoumy 12, Hany Fawzy Ali 9, Mohamed Morshdy Aldesoky 13, Raafat Abd-Rabow Abd-Eltwab 13, Samia M Manawy 14, Eman Mohamed Faruk 15&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infants getting an additional 800 IU of vitamin D for 2 years had 60% fewer psychiatric symptoms at age 7 – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/infants-getting-an-additional-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-2-years-had-60-percent-few-ms-at-age-7-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/infants-getting-an-additional-800-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-2-years-had-60-percent-few-ms-at-age-7-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;~~#00F:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reduced: Autism, ADHD, Depression. etc&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finland was supplementing milk with Vitamin D during the study, so both groups got more D&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefit if it had increased vitamin D dose with increased body weight&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Infant body weight triples in 24 months - so probably need 3600 IU at 24 months&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefit if it had adjusted vitamin D dose with BMI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Obese needs &amp;gt;2X more vitamin D&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefits if supplementation had started before birth&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study might have found better benefits with non-daily supplementation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study found a 79% reduction in problems if 1200 IU  when mothers had Vitamin D levels &amp;lt;30 ng&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preemies need even more vitamin D – no comment in study about preemies~~&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effect-of-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-the-first-2-years-of-life-on-psychiatric-symptoms-at-ages-6-to-8-years-a-randomized-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;Effect of Vitamin D3 Supplementation in the First 2 Years of Life on Psychiatric Symptoms at Ages 6 to 8 Years: A Randomized Clinical Trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JAMA Netw Open. 2023 May 1;6(5):e2314319. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.14319.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.14319.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Response to infant 2,000 IU Vitamin D daily was in 194 ng, monthly dosing was 20% less – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/response-to-infant-2000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-was-in-194-ng-monthly-dosing-was-20-percent-less-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/response-to-infant-2000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-was-in-194-ng-monthly-dosing-was-20-percent-less-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;daily-vs-monthly-oral-vitamin-d3-for-treatment-of-symptomatic-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-infants-a-randomized-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;Daily vs. monthly oral vitamin D3 for treatment of symptomatic vitamin D deficiency in infants: a randomized controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab . 2023 May 18. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1515/jpem-2023-0146&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1515/jpem-2023-0146&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anupriya Gora 1, Preeti Singh 2, Ekta Debnath 3, Rajeev Kumar Malhotra 4, Anju Seth 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objectives: Compare the efficacy and safety of daily vs. monthly oral vitamin D3 in treating symptomatic vitamin D deficiency in infants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Randomized Controlled Trials in VitaminDWiki - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/randomized-controlled-trials-in-vitamindwiki-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/randomized-controlled-trials-in-vitamindwiki-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;959-vitamindwiki-pages-with-rct-in-title&#34;&gt;959+ VitaminDWiki pages with RCT in title&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{list max=&amp;ldquo;2050&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;rct&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; shownbitems=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xA;&#xA;{column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=title format=&amp;ldquo;objectlink&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color: #e0e0e0;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;&#xA;Markdown:&#xA;--------&#xA;&#xA;#### 959+ VitaminDWiki pages with RCT in title&#xA;&#xA;This list is automatically updated&#xA;&#xA;{LIST()}&#xA;&#xA;{list max=&amp;quot;2050&amp;quot;}&#xA;&#xA;&amp;lt;!-- {filter field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;rct&amp;quot;} --&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;&amp;lt;!-- {filter type=&amp;quot;wiki page&amp;quot;} --&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;{sort mode=&amp;quot;modification_date_major_desc&amp;quot;}&#xA;&#xA;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;quot;table&amp;quot;)}&#xA;&#xA;   {tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;quot;n&amp;quot; shownbitems=&amp;quot;y&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&#xA;&#xA;    {column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xA;&#xA;    {column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xA;&#xA;{OUTPUT}&#xA;&#xA;{FORMAT(name=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;)}{display name=title format=&amp;quot;objectlink&amp;quot;}{FORMAT}&#xA;&#xA;{FORMAT(name=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;quot;date&amp;quot;}{FORMAT}&#xA;&#xA;{LIST}&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;AST Structure:&#xA;-------------&#xA;├── HeadingNode&#xA;│   full_match: `!!!!959+ VitaminDWiki pages with RCT in title`&#xA;│   inner_content: `959+ VitaminDWiki pages with RCT in title`&#xA;│   level: `4`&#xA;│   children:&#xA;│   ├── TextNode&#xA;│   │   full_match: `959+ VitaminDWiki pages with RCT in title`&#xA;│   │   inner_content: `959+ VitaminDWiki pages with RCT in title`├── TextNode&#xA;│   full_match: `\n`&#xA;│   inner_content: `\n`├── EmphasisNode&#xA;│   full_match: `&amp;#39;&amp;#39;This list is automatically updated&amp;#39;&amp;#39;`&#xA;│   inner_content: `This list is automatically updated`&#xA;│   children:&#xA;│   ├── TextNode&#xA;│   │   full_match: `This list is automatically updated`&#xA;│   │   inner_content: `This list is automatically updated`├── TextNode&#xA;│   full_match: `\n{LIST()}\n{list max=&amp;quot;2050&amp;quot;}\n`&#xA;│   inner_content: `\n{LIST()}\n{list max=&amp;quot;2050&amp;quot;}\n`├── FilterNode&#xA;│   full_match: `{filter field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;rct&amp;quot;}`&#xA;│   inner_content: ``&#xA;│   attrs_dict:&#xA;│   │   raw_content: field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;rct&amp;quot;&#xA;│   │   field: title&#xA;│   │   content: rct├── TextNode&#xA;│   full_match: `\n`&#xA;│   inner_content: `\n`├── FilterNode&#xA;│   full_match: `{filter type=&amp;quot;wiki page&amp;quot;}`&#xA;│   inner_content: ``&#xA;│   attrs_dict:&#xA;│   │   raw_content: type=&amp;quot;wiki page&amp;quot;&#xA;│   │   type: wiki page├── TextNode&#xA;│   full_match: `\n{sort mode=&amp;quot;modification_date_major_desc&amp;quot;}\n{OUTPUT(template=&amp;quot;table&amp;quot;)}\n   {tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;quot;n&amp;quot; shownbitems=&amp;quot;y&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}\n    {column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}\n    {column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}\n{OUTPUT}\n{FORMAT(name=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;)}{display name=title format=&amp;quot;objectlink&amp;quot;}{FORMAT}\n{FORMAT(name=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;quot;date&amp;quot;}{FORMAT}\n{LIST}\n`&#xA;│   inner_content: `\n{sort mode=&amp;quot;modification_date_major_desc&amp;quot;}\n{OUTPUT(template=&amp;quot;table&amp;quot;)}\n   {tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;quot;n&amp;quot; shownbitems=&amp;quot;y&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}\n    {column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}\n    {column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}\n{OUTPUT}\n{FORMAT(name=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;)}{display name=title format=&amp;quot;objectlink&amp;quot;}{FORMAT}\n{FORMAT(name=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;quot;date&amp;quot;}{FORMAT}\n{LIST}\n`&#xA;&#xA;Original Tiki:&#xA;-------------&#xA;!!!!959+ VitaminDWiki pages with RCT in title&#xD;&#xA;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;This list is automatically updated&amp;#39;&amp;#39;&#xD;&#xA;{LIST()}&#xD;&#xA;{list max=&amp;quot;2050&amp;quot;}&#xD;&#xA;{filter field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;rct&amp;quot;}&#xD;&#xA;{filter type=&amp;quot;wiki page&amp;quot;}&#xD;&#xA;{sort mode=&amp;quot;modification_date_major_desc&amp;quot;}&#xD;&#xA;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;quot;table&amp;quot;)}&#xD;&#xA;   {tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;quot;n&amp;quot; shownbitems=&amp;quot;y&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&#xD;&#xA;    {column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xD;&#xA;    {column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xD;&#xA;{OUTPUT}&#xD;&#xA;{FORMAT(name=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;)}{display name=title format=&amp;quot;objectlink&amp;quot;}{FORMAT}&#xD;&#xA;{FORMAT(name=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;quot;date&amp;quot;}{FORMAT}&#xD;&#xA;{LIST}&#xD;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-stroke Vitamin D supplementation helped in 11 ways</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-stroke-vitamin-d-supplementation-helped-in-11-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-stroke-vitamin-d-supplementation-helped-in-11-ways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-systematic-review-examining-the-effect-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-functional-outcomes-post-stroke&#34;&gt;A systematic review examining the effect of vitamin D supplementation on functional outcomes post-stroke&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clin Rehabil. 2023 May 11 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/02692155231174599&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1177/02692155231174599&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jamie L Fleet 1 2 3, Amanda McIntyre 3 4, Shannon Janzen 3, Marcus Saikaley 3, Michael Qaqish 5, Robert Cianfarani 5, Alexandra Papaioannou 5 6 7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objective: The objective of this systematic review was to explore the effect of vitamin D supplementation on functional outcomes (motor function, mobility, activities of daily living and stroke impairment) among individuals post-stroke (PROSPERO CRD42022296462).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4X reduction in prediabetes progressing to T2D if more than 50 ng of vitamin D – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/4x-reduction-in-prediabetes-progressing-to-t2d-if-more-than-50-ng-of-vitamin-d-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/4x-reduction-in-prediabetes-progressing-to-t2d-if-more-than-50-ng-of-vitamin-d-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-and-risk-for-type-2-diabetes-in-people-with-prediabetes--a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-individual-participant-data-from-3-randomized-clinical-trials&#34;&gt;Vitamin D and Risk for Type 2 Diabetes in People With Prediabetes : A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Individual Participant Data From 3 Randomized Clinical Trials&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ann Intern Med. 2023 Mar;176(3):355-363. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7326/M22-3018&#34;&gt;doi: 10.7326/M22-3018&lt;/a&gt;   PDF is behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anastassios G Pittas 1, Tetsuya Kawahara 2, Rolf Jorde 3, Bess Dawson-Hughes 4, Ellen M Vickery 1, Edith Angellotti 5, Jason Nelson 1, Thomas A Trikalinos 6, Ethan M Balk 6&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Sclerosis is again not fought by 5,000 IU vitamin D daily (need at least 10X more) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-is-again-not-fought-by-5000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-need-at-least-10x-more-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/multiple-sclerosis-is-again-not-fought-by-5000-iu-vitamin-d-daily-need-at-least-10x-more-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fighting MS with Vitamin D needs some combination of:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Larger Vitamin D doses: &amp;gt;50,000 IU if taken daily&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gut-friendly form of vitamin D&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magnesium - increases effective IU by 30%&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Take Vitamin D with evening meal - increases effective IU by 30%&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D Receptor activators: i.e. Resveratrol, Curcumin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Take Vitamin D non-daily - say weekly - gets past any Vitamin D Receptor limitation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;high-dose-vitamin-d3-supplementation-in-relapsing-remitting-multiple-sclerosis-a-randomised-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;High-dose vitamin D3 supplementation in relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis: a randomised clinical trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EClinicalMedicine. 2023 Apr 13;59:101957. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.101957&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.101957&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resulting childhood Asthma cut in half if 4,400 IU Vitamin D (5 ways to improve it) - RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/resulting-childhood-asthma-cut-in-half-if-4400-iu-vitamin-d-5-ways-to-improve-it-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/resulting-childhood-asthma-cut-in-half-if-4400-iu-vitamin-d-5-ways-to-improve-it-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;baseline-25ohd-timing-of-supplementation-initiation-and-prenatal-vitamin-d-supplementation-efficacy-to-prevent-offspring-asthma-or-recurrent-wheeze&#34;&gt;Baseline 25(OH)D, timing of supplementation initiation and prenatal vitamin D supplementation efficacy to prevent offspring asthma or recurrent wheeze&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Am J Clin Nutr. 2023 Apr 17;S0002-9165(23)46848-7. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajcnut.2023.04.019&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.ajcnut.2023.04.019&lt;/a&gt;  PDF costs $31&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iskander L C Shadid 1, Nicklas Brustad 2, Mengdi Lu 3, Bo L Chawes 2, Hans Bisgaard 2, Robert S Zeiger 4, George T O&amp;rsquo;Connor 5, Leonard B Bacharier 6, Henk-Jan Guchelaar 7, Augusto A Litonjua 8, Scott T Weiss 3, Hooman Mirzakhani 9&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NAFLD and Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nafld-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nafld-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;nafld--decreased-semi-activation-of-vitamin-d-should-use-a-form-that-does-not-need-the-liver&#34;&gt;NAFLD ==&amp;gt; decreased semi-activation of vitamin D: should use a form that does not need the liver&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/topical-vitamin-d&#34; style=&#34;color: red; text-decoration: underline;&#34; title=&#34;This post/category does not exist yet: Topical Vitamin D&#34;&gt;Topical Vitamin D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alternately: use larger doses of Vitamin D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;nafld-increased-17x-to-12x-in-recent-years-in-those-under-20---oct-2023&#34;&gt;NAFLD increased 1.7X to 12X in recent years in those under 20 - Oct 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NAFLD Has Become a Health Emergency Among Children - Mercola&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vLzPDfT2RIQ&amp;amp;t=3s&amp;amp;ab_channel=JayFeldmanWellness&#34;&gt;1 hour YouTube video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fracture 4X less likely following kidney transplant if high-dose Vitamin D (100,000 every 2 weeks) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fracture-4x-less-likely-following-kidney-transplant-if-high-dose-vitamin-d-100000-every-2-weeks-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fracture-4x-less-likely-following-kidney-transplant-if-high-dose-vitamin-d-100000-every-2-weeks-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;nonskeletal-and-skeletal-effects-of-high-doses-versus-low-doses-of-vitamin-d3-in-renal-transplant-recipients-results-of-the-vitale-vitamin-d-supplementation-in-renal-transplant-recipients-study-a-randomized-clinical-trial&#34;&gt;Nonskeletal and skeletal effects of high doses versus low doses of vitamin D3 in renal transplant recipients: Results of the VITALE (VITamin D supplementation in renAL transplant recipients) study, a randomized clinical trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Am J Transplant . 2023 Jan 9;S1600-6135(22)29286-7. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajt.2022.12.007&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.ajt.2022.12.007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Marie Courbebaisse 1, Aurelie Bourmaud 2, Jean-Claude Souberbielle 3, Rebecca Sberro-Soussan 4, Valérie Moal 5, Yannick Le Meur 6, Nassim Kamar 7, Laetitia Albano 8, Antoine Thierry 9, Jacques Dantal 10, Clément Danthu 11, Karine Moreau 12, Emmanuel Morelon 13, Anne-Elisabeth Heng 14, Dominique Bertrand 15, Nadia Arzouk 16, Peggy Perrin 17, Marie-Pascale Morin 18, Philippe Rieu 19, Claire Presne 20, Philippe Grimbert 21, Didier Ducloux 22, Matthias Büchler 23, Moglie Le Quintrec 24, Nacéra Ouali 25, Vincent Pernin 26, Nicolas Bouvier 27, Antoine Durrbach 28, Eric Alamartine 29, Christine Randoux 30, Virginie Besson 31, Marc Hazzan 32, Justine Pages 33, Sandra Colas 34, Marie-Liesse Piketty 3, Gérard Friedlander 35, Dominique Prié 36, Corinne Alberti 2, Eric Thervet 37&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2,000 IU of Vitamin D per kg of food – best growth, bone strength, etc. (pig trial)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-of-food-best-growth-bone-strength-etc-pig-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-per-kg-of-food-best-growth-bone-strength-etc-pig-trial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;effects-of-25ohvd3-on-growth-performance-pork-quality-and-calcium-deposit-in-growing-finishing-pigs&#34;&gt;Effects of 25(OH)VD3 on Growth Performance, Pork Quality and Calcium Deposit in Growing-Finishing Pigs&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Animals (Basel) . 2022 Dec 26;13(1):86. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ani13010086.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/ani13010086.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zeyu Zhang 1, Gang Zhang 1, Jindang Cao 2, Baoqin Qiu 2, Xiaoyu Qin 2, Jinbiao Zhao 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study was conducted to evaluate the effects of 25(OH)VD3 with different inclusion levels of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;0, 25, 50 and 75 µg/kg in the diet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  on growth performance, nutrient digestibility, bone properties and pork quality in growing-finishing pigs. The results showed that the average daily gain (p &amp;lt; 0.05) and body weight (p &amp;lt; 0.10) of pigs showed a trend of increasing quadratically as inclusion levels of 25(OH)VD3 increased.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
