<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Immunity on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/immunity.html</link><description>Recent content in Immunity on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/immunity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Influenza in Norway not reduced by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/influenza-in-norway-not-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/influenza-in-norway-not-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-did-not-prevent-influenza-like-illness-as-diagnosed-retrospectively-by-questionnaires-in-subjects-participating-in-randomized-clinical-trials">Vitamin D supplementation did not prevent influenza-like illness as diagnosed retrospectively by questionnaires in subjects participating in randomized clinical trials.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Scand J Infect Dis. 2011 Oct 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorde R &lt;a href="mailto:rolf.jorde@unn.no">rolf.jorde@unn.no&lt;/a> , Witham M, Janssens W, Rolighed L, Borchhardt K, Boer IH, Grimnes G, Hutchinson MS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinology Research Group, Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, and Medical Clinic, University Hospital of North Norway , Tromsø , Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with a number of diseases, including influenza. Whether or not this reflects a causal relationship is unknown. We therefore wanted to examine if supplementation with vitamin D would affect the incidence and severity of influenza-like disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An update on vitamin D and human immunity</title><link>/posts/an-update-on-vitamin-d-and-human-immunity.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/an-update-on-vitamin-d-and-human-immunity.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Martin Hewison &lt;a href="mailto:mhewison@mednet.ucla.edu">mhewison@mednet.ucla.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1111/j.1365-2265.2011.04261.x&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical Endocrinology&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accepted Article (Accepted, unedited articles published online for future issues)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keywords: vitamin D;CYP27B1;vitamin D receptor;toll-like receptor;monocyte;neutrophil;T-cell;cathelicidin;tuberculosis&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the last five years there has been a remarkable change in our understanding of the health benefits of vitamin D. The classical actions of vitamin D as a determinant of mineral metabolism and rachitic bone disease have been expanded to include a broader role in skeletal homeostasis and prevalent bone disorders such as osteoporosis. However, it is the non-skeletal functions of vitamin D that have attracted most attention. Although, pluripotent responses to vitamin D have been recognized for many years, our new perspective on non-classical vitamin D function stems from two more recent concepts. The first is that impaired, vitamin D status is common to many populations across the globe. This has prompted studies to explore the health impact of sub-optimal circulating levels of vitamin D, with association studies linking vitamin D ‘insufficiency’ to several chronic health problems including autoimmune and cardiovascular disease, hypertension and common cancers. In support of a broader role for vitamin D in human health, studies in vitro and using animal models have highlighted immunomodulatory and anti-cancer effects of vitamin D that appear to depend on localized activation of vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Influenza Mortality not well modeled by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/influenza-mortality-not-well-modeled-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/influenza-mortality-not-well-modeled-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="shortcomings-of-vitamin-d-based-model-simulations-of-seasonal-influenza">Shortcomings of vitamin D-based model simulations of seasonal influenza.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2011;6(6):e20743. Epub 2011 Jun 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shaman J, Jeon CY, Giovannucci E, Lipsitch M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Environmental Health Sciences, Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University, New York, New York, United States of America. &lt;a href="mailto:jls106@columbia.edu">jls106@columbia.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seasonal variation in serum concentration of the vitamin D metabolite 25(OH) vitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>, which contributes to host immune function, has been hypothesized to be the underlying source of observed influenza seasonality in temperate regions. The objective of this study was to determine whether observed 25(OH)D levels could be used to simulate observed influenza infection rates. Data of mean and variance in 25(OH)D serum levels by month were obtained from the Health Professionals Follow-up Study and used to parameterize an individual-based model of influenza transmission dynamics in two regions of the United States. Simulations were compared with observed daily influenza excess &lt;strong>mortality data.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some immunodeficiency diseases associated with low vitamin D and increased Osteoporosis</title><link>/posts/some-immunodeficiency-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-increased-osteoporosis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-immunodeficiency-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-increased-osteoporosis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="osteoporosis-an-ignored-complication-of-cvid">Osteoporosis: An ignored complication of CVID.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2011 Nov;22(7):676-83. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01187.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01187.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Jun 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Baris S, Ozen A, Ercan H, Karakoc-Aydiner E, Cagan H, Ozdemir C, Barlan M, Bahceciler NN, Barlan IB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatric Allergy and Immunology, Marmara University, Istanbul, Turkey Division of Pediatric Allergy and Immunology, Yeditepe University, Istanbul, Turkey Division of Radiology, Florence Nightingale Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:? Multiple factors in common variable immunodeficiency (CVID) might interfere with optimal growth and maturation and potentially compromise bone health.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D helps T-cell and immune system – overview</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-t-cell-and-immune-system-overview.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-t-cell-and-immune-system-overview.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-immune-function-an-overview">Vitamin D and immune function: an overview&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Proc Nutr Soc. 2011 Aug 18:1-12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hewison M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UCLA and Orthopaedic Hospital Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and the Orthopaedic Hospital Research Center, David Geffen School of Medicine at UCLA, 615 Charles E. Young, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/hewsion.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;p>Immunomodulatory actions of vitamin D have been recognised for over a quarter of a century, but it is only in the last few years that the significance of this to normal human physiology has become apparent. Two key factors have underpinned this revised perspective. Firstly, there are increasing data linking vitamin insufficiency with prevalent immune disorders. Improved awareness of low circulating levels of precursor 25-hydroxyvitamin D in populations across the globe has prompted epidemiological investigations of health problems associated with vitamin D insufficiency. Prominent among these are autoimmune diseases such as multiple sclerosis, type 1 diabetes and Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease, but more recent studies indicate that infections such as tuberculosis may also be linked to low 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels. The second factor expanding the link between vitamin D and the immune system is our improved knowledge of the mechanisms that facilitate this association.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Staph infection reduced 50 percent when have more than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/staph-infection-reduced-50-percent-when-have-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/staph-infection-reduced-50-percent-when-have-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="staphylococcus-aureus-nasal-carriage-is-associated-with-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-gender-and-smoking-status-the-tromsø-staph-and-skin-study">Staphylococcus aureus nasal carriage is associated with serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels, gender and smoking status. The Tromsø Staph and Skin Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2011 Aug 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olsen K, Falch BM, Danielsen K, Johannessen M, Ericson Sollid JU, Thune I, Grimnes G, Jorde R, Simonsen GS, Furberg AS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Microbiology and Infection Control, University Hospital of North Norway, 9038, Tromsø, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:karina.olsen@unn.no">karina.olsen@unn.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D induces the expression of antimicrobial peptides with activity against Staphylococcus aureus. Thus, we studied the association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and S. aureus nasal colonization and carriage. Nasal swabs, blood samples and clinical data from 2,115 women and 1,674 men, aged 30-87 years, were collected in the Tromsø Staph and Skin Study 2007-08, as part of the population-based sixth Tromsø Study. Multivariate logistic regression analyses were stratified by recognized risk factors for S. aureus carriage: sex, age and smoking. In non-smoking men, we observed a 6.6% and 6.7% decrease in the probability of S. aureus colonization and carriage, respectively, by each 5 nmol/l increase in serum 25(OH)D concentration (P?&lt;?0.001 and P?=?0.001), and serum 25(OH)D?>?59 nmol/l and ?75 nmol/l as thresholds for ~30% and ~50% reduction in S. aureus colonization and carriage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mastocytosis and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mastocytosis-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mastocytosis-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bone-mineral-density-bone-turnover-markers-and-fractures-in-patients-with-indolent-systemic-mastocytosis---2011">Bone mineral density, bone turnover markers and fractures in patients with indolent systemic mastocytosis - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mastocytosis-society-survey-of-supplementation---2018">Mastocytosis Society Survey of supplementation - 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#web">Web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="bone-mineral-density-bone-turnover-markers-and-fractures-in-patients-with-indolent-systemic-mastocytosis---2011">Bone mineral density, bone turnover markers and fractures in patients with indolent systemic mastocytosis - 2011&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Maurizio Rossinia, b, low asterisk, E-mail The Corresponding Author, Roberta Zanottib, c, Patrizia Bonadonnab, d, Anna Artusob, c, Beatrice Carusob, e, Donatella Schenab, f, Decio Vecchiatoa, b, Massimiliano Bonifaciob, c, Ombretta Viapianaa, b, Davide Gattia, b, Gianenrico Sennab, d, Annamaria Ricciog, Giovanni Passalacquag, Giovanni Pizzolob, c and Silvano Adamia, b&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yet again - more than 10000 IU of vitamin D treats MS</title><link>/posts/yet-again-more-than-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-treats-ms.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yet-again-more-than-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-treats-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="sunshine-vitamin-sheds-light-on-ms">Sunshine Vitamin Sheds Light on MS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://sciencemedicine.org/content/3/90/90ec102.short%20">Science Translational Medicine Home &amp;gt; 6 July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol. 3, Issue 90, p. 90ec102&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rebecca S. Boxer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Case Western Reserve University, School of Medicine, Cleveland, OH 44106, USA. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:Rebecca.Boxer@UHhospitals.org">Rebecca.Boxer@UHhospitals.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mother’s advice to get out into the sunshine may be better advice then many realize. Vitamin D, the sunshine vitamin, which is produced in skin exposed to ultraviolet (UVB) light, may have important down-regulatory effects on the inflammatory response in patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Additional 4 ng of vitamin D reduced chance of infection by 7 percent</title><link>/posts/additional-4-ng-of-vitamin-d-reduced-chance-of-infection-by-7-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/additional-4-ng-of-vitamin-d-reduced-chance-of-infection-by-7-percent.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D patent for treating immune system diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wo2008039409httpwwwwipointpatentscopesearchenwo2008039409-world-wide-patent---2008">&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/WO2008039409">(WO2008039409)&lt;/a> World-Wide patent - 2008&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="treatment-and-prevention-of-diseases-or-conditions-of-the--immune-system-or-infectious-diseases">TREATMENT AND PREVENTION OF DISEASES OR CONDITIONS OF THE &lt;strong>IMMUNE SYSTEM OR INFECTIOUS DISEASES&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>allergic rhinitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eczema,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>psoriasis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>food allergy,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>type-1 diabetes,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>ulcerative colitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>rheumatoid arthritis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>multiple sclerosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>lupus,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>tuberculosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>parasitic infection, etc,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>MRSA inpatient cost 2X higher if less than 20 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mrsa-inpatient-cost-2x-higher-if-less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mrsa-inpatient-cost-2x-higher-if-less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="healthcare-costs-of-methicillin-resistant-staphylococcus-aureus-and-pseudomonas-aeruginosa-infections-in-veterans-role-of-vitamin-d-deficiency">Healthcare costs of methicillin resistant Staphylococcus aureus and Pseudomonas aeruginosa infections in veterans: role of vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2011 Jun 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Youssef D, Bailey B, El-Abbassi A, Vannoy M, Manning T, Moorman JP, Peiris AN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Infectious Diseases, East Tennessee State University, Johnson City, TN, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:estecina@hotmail.com">estecina@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methicillin resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) and Pseudomonas aeruginosa (P. aeruginosa) infections are frequently associated with hospitalization and increased healthcare costs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Elderly taking extra vitamin D should expect fewer falls AND less flu</title><link>/posts/elderly-taking-extra-vitamin-d-should-expect-fewer-falls-and-less-flu.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/elderly-taking-extra-vitamin-d-should-expect-fewer-falls-and-less-flu.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="preventing-two-birds-with-one-stone-improving-vitamin-d-levels-in-the-elderly">(Preventing) two birds with one stone: improving vitamin d levels in the elderly.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Prim Health Care. 2011 Jun 1;3(2):150-2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lawless S, White P, Murdoch P, Leitch S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amity Health Centre, 343 Highgate, Roslyn, Dunedin 9010, New Zealand. &lt;a href="mailto:susie@amityhc.co.nz">susie@amityhc.co.nz&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND CONTEXT: A majority of adults have sub-optimal vitamin D levels in the winter in southern New Zealand. This is associated with an increased risk of falls and fragility fractures in the elderly, with long-term adverse outcomes likely. Vitamin D supplementation decreases the risks of both falls and fractures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is a T-cell modulator in multiple sclerosis – April 2011.</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-a-t-cell-modulator-in-multiple-sclerosis-april-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-a-t-cell-modulator-in-multiple-sclerosis-april-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-as-a-t-cell-modulator-in-multiple-sclerosis">Vitamin D as a T-cell modulator in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Vitam Horm. 2011;86:401-28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Smolders J, Damoiseaux J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School for Mental Health and Neuroscience, Maastricht University Medical Center, Maastricht, The Netherlands; Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Clinical and Experimental Immunology, Maastricht University Medical Center, Maastricht, The Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a potent immune modulator, keeping the T-cell compartment in a more tolerogenic state. Multiple sclerosis (MS), a disease in which an autoreactive T-cell response contributes to inflammation in the central nervous system, has been associated with vitamin D deficiency. The effects of vitamin D on the immune system are believed to be an important driver of this association. In this chapter, we elaborate on vitamin D as a modulator of the T-cell response. This discussion will be placed in the perspective of MS as a T-cell-mediated disease and in the perspective of the numerous association studies on vitamin D deficiency and multiple health outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Can Vitamin D Replace Flu Shots – WSJ</title><link>/posts/can-vitamin-d-replace-flu-shots-wsj.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/can-vitamin-d-replace-flu-shots-wsj.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="can-vitamin-d-replace-flu-shotshttponlinewsjcomarticlesb10001424052748704156304576003531437073192html20">&lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704156304576003531437073192.html%20">Can Vitamin D Replace Flu Shots?&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="by-laura-johannes--wall-street-journal--dec-2010">By LAURA JOHANNES Wall Street Journal Dec 2010&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vitamin D, long known for its beneficial effect on bones, is increasingly being studied to see if it helps prevent colds and flus. Based on early research results, some doctors are recommending high doses to help stave off the upper respiratory infections, with some even speculating it could be a substitute to the annual flu shot. But while it&amp;rsquo;s well established that vitamin D boosts the immune system, many scientists say so far there&amp;rsquo;s insufficient evidence that taking it will help keep a cold or flu away.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Journal on vitamins and hormones has several papers on vitamin D – 2011</title><link>/posts/journal-on-vitamins-and-hormones-has-several-papers-on-vitamin-d-2011.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/journal-on-vitamins-and-hormones-has-several-papers-on-vitamin-d-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-regulation-of-immune-function">Vitamin D regulation of immune function&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-inflammatory-bowel-disease">Vitamin d and inflammatory bowel disease.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-innate-and-adaptive-immunity">Vitamin d and innate and adaptive immunity.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-and-chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-disease-a-vicious-circle">Vitamin d deficiency and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease a vicious circle.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-and-connective-tissue-disease">Vitamin d deficiency and connective tissue disease.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#maternal-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-its-relation-to-immune-mediated-diseases-in-the-offspring">Maternal vitamin d during pregnancy and its relation to immune-mediated diseases in the offspring.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-effects-on-lung-immunity-and-respiratory-diseases">Vitamin d effects on lung immunity and respiratory diseases.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-endocrine-system-and-the-immune-response-in-rheumatic-diseases">Vitamin d endocrine system and the immune response in rheumatic diseases.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#all-of-the-papers-in-the-issue">All of the papers in the issue&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-regulation-of-immune-function">Vitamin D regulation of immune function&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Vitam Horm. 2011;86:1-21.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antimicrobial implications of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/antimicrobial-implications-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/antimicrobial-implications-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Dermato-Endocreinology, Volume 3, Issue 4 October/November/December 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dima A. Youssef, Christopher W.T. Miller, Adel M. El-Abbassi, Della C. Cutchins, Coleman Cutchins, William Grant and Alan N. Peiris&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dima A. Youssef, Mountain Home VAMC Medicine Service; Mountain Home, TN USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christopher W.T. Miller, Department of Psychiatry; University of Maryland; Baltimore, MD USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adel M. El-Abbassi, Mountain Home VAMC Medicine Service; Mountain Home, TN USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Della C. Cutchins, Mountain Home VAMC Medicine Service; Mountain Home, TN USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vaginal suppository of 6300 IU vitamin D stopped vaginal infection</title><link>/posts/vaginal-suppository-of-6300-iu-vitamin-d-stopped-vaginal-infection.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vaginal-suppository-of-6300-iu-vitamin-d-stopped-vaginal-infection.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="article-re-published-in-2014-had-pregnancy-warning">Article re-published in 2014 had pregnancy warning&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Chronical cervical infections and dysplasia (CIN I, CIN II): Vaginal vitamin D (high dose) treatment - A new effective method?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No data about taking Vitamin D suppository while pregnant&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/chronical-cervical-infections-and-dysplasia-cin-i-cin-ii-vaginal-vitamin-d-high-dose-treatment.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor990note-the-original-article-below-had-been-retractedspan">&lt;span style="color:#990;">Note: The original article below had been retracted&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;This article has been retracted due to wrong content with serious consequences.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>see attached retraction PDF&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="chronical-cervical-infections-and-dysplasia-cin-i-cin-ii-vaginal-vitamin-d-high-dose-treatment-a-new-effective-method">Chronical cervical infections and dysplasia (CIN I, CIN II)-vaginal vitamin D (high dose) treatment: a new effective method.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2011 Feb 12.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yeast Infection and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/yeast-infection-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yeast-infection-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d3-a-new-drug-against-candida-albicans-petri-dish---nov-2016">Vitamin D3 a new drug against Candida albicans (petri dish) - Nov 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#from-httpwwwcandidaalbicanorg">from &lt;a href="http://www.candidaalbican.org/">http://www.candidaalbican.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#appears-that-calcium-is-needed-to-reduce-candida-albicans-and-vitamin-d-is-needed-to-increase-calcium">Appears that Calcium is needed to reduce Candida Albicans, and vitamin D is needed to increase Calcium&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#from-httpforumlowcarberorgshowthreadphpt299830">from &lt;a href="http://forum.lowcarber.org/showthread.php?t=299830">http://forum.lowcarber.org/showthread.php?t=299830&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#from-httpwwwcandidacurezonecomcandida-albicans-fungushtml">from &lt;a href="http://www.candidacurezone.com/candida-albicans-fungus.html">http://www.candidacurezone.com/candida-albicans-fungus.html&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#candida-may-interfere-with-absorption-of-magnesium-in-the-gut">Candida may interfere with absorption of Magnesium in the gut&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#oral-candidiasis-57-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-in-person-with-hiv---2012">Oral Candidiasis 5.7 X more likely if low vitamin D in person with HIV - 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-a-new-drug-against-candida-albicans-petri-dish---nov-2016">Vitamin D3 a new drug against Candida albicans (petri dish) - Nov 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1156523316302232">Vitamin D3 a new drug against Candida albicans&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10X reactions to flu vaccine when vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/10x-reactions-to-flu-vaccine-when-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10x-reactions-to-flu-vaccine-when-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-council-nov-2010-newsletterhttpwwwvitamindcouncilorgnewsletterinfluenza-flu-shots-and-vitamin-dshtml">&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindcouncil.org/newsletter/influenza-flu-shots-and-vitamin-d.shtml">Vitamin D Council Nov 2010 newsletter&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="clips">Clips&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;First, I estimate that only about 1/1,000 of people who think they have influenza A actually have influenza A. Most have other viruses.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I continue to get a flu shot as does my wife and children. &amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="interview-of-dr-cannell-dec-1-2010postsinterview-of-dr-cannell-talking-about-institute-of-medicine">&lt;a href="/posts/interview-of-dr-cannell">Interview of Dr. Cannell Dec 1 2010&lt;/a> talking about Institute of Medicine&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="clip">Clip&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">DC&lt;/span>:: I agree. In fact there is even a possibility that the &lt;strong>flu vaccine&lt;/strong> is not going to work very well in people with high vitamin D levels. The Russians have observed that when they gave the flu vaccine in the summer, that they got much less of a reaction, you know, mild fever or body aches or anything. When they gave it in the winter, there was &lt;strong>10 or 15 times higher rate of having the symptoms&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inexpensive Trick to Cure a Cold - vitamin D - Mercola</title><link>/posts/inexpensive-trick-to-cure-a-cold-vitamin-d-mercola.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inexpensive-trick-to-cure-a-cold-vitamin-d-mercola.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="clipped-from-a-simple-inexpensive-trick-to-cure-a-coldhttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20101122the-common-cold-simple-strategies-for-prevention-and-treatmentaspx-nov-22-2010">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2010/11/22/the-common-cold-simple-strategies-for-prevention-and-treatment.aspx">A Simple, Inexpensive Trick to Cure a Cold&lt;/a> Nov 22, 2010&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="how-do-you-catch-a-cold">How Do You Catch a Cold?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The most common way cold viruses are spread is not from being around coughing or sneezing, or walking barefoot in the rain, but rather from hand-to-hand contact. For instance, someone with a cold blows their nose then shakes your hand or touches surfaces that you also touch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cold viruses can live on pens, computer keyboards, coffee mugs and other objects for hours, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to come into contact with such viruses during daily life.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>