<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Immunity on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/immunity.html</link><description>Recent content in Immunity on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/immunity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Liver and interactions with vitamin D deficiency - Review</title><link>/posts/liver-and-interactions-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/liver-and-interactions-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-in-liver-diseases-from-mechanisms-to-clinical-trials">Vitamin D in liver diseases: From mechanisms to clinical trials&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10.1111/(ISSN)1440-1746">Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology&lt;/a> , &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jgh.2013.28.issue-s1/issuetoc">Vol 28 Issue &lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Yuan-Ping Han1,2, &lt;a href="mailto:hanyp@scu.edu.cn">hanyp@scu.edu.cn&lt;/a>, Yuan-Ping Han, Ming Kong&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>, Sujun Zheng&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>, Yan Ren&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>, #Longdon Zhu&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>, Hongbo Shi&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>, Zhongping Duan&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Article first published online: 15 JUL 2013DOI: 10.1111/jgh.12016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Special Issue: 7th International Symposium on Alcoholic Liver and Pancreatic Diseases and Cirrhosis.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Funding for this conference was made possible (in part) by Grant 5 R13AA20691-02 from the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA). Guest Editors: Bin Gao and Fu-Sheng Wang&lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jgh.2013.28.issue-s1/issuetoc">Volume 28, Issue Supplement S1, &lt;/a>pages 49–55, August 2013&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Immune Function – Review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-immune-function-review.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-immune-function-review.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5(7), 2502-2521; doi:10.3390/nu5072502 (doi registration under processing)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara Prietlemail, Gerlies Treiberemail, Thomas R. Pieberemail and Karin Amrein &lt;a href="mailto:karin.amrein@medunigraz.at">karin.amrein@medunigraz.at&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Internal Medicine, Medical University of Graz, Auenbruggerplatz 15, A 8036 Graz, Austria&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(This article belongs to the Special Issue Nutrients and Immune Function)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D metabolizing enzymes and vitamin D receptors are present in many cell types including various immune cells such as antigen-presenting-cells, T cells, B cells and monocytes. In vitro data show that, in addition to modulating innate immune cells, vitamin D also promotes a more tolerogenic immunological status. In vivo data from animals and from human vitamin D supplementation studies have shown beneficial effects of vitamin D on immune function, in particular in the context of autoimmunity. In this review, currently available data are summarized to give an overview of the effects of vitamin D on the immune system in general and on the regulation of inflammatory responses, as well as regulatory mechanisms connected to autoimmune diseases particularly in type 1 diabetes mellitus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The vitamin D receptor and T cell function</title><link>/posts/the-vitamin-d-receptor-and-t-cell-function.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-vitamin-d-receptor-and-t-cell-function.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor00ffigure-1--proposed-model-for-vdr-signaling-in-t-cells-span">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">FIGURE 1 | Proposed model for VDR signaling in T cells. &lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/t-cell.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Fontiers in IMMUNOLOGY, 18 June 2013 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2013.00148">doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2013.00148&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martin Kongsbak, Trine B. Levring, Carsten Geisler and Marina Rode von Essen*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of International Health, Immunology and Microbiology, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Correspondence: Marina Rode von Essen, Department of International Health, Immunology and Microbiology, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Blegdamsvej 3C, DK-2200 Copenhagen, Denmark e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:messen@sund.ku.dk">messen@sund.ku.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Deficiency May Help Spread of Hepatitis B Throughout Liver</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-may-help-spread-of-hepatitis-b-throughout-liver.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-may-help-spread-of-hepatitis-b-throughout-liver.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="press-release-06-june-2013-wiley">Press release: 06 June 2013 Wiley&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Researchers from Germany have found that low levels of vitamin D are associated with high levels of hepatitis B virus (HBV) replication. Findings published online in Hepatology, a journal of the American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases, suggest seasonal fluctuations in vitamin D and HBV levels point to a link in these variables among patients with chronic HBV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While highly effective vaccines are available, HBV still remains &lt;strong>one of the most significant infectious diseases worldwide&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D protects against many types of health problems – review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-protects-against-many-types-of-health-problems-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-effects-on-musculoskeletal-health-immunity-autoimmunity-cardiovascular-disease-cancer-fertility-pregnancy-dementia-and-mortality-a-review-of-recent-evidence">Vitamin D effects on musculoskeletal health, immunity, autoimmunity, cardiovascular disease, cancer, fertility, pregnancy, dementia and mortality-A review of recent evidence.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Autoimmun Rev. 2013 Mar 28. pii: S1568-9972(13)00040-2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.">doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pawel Pludowski a &lt;a href="mailto:p.pludowski@czd.pl">p.pludowski@czd.pl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael F. Holick b,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stefan Pilzc, d,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carol L. Wagner e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce W. Hollis e,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B. Grant f,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yehuda Shoenfeld g,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elisabeth Lerchbaum c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David J. Llewellyn h,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katharina Kienreich c,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maya Soni h&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a Department of Biochemistry, Radioimmunology and Experimental Medicine, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Health Institute, Warsaw, Poland&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Middle ear infection (Otitis Media) and Vitamin D – many studies</title><link>/posts/middle-ear-infection-otitis-media-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/middle-ear-infection-otitis-media-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#association-between-vitamin-d-and-ear-disease-a-meta-analysis-and-systematic-review---feb-2022">Association between vitamin D and ear disease: a meta-analysis and systematic review - Feb 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-seems-promising-for-otitis-media---review-july-2019">Vitamin D seems promising for Otitis Media - Review July 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-reduces-the-risk-of-acute-otitis-media-in-otitis-prone-children---2013">Vitamin D Supplementation Reduces the Risk of Acute Otitis Media in Otitis-Prone Children - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#13-less-likely-to-get-come-for-each-4-ng-higher-level-of-vitamin-d---sept-2017">13% less likely to get COME for each 4 ng higher level of Vitamin D - Sept 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#more-likely-to-get-otitis-media-with-effusion-as-well-as-less-likely-to-recover-if-low-vitamin-d---feb-2018">More likely to get otitis media with effusion as well as less likely to recover if low vitamin D - Feb 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#international-consensus-on-otitis-media-with-effusion-does-not-contain-the-word-vitamin---feb-2018">International Consensus on otitis media with effusion does not contain the word VITAMIN - Feb 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#meta-analysis-of-5-studies-failed-to-find-a-strong-association-between-low-vit-d-and-om-did-not-look-at-vdbp---oct-2016">Meta-analysis of 5 studies failed to find a strong association between low Vit D and OM (did not look at VDBP) - Oct 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="association-between-vitamin-d-and-ear-disease-a-meta-analysis-and-systematic-review---feb-2022">Association between vitamin D and ear disease: a meta-analysis and systematic review - Feb 2022&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Egyptian Journal of Otolaryngology (2022) 38:27 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/s43163-022-00199-w">https://doi.org/10.1186/s43163-022-00199-w&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and the Immune System</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-immune-system.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-immune-system.html</guid><description>&lt;p>J Investig Med. 2011 August; 59(6): 881–886. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.231/JIM.0b013e31821b8755">doi: 10.231/JIM.0b013e31821b8755&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3166406&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cynthia Aranow, MD, Investigator&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is now clear that vitamin D has important roles in addition to its classic effects on calcium and bone homeostasis. As the vitamin D receptor is expressed on immune cells (B cells, T cells and antigen presenting cells) and these immunologic cells are all are capable of synthesizing the active vitamin D metabolite, vitamin D has the capability of acting in an autocrine manner in a local immunologic milieu. Vitamin D can modulate the innate and adaptive immune responses. Deficiency in vitamin D is associated with increased autoimmunity as well as an increased susceptibility to infection. As immune cells in autoimmune diseases are responsive to the ameliorative effects of vitamin D, the beneficial effects of supplementing vitamin D deficient individuals with autoimmune disease may extend beyond the effects on bone and calcium homeostasis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tonsillectomy, tonsollitis and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/tonsillectomy-tonsollitis-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tonsillectomy-tonsollitis-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tonsils and Adenoids become inflamed when a child is fighting infection&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>    Adenoids are lymph nodes above the tonsils&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When they become inflamed they need to be aided, by vitamin D?, but not removed&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>400,000 Tonsillectomies per year in US costing $ 5,400 each average&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/adenoids-side-view.jpg" alt="image" width="300">
&lt;p>Note: Would need to breath thru the nose, not the mouth, to get any inhaled vitamin D to adenoids&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Huge difference in rate of tonsil removals in different countries&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Valley fever may be prevented and treated with Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/valley-fever-may-be-prevented-and-treated-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/valley-fever-may-be-prevented-and-treated-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#searched-valley-fever-survivor-websitehttpwwwvalleyfeversurvivorcomvfsmbsearchphpmoderesults-jan-2013--77-results-for-vitamin-d">&lt;a href="http://www.valleyfeversurvivor.com/vfsmb/search.php?mode=results">Searched Valley Fever Survivor website&lt;/a> Jan 2013 77 results for Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#valley-fever-in-wikipediahttpenwikipediaorgwikicoccidioidomycosis-fungal-infection-has-the-following-map">&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coccidioidomycosis">Valley Fever in WikiPedia&lt;/a> fungal infection, has the following map&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#those-with-coccidioidomycosis-were-80-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-deficient---oct-2011">Those with Coccidioidomycosis were 80% more likely to be vitamin D deficient - Oct 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#valley-fever-prevalance-increased-13x-to-8x---sept-2021">Valley fever prevalance increased 1.3X to 8X - Sept 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#comment-by-vitamindwiki">Comment by VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="searched-valley-fever-survivor-websitehttpwwwvalleyfeversurvivorcomvfsmbsearchphpmoderesults-jan-2013--77-results-for-vitamin-d">&lt;a href="http://www.valleyfeversurvivor.com/vfsmb/search.php?mode=results">Searched Valley Fever Survivor website&lt;/a> Jan 2013 77 results for Vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>above link dead but &lt;a href="https://www.valleyfeversurvivor.com">https://www.valleyfeversurvivor.com&lt;/a> works as of Dec 2022&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vaccine and 1000 IU of vitamin D started concurrently, vitamin D did not help – RCT</title><link>/posts/vaccine-and-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-started-concurrently-vitamin-d-did-not-help-rct.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vaccine-and-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-started-concurrently-vitamin-d-did-not-help-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="impact-of-vitamin-d-administration-on-immunogenicity-of-trivalent-inactivated-influenza-vaccine-in-previously-unvaccinated-children">Impact of vitamin D administration on immunogenicity of trivalent inactivated influenza vaccine in previously unvaccinated children.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2013 Jan 16;9(5).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Principi N, Marchisio P, Terranova L, Zampiero A, Baggi E, Daleno C, Tirelli S, Pelucchi C, Esposito S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pediatric Clinic 1; Department of Pathophysiology and Transplantation; Università degli Studi di Milano; Fondazione IRCCS Ca&amp;rsquo; Granda Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico; Milan, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As vitamin D (VD) has a significant regulatory effect on innate and adaptive immunity, the aim of this prospective, randomized, single-blinded, placebo-controlled study was to measure the impact of VD administration on the immune response to trivalent influenza vaccination (TIV). A total of 116 children (61 males, 52.6%; mean age 3.0 ± 1.0 y) with a history of recurrent acute otitis media (AOM), who had not been previously vaccinated against influenza, were randomized to receive daily VD 1,000 IU or placebo by mouth for four months. All of them received two doses of TIV (Fluarix, GlaxoSmithKline Biologicals) one month apart, with the first dose administered when VD supplementation was started. There was no difference in seroconversion or seroprotection rates, or antibody titers, in relation to any of the three influenza vaccine antigens between the VD and placebo groups, independently of baseline and post-treatment VD levels. The safety profile was also similar in the two groups. These data indicate that the daily administration of VD 1,000 IU for four months from the time of the injection of the first dose of TIV does not significantly modify the antibody response evoked by influenza vaccine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D prevents infections</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-prevents-infections.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-prevents-infections.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="how-important-is-vitamin-d-in-preventing-infections">How important is vitamin D in preventing infections?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Osteoporos Int. 2012 Nov 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lang PO, Samaras N, Samaras D, Aspinall R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nescens Centre of Preventive Medicine, Clinic of Genolier, Route du Muids, 3, 1272, Genolier, Switzerland, &lt;a href="mailto:polang@nescens.com">polang@nescens.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interaction with the immune system is one of the most recently established nonclassic effects of vitamin D (VitD). For many years, this was considered to be limited to granulomatous diseases in which synthesis of active 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)(2)D(3)) or calcitriol is known to be increased. However, recent reports have supported a role for 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) in promoting normal function of the innate and adaptive immune systems. Crucially, these effects seem to be mediated not only by the endocrine function of circulating calcitriol but also via paracrine (i.e., refers to effects to adjacent or nearby cells) and/or intracrine activity (i.e., refers to a hormone acting inside a cell) of 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) from its precursor 25(OH)D(3), the main circulating metabolite of VitD. The ability of this vitamin to influence human immune responsiveness seems to be highly dependent on the 25(OH)D(3) status of individuals and may lead to aberrant response to infection or even to autoimmunity in those who are lacking VitD. The potential health significance of this has been underlined by increasing awareness of impaired status in populations across the globe. This review will examine the current understanding of how VitD status may modulate the responsiveness of the human immune system. Furthermore, we discuss how it may play a role in host resistance to common pathogens and how effective is its supplementation for treatment or prevention of infectious diseases in humans.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: antibiotic resistant bacteria can be controlled with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-antibiotic-resistant-bacteria-can-be-controlled-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-antibiotic-resistant-bacteria-can-be-controlled-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>The lower the vitamin D level the more severe the rare bronchiectasis</title><link>/posts/the-lower-the-vitamin-d-level-the-more-severe-the-rare-bronchiectasis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-lower-the-vitamin-d-level-the-more-severe-the-rare-bronchiectasis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-is-associated-with-chronic-bacterial-colonisation-and-disease-severity-in-bronchiectasis">Vitamin-D deficiency is associated with chronic bacterial colonisation and disease severity in bronchiectasis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Thorax doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2012-202125&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James D Chalmers1, Brian J McHugh1, Catherine Docherty2, John R W Govan2, Adam T Hill1,3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 The University of Edinburgh/MRC Centre for Research Inflammation, The Queen&amp;rsquo;s Medical Research Institute, Edinburgh, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Cystic Fibrosis Group, University of Edinburgh, School of Medicine and Veterinary Medicine, Edinburgh, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Respiratory Medicine, Royal Infirmary of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UV improves immune system without increasing vitamin D levels in male mice</title><link>/posts/uv-improves-immune-system-without-increasing-vitamin-d-levels-in-male-mice.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uv-improves-immune-system-without-increasing-vitamin-d-levels-in-male-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="acute-erythemal-ultraviolet-radiation-causes-systemic-immunosuppression-in-the-absence-of-increased-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-levels-in-male-mice">Acute Erythemal Ultraviolet Radiation Causes Systemic Immunosuppression in the Absence of Increased 25-Hydroxyvitamin D(3) Levels in Male Mice.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(9):e46006. Epub 2012 Sep 26.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gorman S, Scott NM, Tan DH, Weeden CE, Tuckey RC, Bisley JL, Grimbaldeston MA, Hart PH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telethon Institute for Child Health Research and Centre for Child Health Research, University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is synthesised by ultraviolet (UV) irradiation of skin and is hypothesized to be a direct mediator of the immunosuppression that occurs following UV radiation (UVR) exposure. Both UVR and vitamin D drive immune responses towards tolerance by ultimately increasing the suppressive activities of regulatory T cells. To examine a role for UVR-induced vitamin D, vitamin D(3)-deficient mice were established by dietary vitamin D(3) restriction. In comparison to vitamin D(3)-replete mice, vitamin D(3)-deficient mice had significantly reduced serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3) (25(OH)D(3), &amp;lt;20 nmol.L(-1)) and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) (1,25(OH)(2)D(3), &amp;lt;20 pmol.L(-1)). Following either acute erythemal UVR, or chronic sub-erythemal UVR (8 exposures over 4 weeks) treatment, serum 25(OH)D(3) levels significantly increased in vitamin D(3)-deficient female &lt;strong>but not male mice&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many infant infections avoided with supplementation with 400 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/many-infant-infections-avoided-with-supplementation-with-400-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-infant-infections-avoided-with-supplementation-with-400-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Colds not decreased if people already vitamin D sufficient – RCT</title><link>/posts/colds-not-decreased-if-people-already-vitamin-d-sufficient-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colds-not-decreased-if-people-already-vitamin-d-sufficient-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D probably can prevent and treat TB and infectious diseases – 2012</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-probably-can-prevent-and-treat-tb-and-infectious-diseases-2012.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-probably-can-prevent-and-treat-tb-and-infectious-diseases-2012.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>An update on vitamin D and human immunity</title><link>/posts/an-update-on-vitamin-d-and-human-immunity.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/an-update-on-vitamin-d-and-human-immunity.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>TB vaccinations increased vitamin D levels a year later</title><link>/posts/tb-vaccinations-increased-vitamin-d-levels-a-year-later.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tb-vaccinations-increased-vitamin-d-levels-a-year-later.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="bcg-vaccination-a-role-for-vitamin-d">BCG Vaccination: A Role for Vitamin D?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2011; 6(1): e16709.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published online 2011 January 31. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0016709">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0016709&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maeve K. Lalor,1,* Sian Floyd,2 Patricia Gorak-Stolinska,1 Rosemary E. Weir,1 Rose Blitz,1 Keith Branson,2 Paul E. Fine,2 and Hazel M. Dockrell1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: BCG vaccination is administered in infancy in most countries with the aim of providing &lt;strong>protection against tuberculosis&lt;/strong> . There is increasing interest in the role of vitamin D in immunity to tuberculosis. This study objective was to determine if there was an association between circulating 25(OH)D concentrations and BCG vaccination status and cytokine responses following BCG vaccination in infants.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>7 percent less likely to get immune mediated disease if born in the fall</title><link>/posts/7-percent-less-likely-to-get-immune-mediated-disease-if-born-in-the-fall.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/7-percent-less-likely-to-get-immune-mediated-disease-if-born-in-the-fall.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#month-of-birth-vitamin-d-and-risk-of-immune-mediated-disease-a-case-control-study">Month of birth, vitamin D and risk of immune mediated disease: a case control study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#october-births-are-12-less-likely-to-get-influenza-they-think-because-of-vaccination---feb-2024">October births are 12% less likely to get influenza (they think because of vaccination) - Feb 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="month-of-birth-vitamin-d-and-risk-of-immune-mediated-disease-a-case-control-study">Month of birth, vitamin D and risk of immune mediated disease: a case control study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>BMC Medicine 2012, 10:69 doi:10.1186/1741-7015-10-69&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giulio Disanto, George Chaplin, Julia M Morahan, Gavin Giovannoni, Elina Hypponen, George C Ebers and Sreeram V Ramagopalan&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Severe Sleep Loss Reduced Immune System – wonder about vitamin D reduction</title><link>/posts/severe-sleep-loss-reduced-immune-system-wonder-about-vitamin-d-reduction.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/severe-sleep-loss-reduced-immune-system-wonder-about-vitamin-d-reduction.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D: Oxidative Stress, Immunity, and Aging – book</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-oxidative-stress-immunity-and-aging-book.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-oxidative-stress-immunity-and-aging-book.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Series: Oxidative Stress and DiseasePublished:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>December 05, 2012 by CRC Press - 480 Pages&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Editor:Adrian F. Gombart &lt;a href="mailto:adrian.gombart@oregonstate.edu">adrian.gombart@oregonstate.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hardback $149.95 ISBN 9781439850206Cat# K12283&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Focuses on the role of vitamin D in oxidation, immunity, and aging&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Includes the molecular and cellular mechanisms responsible for the benefits of vitamin D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Covers the role vitamin D plays in oxidative stress including cancer, the nervous system, stress-mediated diseases, photoprotection and energy metabolism&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Discusses the role of vitamin D in the regulation of the aging process and its impact on diseases of aging including senescence, mortality, cardiovascular disease, and inflammation&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PTH boosts immune response when vitamin D levels are low</title><link>/posts/pth-boosts-immune-response-when-vitamin-d-levels-are-low.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pth-boosts-immune-response-when-vitamin-d-levels-are-low.html</guid><description>&lt;p>(reminder: PTH = parathyroid hormone)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hormone Plays Surprise Role in Fighting Skin Infections&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: University of California, San Diego Health Sciences&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="boosts-immune-response-when-vitamin-d-levels-are-low">Boosts immune response when vitamin D levels are low&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Newswise — Antimicrobial peptides (AMPs) are molecules produced in the skin to fend off infection-causing microbes. Vitamin D has been credited with a role in their production and in the body’s overall immune response, but scientists at the University of California, San Diego School of Medicine say a hormone previously associated only with maintaining calcium homeostasis and bone health is also critical, boosting AMP expression when dietary vitamin D levels are inadequate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D's potential to reduce the risk of hospital-acquired infections</title><link>/posts/vitamin-ds-potential-to-reduce-the-risk-of-hospital-acquired-infections.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-ds-potential-to-reduce-the-risk-of-hospital-acquired-infections.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="health-careassociated-and-hospital-acquired-infections-are-two-entities-associated-with-increased-morbidity-and-mortality-dermato-endrocinology-volume-4-issue-2---aprilmayjune-2012">Health care–associated and hospital-acquired infections are two entities associated with increased morbidity and mortality. Dermato Endrocinology Volume 4, Issue 2 April/May/June 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dima A. Youssef &lt;a href="mailto:estecina@hotmail.com">estecina@hotmail.com&lt;/a>, Tamra Ranasinghe, William B. Grant and Alan N. Peiris&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They are highly costly and constitute a great burden to the health care system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency (&amp;lt; 20 ng/ml) is prevalent and may be a key contributor to both acute and chronic ill health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is associated with decreased innate immunity and increased risk for infections.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3X more colds by overweight who were low on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/3x-more-colds-by-overweight-who-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/3x-more-colds-by-overweight-who-were-low-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Narcolepsy with Cataplexy 5X more probable with lowest vitamin D</title><link>/posts/narcolepsy-with-cataplexy-5x-more-probable-with-lowest-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/narcolepsy-with-cataplexy-5x-more-probable-with-lowest-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-vitamin-d-in-narcolepsy-with-cataplexy">Low Vitamin D in Narcolepsy with Cataplexy&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bertrand Carlander 1, Anne Marie Puech-Cathala2, Isabelle Jaussent3, Sabine Scholz1, Sophie Bayard1,3, Valérie Cochen1, Yves Dauvilliers1,3*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 National Reference Network for Narcolepsy, Department of Neurology, Hôpital Gui-de-Chauliac, CHU Montpellier, Montpellier, France,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Laboratoire d&amp;rsquo;Hormonologie, Hôpital Lapeyronie, CHU Montpellier, Montpellier, France,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Inserm U1061, University of Montpellier 1, Montpellier, France&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received: February 23, 2011; Accepted: April 19, 2011; Published: May 25, 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Narcolepsy with cataplexy (NC) is currently thought to be an autoimmune-mediated disorder in which environmental risk factors make a significant contribution to its development. It was proposed that vitamin D deficiency plays a role in autoimmune diseases. Here we investigated whether NC can be associated with 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) level deficiency in patients with NC compared with gender- and age-matched normal controls.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cow, mouse, and human immune system and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cow-mouse-and-human-immune-system-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cow-mouse-and-human-immune-system-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Review of infectious diseases vitamin D trials</title><link>/posts/review-of-infectious-diseases-vitamin-d-trials.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-infectious-diseases-vitamin-d-trials.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bacterial infection in cows reduced with vitamin D</title><link>/posts/bacterial-infection-in-cows-reduced-with-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bacterial-infection-in-cows-reduced-with-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="treatment-of-an-intramammary-bacterial-infection-with-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3">Treatment of an intramammary bacterial infection with 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3).&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2011;6(10):e25479. Epub 2011 Oct 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lippolis JD, Reinhardt TA, Sacco RA, Nonnecke BJ, Nelson CD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ruminant Diseases and Immunology Research Unit, National Animal Disease Center, Agricultural Research Service, United States Department of Agriculture, Ames, Iowa, United States of America. &lt;a href="mailto:john.lippolis@ars.usda.gov">john.lippolis@ars.usda.gov&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deficiency of serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3) has been correlated with increased risk of infectious diseases such as tuberculosis and influenza. A plausible reason for this association is that expression of genes encoding important antimicrobial proteins depends on concentrations of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) produced by activated immune cells at sites of infection, and that synthesis of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) is dependent on the availability of 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3). Thus, increasing the availability of 25(OH)D(3) for immune cell synthesis of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) at sites of infection has been hypothesized to aid in clearance of the infection. This report details the treatment of an acute intramammary infection with infusion of 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3) to the site of infection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Food allergy 80 percent more likely if have certain genes and vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/food-allergy-80-percent-more-likely-if-have-certain-genes-and-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/food-allergy-80-percent-more-likely-if-have-certain-genes-and-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="gene-vitamin-d-interactions-on-food-sensitization-a-prospective-birth-cohort-study">Gene-vitamin D interactions on food sensitization: a prospective birth cohort study.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Allergy. 2011 Nov;66(11):1442-8. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1398-9995.2011.02681.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1398-9995.2011.02681.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Aug 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liu X, Wang G, Hong X, Wang D, Tsai HJ, Zhang S, Arguelles L, Kumar R, Wang H, Liu R, Zhou Y, Pearson C, Ortiz K, Schleimer R, Holt PG, Pongracic J, Price HE, Langman C, Wang X.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary Ann and J. Milburn Smith Child Health Research Program, Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Hospital, Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Research Center, Department of Pediatrics, Feinberg School of Medicine, Northwestern University, Chicago, IL, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:xnliu@childrensmemorial.org">xnliu@childrensmemorial.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some immunity diseases associated with low vitamin D and Osteoporosis</title><link>/posts/some-immunity-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-osteoporosis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-immunity-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-osteoporosis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="osteoporosis-an-ignored-complication-of-cvid">Osteoporosis: an ignored complication of CVID.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>ediatr Allergy Immunol. 2011 Nov;22(7):676-83. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01187.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01187.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Jun 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Baris S, Ozen A, Ercan H, Karakoc-Aydiner E, Cagan H, Ozdemir C, Barlan M, Bahceciler NN, Barlan IB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatric Allergy and Immunology, Marmara University, Istanbul, Turkey. &lt;a href="mailto:safabaris@hotmail.com">safabaris@hotmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Multiple factors in common variable immunodeficiency (CVID) might interfere with optimal growth and maturation and potentially compromise bone health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: We aimed to evaluate bone mineral density (BMD) of patients with CVID using dual energy X-ray absorptiometry (DEXA) and investigate risk factors associated with decreased bone density.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Viral infection reduced 90 percent with 2000 IU of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/viral-infection-reduced-90-percent-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/viral-infection-reduced-90-percent-with-2000-iu-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="comments-ample-evidence-exists-from-human-studies-that-vitamin-d-reduces-the-risk-of-selected-bacterial-and-viral-infections">Comments: Ample evidence exists from human studies that vitamin D reduces the risk of selected bacterial and viral infections&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Experimental Biology and Medicine Dec 2010; 235: 1395-1396&lt;/p>
&lt;p>William B Grant1, Mark Goldstein2 and Luca Mascitelli3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center (SUNARC), P.O. Box 641603, San Francisco, CA 94164-1603;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Fountain Medical Court, 9410 Fountain Medical Court, Suite A-200, Bonita Springs, FL 34135, USA;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Comando Brigata Alpina &amp;lsquo;Julia&amp;rsquo;, Medical Service, S. Agostino, 8, Udine 33100, Italy&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Influenza, solar radiation and vitamin D - 2009</title><link>/posts/influenza-solar-radiation-and-vitamin-d-2009.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/influenza-solar-radiation-and-vitamin-d-2009.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Dermato-Endocrinology 1:6, 307-309; November/December, 2009; © 2009 Landes Bioscience&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johan Moan, 1,2; Arne Dahlback, 2; LiWei Ma 1, and Asta Juzeniene 1, &lt;a href="mailto:asta.juzeniene@rr-research.no">asta.juzeniene@rr-research.no&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of radiation Biology; institute for Cancer research; the Norwegian radium Hospital; oslo University Hospital; Montebello, oslo Norway;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 institute of physics; University of oslo; Blindern, oslo Norway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVES: Seasonal variations in ultraviolet B (UVB) radiation cause seasonal variations in vitamin D status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This may influence immune responses and play a role in the seasonality of influenza.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On the epidemiology of influenza – 2008</title><link>/posts/on-the-epidemiology-of-influenza-2008.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/on-the-epidemiology-of-influenza-2008.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Influenza vaccine meta-analysis found moderate protection – Lancet</title><link>/posts/influenza-vaccine-meta-analysis-found-moderate-protection-lancet.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/influenza-vaccine-meta-analysis-found-moderate-protection-lancet.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="efficacy-and-effectiveness-of-influenza-vaccines-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Efficacy and effectiveness of influenza vaccines: a systematic review and meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Lancet Infect Dis. 2011 Oct 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osterholm MT, Kelley NS, Sommer A, Belongia EA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Center for Infectious Disease Research and Policy, University of Minnesota, MN, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/7x-less-risk-of-influenza-if-vitamin-d-levels-higher-than-30-ng" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: 7X less risk of influenza if Vitamin D levels higher than 30 ng – Oct 2017">7X less risk of influenza if Vitamin D levels higher than 30 ng – Oct 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: No published meta-analyses have assessed efficacy and effectiveness of licensed influenza vaccines in the USA with sensitive and highly specific diagnostic tests to confirm influenza.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The difference between a prophet and a madman – by Dr. Cannell</title><link>/posts/the-difference-between-a-prophet-and-a-madman-by-dr-cannell.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-difference-between-a-prophet-and-a-madman-by-dr-cannell.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Br J Nutr. 2011 Nov;106(9):1317-8. Epub 2011 Jun 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cannell JJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D Council, 1241 Johnson Avenue, CA, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:jjcannell@vitamindcouncil.org">jjcannell@vitamindcouncil.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which is a comment on Br J Nutr. 2011 Nov;106(9):1433-40. &lt;a href="/posts/click-here-at-vitamindwiki" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1811">CLICK HERE at VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following was copied from &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Facebook &lt;/span>&lt;/strong> - &lt;strong>bolding&lt;/strong> emphasis by VitaminDWiki&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I realize that when I write for a journal that most of my readers cannot access my writing. This month the British Journal of Nutrition invited me to write an article; it is below. To put the article into context, my long-time readers will remember the excitement back in 2005 when I discovered that vitamin D appeared to prevent influenza.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reduce probability of getting the Flu</title><link>/posts/reduce-probability-of-getting-the-flu.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reduce-probability-of-getting-the-flu.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="this-page-is-in-two-sections---what-to-do-followed-by--details">This page is in two sections: &lt;strong>WHAT TO DO,&lt;/strong> followed by &lt;strong>DETAILS&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - &lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-staggering-body-of-evidence-and-study-points-to-vitamin-d-as-a-better-flu-deterrent-than-a-flu-shot">A staggering body of evidence and study points to vitamin D as a better flu deterrent than a flu shot.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="greatly-reduce-your-chance-of-getting-the-flu-by-taking-just-one-vitamin-d-capsule-twice-a-month">Greatly reduce your chance of getting the flu by taking just one vitamin D capsule twice a month&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Buy a bottle of &lt;strong>50,000 IU of vitamin D3&lt;/strong> capsules and mark your calendar to take &lt;strong>one every second week&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Influenza in Norway not reduced by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/influenza-in-norway-not-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/influenza-in-norway-not-reduced-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-did-not-prevent-influenza-like-illness-as-diagnosed-retrospectively-by-questionnaires-in-subjects-participating-in-randomized-clinical-trials">Vitamin D supplementation did not prevent influenza-like illness as diagnosed retrospectively by questionnaires in subjects participating in randomized clinical trials.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Scand J Infect Dis. 2011 Oct 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jorde R &lt;a href="mailto:rolf.jorde@unn.no">rolf.jorde@unn.no&lt;/a> , Witham M, Janssens W, Rolighed L, Borchhardt K, Boer IH, Grimnes G, Hutchinson MS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Endocrinology Research Group, Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, and Medical Clinic, University Hospital of North Norway , Tromsø , Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with a number of diseases, including influenza. Whether or not this reflects a causal relationship is unknown. We therefore wanted to examine if supplementation with vitamin D would affect the incidence and severity of influenza-like disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Influenza Mortality not well modeled by vitamin D</title><link>/posts/influenza-mortality-not-well-modeled-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/influenza-mortality-not-well-modeled-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="shortcomings-of-vitamin-d-based-model-simulations-of-seasonal-influenza">Shortcomings of vitamin D-based model simulations of seasonal influenza.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2011;6(6):e20743. Epub 2011 Jun 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shaman J, Jeon CY, Giovannucci E, Lipsitch M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Environmental Health Sciences, Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University, New York, New York, United States of America. &lt;a href="mailto:jls106@columbia.edu">jls106@columbia.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seasonal variation in serum concentration of the vitamin D metabolite 25(OH) vitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>, which contributes to host immune function, has been hypothesized to be the underlying source of observed influenza seasonality in temperate regions. The objective of this study was to determine whether observed 25(OH)D levels could be used to simulate observed influenza infection rates. Data of mean and variance in 25(OH)D serum levels by month were obtained from the Health Professionals Follow-up Study and used to parameterize an individual-based model of influenza transmission dynamics in two regions of the United States. Simulations were compared with observed daily influenza excess &lt;strong>mortality data.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some immunodeficiency diseases associated with low vitamin D and increased Osteoporosis</title><link>/posts/some-immunodeficiency-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-increased-osteoporosis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-immunodeficiency-diseases-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-increased-osteoporosis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="osteoporosis-an-ignored-complication-of-cvid">Osteoporosis: An ignored complication of CVID.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2011 Nov;22(7):676-83. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01187.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1399-3038.2011.01187.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2011 Jun 6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Baris S, Ozen A, Ercan H, Karakoc-Aydiner E, Cagan H, Ozdemir C, Barlan M, Bahceciler NN, Barlan IB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Pediatric Allergy and Immunology, Marmara University, Istanbul, Turkey Division of Pediatric Allergy and Immunology, Yeditepe University, Istanbul, Turkey Division of Radiology, Florence Nightingale Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:? Multiple factors in common variable immunodeficiency (CVID) might interfere with optimal growth and maturation and potentially compromise bone health.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D helps T-cell and immune system – overview</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-t-cell-and-immune-system-overview.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-helps-t-cell-and-immune-system-overview.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-immune-function-an-overview">Vitamin D and immune function: an overview&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Proc Nutr Soc. 2011 Aug 18:1-12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hewison M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UCLA and Orthopaedic Hospital Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and the Orthopaedic Hospital Research Center, David Geffen School of Medicine at UCLA, 615 Charles E. Young, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/hewsion.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;p>Immunomodulatory actions of vitamin D have been recognised for over a quarter of a century, but it is only in the last few years that the significance of this to normal human physiology has become apparent. Two key factors have underpinned this revised perspective. Firstly, there are increasing data linking vitamin insufficiency with prevalent immune disorders. Improved awareness of low circulating levels of precursor 25-hydroxyvitamin D in populations across the globe has prompted epidemiological investigations of health problems associated with vitamin D insufficiency. Prominent among these are autoimmune diseases such as multiple sclerosis, type 1 diabetes and Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease, but more recent studies indicate that infections such as tuberculosis may also be linked to low 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels. The second factor expanding the link between vitamin D and the immune system is our improved knowledge of the mechanisms that facilitate this association.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Staph infection reduced 50 percent when have more than 30 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/staph-infection-reduced-50-percent-when-have-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/staph-infection-reduced-50-percent-when-have-more-than-30-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="staphylococcus-aureus-nasal-carriage-is-associated-with-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-gender-and-smoking-status-the-tromsø-staph-and-skin-study">Staphylococcus aureus nasal carriage is associated with serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels, gender and smoking status. The Tromsø Staph and Skin Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2011 Aug 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Olsen K, Falch BM, Danielsen K, Johannessen M, Ericson Sollid JU, Thune I, Grimnes G, Jorde R, Simonsen GS, Furberg AS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Microbiology and Infection Control, University Hospital of North Norway, 9038, Tromsø, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:karina.olsen@unn.no">karina.olsen@unn.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D induces the expression of antimicrobial peptides with activity against Staphylococcus aureus. Thus, we studied the association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and S. aureus nasal colonization and carriage. Nasal swabs, blood samples and clinical data from 2,115 women and 1,674 men, aged 30-87 years, were collected in the Tromsø Staph and Skin Study 2007-08, as part of the population-based sixth Tromsø Study. Multivariate logistic regression analyses were stratified by recognized risk factors for S. aureus carriage: sex, age and smoking. In non-smoking men, we observed a 6.6% and 6.7% decrease in the probability of S. aureus colonization and carriage, respectively, by each 5 nmol/l increase in serum 25(OH)D concentration (P?&lt;?0.001 and P?=?0.001), and serum 25(OH)D?>?59 nmol/l and ?75 nmol/l as thresholds for ~30% and ~50% reduction in S. aureus colonization and carriage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mastocytosis and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mastocytosis-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mastocytosis-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bone-mineral-density-bone-turnover-markers-and-fractures-in-patients-with-indolent-systemic-mastocytosis---2011">Bone mineral density, bone turnover markers and fractures in patients with indolent systemic mastocytosis - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mastocytosis-society-survey-of-supplementation---2018">Mastocytosis Society Survey of supplementation - 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#web">Web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="bone-mineral-density-bone-turnover-markers-and-fractures-in-patients-with-indolent-systemic-mastocytosis---2011">Bone mineral density, bone turnover markers and fractures in patients with indolent systemic mastocytosis - 2011&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Maurizio Rossinia, b, low asterisk, E-mail The Corresponding Author, Roberta Zanottib, c, Patrizia Bonadonnab, d, Anna Artusob, c, Beatrice Carusob, e, Donatella Schenab, f, Decio Vecchiatoa, b, Massimiliano Bonifaciob, c, Ombretta Viapianaa, b, Davide Gattia, b, Gianenrico Sennab, d, Annamaria Ricciog, Giovanni Passalacquag, Giovanni Pizzolob, c and Silvano Adamia, b&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yet again - more than 10000 IU of vitamin D treats MS</title><link>/posts/yet-again-more-than-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-treats-ms.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yet-again-more-than-10000-iu-of-vitamin-d-treats-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="sunshine-vitamin-sheds-light-on-ms">Sunshine Vitamin Sheds Light on MS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://sciencemedicine.org/content/3/90/90ec102.short%20">Science Translational Medicine Home &amp;gt; 6 July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vol. 3, Issue 90, p. 90ec102&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rebecca S. Boxer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Case Western Reserve University, School of Medicine, Cleveland, OH 44106, USA. E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:Rebecca.Boxer@UHhospitals.org">Rebecca.Boxer@UHhospitals.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mother’s advice to get out into the sunshine may be better advice then many realize. Vitamin D, the sunshine vitamin, which is produced in skin exposed to ultraviolet (UVB) light, may have important down-regulatory effects on the inflammatory response in patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Additional 4 ng of vitamin D reduced chance of infection by 7 percent</title><link>/posts/additional-4-ng-of-vitamin-d-reduced-chance-of-infection-by-7-percent.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/additional-4-ng-of-vitamin-d-reduced-chance-of-infection-by-7-percent.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D patent for treating immune system diseases</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-for-treating-immune-system-diseases.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wo2008039409httpwwwwipointpatentscopesearchenwo2008039409-world-wide-patent---2008">&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/patentscope/search/en/WO2008039409">(WO2008039409)&lt;/a> World-Wide patent - 2008&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="treatment-and-prevention-of-diseases-or-conditions-of-the--immune-system-or-infectious-diseases">TREATMENT AND PREVENTION OF DISEASES OR CONDITIONS OF THE &lt;strong>IMMUNE SYSTEM OR INFECTIOUS DISEASES&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>allergic rhinitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eczema,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>psoriasis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>food allergy,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>type-1 diabetes,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>ulcerative colitis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>rheumatoid arthritis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>multiple sclerosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>lupus,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>tuberculosis,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>parasitic infection, etc,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>MRSA inpatient cost 2X higher if less than 20 ng vitamin D</title><link>/posts/mrsa-inpatient-cost-2x-higher-if-less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mrsa-inpatient-cost-2x-higher-if-less-than-20-ng-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="healthcare-costs-of-methicillin-resistant-staphylococcus-aureus-and-pseudomonas-aeruginosa-infections-in-veterans-role-of-vitamin-d-deficiency">Healthcare costs of methicillin resistant Staphylococcus aureus and Pseudomonas aeruginosa infections in veterans: role of vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2011 Jun 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Youssef D, Bailey B, El-Abbassi A, Vannoy M, Manning T, Moorman JP, Peiris AN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Infectious Diseases, East Tennessee State University, Johnson City, TN, USA, &lt;a href="mailto:estecina@hotmail.com">estecina@hotmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methicillin resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) and Pseudomonas aeruginosa (P. aeruginosa) infections are frequently associated with hospitalization and increased healthcare costs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Elderly taking extra vitamin D should expect fewer falls AND less flu</title><link>/posts/elderly-taking-extra-vitamin-d-should-expect-fewer-falls-and-less-flu.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/elderly-taking-extra-vitamin-d-should-expect-fewer-falls-and-less-flu.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="preventing-two-birds-with-one-stone-improving-vitamin-d-levels-in-the-elderly">(Preventing) two birds with one stone: improving vitamin d levels in the elderly.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>J Prim Health Care. 2011 Jun 1;3(2):150-2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lawless S, White P, Murdoch P, Leitch S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amity Health Centre, 343 Highgate, Roslyn, Dunedin 9010, New Zealand. &lt;a href="mailto:susie@amityhc.co.nz">susie@amityhc.co.nz&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND AND CONTEXT: A majority of adults have sub-optimal vitamin D levels in the winter in southern New Zealand. This is associated with an increased risk of falls and fragility fractures in the elderly, with long-term adverse outcomes likely. Vitamin D supplementation decreases the risks of both falls and fractures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is a T-cell modulator in multiple sclerosis – April 2011.</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-a-t-cell-modulator-in-multiple-sclerosis-april-2011.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-a-t-cell-modulator-in-multiple-sclerosis-april-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-as-a-t-cell-modulator-in-multiple-sclerosis">Vitamin D as a T-cell modulator in multiple sclerosis&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Vitam Horm. 2011;86:401-28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Smolders J, Damoiseaux J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School for Mental Health and Neuroscience, Maastricht University Medical Center, Maastricht, The Netherlands; Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Clinical and Experimental Immunology, Maastricht University Medical Center, Maastricht, The Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D is a potent immune modulator, keeping the T-cell compartment in a more tolerogenic state. Multiple sclerosis (MS), a disease in which an autoreactive T-cell response contributes to inflammation in the central nervous system, has been associated with vitamin D deficiency. The effects of vitamin D on the immune system are believed to be an important driver of this association. In this chapter, we elaborate on vitamin D as a modulator of the T-cell response. This discussion will be placed in the perspective of MS as a T-cell-mediated disease and in the perspective of the numerous association studies on vitamin D deficiency and multiple health outcomes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Can Vitamin D Replace Flu Shots – WSJ</title><link>/posts/can-vitamin-d-replace-flu-shots-wsj.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/can-vitamin-d-replace-flu-shots-wsj.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="can-vitamin-d-replace-flu-shotshttponlinewsjcomarticlesb10001424052748704156304576003531437073192html20">&lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704156304576003531437073192.html%20">Can Vitamin D Replace Flu Shots?&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="by-laura-johannes--wall-street-journal--dec-2010">By LAURA JOHANNES Wall Street Journal Dec 2010&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Vitamin D, long known for its beneficial effect on bones, is increasingly being studied to see if it helps prevent colds and flus. Based on early research results, some doctors are recommending high doses to help stave off the upper respiratory infections, with some even speculating it could be a substitute to the annual flu shot. But while it&amp;rsquo;s well established that vitamin D boosts the immune system, many scientists say so far there&amp;rsquo;s insufficient evidence that taking it will help keep a cold or flu away.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Journal on vitamins and hormones has several papers on vitamin D – 2011</title><link>/posts/journal-on-vitamins-and-hormones-has-several-papers-on-vitamin-d-2011.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/journal-on-vitamins-and-hormones-has-several-papers-on-vitamin-d-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-regulation-of-immune-function">Vitamin D regulation of immune function&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-inflammatory-bowel-disease">Vitamin d and inflammatory bowel disease.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-innate-and-adaptive-immunity">Vitamin d and innate and adaptive immunity.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-and-chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-disease-a-vicious-circle">Vitamin d deficiency and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease a vicious circle.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-and-connective-tissue-disease">Vitamin d deficiency and connective tissue disease.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#maternal-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-and-its-relation-to-immune-mediated-diseases-in-the-offspring">Maternal vitamin d during pregnancy and its relation to immune-mediated diseases in the offspring.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-effects-on-lung-immunity-and-respiratory-diseases">Vitamin d effects on lung immunity and respiratory diseases.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-endocrine-system-and-the-immune-response-in-rheumatic-diseases">Vitamin d endocrine system and the immune response in rheumatic diseases.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#all-of-the-papers-in-the-issue">All of the papers in the issue&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="vitamin-d-regulation-of-immune-function">Vitamin D regulation of immune function&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Vitam Horm. 2011;86:1-21.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antimicrobial implications of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/antimicrobial-implications-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/antimicrobial-implications-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Dermato-Endocreinology, Volume 3, Issue 4 October/November/December 2011&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dima A. Youssef, Christopher W.T. Miller, Adel M. El-Abbassi, Della C. Cutchins, Coleman Cutchins, William Grant and Alan N. Peiris&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dima A. Youssef, Mountain Home VAMC Medicine Service; Mountain Home, TN USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christopher W.T. Miller, Department of Psychiatry; University of Maryland; Baltimore, MD USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adel M. El-Abbassi, Mountain Home VAMC Medicine Service; Mountain Home, TN USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Della C. Cutchins, Mountain Home VAMC Medicine Service; Mountain Home, TN USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vaginal suppository of 6300 IU vitamin D stopped vaginal infection</title><link>/posts/vaginal-suppository-of-6300-iu-vitamin-d-stopped-vaginal-infection.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vaginal-suppository-of-6300-iu-vitamin-d-stopped-vaginal-infection.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="article-re-published-in-2014-had-pregnancy-warning">Article re-published in 2014 had pregnancy warning&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Chronical cervical infections and dysplasia (CIN I, CIN II): Vaginal vitamin D (high dose) treatment - A new effective method?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No data about taking Vitamin D suppository while pregnant&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/chronical-cervical-infections-and-dysplasia-cin-i-cin-ii-vaginal-vitamin-d-high-dose-treatment.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor990note-the-original-article-below-had-been-retractedspan">&lt;span style="color:#990;">Note: The original article below had been retracted&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;This article has been retracted due to wrong content with serious consequences.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>see attached retraction PDF&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="chronical-cervical-infections-and-dysplasia-cin-i-cin-ii-vaginal-vitamin-d-high-dose-treatment-a-new-effective-method">Chronical cervical infections and dysplasia (CIN I, CIN II)-vaginal vitamin D (high dose) treatment: a new effective method.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2011 Feb 12.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yeast Infection and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/yeast-infection-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/yeast-infection-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d3-a-new-drug-against-candida-albicans-petri-dish---nov-2016">Vitamin D3 a new drug against Candida albicans (petri dish) - Nov 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#from-httpwwwcandidaalbicanorg">from &lt;a href="http://www.candidaalbican.org/">http://www.candidaalbican.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#appears-that-calcium-is-needed-to-reduce-candida-albicans-and-vitamin-d-is-needed-to-increase-calcium">Appears that Calcium is needed to reduce Candida Albicans, and vitamin D is needed to increase Calcium&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#from-httpforumlowcarberorgshowthreadphpt299830">from &lt;a href="http://forum.lowcarber.org/showthread.php?t=299830">http://forum.lowcarber.org/showthread.php?t=299830&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#from-httpwwwcandidacurezonecomcandida-albicans-fungushtml">from &lt;a href="http://www.candidacurezone.com/candida-albicans-fungus.html">http://www.candidacurezone.com/candida-albicans-fungus.html&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#candida-may-interfere-with-absorption-of-magnesium-in-the-gut">Candida may interfere with absorption of Magnesium in the gut&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#oral-candidiasis-57-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-in-person-with-hiv---2012">Oral Candidiasis 5.7 X more likely if low vitamin D in person with HIV - 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-a-new-drug-against-candida-albicans-petri-dish---nov-2016">Vitamin D3 a new drug against Candida albicans (petri dish) - Nov 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1156523316302232">Vitamin D3 a new drug against Candida albicans&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10X reactions to flu vaccine when vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/10x-reactions-to-flu-vaccine-when-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10x-reactions-to-flu-vaccine-when-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-council-nov-2010-newsletterhttpwwwvitamindcouncilorgnewsletterinfluenza-flu-shots-and-vitamin-dshtml">&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindcouncil.org/newsletter/influenza-flu-shots-and-vitamin-d.shtml">Vitamin D Council Nov 2010 newsletter&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="clips">Clips&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;First, I estimate that only about 1/1,000 of people who think they have influenza A actually have influenza A. Most have other viruses.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I continue to get a flu shot as does my wife and children. &amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="interview-of-dr-cannell-dec-1-2010postsinterview-of-dr-cannell-talking-about-institute-of-medicine">&lt;a href="/posts/interview-of-dr-cannell">Interview of Dr. Cannell Dec 1 2010&lt;/a> talking about Institute of Medicine&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="clip">Clip&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">DC&lt;/span>:: I agree. In fact there is even a possibility that the &lt;strong>flu vaccine&lt;/strong> is not going to work very well in people with high vitamin D levels. The Russians have observed that when they gave the flu vaccine in the summer, that they got much less of a reaction, you know, mild fever or body aches or anything. When they gave it in the winter, there was &lt;strong>10 or 15 times higher rate of having the symptoms&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inexpensive Trick to Cure a Cold - vitamin D - Mercola</title><link>/posts/inexpensive-trick-to-cure-a-cold-vitamin-d-mercola.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/inexpensive-trick-to-cure-a-cold-vitamin-d-mercola.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="clipped-from-a-simple-inexpensive-trick-to-cure-a-coldhttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20101122the-common-cold-simple-strategies-for-prevention-and-treatmentaspx-nov-22-2010">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2010/11/22/the-common-cold-simple-strategies-for-prevention-and-treatment.aspx">A Simple, Inexpensive Trick to Cure a Cold&lt;/a> Nov 22, 2010&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="how-do-you-catch-a-cold">How Do You Catch a Cold?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The most common way cold viruses are spread is not from being around coughing or sneezing, or walking barefoot in the rain, but rather from hand-to-hand contact. For instance, someone with a cold blows their nose then shakes your hand or touches surfaces that you also touch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cold viruses can live on pens, computer keyboards, coffee mugs and other objects for hours, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to come into contact with such viruses during daily life.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>