<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Supplement on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/supplement.html</link><description>Recent content in Supplement on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/supplement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alzheimer’s and Vitamins D, B, C, E, as well as Omega-3, metals, etc.</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-and-vitamins-d-b-c-e-as-well-as-omega-3-metals-etc.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-and-vitamins-d-b-c-e-as-well-as-omega-3-metals-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Importance and management of micronutrient deficiencies in patients with Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbara Rita Cardoso1 Cristiane Cominetti2 Silvia Maria Franciscato Cozzolino1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Sao Paulo (USP), Sao Paulo, Brazil; 2Faculty of Nutrition, Federal University of Goias, Goias, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Barbara Rita Cardoso; Av Prof Lineu Prestes, 580 - Bloco &amp;lsquo;4 - CEP: 05508-900 – Sao Paulo - SP - Brazil Tel +55 3 09&amp;rsquo; 3625, +55 8 353 8223 Email &lt;a href="mailto:barbaracardoso@usp.br">barbaracardoso@usp.br&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Supplement amounts can now be searched in a database</title><link>/posts/supplement-amounts-can-now-be-searched-in-a-database.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/supplement-amounts-can-now-be-searched-in-a-database.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="office-of-dietary-supplements--us-national-library-of-medicinehttpwwwdsldnlmnihgovdsldadvancedsearchjsp20">&lt;a href="http://www.dsld.nlm.nih.gov/dsld/advancedsearch.jsp%20">Office of Dietary Supplements &amp;amp; US National Library of Medicine&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Allows searching by dose size&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Allows greater than and less than searching (e.g. &amp;gt; 10,000 IU)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Example: 24 product having &amp;gt; 9,999 IU vitamin D as of Nov 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Example: 1328 products having &amp;gt; 200 mg of Magnesium as of Nov 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Allows searching for multiple ingredients – such as Vitamin D &lt;strong>AND&lt;/strong> Magnesium&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Do not use quotes (e.g. search for Vitamin D, not “Vitamin D”)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D relationship to many other vitamins</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-relationship-to-many-other-vitamins.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-relationship-to-many-other-vitamins.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="to-the-substantiation-of-the-joint-use-of-vitamin-d-and-the-rest-of-the-12-vitamins-necessary-for-the-creation-and-realization-of-the-vital-functions-of-its-hormone-active-form-the-vitamin-d--12-vitamins-approach">To the Substantiation of the Joint Use of Vitamin D and the Rest of the 12 Vitamins Necessary for the Creation and Realization of the Vital Functions of its Hormone-Active Form (The Vitamin D + 12 Vitamins Approach)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Nutritional Therapeutics, 2013, 2, 1-7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>V.B. Spirichev &lt;a href="mailto:valetek@post.ru">valetek@post.ru&lt;/a>, Doctor of Biological Sciences, Moscow, Russia&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/common-deficiencies-d3-omega-3-k2-mg-b12-e-a-iodine-etc-mercola" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Common deficiencies D3, Omega-3, K2, Mg, B12, E, A, Iodine, etc – Mercola Oct 2015">Common deficiencies D3, Omega-3, K2, Mg, B12, E, A, Iodine, etc – Mercola Oct 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Abstract: The realization of the multiple vital functions of vitamin D in a human organism closely depends on the sufficient provision of the rest of the vitamins necessary for the creation of the hormone-active form of vitamin D, as well as on the normal realization of the vital biochemical and physiological processes it controls.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Supplements - why and which</title><link>/posts/supplements-why-and-which.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/supplements-why-and-which.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-us-adults-use-dietary-supplements">Why US Adults Use Dietary Supplements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>JAMA Intern Med. Published online February 4, 2013. doi:10.1001/jamainternmed.2013.2299 Regan L. Bailey, PhD, RD; Jaime J. Gahche, MPH; Paige E. Miller, PhD, RD; Paul R. Thomas, PhD, RD; Johanna T. Dwyer, PhD, RD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Dietary supplements are used by more than half of adults, although to our knowledge, the reasons motivating use have not been previously examined in US adults using nationally representative data. The purpose of this analysis was to examine motivations for dietary supplement use, characterize the types of products used for the most commonly reported motivations, and to examine the role of physicians and health care practitioners in guiding choices about dietary supplements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Consumerlabs Supplement Survey – Highlights</title><link>/posts/consumerlabs-supplement-survey-highlights.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/consumerlabs-supplement-survey-highlights.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="press-release-by-consumer-labshttpswwwconsumerlabcomnewshighlights_vitamin_supplements_survey1_31_2013">&lt;a href="https://www.consumerlab.com/news/highlights_vitamin_supplements_survey/1_31_2013/?">Press Release by Consumer Labs&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.consumerlab.com/freetrialwcc-signup.asp?CLTRKID=NEWSLETTER">Note: Consumer Labs has a 5 day free trial&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>10,000 people responding to email survey.in Nov 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On average taking 6.6 supplements per day&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>People purchasing this year compared to last year&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>72% fish/marine oils&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>65% multivitamins&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;gt; 56% Vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>-2% Calcium and multivitamins&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Online stored used by 45% of respondents (recall that this was an email survey)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Internet shopping decreases with age, but still 30% of those &amp;gt;85 years old&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to get Vitamin D and cofactors without taking pills</title><link>/posts/how-to-get-vitamin-d-and-cofactors-without-taking-pills.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-get-vitamin-d-and-cofactors-without-taking-pills.html</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a frequently-asked-question at VitaminDWiki.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are a few answers.    (These numbers assume that you want 10,000 IU of vitamin D daily.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1) Sublinqual + Mg liquid&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get Vitamin D3 and Vitamin K-2 as a sublingual&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get the next most important cofactor, &lt;a href="/posts/magnesium" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 947">Magnesium&lt;/a> as a liquid&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skip the other cofactors unless you are very concerned about your bones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sublingual from &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Vitamin-D3-5000-IU-Sublingual/dp/B003CWH96G/ref=sr_1_1?s=hpc&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1359931115&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=michael%27s+vitamin+d3">Michael&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> has 5,000 IU of vitamin D + 90 micrograms of Vitamin K-2&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some companies provide Vitamin D AND cofactors</title><link>/posts/some-companies-provide-vitamin-d-and-cofactors.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-companies-provide-vitamin-d-and-cofactors.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Add vitamin D to animal feed to fortify the resulting human food</title><link>/posts/add-vitamin-d-to-animal-feed-to-fortify-the-resulting-human-food.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/add-vitamin-d-to-animal-feed-to-fortify-the-resulting-human-food.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin and Mineral deficiencies – Ames Triage Theory</title><link>/posts/vitamin-and-mineral-deficiencies-ames-triage-theory.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-and-mineral-deficiencies-ames-triage-theory.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-and-mineral-inadequacy-accelerates-aging-associated-diseases">Vitamin and Mineral Inadequacy Accelerates Aging-Associated Diseases&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Commonwealth Medical College 12 April 2012 - Revised&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce N. Ames Senior Scientist, Nutrition and Metabolism Center Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Oakland Research Institute, Oakland, California;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Professor Emeritus University of California, Berkeley&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I posited, and have buttressed, &amp;ldquo;triage theory&amp;rdquo; (1,2): metabolism responds to moderate deficiency of an essential vitamin or mineral (V/M) so that the scarce V/M is preferentially retained by V/M-dependent proteins necessary for short-term survival and reproduction. In contrast, proteins needed for long term health, which I term &amp;ldquo;longevity proteins&amp;rdquo; because they defend against the diseases associated with aging, lose the V/M and are disabled. Most of the world&amp;rsquo;s population, including that of the U.S., are moderately deficient in one or more of the ~30 essential V/Ms. Moreover, since the damage from moderate deficiency is insidious, its importance for long-term health is not being appreciated. Strong support for triage theory comes from Joyce McCann&amp;rsquo;s analyses of the literature on proteins dependent on vitamin K (3) and on selenium (4). Both have built into metabolism this trade-off between short-term survival and long-term health and each uses a different mechanism to accomplish this end. Theory and evidence suggest that this metabolic trade-off accelerates aging-associated diseases, such as cancer, cognitive decline, and cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>US supplements survey – 34 percent take omega-3, 30 percent take vitamin D</title><link>/posts/us-supplements-survey-34-percent-take-omega-3-30-percent-take-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/us-supplements-survey-34-percent-take-omega-3-30-percent-take-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Importance of Vitamins D and K</title><link>/posts/importance-of-vitamins-d-and-k.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/importance-of-vitamins-d-and-k.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamins-d-and-k-as-pleiotropic-nutrients-clinical-importance-to-the-skeletal-and-cardiovascular-systems-and-preliminary-evidence-for-synergy">Vitamins D and K as pleiotropic nutrients: clinical importance to the skeletal and cardiovascular systems and preliminary evidence for synergy.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Altern Med Rev. 2010 Sep;15(3):199-222.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kidd PM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of California, Berkeley, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:dockidd@dockidd.com">dockidd@dockidd.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/overview-vitamin-k-and-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 765">Overview Vitamin K and Vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Vitamins D and K are lipid-phase nutrients that are pleiotropic - endowed with versatile homeostatic capacities at the organ, tissue, and cellular levels. Their metabolic and physiologic roles overlap considerably, as evidenced in the bone and cardiovascular systems. Vitamin D? (cholecalciferol, D?) is the prehormone for the vitamin D endocrine system. Vitamin D? undergoes initial enzymatic conversion to 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25D, calcidiol), then to the seco-steroid hormone 1alpha, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25D, calcitriol). Beyond its endocrine roles in calcium homeostasis, 1,25D likely has autocrine, paracrine, and intracrine effects. At least 17 tissues likely synthesize 1,25D, and 35 carry the vitamin D receptor (VDR). Vitamin D functional deficiency is widespread in human populations. Vitamin K? (phylloquinone) is more abundant in foods but less bioactive than the vitamin K? menaquinones (especially MK-4, menatetrenone). Menadione (vitamin K?) has minimal K activity. Vitamin K compounds undergo oxidation-reduction cycling within the endoplasmic reticulum membrane, donating electrons to activate specific proteins via enzymatic gamma-carboxylation of glutamate groups before being enzymatically re-reduced. Warfarin inhibits this vitamin K reduction, necessitating K supplementation during anticoagulation therapy. Along with coagulation factors (II, VII, IX, X, and prothrombin), protein C and protein S, osteocalcin (OC), matrix Gla protein (MGP), periostin, Gas6, and other vitamin K-dependent (VKD) proteins support calcium homeostasis, facilitate bone mineralization, inhibit vessel wall calcification, support endothelial integrity, are involved in cell growth control and tissue renewal, and have numerous other effects. This review updates vitamin D and K skeletal and cardiovascular benefits and evidence for their synergy of action.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Healthy bones need: Calcium, Vitamin D, Magnesium, Silicon, Vitamin K, and Boron – 2012</title><link>/posts/healthy-bones-need-calcium-vitamin-d-magnesium-silicon-vitamin-k-and-boron-2012.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/healthy-bones-need-calcium-vitamin-d-magnesium-silicon-vitamin-k-and-boron-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Essential Nutrients for Bone Health and a Review of their Availability in the Average North American Diet.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open Orthop J. 2012;6:143-9&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price CT, Langford JR, Liporace FA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Orlando Health, 1222 Orange Avenue, 5 Floor, Orlando, Florida 32806, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Osteoporosis and low bone mineral density affect millions of Americans. The majority of adults in North America have insufficient intake of vitamin D and calcium along with inadequate exercise. Physicians are aware that vitamin D, calcium and exercise are essential for maintenance of bone health. Physicians are less likely to be aware that dietary insufficiencies of magnesium, silicon, Vitamin K, and boron are also widely prevalent, and each of these essential nutrients is an important contributor to bone health. In addition, specific nutritional factors may improve calcium metabolism and bone formation. It is the authors&amp;rsquo; opinion that nutritional supplements should attempt to provide ample, but not excessive, amounts of factors that are frequently insufficient in the typical American diet.In contrast to dietary insufficiencies, several nutrients that support bone health are readily available in the average American diet. These include zinc, manganese, and copper which may have adverse effects at higher levels of intake. Some multivitamins and bone support products provide additional quantities of nutrients that may be unnecessary or potentially harmful.The purpose of this paper is to identify specific nutritional components of bone health, the effects on bone, the level of availability in the average American diet, and the implications of supplementation for each nutritional component. A summary of recommended dietary supplementation is included.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The role of vitamins in cancer: a review – 2011</title><link>/posts/the-role-of-vitamins-in-cancer-a-review-2011.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-role-of-vitamins-in-cancer-a-review-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Nutr Cancer. 2011;63(4):479-94.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mamede AC, Tavares SD, Abrantes AM, Trindade J, Maia JM, Botelho MF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Biophysics/Biomathematics Institute, IBILI, Faculty of Medicine, University of Coimbra, Coimbra, Portugal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamins are essential nutrients for human metabolism, playing an important role as coenzymes or enzymes in many vital processes for the normal functioning of the body. In recent years, it has become apparent that vitamins are crucial in health and human disease, due to several studies that studied this relationship. Currently, it is known that vitamins can have an important role in the prevention and treatment of cancer, but until now no conclusive results were obtained. In this review, we will present the work and more relevant conclusions obtained in recent years of investigation about the relationship between vitamins and cancer, namely vitamin A, vitamin B complex, vitamin C, vitamin D, vitamin E, and vitamin K.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D increased absorption of Phosphorus and Calcium in steers</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-increased-absorption-of-phosphorus-and-calcium-in-steers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-increased-absorption-of-phosphorus-and-calcium-in-steers.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="phosphorus-and-calcium-retention-in-steers-fed-a-roughage-diet-is-influenced-by-dietary-25oh-vitamin-d">Phosphorus and calcium retention in steers fed a roughage diet is influenced by dietary 25OH-vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Animal Production Science - &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1071/AN11293">http://dx.doi.org/10.1071/AN11293&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J. J. McGrath A C, D. B. Savage A, J. V. Nolan A and R. Elliott B&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Environmental and Rural Science, University of New England, Armidale, NSW 2350, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B DSM Nutritional Products Australia Pty Ltd, Princeton Court 3, Suite 6, 13 Princeton Street, Kenmore, Qld 4069, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C Corresponding author. Email: &lt;a href="mailto:jmcgrat4@une.edu.au">jmcgrat4@une.edu.au&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5000 IU Vitamin D3 with some cofactors</title><link>/posts/5000-iu-vitamin-d3-with-some-cofactors.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5000-iu-vitamin-d3-with-some-cofactors.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#osteo-tech-by-biotech-phamaca">Osteo-tech by BioTech Phamaca&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#stop-aging-nowhttpwwwstopagingnowcomrvdrevolution-d-advanced-vitamin-d3-formula">&lt;a href="http://www.stopagingnow.com/RVD/Revolution-D-Advanced-Vitamin-D3-Formula">Stop Aging Now&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#d-3-plus-biotech-pharmacalhttpwwwbiotechpharmacalcomproducts-t4039vitamin-ad3-plus-180ctaspx">&lt;a href="http://www.biotechpharmacal.com/products-t4039/Vitamin-A/d3-plus-180ct.aspx">D-3 Plus Biotech Pharmacal&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="osteo-tech-by-biotech-phamaca">Osteo-tech by BioTech Phamaca&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Bio-Tech-OSTE7-OsteoTech-100-caps/dp/B0058A9DVE/ref=sr_1_26?s=hpc&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1370382375&amp;amp;sr=1-26&amp;amp;keywords=bio-tech%20">Amazon&lt;/a> $22.66 for 25 day supply&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Capsules per day, Servings Per Container 25 (100 pills) Daily cost = $23/25 = &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#090;">92 cents/day&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amount % Daily US RDA (from contents of 4 pills)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Calcium 400 mg&lt;/strong> 40% (from microcrystalline hydroxyapatite as New Zealand bovine whole bone extract)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Phosphorous 164 mg&lt;/strong> 16% (from microcrystalline hydroxyapatite)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Magnesium 200 mg&lt;/strong> 50% (as magnesium carbonate)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic – Dietary supplement monopoly board</title><link>/posts/off-topic-dietary-supplement-monopoly-board.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-dietary-supplement-monopoly-board.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-dietary-supplement-label-the-fda-doesnt-want-you-to-seehttpwwwlewrockwellcomsardisardi196html20--by-bill-sardi-nov-24-2011">&lt;a href="http://www.lewrockwell.com/sardi/sardi196.html%20">The Dietary Supplement Label the FDA Doesn’t Want You To See&lt;/a> By Bill Sardi Nov 24, 2011&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="contains-the-following-boardwalk--graphic-although-there-is-no-concept-of-sequence">Contains the following boardwalk graphic, although there is no concept of sequence&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;897&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Legend, clockwise:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>FDA = government agency whose purpose is largely to promote drugs over dietary supplements;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>NIH = National Institutes of Health, Office of Dietary Supplements, which is now threatening to declare all supplements are drugs;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Adverse Event Reporting Hotline = phone number to call if dietary supplements cause a serious side effect;     (unable to find it)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Very low on micronutrients such as vitamin D and Magnesium – NHANES data</title><link>/posts/very-low-on-micronutrients-such-as-vitamin-d-and-magnesium-nhanes-data.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/very-low-on-micronutrients-such-as-vitamin-d-and-magnesium-nhanes-data.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="foods-fortificants-and-supplements-where-do-americans-get-their-nutrients">Foods, Fortificants, and Supplements: Where Do Americans Get Their Nutrients?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Victor L. Fulgoni III4, &lt;a href="mailto:vic3rd@aol.com">vic3rd@aol.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Debra R. Keast5,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regan L. Bailey6, and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johanna Dwyer7&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Nutrition Impact LLC, Battle Creek, MI&lt;/p>
&lt;p>5 Food and Nutrition Database Research, Inc., Okemos, MI&lt;/p>
&lt;p>6 Office of Dietary Supplements, Bethesda, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>7 Jean Mayer USDA Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging, and Schools of Medicine and Friedman School of Nutrition Science and Policy, Tufts University, Boston, MA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Silicon or silica as a vitamin D co-factor</title><link>/posts/silicon-or-silica-as-a-vitamin-d-co-factor.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/silicon-or-silica-as-a-vitamin-d-co-factor.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="silica-is-useful-as-a-vitamin-d-co-factor-in-building-bones-hair-teeth">Silica is useful as a vitamin D co-factor in building bones, hair, teeth.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="no-consensus-on-bioavailability-of-the-different-forms-of-silica">No consensus on bioavailability of the different forms of silica&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="no-consensus-on-how-much-silica-is-needed">No consensus on how much silica is needed&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="some-useful-papers-are-attached-to-the-bottom-of-this-web-page">Some useful papers are attached to the bottom of this web page.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update; &lt;a href="/posts/silicon-vitamin-d-and-bone-health-multiple-studies" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Silicon, Vitamin D and Bone Health - multiple studies">Silicon, Vitamin D and Bone Health - multiple studies&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-web-march-2018">See web (March 2018)&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3671293/">Silicon: A Review of Its Potential Role in the Prevention and Treatment of Postmenopausal Osteoporosis&lt;/a> May 2016&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/silicon-osteo.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low cost cofactors - details</title><link>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-details.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-cost-cofactors-details.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-hrefpostsclick-here-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1270click-herea-for-main-co-factor-page">&lt;a href="/posts/click-here" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1270">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for main Co-factor page&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="liquid-details">Liquid details&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="solid-details-are-in-rtf-file-at-the-bottom-of-this-page">Solid details are in RTF file at the bottom of this page&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="trimedica-just-an-ouncehttpwwwvitaminshoppecomstoreenbrowsesku_detailjspidtp-2017sourcetypecssourcefgcm_mmcshopping20engines-_-googleproduct-_-just20an20ounce20calcium20magnesium20-201620ounces20liquid20-20vitamin20k-_-tp-2017ci_src14110944ci_skutp-2017-vitamin-shoppe">&lt;a href="http://www.vitaminshoppe.com/store/en/browse/sku_detail.jsp?id=TP-2017&amp;amp;sourceType=cs&amp;amp;source=FG&amp;amp;cm_mmc=Shopping%20Engines-_-googleproduct-_-Just%20An%20Ounce%20Calcium%20Magnesium%20-%2016%20Ounces%20Liquid%20-%20Vitamin%20K-_-TP-2017&amp;amp;ci_src=14110944&amp;amp;ci_sku=TP-2017">Trimedica Just An Ounce&lt;/a> Vitamin Shoppe&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;381&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="source-of-life-men-liquidhttpwww4allvitaminscomproduct_infophpproducts_id1186product_configuration_id1544referrergoogle20-26-for-30-ounce--1-ounce-per-day-081-per-day">&lt;a href="http://www.4allvitamins.com/product_info.php?products_id=1186&amp;amp;product_configuration_id=1544&amp;amp;referrer=google%20">Source of Life Men Liquid&lt;/a> $26 for 30 ounce 1 ounce per day, $0.81 per day&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;379&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="span-stylecolor090osteo-densityspan--swansonhttpwwwswansonvitaminscomlft006itemdetailn0--9-for-16-ounces-12-ounce-per-dose-so-32-doses-for-9-021-per-day">&lt;a href="http://www.swansonvitamins.com/LFT006/ItemDetail?n=0">&lt;span style="color:#090;">Osteo Density&lt;/span> – Swanson&lt;/a> $9 for 16 ounces, 1/2 ounce per dose, so 32 doses for $9, $0.21 per day&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="other-suppliers-of-osteo-density-via-google-shoppinghttpwwwgooglecomproductscataloghlenbiw1103bih439q22osteodensity22liquidum1ieutf-8cid14284603075173101785eii8kdtcjwfyy8sqp5natcagsaxoiproduct_catalog_resultctresultresnum1ved0cdgq8wiwaa">&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/products/catalog?hl=en&amp;amp;biw=1103&amp;amp;bih=439&amp;amp;q=%22osteo+density%22+liquid&amp;amp;um=1&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;cid=14284603075173101785&amp;amp;ei=I8kdTcjWFYy8sQP5naTcAg&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;oi=product_catalog_result&amp;amp;ct=result&amp;amp;resnum=1&amp;amp;ved=0CDgQ8wIwAA#">Other suppliers of Osteo Density via Google Shopping&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>{IMG(attId=&amp;ldquo;380,383&amp;rdquo;)}{IMG}&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero Deaths from Vitamins Minerals Amino Acids or Herbs</title><link>/posts/zero-deaths-from-vitamins-minerals-amino-acids-or-herbs.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/zero-deaths-from-vitamins-minerals-amino-acids-or-herbs.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="us-govt-report-for-2009httporthomolecularorgresourcesomnsv07n01shtml">&lt;a href="http://orthomolecular.org/resources/omns/v07n01.shtml">US Govt report for 2009&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="prescription-drug-overdose-deaths-in-us-may-be-20000-x-higher-than-deaths-due-to-all-vitamins-herbs-etc">Prescription drug overdose deaths in US may be 20,000 X higher than deaths due to all vitamins, herbs, etc.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="deaths-due-to-prescription-drugs--180000-x-higher-than-deaths-due-to-all-vitamins-herbs-etc">Deaths due to prescription drugs &amp;gt; 180,000 X higher than deaths due to all vitamins, herbs, etc.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="the-new-200-page-annual-report-of-the-american-association-of-poison-control-centers-published-in-the-journal-clinical-toxicology-shows">The new 200-page annual report of the American Association of Poison Control Centers, published in the journal Clinical Toxicology, shows&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>zero deaths from multiple vitamins;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>zero deaths from any of the B vitamins;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Strontium and Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/strontium-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/strontium-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clipped-from-wikipedia">Clipped from Wikipedia&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#natural-news-oct-2011httpwwwnaturalnewscom033777_strontium_bone_healthhtml">&lt;a href="http://www.naturalnews.com/033777_strontium_bone_health.html">Natural News Oct 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clipped-gill-sanson-2006httpgilliansansonwordpresscom20060307strontium-e28093-a-novel-bone-building-treatment">Clipped &lt;a href="http://gilliansanson.wordpress.com/2006/03/07/strontium-%E2%80%93-a-novel-bone-building-treatment/">Gill Sanson 2006&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clipped-from-httpwwwosteoporosis-vitaminscomstrontium-citratehtml">Clipped from &lt;a href="http://www.osteoporosis-vitamins.com/strontium-citrate.html">http://www.osteoporosis-vitamins.com/strontium-citrate.html&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#httpstrontiumforbonesblogspotcom">&lt;a href="http://strontiumforbones.blogspot.com/">http://strontiumforbones.blogspot.com/&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#efficacy-of-strontium-ranelate-on-bone-mineral-density-in-men-with-osteoporosis">Efficacy of strontium ranelate on bone mineral density in men with osteoporosis.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#medical-treatment-of-osteoporosis-in-the-elderly">Medical treatment of osteoporosis in the elderly.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#management-of-osteoporosis-in-the-elderly">Management of osteoporosis in the elderly.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#osteoporosis-and-osteoporotic-fracture-occurrence-and-prevention-in-the-elderly-a-geriatric-perspective">Osteoporosis and osteoporotic fracture occurrence and prevention in the elderly: a geriatric perspective.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#google-search-resultshttpwwwgooglecomsearchq22strontiumranelate22hlentbsshop3a1aqfsclientpsyhlentbsshop1sourcehpq22strontiumranelate22-documentaqfaqiaqloqgs_rfaipbx1fp9bef8cda26d1a6ec-for-strontium-renalte">&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=%22+strontium+ranelate%22&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;tbs=shop%3A1&amp;amp;aq=f#sclient=psy&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;tbs=shop:1&amp;amp;source=hp&amp;amp;q=%22+strontium+ranelate%22+-document&amp;amp;aq=f&amp;amp;aqi=&amp;amp;aql=&amp;amp;oq=&amp;amp;gs_rfai=&amp;amp;pbx=1&amp;amp;fp=9bef8cda26d1a6ec">Google Search results&lt;/a> for Strontium Renalte&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#strontium-and-vitamin-d3-interactions-in-bones-of-chickens--fall-2013-effect-of-vitamin-d3-and-strontium-on-performance-nutrient-retention-and-bone-mineral-composition-in-broiler-chickens-animal-production-science">Strontium and Vitamin D3 interactions in bones of chickens – Fall 2013** Effect of vitamin D3 and strontium on performance, nutrient retention and bone mineral composition in broiler chickens **Animal Production Science&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="clipped-from-wikipedia">Clipped from Wikipedia&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The drug strontium ranelate, made by combining strontium with ranelic acid, was found to aid bone growth, increase bone density, and lessen vertebral, peripheral and hip fractures.&lt;sup>[33]&lt;/sup>&lt;sup>[34]&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Masterjohn on relationships between Vitamin A D and K</title><link>/posts/masterjohn-on-relationships-between-vitamin-a-d-and-k.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/masterjohn-on-relationships-between-vitamin-a-d-and-k.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-vitamin-d-safe-still-depends-on-vitamins-a-and-k-testimonials-and-a-human-study">Is Vitamin D Safe? Still Depends on Vitamins A and K! Testimonials and a Human Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.westonaprice.org/blogs/is-vitamin-d-safe-still-depends-on-vitamins-a-and-k-testimonials-and-a-human-study.html">Christopher Masterjohn in WAPF Blog on 12/15/10&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the last several weeks, two momentous occasions have occurred in the world of vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, the Institute of Medicine (IOM) released its new report. It tripled the recommended intakes, doubled the upper limit, and commissioned researchers to go forth and test the effects of intakes higher than the upper limit, as this would be safe under proper supervision and provide valuable information.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>