<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Patent on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/patent.html</link><description>Recent content in Patent on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/patent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vitamin D fortification patents have earned Univ. of Wisconsin 300 million dollars– 2016</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-fortification-patents-have-earned-univ-of-wisconsin-300-million-dollars-2016.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-fortification-patents-have-earned-univ-of-wisconsin-300-million-dollars-2016.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D receptor substitutes are being patented</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-substitutes-are-being-patented.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-substitutes-are-being-patented.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="therapeutic-application-of-vitamin-d-receptor-ligands-an-updated-patent-review">Therapeutic application of vitamin D receptor ligands: an updated patent review.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Expert Opin Ther Pat. 2015 Sep 24:1-11. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Takada I1, Makishima M1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1a Nihon University School of Medicine, Division of Biochemistry, Department of Biomedical Sciences , 30-1 Oyaguchi-kamicho, Itabashi-ku, Tokyo 173-8610, Japan +81 3 39 72 81 99 ; +81 3 39 72 81 99 ; &lt;a href="mailto:makishima.makoto@nihon-u.ac.jp">makishima.makoto@nihon-u.ac.jp&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The vitamin D receptor (VDR) is a promising drug target in the treatment of cancer, autoimmune disease, inflammation, infection and cardiovascular disease, as well as bone and mineral disorders. Although many VDR ligands have been developed and shown to activate VDR in vitro and in vivo, including vitamin D derivatives and non-secosteroidal compounds, a principal adverse effect of hypercalcemia has limited their clinical application.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D patent application – note the medical claims</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-application-note-the-medical-claims.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-application-note-the-medical-claims.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="methods-for-controlled-release-oral-dosage-of-a-vitamin-d-compoundhttpwwwfreepatentsonlinecomy20140357603html">&lt;a href="http://www.freepatentsonline.com/y2014/0357603.html">Methods for Controlled Release Oral Dosage of a Vitamin D Compound&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>United States Patent Application 20140357603&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/patent-including-images.pdf">Download the Patent PDF with text and images from VitaminDWiki.&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few claims and comments by VitaminDWiki follow&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Claim 34.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The method of claim 21, wherein the patient has a disease selected from the group consisting of&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>cancer&lt;/strong> , including but not limited to&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>breast, lung, skin, melanoma, colon, colorectal, rectal, prostate and bone cancer; an&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tuberculosis is controlled by Interleukin-32 when it has enough Vitamin D – patent applied for</title><link>/posts/tuberculosis-is-controlled-by-interleukin-32-when-it-has-enough-vitamin-d-patent-applied-for.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tuberculosis-is-controlled-by-interleukin-32-when-it-has-enough-vitamin-d-patent-applied-for.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="new-interaction-discovered-between-vitamin-d-and-certain-protein-in-tuberculosishttpwwwvitamindcouncilorgvitamin-d-newsnew-interaction-discovered-between-vitamin-d-and-certain-protein-in-tuberculosis-vitamin-d-council-describes-the-study">&lt;a href="http://www.vitamindcouncil.org/vitamin-d-news/new-interaction-discovered-between-vitamin-d-and-certain-protein-in-tuberculosis/#">New interaction discovered between vitamin D and certain protein in tuberculosis&lt;/a> Vitamin D Council describes the study&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="study-identifies-protein-that-helps-prevent-active-tuberculosis-in-infected-patientshttpnewsroomuclaedureleasesstudy-identifies-protein-that-helps-prevent-active-tuberculosis-in-infected-patients-ucla-newsroom">&lt;a href="http://newsroom.ucla.edu/releases/study-identifies-protein-that-helps-prevent-active-tuberculosis-in-infected-patients">Study identifies protein that helps prevent active tuberculosis in infected patients&lt;/a> UCLA Newsroom&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“When vitamin D levels were low, IL-32 was not able to kill the bacteria,”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>. . applied for a patent application for further development of IL-32 as a potential diagnostic marker to see which patients with latent TB are at risk for activation of the disease, as well as for use as a possible therapeutic to treat tuberculosis by stimulating antimicrobial activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer risk reduced by combination of memantine and vitamin D (patented)</title><link>/posts/alzheimer-risk-reduced-by-combination-of-memantine-and-vitamin-d-patented.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimer-risk-reduced-by-combination-of-memantine-and-vitamin-d-patented.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplements-a-novel-therapeutic-approach-for-alzheimer-patients">Vitamin D supplements: a novel therapeutic approach for Alzheimer patients&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.frontiersin.org/Journal/FullText.aspx?s=322&amp;amp;%20name=experimental%20pharmacology%20and%20drug%20discovery&amp;amp;%20ART%20DOI=10.3389/fphar.2014.00006%20">Frontiers in Pharmacology, 1663-9812&lt;/a> 09 Dec 2013, 08 Jan 2014, 08 Jan 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cedric Annweiler, Spyridon N Karras, Panagiotis Anagnostis and Olivier Beauchet&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Opinion Article&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.frontiersin.org">www.frontiersin.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D supplements: a novel therapeutic approach for Alzheimer patients; Running title: Vitamin D supplements in Alzheimer disease. Front. Pharmacol. 5:6. doi:10.3389/fphar.2014.00006&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1: Department of Geriatric Medicine, UPRES EA 4638, University Hospital, Angers, France&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D analogs – 25 years of trying to trying to patent vitamin D</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-analogs-25-years-of-trying-to-trying-to-patent-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-analogs-25-years-of-trying-to-trying-to-patent-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-future-of-vitamin-d-analogs">The future of vitamin D analogs.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Front Physiol. 2014 Apr 3;5:122. eCollection 2014.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leyssens C, Verlinden L, Verstuyf A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical and Experimental Endocrinology, Department of Clinical and Experimental Medicine, KU Leuven Leuven, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The active form of vitamin D3, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3, is a major regulator of bone and calcium homeostasis. In addition, this hormone also inhibits the proliferation and stimulates the differentiation of normal as well as malignant cells. Supraphysiological doses of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 are required to reduce cancer cell proliferation. &lt;strong>However, these doses will lead in vivo to calcemic side effects such as hypercalcemia and hypercalciuria&lt;/strong> . During the last 25 years, many structural analogs of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 have been synthesized by the introduction of chemical modifications in the A-ring, central CD-ring region or side chain of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 in the hope to find molecules with a clear dissociation between the beneficial antiproliferative effects and adverse calcemic side effects. One example of such an analog with a good dissociation ratio is calcipotriol (Daivonex®), which is clinically used to treat the hyperproliferative skin disease psoriasis. Other vitamin D analogs were clinically approved for the treatment of osteoporosis or secondary hyperparathyroidism. No vitamin D analog is currently used in the clinic for the treatment of cancer although several analogs have been shown to be potent drugs in animal models of cancer. Transcriptomics studies as well as in vitro cell biological experiments unraveled basic mechanisms involved in the antineoplastic effects of vitamin D and its analogs. 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 and analogs act in a cell type- and tissue-specific manner. Moreover, a blockade in the transition of the G0/1 toward S phase of the cell cycle, induction of apoptosis, inhibition of migration and invasion of tumor cells together with effects on angiogenesis and inflammation have been implicated in the pleiotropic effects of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 and its analogs. In this review we will give an overview of the action of vitamin D analogs in tumor cells and look forward how these compounds could be introduced in the clinical practice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Patent application for a skin cream which enhances production of vitamin D – Holick</title><link>/posts/patent-application-for-a-skin-cream-which-enhances-production-of-vitamin-d-holick.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/patent-application-for-a-skin-cream-which-enhances-production-of-vitamin-d-holick.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="compositions-for-providing-vitamin-d-year-round-and-uses-thereofhttpappftusptogovnetacginph-parsersect1pto2sect2hitoffu2fnetahtml2fpto2fsearch-advhtmlr12p1fgl50dpg01s12822vitamind22ttl29osttl22vitamind22rsttl22vitamind22">&lt;a href="http://appft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO2&amp;amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsearch-adv.html&amp;amp;r=12&amp;amp;p=1&amp;amp;f=G&amp;amp;l=50&amp;amp;d=PG01&amp;amp;S1=%28%22vitamin+d%22.TTL.%29&amp;amp;OS=ttl/%22vitamin+d%22&amp;amp;RS=TTL/%22vitamin+d%22">Compositions for Providing Vitamin D Year Round and Uses Thereof&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Methods for enhancing the ability of an individual, exposed to sunlight, to produce vitamin D via the skin. Pharmaceutical compositions comprising provitamin D and at least one of &lt;strong>lumisterol and tachysterol&lt;/strong> and analogs and derivatives thereof are also disclosed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Claim 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A composition comprising a pharmaceutically acceptable carrier and an effective amount of (a) provitamin D or a derivative or analog thereof; (b) at least one of lumisterol and tachysterol or analogs and/or esters thereof, and (c) a pharmaceutically effective carrier, wherein (a) and (b) are present in amounts effective to provide vitamin D or derivatives or analogs and/or esters thereof to an individual at a particular latitude and/or time of the year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D patent update</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-update.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-patent-update.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>