<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Epigenetics on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/epigenetics.html</link><description>Recent content in Epigenetics on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/epigenetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Off-topic: Sulfur is very important to health</title><link>/posts/off-topic-sulfur-is-very-important-to-health.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-sulfur-is-very-important-to-health.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Comment by Henry Lahore of VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Organic sulfur has been proven by many studies to help human health&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Non-organic sulfur appears to help as well - I am unaware of as many studies as for organic&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#search-pubmed-for-span-stylecolor00fsulfroaphonespanhttpswwwncbinlmnihgovpubmedtermsulforaphane5btitle5d-1671-items-in-title-as-of-sept-2024">&lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed?term=Sulforaphane%5BTitle%5D">Search Pubmed for &lt;span style="color:#00F;">Sulfroaphone&lt;/span>&lt;/a> 1671 items in title as of Sept 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#sulforaphane--organic-sulfur--video-dec-2016">Sulforaphane – Organic Sulfur – video Dec 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#msm-the-mineral-essential-for-health-s--sulfur---video-2019">MSM: The Mineral Essential for Health (S = Sulfur) - video 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#off-topic-sulfur-and-human-healthpostsoff-topic-sulfur-and-human-health---many-items-2011-2013">&lt;a href="/posts/off-topic-sulfur-and-human-health">Off topic: Sulfur and Human Health&lt;/a> - many items 2011-2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="search-pubmed-for-span-stylecolor00fsulfroaphonespanhttpswwwncbinlmnihgovpubmedtermsulforaphane5btitle5d-1671-items-in-title-as-of-sept-2024">&lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed?term=Sulforaphane%5BTitle%5D">Search Pubmed for &lt;span style="color:#00F;">Sulfroaphone&lt;/span>&lt;/a> 1671 items in title as of Sept 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Sulforaphane treatment of autism spectrum disorder - RCT 2014&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low vitamin D in pregnancy – epigenetic pancreas problems in offspring (mice)</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-epigenetic-pancreas-problems-in-offspring-mice.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-epigenetic-pancreas-problems-in-offspring-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="maternal-vitamin-d-restricted-diet-has-consequences-in-the-formation-of-pancreatic-isletinsulin-signaling-in-the-adult-offspring-of-mice">Maternal vitamin D-restricted diet has consequences in the formation of pancreatic islet/insulin-signaling in the adult offspring of mice.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocrine. 2016 May 3. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maia-Ceciliano TC1, Barreto-Vianna AR1, Barbosa-da-Silva S1, Aguila MB1, Faria TS1, Mandarim-de-Lacerda CA2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Laboratorio de Morfometria, Metabolismo e Doenca Cardiovascular, Centro Biomedico, Instituto de Biologia, Universidade do Estado de Rio de Janeiro - UERJ, Av. 28 de Setembro, 87 fds, Rio de Janeiro, RJ, 20551-030, Brazil.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lung cancer – reduced deaths if have a good vitamin D gene (CYP27B1)</title><link>/posts/lung-cancer-reduced-deaths-if-have-a-good-vitamin-d-gene-cyp27b1.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/lung-cancer-reduced-deaths-if-have-a-good-vitamin-d-gene-cyp27b1.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="genetic-polymorphisms-in-the-vitamin-d-pathway-in-relation-to-lung-cancer-risk-and-survival">Genetic polymorphisms in the vitamin D pathway in relation to lung cancer risk and survival.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Oncotarget. 2015 Feb 10;6(4):2573-82.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kong J1,2,3, Xu F1, Qu J1, Wang Y1, Gao M1, Yu H4, Qian B1,3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Tianjin Medical University Cancer Institute and Hospital, National Clinical Research Center of Cancer, Tianjin, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Cancer Epigenetics Laboratory, First Affiliated Hospital of Henan University of Science and Technology, Luoyang, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Hongqiao International Institute of Medicine, Shanghai Tongren Hospital/Faculty of Public Health, Shanghai Jiao Tong U. School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple Sclerosis risk factors – Vitamin D, parasites, and EBV – 2015</title><link>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-risk-factors-vitamin-d-parasites-and-ebv-2015.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/multiple-sclerosis-risk-factors-vitamin-d-parasites-and-ebv-2015.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="multiple-sclerosis-and-environmental-factors-the-role-of-vitamin-d-parasites-and-epstein-barr-virus-infection">Multiple sclerosis and environmental factors: the role of vitamin D, parasites, and Epstein-Barr virus infection.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Neurol Scand. 2015;132(199):46-55. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/ane.12431.">doi: 10.1111/ane.12431.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correale J1, Gaitán MI1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Neurology, Institute for Neurological Research Dr. Raúl Carrea, FLENI, Buenos Aires, Argentina.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pathogenic mechanisms underlying multiple sclerosis development have yet to be clearly identified, but considerable evidence indicates that autoimmunity plays an important role in the etiology of the disease. It is generally accepted that autoimmune diseases like MS arise from complex interactions between genetic susceptibility and environmental factors. Although environmental factors unequivocally influencing MS development have yet to be established, accumulating evidence singles out several candidates, including sunlight-UV exposure or vitamin D deficiency, viral infections, hygiene, and cigarette smoking. Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with different autoimmune diseases. Several investigations indicate 125 (OH)2 vitamin D plays a critical role in shaping T-cell response and inducing T cells with immunosuppressive properties. Likewise, helminth infections represent another potential environmental factor exerting immunomodulatory properties. Both epidemiological and experimental data provide evidence to support autoimmune down-regulation secondary to parasite infections in patients with MS, through regulatory T- and B-cell action, with effects extending beyond simple response to an infectious agent. Finally, different epidemiological studies have demonstrated that Epstein-Barr virus infection confers added risk of developing MS. Proposed mechanisms responsible for this association include activation and expansion of self-reactive T and B cells, lower threshold for self-tolerance breakdown, and enhanced autoreactive B-cell survival, all to be discussed in this review. Understanding environmental factors influencing propensity to MS will lead to new and more effective approaches to prevent and treat the disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Asthma at age 20 increased if vitamin D during pregnancy was higher than 50 ng</title><link>/posts/asthma-at-age-20-increased-if-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-was-higher-than-50-ng.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/asthma-at-age-20-increased-if-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-was-higher-than-50-ng.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-long-term-programming-effect-of-maternal-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-in-pregnancy-on-allergic-airway-disease-and-lung-function-in-offspring-after-20-to-25-years-of-follow-up">The long-term programming effect of maternal 25-hydroxyvitamin D in pregnancy on allergic airway disease and lung function in offspring after 20 to 25 years of follow-up.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2015 Jul;136(1):169-176.e2. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaci.2014.12.1924.">doi: 10.1016/j.jaci.2014.12.1924.&lt;/a> Epub 2015 Jan 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hansen S1, Maslova E2, Strøm M2, Linneberg A3, Halldorsson TI4, Granström C2, Dahl R5, Hoffmann HJ6, Olsen SF7.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Compared to 30 to 50 ng of vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>80% increased chance of asthma if mother had &amp;gt; 50 ng of vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rebuttal to the \"Vitamins are Bad\" Editorial</title><link>/posts/rebuttal-to-the-vitamins-are-bad-editorial.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rebuttal-to-the-vitamins-are-bad-editorial.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="by-dr-rhonda-patrick--her-website-is-httpwwwfoundmyfitnesscomhttpwwwfoundmyfitnesscom">By Dr. Rhonda Patrick, her website is &lt;a href="http://www.foundmyfitness.com">http://www.foundmyfitness.com&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>author requested that the text be removed from this webpage&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- ~tc~
In this article I will discuss a recent headline-grabbing editorial that was published in the Annals of Internal Medicine that reviewed three studies on the topic of multivitamins and chronic disease prevention. The editorial, is titled: __Enough is Enough: Stop Wasting Money on Vitamin and Mineral Supplements__, and its purpose was to serve as a direct call to action for medical professionals to advise against the daily use of vitamin and mineral supplements and for scientists to stop further research into the potential benefits of supplements.

Watch the video here: [http://youtu.be/o0u8UdZeOhc]

This editorial ignored decades of well-done nutrition research that has shown that supplementing appropriate levels of micronutrients (such as vitamin D, B vitamins, and omega-3s) are extremely helpful in preventing disease and decreasing all-cause mortality primarily due to widespread dietary inadequacy of essential vitamins, minerals, and fatty acids. According to a NHANES and CDC report published in 2012, the percentage of adults in the US that do not take vitamin and mineral supplements and fall below the estimated average requirement for vitamin and minerals are the following:
*96% for vitamin D (1)
*48% for vitamin C (1)
*96% for vitamin E (1)
*58% for vitamin A (1)
Now compare this to the percentage of Adults in the US who do routinely use multivitamin supplements, in these cases:
*25% for vitamin D (1)
*3% for Vitamin C (1)
*5% for Vitamin E (1)
*2% for Vitamin A (1)
These data demonstrate that many US adults are not getting adequate levels of important vitamins from their diet and vitamin/mineral supplements help to fill these nutritional gaps at a low cost.

The misleading editorial was broken down into three specific categories:
*Effects on cancer incidence and other age-related diseases
*Effects on cognition and cognitive decline
*Effects on cardiovascular disease
The final conclusion of the editorial was that vitamin/mineral supplements were functionally ineffective or, worse yet, deleterious in their effects in all three categories.

This editorial covered one meta-analysis including multiple studies and two other studies. I identified a few common methodological problems with these studies, which the authors relied upon as their supporting evidence. These problems were the following: 

Lack of any objective biochemical analyses on vitamin and mineral levels in plasma or blood cells either at baseline (before treatment) or at the follow-up (after the treatment).
In many cases, the study population was severely deficient in a particular micronutrient and at the end of the trial they were still deficient, meaning the vitamin/mineral dose in the treatment group was inadequate.
Dose being often extremely inadequate or conversely, excessively high.
Study participants being already in an advanced diseased state (which is funny, since the editorial emphasized multivitamins had no effect on prevention).
Some of these studies included meta-analyses, which consisted of multiple studies some of which had positive findings, which were left out and not mentioned in the editorial. I feel that this point, in particular, demonstrates overt bias by the editorial's authors.

__Let's begin with the effects on cancer incidence:__
Out of eleven studies analyzed, two studies showed a protective effect of multivitamin or calcium supplementation on cancer incidence, of course the positive effects were not mentioned in the attention-grabbing editorial. One study began with a severely vitamin D deficient population of women (12 ng/ml) and at the end of the study women had only raised their vitamin D levels (23 ng/ml) from severely deficient to just deficient (2). If you are designing a clinical trial with vitamin D and your population is severely deficient then you should aim at giving the treatment group a dose high enough that will get them up to adequate serum levels of vitamin D, which is generally considered to be above 30 ng/ml.

Several of the studies did not measure the vitamin and mineral levels at baseline or at follow-up; therefore, negative data (meaning no effect on cancer incidence) is meaningless and no conclusions can be made. While the majority of studies included in this particular meta-analysis involved diseased individuals the editorial claimed that vitamins and minerals have no effect on cancer prevention. This is misleading as a very small percentage of these studies looked at cancer prevention and actually had biochemical evidence that treatment worked and those studies found that multivitamin protected against cancer incidence in men but not women (2).When we examine the data we see the reason there was no effect in women is because the plasma levels of vitamins and minerals were the same in the placebo compared to the treatment group, so of course supplementation did not show an effect compared to placebo if their levels of the micronutrient were the same between the two groups. If there were no biochemical data in this study it would not have been possible to understand why there was a protective effect in men but not women. This really highlights the importance of biochemical endpoints to quantify the effectiveness of treatment as well as compliance. For those studies with no quantification of any biochemical data, there can be no conclusions made. I cannot emphasize this enough.

Some of studies included in this meta-analysis also started with a population of individuals that were in an early or late stage of cancer and found that giving them a high dose of particular vitamins namely folate or vitamin A actually accelerated the cancer (2).

This is a really important point that I want to emphasize. You need to understand the potential mechanism before designing a clinical trial in which the treatment may actually harm people. For example, folate is an essential B vitamin because it is required for DNA replication and DNA repair among other things. Folate is required for the incorporation of a specific nucleotide, thymine into DNA. This is important because your body synthesizes new DNA as it makes new cells, meaning folate is required to make DNA for newly made cells. However, if you already have cancer, taking high doses of folic acid is not a good thing because cancer (among other things) is a disease of rapid and excessive cellular proliferation. This means that cancer cells require a continuous supply of nucleotides, amino acids, and energy to flourish. Since folate it necessary to make new DNA, cancer cells may use this to their advantage because they are continuously making new DNA. The results of the study are very specific to folate, and not something that should be generalized to other vitamins and minerals. The fact of the matter is that inhibition of folate metabolism is a well-established chemotherapeutic target for many types of cancer. This does not mean, however, that folate is bad... if you do not have cancer, having adequate levels of folate is very important to prevent cancer. In fact, inadequate folate levels actually damage your DNA - - which is itself known to cause cancer - - in a manner not unlike irradiation (3).

One other vitamin that has shown similar paradoxical effects is vitamin A. Vitamin A ultimately gets converted into a steroid hormone, retinoic acid, which regulates the transcription of many different genes. For example, Retinoic acid plays an important role in the function of the immune system, which is important to fight off cancer. 

With that said, it has been shown that individuals at high risk for lung cancer due to smoking cigarettes or asbestos exposure should avoid high doses of vitamin A because it can accelerate carcinogenesis (3). The same dose of vitamin A given to non-smokers does not affect cancer incidence. It has been shown that the lungs of smokers have a highly oxidative environment in addition to low levels of anti-oxidants such as vitamins C and E (3). Under these highly oxidative conditions caratenoids can be cleaved into products that can damage DNA (which is known to cause carcinogenesis) and these cleaved products also interfere with caratenoids forming active vitamin A hormone (3). 

As for the negative effects of high doses of particular vitamins, it is important to differentiate between the effects on someone in a healthy versus diseased state. In the case of folate, inadequate levels in a healthy person can cause cancer but for someone that already has cancer, high doses of folate is fuel to feed the cancer cells. In the case of vitamin A, people that are smokers or have been exposed to asbestos, need to be cautious about supplementing with high doses of vitamin A and this does not appear to be the case for non-smokers. Well, everyone should be cautious about high doses of vitamin A since it is fat-soluble it can be toxic at high levels to anyone. Too much of a good this can sometimes be a bad thing.

There are also multitude of well-done studies that have shown the protective effects of vitamin D on cancer incidence and metastasis. Theses studies have shown that people with adequate levels of vitamin D have a decreased cancer incidence and all-cause mortality. Additionally, the same has been shown for individuals that have already had cancer: adequate levels of vitamin D were associated with decreased metastasis and relapse.

I also want to point out that many micronutrients are important for immune function, which is a critical line of defense against cancer. You need your immune cells to be functioning at their best so having micronutrient inadequacies is one way to ensure that will not happen.

__Now let's take a look at the two studies that investigated the effect of V/M supplementation on cognitive function:__
The first study looked at the effects of vitamin D on cognition and while this study actually used adequate doses of vitamin D (5,000 IU/day), the serum levels of vitamin D after treatment were 39ng/ml compared to the placebo, which was 30ng/nl (2). Both the placebo and treatment groups were in the adequate range so it is difficult to make any conclusions about the effect of vitamin D on cognitive function. If you want to investigate the effects of vitamin D on cognitive function then I suggest comparing populations that have different serum levels of vitamin D. The second study looked at the effects of a multivitamin similar to centrum silver on cognitive function in men over 65 but did not measure any serum levels of V/M at baseline or after treatment (4). Therefore, with no biochemical analysis, no conclusions can be made. An additional drawback of this study was that cognitive function was assessed by a phone call instead of any substantive, quantitative metric.

__Let's look at the effects on cardiovascular disease:__
Two studies looked at the effect of long-term multivitamin supplementation on cardiovascular diseases. In both studies, no biochemical data on serum levels of vitamins or minerals were provided either at baseline or at the followup. Also, one study required taking 6 pills a day for 4.5 years and with no biochemical data, there is no real way to no if people were compliant (5). Therefore, the conclusions are questionable. Again to highlight the importance of biochemical data, one study demonstrated that vitamins C and E supplementation significantly reduced incidence of athleroslerotic lesions (2). They showed that plasma vitamin E levels increased by 90% and the vitamin C levels increased by 72% after supplementation (2). Why was this positive effect not mentioned in the editorial? Could it be that the positive effects will not grab the attention of the press?

__In summary:__
If you are going to take time to attempt to compile data collected from nutritional clinical trials, I suggest you understand how to critically analyze the data. Clinical trials in nutrition are extremely difficult to do right. It is imperative to measure vitamin/mineral concentrations in the plasma both BEFORE and AFTER treatment.

__ The failures of this editorial are the following:__
* Failures to critically analyze the data in the studies and over generalizing the results.
* Lumping all vitamins and minerals together when effects depend on dose and even individual disease status.
*Failure to quantitate any vitamin/mineral concentrations at baseline or follow-up.
The answer is not to end all research and stop supplementation of vitamins and minerals. 
Instead, the answer is quite the opposite. It is to do MORE research and establish what those very specific edge cases are and for healthcare providers to make recommendations based on knowledge of the positive and negative effects and not to make poorly-informed recommendations caused by lack of knowledge or from having read too many highly misleading editorials.
!!!References
* 1. Bailey RL, Fulgoni VL, 3rd, Keast DR, &amp; Dwyer JT (2012) Examination of vitamin intakes among US adults by dietary supplement use. Journal of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics 112(5):657-663 e654.
*2. Fortmann SP, Burda BU, Senger CA, Lin JS, &amp; Whitlock EP (2013) Vitamin and Mineral Supplements in the Primary Prevention of Cardiovascular Disease and Cancer: An Updated Systematic Evidence Review for the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force. Annals of internal medicine.
*3. Russell RM (2004) The Enigma of β-Carotene in Carcinogenesis: What Can Be Learned from Animal Studies. The Jpurnal of Nutrition 134:262-268.
*4. Grodstein F OBJ, Kang JH, Dushkes R, Cook NR, Okereke O (2013) Long-term multivitamin supplementation and cognitive function in men. A randomized trial. Ann Intern Med. 159:601-612.
*5. Lamas GA BR, Goertz C, Mark DB, Rosenberg Y, Stylianou M. (2013) Oral high-dose multivitamins and minerals after myocardial infarction. A randomized trial. Ann Intern Med. 159:797-804.
~/tc~ -->
&lt;h3 id="about-dr-patrick">About Dr. Patrick:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Dr. Patrick has a Ph.D. in Biomedical Science and has done extensive research on aging, cancer, and nutrition. She is an expert on nutrition and metabolism and currently conducts clinical trials examining the positive effects of vitamin and mineral supplementation on metabolism, inflammation, and aging.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Receptor – environment, genetics and epigenetics</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-environment-genetics-and-epigenetics.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-environment-genetics-and-epigenetics.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="regulation-of-the-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-by-environment-genetics-and-epigenetics">Regulation of the vitamin D receptor gene by environment, genetics and epigenetics&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Gene, Volume 561, Issue 2, 1 May 2015, Pages 171–180, doi:10.1016/j.gene.2015.02.024&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Donovan Saccone, Furaha Asani, Liza Bornman, &lt;a href="mailto:lizab@uj.ac.za">lizab@uj.ac.za&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Biochemistry, Auckland Park Campus, University of Johannesburg, PO Box 524, Auckland Park 2006, South Africa&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Role of VDR in physiology and disease necessitates understanding of its regulation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>We reviewed the regulation of VDR by environment, genetics and epigenetics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D can probably stop 'modern' diseases - Gillie 2014</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-can-probably-stop-modern-diseases-gillie-2014.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-can-probably-stop-modern-diseases-gillie-2014.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d--could-it-stop-modern-diseases">Vitamin D – could it stop &amp;lsquo;modern’ diseases?&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-power-of-the-summer-sun">THE POWER OF THE SUMMER SUN&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#people-with-winter-birthdays-are-at-greater-risk-of-type-1-diabetes">People with winter birthdays are at greater risk of type 1 diabetes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#indoor-lifestyles-blamed">INDOOR LIFESTYLES BLAMED&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#between-1989-and-2006-the-incidence-of-ms-in-iran-increased-more-than-eight-fold">Between 1989 and 2006, the incidence of MS in Iran increased more than eight fold&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#prevention-is-crucial">PREVENTION IS CRUCIAL&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#britains-cloudy-skies-are-bad-news">BRITAIN&amp;rsquo;S CLOUDY SKIES ARE BAD NEWS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d--could-it-stop-modern-diseases">Vitamin D – could it stop &amp;lsquo;modern’ diseases?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>^By Oliver Gillie 10 Mar 2014 and 07 Aug 2014 in &lt;a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/health/10686624/Vitamin-D-could-it-stop-modern-diseases.html">UK Telegraph&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epigenetics meets endocrinology - 2011</title><link>/posts/epigenetics-meets-endocrinology-2011.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/epigenetics-meets-endocrinology-2011.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/epigenetics-meets-endocrinology.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki.&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/eigenetics-endocrinology.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/epigenetics-meets-endocrinology-f3.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/Search+Results?hl=en&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search&amp;amp;googles.x=0&amp;amp;googles.y=0&amp;amp;q=EPIGENETICS&amp;amp;domains=VitaminDWiki.com&amp;amp;sitesearch=VitaminDWiki.com%20">Search VitaminDWiki for EPIGENETICS&lt;/a> 213 items as of Jan 2015&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Anorexia nervosa and Vitamin D - several studies</title><link>/posts/anorexia-nervosa-and-vitamin-d-several-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/anorexia-nervosa-and-vitamin-d-several-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Anorexia Nervosa appears to be associated with&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Season of birth,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Low vitamin D while pregnant,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>High latitude&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#anorexia-nervosa---10-year-update---oct-2021">Anorexia Nervosa - 10 year update - Oct 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-in-anorexia-nervosa-a-meta-analysis---2014">Vitamin D status in anorexia nervosa: A meta-analysis - 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#strong-relationship-between-vitamin-d-status-and-bone-mineral-density-in-anorexia-nervosa---may-2015">Strong relationship between vitamin d status and bone mineral density in anorexia nervosa - May 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#an-after-low-seasonal-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-or-high-latitude---2013">AN after low seasonal vitamin D during pregnancy or high latitude - 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#anorexia-resulted-in-vitamin-d-level-25-ngml--aug-2014">Anorexia resulted in vitamin D level 25 ng/ml – Aug 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#season-of-birth-related-to-an--11-studies-conclude-an-association---2012">Season of birth related to AN – 11 studies conclude an association - 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#season-of-birth-and-anorexia-nervosa-may-2011">Season of birth and anorexia nervosa May 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#speculation-supplementing-with-vitamin-d-while-pregnant-will-reduce-later-anorexia">Speculation: Supplementing with vitamin D while pregnant will reduce later anorexia&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="anorexia-nervosa---10-year-update---oct-2021">Anorexia Nervosa - 10 year update - Oct 2021&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Anorexia Nervosa—What Has Changed in the State of Knowledge about Nutritional Rehabilitation for Patients over the Past 10 Years? A Review of Literature&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels around the world - DSM review</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-around-the-world-dsm-review.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-around-the-world-dsm-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="31-vitamin-d-a-critical-and-essential-micronutrient-for-human-health">3.1 Vitamin D: a critical and essential micronutrient for human health&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Frontiers in Physiology, 1664-042X, Provisional PDF published on: &lt;a href="https://www.frontiersin.org">www.frontiersin.org&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Igor Bendik, Angelika Friedel, Franz F. Roos, Peter Weber &amp;amp; Manfred Eggersdorfer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DSM Nutritional Products Ltd, Kaiseraugst, Switzerland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence: Dr. Igor Bendik, DSM Nutritional Products Ltd,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Human Nutrition and Health, Bldg 201/219A, P.O. Box 2676, CH-4002 Basel, Switzerland, E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:Igor.bendik@dsm.com">Igor.bendik@dsm.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conflict of Interest Statement: All authors are employees of DSM Nutritional Products Ltd. They declare no conflict of interest.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epigenetics of Multiple Sclerosis</title><link>/posts/epigenetics-of-multiple-sclerosis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/epigenetics-of-multiple-sclerosis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epigenetics-of-multiple-sclerosis-an-updated-review---2014">Epigenetics of Multiple Sclerosis: An Updated Review - 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="epigenetics-of-multiple-sclerosis-an-updated-review---2014">Epigenetics of Multiple Sclerosis: An Updated Review - 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>NeuroMolecular Medicine March 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cem İsmail Küçükali, Murat Kürtüncü, Arzu Çoban, Merve Çebi, Erdem Tüzün&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Department of Neuroscience, Institute for Experimental Medicine (DETAE), Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="mailto:drerdem@yahoo.com">drerdem@yahoo.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiple sclerosis (MS) is an inflammatory and neurodegenerative disease characterized with autoimmune response against myelin proteins and progressive axonal loss. The heterogeneity of the clinical course and low concordance rates in monozygotic twins have indicated the involvement of complex heritable and environmental factors in MS pathogenesis. MS is more often transmitted to the next generation by mothers than fathers suggesting an epigenetic influence. One of the possible reasons of this parent-of-origin effect might be the human leukocyte antigen-DRB1*15 allele, which is the major risk factor for MS and regulated by epigenetic mechanisms such as DNA methylation and histone deacetylation. Moreover, major environmental risk factors for MS, vitamin D deficiency, smoking and Ebstein–Barr virus are all known to exert epigenetic changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gout and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/gout-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gout-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-gout---includes-2-treatment-studies-using-50000-iu--weekly-or-twice-a-week-for-2-months---sept-2023">Vitamin D and Gout - includes 2 treatment studies using 50,000 IU weekly or twice a week for 2 months - Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#4x-less-likely-to-die-of-gout-if-40-ng-of-vitamin-d---aug-2024">4X less likely to die of Gout if 40 ng of Vitamin D - Aug 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-gout-facts-etc">Vitamin D and Gout: Facts, etc.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#gout-in-the-uk-increased-20-in-3-years---sept-2022">Gout in the UK increased 20% in 3 years - Sept 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#gout-ra-symptoms-sometimes-the-same-sometimes-different">Gout, RA symptoms sometimes the same, sometimes different&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#gout-epigenetics-vitamin--d-vitamin-d-receptor-omega-3-etc---sept-2022">Gout epigenetics: Vitamin D, Vitamin D Receptor, Omega-3, etc - Sept 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-gout---includes-2-treatment-studies-using-50000-iu--weekly-or-twice-a-week-for-2-months---sept-2023">Vitamin D and Gout - includes 2 treatment studies using 50,000 IU weekly or twice a week for 2 months - Sept 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.cibdol.com/blog/1618-can-vitamin-d-cause-gout">Can vitamin d cause gout?&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Surprise:Three different types of vitamin D can activate the vitamin D receptor</title><link>/posts/surprisethree-different-types-of-vitamin-d-can-activate-the-vitamin-d-receptor.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/surprisethree-different-types-of-vitamin-d-can-activate-the-vitamin-d-receptor.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="gene-expression-profiles-in-human-and-mouse-primary-cells-provide-new-insights-into-the-differential-actions-of-vitamin-d3-metabolites">Gene Expression Profiles in Human and Mouse Primary Cells Provide New Insights into the Differential Actions of Vitamin D3 Metabolites&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(10): e75338. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0075338&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pentti Tuohimaa, Jing-Huan Wang, Sofia Khan, Marianne Kuuslahti, Kui Qian, Tommi Manninen, Petri Auvinen, Mauno Vihinen, Yan-Ru Lou mail&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1α,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1α,25(OH)2D3) had earlier been regarded as the only active hormone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The newly identified actions of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 (25(OH)D3) and 24R,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (24R,25(OH)2D3) broadened the vitamin D3 endocrine system, however, the current data are fragmented and a systematic understanding is lacking. Here we performed the first systematic study of global gene expression to clarify their similarities and differences.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Previous VitaminDWiki News</title><link>/posts/previous-vitamindwiki-news.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/previous-vitamindwiki-news.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-hrefpostsclick-here-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-4259click-herea-for-latest-news">&lt;a href="/posts/click-here" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 4259">CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for latest news&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="top-vitamin-d-news-july-23---aug-5-2013nbsp-nbsp-nbsp-------on-the-web-at-httpisgdvitamindnews">Top Vitamin D News: July 23 - Aug 5, 2013      on the web at &lt;a href="http://is.gd/VitaminDNews">http://is.gd/VitaminDNews&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/populations-with-more-than-50-ng-of-vitamin-d">Populations with more than 50 ng of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>     The &lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-video-being-produced-by-vitamindwiki" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 3914">vitamin D video being produced by VitaminDWiki&lt;/a> will probably suggest &lt;strong>restoring&lt;/strong> vitamin D to 40+ ng&lt;/p>
&lt;p>     Extremely few people now have an optimum level of vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Global Perspective - Holick</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-global-perspective-holick.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-global-perspective-holick.html</guid><description>&lt;p>It is now generally accepted that vitamin D deficiency is a worldwide health problem that affects not only musculoskeletal health but also a wide range of acute and chronic diseases. However, there remains cynicism about the lack of randomized controlled trials to support the association studies regarding the nonskeletal health benefits of vitamin D. This review was obtained by searching English-language studies published up to April 1, 2013, in PubMed, MEDLINE, and the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (search terms: vitamin D and supplementation) and focuses on recent challenges regarding the definition of vitamin D deficiency and how to achieve optimal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations from dietary sources, supplements, and sun exposure. The effect of vitamin D on fetal programming epigenetics and gene regulation could potentially explain why vitamin D has been reported to have such wide-ranging health benefits throughout life. There is potentially a great upside to increasing the vitamin D status of children and adults worldwide for improving musculoskeletal health and reducing the risk of chronic illnesses, including some cancers, autoimmune diseases, infectious diseases, type 2 diabetes mellitus, neurocognitive disorders, and mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Workshop</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-workshop.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-workshop.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="16th-vitamin-d-workshop-and-vitamin-d-portion-of-endo-june-2013posts16th-vitamin-d-workshop-and-vitamin-d-portion-of-endo">&lt;a href="/posts/16th-vitamin-d-workshop-and-vitamin-d-portion-of-endo">16th Vitamin D Workshop and Vitamin D portion of ENDO June 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>San Franciso, California June 12 - 14&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-workshop-slides">Vitamin D Workshop Slides - June 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-workshop-posters">Vitamin D Workshop Posters - June 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamindwiki-poster-20122013" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 2698">VitaminDWiki poster 2012,2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">Commonwealth talk near to workshop: &lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/autism-treated-by-vitamin-d-dr-cannell-video">Autism treated by Vitamin D: Dr. Cannell - video June 2013&lt;/a> video&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/breast-cancer-and-vitamin-d-dr-garland-video">Breast Cancer and Vitamin D: Dr Garland - video June 2013&lt;/a> video&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>16th Vitamin D Workshop and Vitamin D portion of ENDO</title><link>/posts/16th-vitamin-d-workshop-and-vitamin-d-portion-of-endo.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/16th-vitamin-d-workshop-and-vitamin-d-portion-of-endo.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="preliminary-workshop-program-as-of-spring-2013">Preliminary Workshop Program as of Spring 2013&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>updated version is attached as PDF file at the bottom of this page&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See also &lt;a href="/posts/international-congress-on-vitamin-d-vitamind-workshop-ny" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: International Congress on Vitamin D (VitaminD Workshop) – NY May 2019">International Congress on Vitamin D (VitaminD Workshop) – NY May 2019&lt;/a> has links to many previous workshops&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="vitamin-d-workshop-slides---june-2013postsvitamin-d-workshop-slides">&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-workshop-slides">Vitamin D Workshop Slides - June 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;h4 id="june-12">June 12&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="830am-1015am-d-code-encode-chair---j-wesley-pike-phd">8:30am-10:15am: D-Code ENCODE: Chair - J Wesley Pike, PhD&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>8:30-9:15: Plenary Speaker: John Stamatoyannopoulos, MD - What is ENCODE&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes in white blood cells of blacks associated with vitamin D deficiency</title><link>/posts/genes-in-white-blood-cells-of-blacks-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-in-white-blood-cells-of-blacks-associated-with-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-genome-wide-methylation-study-of-severe-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-african-american-adolescents">A Genome-Wide Methylation Study of Severe Vitamin D Deficiency in African American Adolescents&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Journal of Pediatrics. Volume 162, Issue 5 , Pages 1004-1009.e1, May 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Haidong Zhu, MD, PhD email address , Xiaoling Wang, MD, PhD , Huidong Shi, PhD ,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shaoyong Su, PhD , Gregory A. Harshfield, PhD , Bernard Gutin, PhD , Harold Snieder, PhD , Yanbin Dong, MD, PhD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received 2 July 2012; received in revised form 13 September 2012; accepted 31 October 2012. published online 10 December 2012.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Higher weight and blood pressure in second generation from mother mouse who had low vitamin D – 2012</title><link>/posts/higher-weight-and-blood-pressure-in-second-generation-from-mother-mouse-who-had-low-vitamin-d-2012.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/higher-weight-and-blood-pressure-in-second-generation-from-mother-mouse-who-had-low-vitamin-d-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="maternal-vitamin-d-deficiency-delays-glomerular-maturity-in-f1-and-f2-offspring">Maternal vitamin D deficiency delays glomerular maturity in F1 and F2 offspring.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PLoS One. 2012;7(8):e41740. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0041740.">doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0041740.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Aug 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nascimento FA, Ceciliano TC, Aguila MB, Mandarim-de-Lacerda CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laboratory of Morphometry, Metabolism and Cardiovascular Disease, Biomedical Center, Institute of Biology, State University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, RJ, Brazil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: There is a high prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency in women of reproductive age.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: This work studied the first two generations of offspring (F1 and F2) of Swiss mice from mothers fed one of two diets: SC (standard chow) or VitD- (vitamin D-deficient). Functional and developmental kidney measurements were taken.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First and 2nd generation migrants 2X more likely to have psychotic disorders</title><link>/posts/first-and-2nd-generation-migrants-2x-more-likely-to-have-psychotic-disorders.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/first-and-2nd-generation-migrants-2x-more-likely-to-have-psychotic-disorders.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="ethnic-minority-position-and-risk-for-psychotic-disorders">Ethnic minority position and risk for psychotic disorders&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Current Opinion in Psychiatry:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Veling, Wim&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Purpose of review: This article reviews the recent literature about migration, ethnic minority position and the risk of psychotic disorders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent findings: A meta-analysis found that both first and second-generation migrants have on average a two-fold increase in risk for psychotic disorders. In the Netherlands, the risk was most elevated for individuals who migrated in early childhood. Several studies investigated diagnostic ethnic bias and reported greater likelihood of schizophrenia diagnosis in ethnic minority patients at the cost of diagnosis of affective psychotic disorders. Neighbourhood ethnic density was related to prevalence of psychotic experiences in ethnic minority populations in the UK. Perceived discrimination was associated with severity of psychotic and depressive symptoms in ethnic minority patients. Both weak and strong ethnic identification, as well as experiences of social adversity, were related to risk for psychosis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Candidate list of top vitamin D papers for 2012</title><link>/posts/candidate-list-of-top-vitamin-d-papers-for-2012.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/candidate-list-of-top-vitamin-d-papers-for-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="by-william-b-grant-et-al-dec-25-2012">By William B. Grant, et al. Dec 25, 2012&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This list has about 56 papers. I would like to get it down to 10-12 or so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The papers included should be important to the general population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They should also cover a range of topics related to vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-hrefpostsf00click-here-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-3667__f00click-herea-for-the-winners__">&lt;a href="/posts/f00click-here" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 3667">&lt;strong>&lt;del>#F00:CLICK HERE&lt;/a> for the winners&lt;/del>&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="short-list-of-papers---followed-by-abstracts">Short list of papers - followed by abstracts&lt;/h3>
&lt;h5 id="some-fraction-of-the-papers-have-web-pages-on-vitamindwiki">Some fraction of the papers have web pages on VitaminDWiki&lt;/h5>
&lt;h3 id="asthma">Asthma&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bener A, Ehlayel MS, Tulic MK, Hamid Q. Vitamin D deficiency as a strong predictor of asthma in children. . 2012;157(2):168-75.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="autism">Autism&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Kočovská E, Fernell E, Billstedt E, Minnis H, Gillberg C. Vitamin D and autism: clinical review. . 2012 Sep-Oct;33(5):1541-50.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High level of maternal vitamin D and infant food allergy – controversy</title><link>/posts/high-level-of-maternal-vitamin-d-and-infant-food-allergy-controversy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-level-of-maternal-vitamin-d-and-infant-food-allergy-controversy.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="maternal-and-newborn-vitamin-d-status-and-its-impact-on-food-allergy-development-in-the-german-lina-cohort-study">Maternal and newborn vitamin D status and its impact on food allergy development in the German LINA cohort study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Allergy 2012; 68:220–228; DOI: 10.1111/all.12081.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>K. Weisse 1, S. Winkler 1,2, F. Hirche 2, G. Herberth 1, D. Hinz 1, M. Bauer 1, S. Röder 3, U. Rolle-Kampczyk 4, M. von Bergen 4, S. Olek 5, U. Sack 6, T. Richter 7, U. Diez 7, M. Borte 7, G. I. Stangl 2, I. Lehmann 1,3, &lt;a href="mailto:irina.lehmann@ufz.de">irina.lehmann@ufz.de&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Transgeneration vitamin D deficiency related to MS was found in mice</title><link>/posts/transgeneration-vitamin-d-deficiency-related-to-ms-was-found-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/transgeneration-vitamin-d-deficiency-related-to-ms-was-found-in-mice.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prenatal-vitamin-d-deficiency-induces-an-early-and-more-severe-experimental-autoimmune-encephalomyelitis-in-the-second-generation">Prenatal Vitamin D Deficiency Induces an Early and More Severe Experimental Autoimmune Encephalomyelitis in the Second Generation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2012, 13(9), 10911-10919; doi:10.3390/ijms130910911&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Diana Andrea Fernandes de Abreu 1 , Véréna Landel 1 , Adrian G. Barnett 2 , John McGrath 3,4 , Darryl Eyles 3,4 and Francois Feron 1,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Neurobiology of Cell Interactions and Neurophysiopathology, Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, UMR 7259, Aix Marseille Université, Marseille 13015, France&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epigenetics, vitamin D, and Multiple Sclerosis</title><link>/posts/epigenetics-vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/epigenetics-vitamin-d-and-multiple-sclerosis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epigenetic-changes-in-patients-with-multiple-sclerosis---nov-2012">Epigenetic changes in patients with multiple sclerosis - Nov 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#epigenetics---is-it-real-new-york-times-review-of-plos-genetics-article---july-2016">Epigenetics - is it real: New York Times review of PLOS Genetics article - July 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="epigenetic-changes-in-patients-with-multiple-sclerosis---nov-2012">Epigenetic changes in patients with multiple sclerosis - Nov 2012&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nat Rev Neurol. 2012 Nov 20. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2012.226.">doi: 10.1038/nrneurol.2012.226.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Koch MW, Metz LM, Kovalchuk O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Calgary, Foothills Hospital, 1403-29th Street N. W., Calgary, AB T2N 2T9, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epigenetic changes influence gene expression without altering the DNA sequence. DNA methylation, histone modification and microRNA-associated post-transcriptional gene silencing are three key epigenetic mechanisms. Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a disease of the CNS with both inflammatory and neurodegenerative features. Although studies on epigenetic changes in MS only began in the past decade, a growing body of literature suggests that epigenetic changes may be involved in the development of MS, possibly by mediating the effects of environmental risk factors, such as&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>