<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer - Colon on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer---colon.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer - Colon on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer---colon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Emerging role of vitamin D in colorectal cancer</title><link>/posts/emerging-role-of-vitamin-d-in-colorectal-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/emerging-role-of-vitamin-d-in-colorectal-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;p>World J Gastrointest Oncol. 2011 Aug 15;3(8):123-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kang W, Lee S, Jeon E, Yun YR, Kim KH, Jang JH. &lt;a href="mailto:juhjang@inha.ac.kr">juhjang@inha.ac.kr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wonmo Kang, Sujin Lee, Eunyi Jeon, Ye-Rang Yun, Jun-Hyeog Jang, Department of Biochemistry, School of Medicine, Inha University, Incheon 400-712, South Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Colorectal cancer is a common cancer and the fourth leading cause of death in Korea. The incidence and mortality of colorectal cancer varies according to risk factors, such as age, family history, genetic history, food habits, and physical activities. Some studies have focused on the association between vitamin D and colorectal cancer. Today, there is growing evidence that high vitamin D intake and a plasma level of 25(OH)D(3) reduce the incidence of colorectal cancer by modifying cancer angiogenesis, cell apoptosis, differentiation, and proliferation. Taken together, these results suggest that vitamin D supplementation alone, or in combination with anti-cancer agents, might reduce the incidence of colorectal cancer. In this review, we discuss the function and mechanism of vitamin D including the effect of vitamin D on colorectal cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancers and Vitamin D Council</title><link>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Colorectal cancer 26 percent less likely for every 10 ng of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colorectal-cancer-26-percent-less-likely-for-every-10-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-cancer-26-percent-less-likely-for-every-10-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>800 IU of vitamin D not enough to treat colon cancer</title><link>/posts/800-iu-of-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-treat-colon-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-of-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-treat-colon-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="effects-of-supplemental-vitamin-d-and-calcium-on-biomarkers-of-inflammation-in-colorectal-adenoma-patients-a-randomized-controlled-clinical-trialhttpcancerpreventionresearchaacrjournalsorgcontentearly201106281940-6207capr-11-0105abstract">&lt;a href="http://cancerpreventionresearch.aacrjournals.org/content/early/2011/06/28/1940-6207.CAPR-11-0105.abstract">Effects of supplemental vitamin D and calcium on biomarkers of inflammation in colorectal adenoma patients: A randomized, controlled clinical trial&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>– – – – – –&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="far-too-little-vitamin-d-to-help">Far too little vitamin D to help&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="see-vitamindwiki">See VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=41&amp;amp;deep=off&amp;amp;type=">All items in Colon Cancer and Vitamin D&lt;/a> 33 items as of July 2011&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Colon polyps reduced 15 percent by increasing vitamin D by 20 ng – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colon-polyps-reduced-15-percent-by-increasing-vitamin-d-by-20-ng-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-polyps-reduced-15-percent-by-increasing-vitamin-d-by-20-ng-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="meta-analysis-serum-vitamin-d-and-colorectal-adenoma-risk">Meta-analysis: Serum vitamin D and colorectal adenoma risk.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Prev Med. 2011 Jun 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yin L, Grandi N, Raum E, Haug U, Arndt V, Brenner H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To perform a systematic review and meta-analysis of human studies on the association between serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and incident, sporadic colorectal adenoma (CRA) and CRA recurrence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relevant studies among humans were identified by systematically searching Ovid Medline, EMBASE, and ISI Web of Knowledge databases and by cross-referencing. Due to the heterogeneity across studies in categorizing serum vitamin D levels, all results were recalculated for an increase of serum 25(OH)D by 20ng/ml. Summary odds ratios (ORs) were calculated using meta-analysis methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genetics and colon cancer with only 400 IU of vitamin D – Dissertation</title><link>/posts/genetics-and-colon-cancer-with-only-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-dissertation.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genetics-and-colon-cancer-with-only-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-dissertation.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="genetic-and-environmental-factors-influencing-circulating-concentration-of-vitamin-d-metabolites-and-odds-of-colorectal-neoplasia">Genetic and environmental factors influencing circulating concentration of vitamin D metabolites and odds of colorectal neoplasia&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>by Hibler, Elizabeth Anne, Ph.D., THE UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA, 2011, 387 pages; 3450731&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction. Circulating concentrations of vitamin D metabolites are associated with risk for a variety of diseases, including colorectal cancer. It is not known what level of circulating 25(OH)D is optimal for health; however, over-the-counter (OTC) vitamin D supplements are commonly used to improve status, though their effectiveness is unknown. It is also not known if polymorphic variation in genes associated with the vitamin D endocrine system is associated with differences in vitamin D metabolite levels or colorectal neoplasia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency more strongly associated with rectal than colon cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-more-strongly-associated-with-rectal-than-colon-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-more-strongly-associated-with-rectal-than-colon-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="circulating-levels-of-vitamin-d-and-colon-and-rectal-cancer-the-physicians-health-study-and-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Circulating levels of vitamin D and colon and rectal cancer: the Physicians&amp;rsquo; Health Study and a meta-analysis of prospective studies.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Cancer Prev Res (Phila). 2011 Mar 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee JE, Li H, Chan AT, Hollis BW, Lee IM, Stampfer MJ, Wu K, Giovannucci E, Ma J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Food and Nutrition, Sookmyung Women&amp;rsquo;s University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It remains unknown whether increased risk with low levels of vitamin D is present for colon and/or rectal cancer. To investigate the association between circulating vitamin D levels and colon and rectal cancer, we examined the associations between plasma levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)2D) and colon and rectal cancer in the Physicians&amp;rsquo; Health Study and then conducted a meta-analysis of eight prospective studies of circulating levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and colon and rectal cancers, including the Physicians&amp;rsquo; Health Study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Every 100 IU of additional vitamin D decreased colorectal cancer by 4 percent</title><link>/posts/every-100-iu-of-additional-vitamin-d-decreased-colorectal-cancer-by-4-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/every-100-iu-of-additional-vitamin-d-decreased-colorectal-cancer-by-4-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="meta-analyses-of-vitamin-d-intake-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-vitamin-d-receptor-polymorphisms-and-colorectal-cancer-risk">Meta-analyses of vitamin D intake, 25-hydroxyvitamin D status, vitamin D receptor polymorphisms and colorectal cancer risk.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2011 Mar 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Touvier M, Chan DS, Lau RN, Aune D, Vieira R, Greenwood DC, Kampman E, Riboli E, Hercberg S, Norat T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of public health, Imperial College London.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Our objective was to conduct a systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective studies on colorectal cancer and vitamin D intake and 25-hydroxyvitamin D status, as part of the World Cancer Research Fund Continuous Update Project. We also aimed at conducting meta-analysis of all studies on colorectal cancer and vitamin D receptor (VDR) single-nucleotide polymorphisms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IBD colorectal Cancer and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ibd-colorectal-cancer-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ibd-colorectal-cancer-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-gastrointestinal-diseases-inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-colorectal-cancer">Vitamin D and gastrointestinal diseases: inflammatory bowel disease and colorectal cancer&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Therap Adv Gastroenterol. 2011 January; 4(1): 49–62.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/1756283X10377820.">doi: 10.1177/1756283X10377820.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3036961&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maitreyi Raman; Division of Gastroenterology, University of Calgary, 6D26, Teaching, Research and Wellness Building, 3280 Hospital Drive N.W., Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 4N1; &lt;a href="mailto:mkothand@ucalgary.ca">mkothand@ucalgary.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andrew N. Milestone; St. Marks Hospital, Harrow, Middlesex, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Julian R.F. Walters; Division of Medicine, Imperial College Healthcare, London, Hammersmith Hospital, Imperial College London, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increasing vitamin D increases colon cancer in Finnish smokers</title><link>/posts/increasing-vitamin-d-increases-colon-cancer-in-finnish-smokers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increasing-vitamin-d-increases-colon-cancer-in-finnish-smokers.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-risks-of-colon-and-rectal-cancer-in-finnish-men">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Risks of Colon and Rectal Cancer in Finnish Men.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Epidemiol. 2011 Jan 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Risks of Colon and Rectal Cancer in Finnish Men.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weinstein SJ, Yu K, Horst RL, Ashby J, Virtamo J, Albanes D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prospective investigations of circulating vitamin D concentrations suggest inverse associations with colorectal cancer risk, although inconsistencies remain and few studies have examined the impact of season. The authors conducted a prospective case-control study of 239 colon cancer cases and 192 rectal cancer cases (diagnosed in 1993-2005) and 428 controls matched on age and blood collection date within the Alpha-Tocopherol, Beta-Carotene Cancer Prevention Study, a cohort study of Finnish male smokers. Baseline serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentrations were categorized using a priori defined cutpoints of &amp;lt;25, 25-&amp;lt;37.5, 37.5-&amp;lt;50, 50-&amp;lt;75, and ?75 nmol/L and by season-specific and season-standardized 25(OH)D quartiles. Conditional logistic regression models yielded multivariate-adjusted odds ratios for the predefined cutpoints of 0.63, 0.91, 0.73, 1.00 (referent), and 1.44 for colon cancer and 0.64, 0.58, 0.84, 1.00, and 0.76 for rectal cancer, respectively (all 95% confidence intervals included 1.00).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Colon Cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-colon-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-colon-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="aboutcom-colon-cancer-sectionhttpcoloncanceraboutcomb20101201new-vitamin-d-recommendations-reignite-controversyhtm">&lt;a href="http://coloncancer.about.com/b/2010/12/01/new-vitamin-d-recommendations-reignite-controversy.htm">About.com Colon Cancer section&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="updated-dec-1-2010-just-after-the-a-hrefpostsinstitue-of-medicine-pronouncement-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1193institue-of-medicine-pronouncementa">Updated Dec 1, 2010, just after the &lt;a href="/posts/institue-of-medicine-pronouncement" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1193">Institue of Medicine pronouncement&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>clip - - - -&lt;/p>
&lt;p>^&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My Vitamin D Opinion&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I titled this section with the words &amp;ldquo;my opinion&amp;rdquo; because I want to make it absolutely clear that I am giving my opinion. I am a nutritionist, dietitian, and epidemiologist with experience in cancer research, so I feel that I have something to offer on this topic. But always, talk to your doctor if you have any questions about what is right for you with dietary supplements, including vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>8000 IU supplementation to people with various cancers</title><link>/posts/8000-iu-supplementation-to-people-with-various-cancers.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/8000-iu-supplementation-to-people-with-various-cancers.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="impact-of-oral-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-oncology">Impact of oral vitamin D supplementation on serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in oncology&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pankaj G Vashi email, Kristen Trukova email, Carolyn A Lammersfeld email, Donald P Braun email and Digant Gupta email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrition Journal 2010, 9:60doi:10.1186/1475-2891-9-60, 	23 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> is the major circulating form of vitamin D and a standard indicator of vitamin D status. Emerging evidence in the literature suggests a high prevalence of suboptimal vitamin D (as defined by serum 25(OH)D levels of &amp;lt;32 ng/ml) as well as an association between lower serum levels and higher mortality in cancer. We investigated the effect of oral vitamin D supplementation as a means for restoring suboptimal levels to optimal levels in cancer.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>