<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cancer - Colon on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cancer---colon.html</link><description>Recent content in Cancer - Colon on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cancer---colon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hypothesis: low vitamin D increases probability of colon cancer</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-low-vitamin-d-increases-probability-of-colon-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-low-vitamin-d-increases-probability-of-colon-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="selection-approach-suggests-causal-association-between-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-colorectal-cancer">Selection Approach Suggests Causal Association between 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Colorectal Cancer.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Model PLoS ONE 8(5): e63475. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0063475&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zgaga L, Agakov F, Theodoratou E, Farrington SM, Tenesa A, et al.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction: Vitamin D deficiency has been associated with increased risk of colorectal cancer (CRC), but causal relationship has not yet been confirmed. We investigate the direction of causation between vitamin D and CRC by extending the conventional approaches to allow pleiotropic relationships and by explicitly modelling unmeasured confounders.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>45 percent fewer deaths from digestive cancers for 10 ng increase in vitamin D – 2006</title><link>/posts/45-percent-fewer-deaths-from-digestive-cancers-for-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-2006.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/45-percent-fewer-deaths-from-digestive-cancers-for-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-2006.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="prospective-study-of-predictors-of-vitamin-d-status-and-cancer-incidence-and-mortality-in-men">Prospective study of predictors of vitamin D status and cancer incidence and mortality in men.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Natl Cancer Inst. 2006 Apr 5;98(7):451-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giovannucci E, Liu Y, Rimm EB, Hollis BW, Fuchs CS, Stampfer MJ, Willett WC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Harvard Medical School, Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Boston, MA, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:edward.giovannucci@channing.harvard.edu">edward.giovannucci@channing.harvard.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D has potent anticancer properties, especially against digestive-system cancers. Many human studies have used geographic residence as a marker of solar ultraviolet B and hence vitamin D exposure. Here, we considered multiple determinants of vitamin D exposure (dietary and supplementary vitamin D, skin pigmentation, adiposity, geographic residence, and leisure-time physical activity-to estimate sunlight exposure) in relation to cancer risk in the Health Professionals Follow-Up Study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D monotherapy reduces colorectal cancer but has calcemic side effects</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-monotherapy-reduces-colorectal-cancer-but-has-calcemic-side-effects.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-monotherapy-reduces-colorectal-cancer-but-has-calcemic-side-effects.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="antineoplastic-effects-of-125oh2d3-and-its-analogs-in-breast-prostate-and-colorectal-cancer">Antineoplastic effects of 1,25(OH)2D3 and its analogs in breast, prostate and colorectal cancer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Endocr Relat Cancer April 1, 2013 20 R31-R47&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carlien Leyssens,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lieve Verlinden and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annemieke Verstuyf, &lt;a href="mailto:mieke.verstuyf@med.kuleuven.be">mieke.verstuyf@med.kuleuven.be&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinical and Experimental Endocrinology, KU Leuven, Herestraat 49, bus 902, 3000 Leuven, Belgium&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The active form of vitamin D3, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3), is mostly known for its importance in the maintenance of calcium and phosphate homeostasis. However, next to its classical effects on bone, kidney and intestine, 1,25(OH)2D3 also exerts antineoplastic effects on various types of cancer. The use of 1,25(OH)2D3 itself as treatment against neoplasia is hampered by its calcemic side effects. Therefore, 1,25(OH)2D3-derived analogs were developed that are characterized by lower calcemic side effects and stronger antineoplastic effects. This review mainly focuses on the role of 1,25(OH)2D3 in breast, prostate and colorectal cancer (CRC) and the underlying signaling pathways. 1,25(OH)2D3 and its analogs inhibit proliferation, angiogenesis, migration/invasion and induce differentiation and apoptosis in malignant cell lines. Moreover, prostaglandin synthesis and Wnt/b-catenin signaling are also influenced by 1,25(OH)2D3 and its analogs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colorectal Cancer and Vitamin D infographic</title><link>/posts/colorectal-cancer-and-vitamin-d-infographic.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-cancer-and-vitamin-d-infographic.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Colon Cancer vs vitamin D, 30 ng is good - Chart</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-vs-vitamin-d-30-ng-is-good-chart.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-vs-vitamin-d-30-ng-is-good-chart.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-the-relationship-between-uv-b-and-global-incidence-rates-of-colorectal-cancer">What is the relationship between UV B and global incidence rates of colorectal cancer?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dermato-Endocinology Volume 5, Issue 1 February/March 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Raphael E. Cuomo, Sharif B. Mohr, Edward D. Gorham and Cedric F. Garland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of this study is to examine the relationship between UV B and global incidence of colorectal cancer, while controlling for relevant covariates. Linear regression was used to assess the relationship between latitude and incidence rates of colon cancer in 173 countries. Multiple linear regression was employed to investigate the relationship between UVB dose and colorectal cancer rates while controlling for per capita intake of energy from animal sources, per capita health expenditure, pigmentation, and life expectancy. Data on all variables were available for &lt;strong>139 countries&lt;/strong> . Incidence of colon cancer was highest in countries distant from the equator (R2 = 0.50, p &amp;lt; 0.0001). UV B dose (p &amp;lt; 0.0001) was independently, inversely associated with incidence rates of colorectal cancer after controlling for intake of energy from animal sources, per capita health expenditure, pigmentation, and life expectancy (R2 for overall model = 0.76, p &amp;lt; 0.0001). Consistent with previous research, UVB was inversely associated with incidence of colon cancer. Further research on vitamin D and prevention of colon cancer in individuals should be conducted, including studies of higher serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations than have been studied to date.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pathways that vitamin D prevents and treats colon cancer discovered, 2000 IU needed</title><link>/posts/pathways-that-vitamin-d-prevents-and-treats-colon-cancer-discovered-2000-iu-needed.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pathways-that-vitamin-d-prevents-and-treats-colon-cancer-discovered-2000-iu-needed.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="using-components-of-the-vitamin-d-pathway-to-prevent-and-treat-colon-cancer">Using components of the vitamin D pathway to prevent and treat colon cancer.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nutr Rev. 2012 Dec;70(12):721-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1753-4887.2012.00522.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1753-4887.2012.00522.x.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Oct 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stubbins RE, Hakeem A, Núñez NP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas 78712, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this review was to analyze the components of vitamin D and their potential usefulness in preventing and treating colorectal cancer. The active form of vitamin D, 1α,25(OH(2) )D(3) , targets the &lt;strong>wnt/β-catenin pathway&lt;/strong> by upregulating key tumor suppressor genes such as E-cadherin, which promotes an epithelial phenotype, but this is only possible when the vitamin D receptor (VDR) is present. Colorectal cell lines have shown that VDR expression levels decrease in the later stages of colon cancer. In colorectal cancers with low VDR expression, treatments to increase VDR expression could target alterations at the genomic and epigenomic levels by modulating transcription factors such as SNAIL1 and by utilizing histone deacetyltransferase inhibitors, respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The sun appears better at reducing incidence of some cancers than vitamin D</title><link>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-sun-appears-better-at-reducing-incidence-of-some-cancers-than-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="is-prevention-of-cancer-by-sun-exposure-more-than-just-the-effect-of-vitamin-d--a-systematic-review-of-epidemiological-studies">Is prevention of cancer by sun exposure more than just the effect of vitamin D? -A systematic review of epidemiological studies.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Eur J Cancer. 2012 Dec 10. pii: S0959-8049(12)00885-4. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.">doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2012.11.001.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>van der Rhee H, Coebergh JW, de Vries E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Hagaziekenhuis, P.O. Box 40551, Leyweg 275, 2504 LN Den Haag, Zuid-Holland, The Netherlands. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:hvdrhee@casema.nl">hvdrhee@casema.nl&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The number of studies reporting on the association between sunlight exposure, vitamin D and cancer risk is steadily increasing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epidemiology of Vitamin D and Colorectal Cancer</title><link>/posts/epidemiology-of-vitamin-d-and-colorectal-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/epidemiology-of-vitamin-d-and-colorectal-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry Volume 13 Issue 1, pp.11-19 (9)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Edward Giovannucci&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Garland and Garland first hypothesized that better vitamin D status lowered risk of colorectal cancer in 1980. Subsequently, the relation between vitamin D status and colorectal cancer risk has been investigated in epidemiologic studies. Various approaches have been used to estimate vitamin D status, including direct measures of circulating 25(OH)vitamin D levels, surrogates or determinants of vitamin D (including region of residence, intake, and sun exposure estimates, or a combination of these). These measures of vitamin D status have been studied in relation to colorectal adenoma, precursors of cancer, and colorectal cancer incidence and mortality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer - Colon</title><link>/posts/cancer-colon.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-colon.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>!!!!Now USPSTF also suggests start CRC screening at age 45 - Oct 2020
USPSTF = US &lt;strong>Preventive&lt;/strong> Services Task Force
Instead of &lt;strong>preventing&lt;/strong> CRC with Vitamin D - which has been proven in ((Colorectal cancer treated by Vitamin D – 19th meta-analysis – Sept 2020|19 meta-analyses)),
&lt;del>hs&lt;/del> &lt;del>hs&lt;/del> they propose increasing CRC jobs by doing testing even earlier in life
[https://www.mdedge.com/internalmedicine/article/230762/oncology/now-uspstf-also-suggests-start-crc-screening-age-45?ecd=wnl_evn_201027_mdedge_8pm&amp;amp;uac=138704MX&amp;amp;utm_source=News%5FMDedge%5FeNL%5F102720%5FF&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=USPSTF%3A%20Start%20CRC%20screening%20at%20age%2045|MD Edge]
&lt;del>/tc&lt;/del> &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>After 30 years it still appears that vitamin D deals with colorectal cancer</title><link>/posts/after-30-years-it-still-appears-that-vitamin-d-deals-with-colorectal-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/after-30-years-it-still-appears-that-vitamin-d-deals-with-colorectal-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="epidemiology-of-vitamin-d-and-colorectal-cancer">Epidemiology of Vitamin D And Colorectal Cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Anticancer Agents Med Chem. 2012 Oct 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giovannucci E., Departments of Nutrition and Epidemiology, Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, U.S.A. &lt;a href="mailto:egiovann@hsph.harvard.edu">egiovann@hsph.harvard.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Garland and Garland first hypothesized that better vitamin D status lowered risk of colorectal cancer in &lt;strong>1980&lt;/strong> . Subsequently, the relation between vitamin D status and colorectal cancer risk has been investigated in epidemiologic studies. Various approaches have been used to estimate vitamin D status, including direct measures of circulating 25(OH)vitamin D levels, surrogates or determinants of vitamin D (including region of residence, intake, and sun exposure estimates, or a combination of these).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D is one of several ways to prevent, but not treat colon cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-is-one-of-several-ways-to-prevent-but-not-treat-colon-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-is-one-of-several-ways-to-prevent-but-not-treat-colon-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dietary-lifestyle-and-colorectal-cancer-onset-recurrence-and-survival-myth-or-reality">Dietary Lifestyle and Colorectal Cancer Onset, Recurrence, and Survival: Myth or Reality?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>JOURNAL OF GASTROINTESTINAL CANCER, 2012, DOI: 10.1007/s12029-012-9425-y&lt;/p>
&lt;p>REVIEW ARTICLE&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katia Lofano, Mariabeatrice Principi, Maria Principia Scavo, Maria Pricci, Enzo Ierardi and Alfredo Di Leo&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background and Purpose&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interest in the possibility that diet might help to reduce the risk of colorectal cancer dates back to 1970 based on both the large variation in rates of specific cancers in different countries and the impressive changes observed in the incidence of cancer in &lt;strong>migrants&lt;/strong> from low- to high-risk areas. Here, we report the state of art of literature data about this topic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10 percent of colon cancer linked to Vitamin D Receptor – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/10-percent-of-colon-cancer-linked-to-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10-percent-of-colon-cancer-linked-to-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-and-colorectal-cancer-risk-a-systematic-meta-analysis">Vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms and colorectal cancer risk: A systematic meta-analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>World J Gastroenterol. 2012 Apr 14;18(14):1672-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bai YH, Lu H, Hong D, Lin CC, Yu Z, Chen BC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yong-Heng Bai, Dan Hong, Cheng-Cheng Lin, Bi-Cheng Chen, Wenzhou Key Laboratory of Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical College, Wenzhou 325000, Zhejiang Province, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the relationship between polymorphisms present in the vitamin D receptor (VDR) gene and colorectal cancer risk, a systematic meta-analysis of population-based studies was performed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When advanced Colon Cancer is not treated by Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/when-advanced-colon-cancer-is-not-treated-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/when-advanced-colon-cancer-is-not-treated-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-resistance-and-colon-cancer-prevention">Vitamin D resistance and colon cancer prevention&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Charles Giardina &lt;a href="mailto:charles.giardina@uconn.edu">charles.giardina@uconn.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James P. Madigan1,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cassandra A. Godman Tierney,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce M. Brenner1 and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daniel W. Rosenberg1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Molecular and Cell Biology, University of Connecticut, 91 North Eagleville Road, U3215, Storrs, CT 06269, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Center for Molecular Medicine, University of Connecticut Health Center, Farmington, CT 06030, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received September 27, 2011; Revision received November 18, 2011; Accepted December 7, 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Observational studies have been largely consistent in showing an inverse association between vitamin D and an individual’s risk of developing colorectal cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting little UV is associated with 15 types of Cancer</title><link>/posts/getting-little-uv-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/getting-little-uv-is-associated-with-15-types-of-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="ecological-studies-of-the-uvbvitamin-dcancer-hypothesis">Ecological Studies of the UVB–Vitamin D–Cancer Hypothesis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Anticancer Research January 2012 vol. 32 no. 1 223-236&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WILLIAM B. GRANT, Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, P.O. Box 641603, San Francisco, CA 94164-1603, U.S.A. &lt;a href="mailto:wbgrant@infionline.net">wbgrant@infionline.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aim: This paper reviews ecological studies of the ultraviolet-B (UVB)–vitamin D–cancer hypothesis based on geographical variation of cancer incidence and/or mortality rates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Materials and Methods: The review is based largely on three ecological studies of cancer rates from the United States; one each from Australia, China, France, Japan, and Spain; and eight multicountry, multifactorial studies of cancer incidence rates from &lt;strong>more than 100 countries&lt;/strong> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Graphs of Vitamin D and Cancer – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/graphs-of-vitamin-d-and-cancer-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/graphs-of-vitamin-d-and-cancer-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-with-or-without-calcium-supplementation-for-prevention-of-cancer-and-fractures-an-updated-meta-analysis-for-the-us-preventive-services-task-force">Vitamin D With or Without Calcium Supplementation for Prevention of Cancer and Fractures: An Updated Meta-analysis for the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-high-vitamin-d-levels-are-from-those-individuals-with-high-responses-to-only-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d">The high vitamin D levels are from those individuals with high responses to only 1,000 IU of vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-with-or-without-calcium-supplementation-for-prevention-of-cancer-and-fractures-an-updated-meta-analysis-for-the-us-preventive-services-task-force">Vitamin D With or Without Calcium Supplementation for Prevention of Cancer and Fractures: An Updated Meta-analysis for the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Ann Intern Med. 2011 Dec 20;155(12):827-38.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancer patients 64% less likely to die if have high level of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cancer-patients-64-percent-less-likely-to-die-if-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancer-patients-64-percent-less-likely-to-die-if-have-high-level-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="serum-levels-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-survival-in-norwegian-patients-with-cancer-of-breast-colon-lung-and-lymphoma-a-population-based-study">Serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D and survival in Norwegian patients with cancer of breast, colon, lung, and lymphoma: a population-based study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2011 Dec 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tretli S, Schwartz GG, Torjesen PA, Robsahm TE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cancer Registry of Norway, Institute of Population-based Cancer Research, PB 5313, Majorstuen, 0304, Oslo, Norway, &lt;a href="mailto:steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no">steinar.tretli@kreftregisteret.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE: We investigated the association between serum levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OHD) and risk of death in Norwegian cancer patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colon cancer probability increases with decreased vitamin D – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colon-cancer-probability-increases-with-decreased-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-cancer-probability-increases-with-decreased-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="meta-analysis-serum-vitamin-d-and-colorectal-adenoma-risk">Meta-analysis: Serum vitamin D and colorectal adenoma risk.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Prev Med. 2011 Jul-Aug;53(1-2):10-6. Epub 2011 Jun 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yin L, Grandi N, Raum E, Haug U, Arndt V, Brenner H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Division of Clinical Epidemiology and Aging Research, German Cancer Research Center, Bergheimer Strasse 20, Heidelberg, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To perform a systematic review and meta-analysis of human studies on the association between serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and incident, sporadic colorectal adenoma (CRA) and CRA recurrence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Non-cancer colon growths 7 % less likely per 10 ng increase in Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/non-cancer-colon-growths-7-percent-less-likely-per-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/non-cancer-colon-growths-7-percent-less-likely-per-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#circulating-levels-of-vitamin-d-vitamin-d-receptor-polymorphisms-and-colorectal-adenoma-a-meta-analysis">Circulating levels of vitamin D, vitamin D receptor polymorphisms, and colorectal adenoma: a meta-analysis.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="circulating-levels-of-vitamin-d-vitamin-d-receptor-polymorphisms-and-colorectal-adenoma-a-meta-analysis">Circulating levels of vitamin D, vitamin D receptor polymorphisms, and colorectal adenoma: a meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutr Res Pract. 2011 Oct;5(5):464-70&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee JE; Department of Food and Nutrition, Sookmyung Women&amp;rsquo;s University, 52 Hyochangwon gil, Yongsan-gu, Seoul 140-742, Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Growing evidence suggests an elevated risk for colorectal neoplasia among individuals with low levels of vitamin D, the biological actions of which are mediated by the vitamin D receptor (VDR). To investigate the association among vitamin D status, VDR polymorphisms (FokI, and BsmI), and colorectal adenoma, we conducted a meta-analysis of nine studies of circulating levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and five studies of FokI or BsmI polymorphisms in relation to colorectal adenomas. Study-specific relative risks (RRs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were pooled using a random-effects model. A total of 3398 colorectal adenomas for 25(OH)D and 1754 colorectal adenomas for VDR were included in the meta-analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Emerging role of vitamin D in colorectal cancer</title><link>/posts/emerging-role-of-vitamin-d-in-colorectal-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/emerging-role-of-vitamin-d-in-colorectal-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;p>World J Gastrointest Oncol. 2011 Aug 15;3(8):123-7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kang W, Lee S, Jeon E, Yun YR, Kim KH, Jang JH. &lt;a href="mailto:juhjang@inha.ac.kr">juhjang@inha.ac.kr&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wonmo Kang, Sujin Lee, Eunyi Jeon, Ye-Rang Yun, Jun-Hyeog Jang, Department of Biochemistry, School of Medicine, Inha University, Incheon 400-712, South Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Colorectal cancer is a common cancer and the fourth leading cause of death in Korea. The incidence and mortality of colorectal cancer varies according to risk factors, such as age, family history, genetic history, food habits, and physical activities. Some studies have focused on the association between vitamin D and colorectal cancer. Today, there is growing evidence that high vitamin D intake and a plasma level of 25(OH)D(3) reduce the incidence of colorectal cancer by modifying cancer angiogenesis, cell apoptosis, differentiation, and proliferation. Taken together, these results suggest that vitamin D supplementation alone, or in combination with anti-cancer agents, might reduce the incidence of colorectal cancer. In this review, we discuss the function and mechanism of vitamin D including the effect of vitamin D on colorectal cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cancers and Vitamin D Council</title><link>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cancers-and-vitamin-d-council.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Colorectal cancer 26 percent less likely for every 10 ng of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colorectal-cancer-26-percent-less-likely-for-every-10-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colorectal-cancer-26-percent-less-likely-for-every-10-ng-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>800 IU of vitamin D not enough to treat colon cancer</title><link>/posts/800-iu-of-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-treat-colon-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/800-iu-of-vitamin-d-not-enough-to-treat-colon-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="effects-of-supplemental-vitamin-d-and-calcium-on-biomarkers-of-inflammation-in-colorectal-adenoma-patients-a-randomized-controlled-clinical-trialhttpcancerpreventionresearchaacrjournalsorgcontentearly201106281940-6207capr-11-0105abstract">&lt;a href="http://cancerpreventionresearch.aacrjournals.org/content/early/2011/06/28/1940-6207.CAPR-11-0105.abstract">Effects of supplemental vitamin D and calcium on biomarkers of inflammation in colorectal adenoma patients: A randomized, controlled clinical trial&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>– – – – – –&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="far-too-little-vitamin-d-to-help">Far too little vitamin D to help&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="see-vitamindwiki">See VitaminDWiki&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=41&amp;amp;deep=off&amp;amp;type=">All items in Colon Cancer and Vitamin D&lt;/a> 33 items as of July 2011&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Colon polyps reduced 15 percent by increasing vitamin D by 20 ng – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/colon-polyps-reduced-15-percent-by-increasing-vitamin-d-by-20-ng-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/colon-polyps-reduced-15-percent-by-increasing-vitamin-d-by-20-ng-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="meta-analysis-serum-vitamin-d-and-colorectal-adenoma-risk">Meta-analysis: Serum vitamin D and colorectal adenoma risk.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Prev Med. 2011 Jun 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yin L, Grandi N, Raum E, Haug U, Arndt V, Brenner H.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To perform a systematic review and meta-analysis of human studies on the association between serum 25 hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and incident, sporadic colorectal adenoma (CRA) and CRA recurrence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relevant studies among humans were identified by systematically searching Ovid Medline, EMBASE, and ISI Web of Knowledge databases and by cross-referencing. Due to the heterogeneity across studies in categorizing serum vitamin D levels, all results were recalculated for an increase of serum 25(OH)D by 20ng/ml. Summary odds ratios (ORs) were calculated using meta-analysis methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genetics and colon cancer with only 400 IU of vitamin D – Dissertation</title><link>/posts/genetics-and-colon-cancer-with-only-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-dissertation.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genetics-and-colon-cancer-with-only-400-iu-of-vitamin-d-dissertation.html</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="genetic-and-environmental-factors-influencing-circulating-concentration-of-vitamin-d-metabolites-and-odds-of-colorectal-neoplasia">Genetic and environmental factors influencing circulating concentration of vitamin D metabolites and odds of colorectal neoplasia&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>by Hibler, Elizabeth Anne, Ph.D., THE UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA, 2011, 387 pages; 3450731&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction. Circulating concentrations of vitamin D metabolites are associated with risk for a variety of diseases, including colorectal cancer. It is not known what level of circulating 25(OH)D is optimal for health; however, over-the-counter (OTC) vitamin D supplements are commonly used to improve status, though their effectiveness is unknown. It is also not known if polymorphic variation in genes associated with the vitamin D endocrine system is associated with differences in vitamin D metabolite levels or colorectal neoplasia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D deficiency more strongly associated with rectal than colon cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-more-strongly-associated-with-rectal-than-colon-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-deficiency-more-strongly-associated-with-rectal-than-colon-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="circulating-levels-of-vitamin-d-and-colon-and-rectal-cancer-the-physicians-health-study-and-a-meta-analysis-of-prospective-studies">Circulating levels of vitamin D and colon and rectal cancer: the Physicians&amp;rsquo; Health Study and a meta-analysis of prospective studies.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Cancer Prev Res (Phila). 2011 Mar 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee JE, Li H, Chan AT, Hollis BW, Lee IM, Stampfer MJ, Wu K, Giovannucci E, Ma J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Food and Nutrition, Sookmyung Women&amp;rsquo;s University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It remains unknown whether increased risk with low levels of vitamin D is present for colon and/or rectal cancer. To investigate the association between circulating vitamin D levels and colon and rectal cancer, we examined the associations between plasma levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)2D) and colon and rectal cancer in the Physicians&amp;rsquo; Health Study and then conducted a meta-analysis of eight prospective studies of circulating levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and colon and rectal cancers, including the Physicians&amp;rsquo; Health Study.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Every 100 IU of additional vitamin D decreased colorectal cancer by 4 percent</title><link>/posts/every-100-iu-of-additional-vitamin-d-decreased-colorectal-cancer-by-4-percent.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/every-100-iu-of-additional-vitamin-d-decreased-colorectal-cancer-by-4-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="meta-analyses-of-vitamin-d-intake-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-status-vitamin-d-receptor-polymorphisms-and-colorectal-cancer-risk">Meta-analyses of vitamin D intake, 25-hydroxyvitamin D status, vitamin D receptor polymorphisms and colorectal cancer risk.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2011 Mar 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Touvier M, Chan DS, Lau RN, Aune D, Vieira R, Greenwood DC, Kampman E, Riboli E, Hercberg S, Norat T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of public health, Imperial College London.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Our objective was to conduct a systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective studies on colorectal cancer and vitamin D intake and 25-hydroxyvitamin D status, as part of the World Cancer Research Fund Continuous Update Project. We also aimed at conducting meta-analysis of all studies on colorectal cancer and vitamin D receptor (VDR) single-nucleotide polymorphisms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IBD colorectal Cancer and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/ibd-colorectal-cancer-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ibd-colorectal-cancer-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-gastrointestinal-diseases-inflammatory-bowel-disease-and-colorectal-cancer">Vitamin D and gastrointestinal diseases: inflammatory bowel disease and colorectal cancer&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Therap Adv Gastroenterol. 2011 January; 4(1): 49–62.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/1756283X10377820.">doi: 10.1177/1756283X10377820.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PMCID: PMC3036961&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maitreyi Raman; Division of Gastroenterology, University of Calgary, 6D26, Teaching, Research and Wellness Building, 3280 Hospital Drive N.W., Calgary, Alberta, Canada T2N 4N1; &lt;a href="mailto:mkothand@ucalgary.ca">mkothand@ucalgary.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andrew N. Milestone; St. Marks Hospital, Harrow, Middlesex, UK&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Julian R.F. Walters; Division of Medicine, Imperial College Healthcare, London, Hammersmith Hospital, Imperial College London, UK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increasing vitamin D increases colon cancer in Finnish smokers</title><link>/posts/increasing-vitamin-d-increases-colon-cancer-in-finnish-smokers.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increasing-vitamin-d-increases-colon-cancer-in-finnish-smokers.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-and-risks-of-colon-and-rectal-cancer-in-finnish-men">Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Risks of Colon and Rectal Cancer in Finnish Men.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Epidemiol. 2011 Jan 19.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D and Risks of Colon and Rectal Cancer in Finnish Men.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weinstein SJ, Yu K, Horst RL, Ashby J, Virtamo J, Albanes D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prospective investigations of circulating vitamin D concentrations suggest inverse associations with colorectal cancer risk, although inconsistencies remain and few studies have examined the impact of season. The authors conducted a prospective case-control study of 239 colon cancer cases and 192 rectal cancer cases (diagnosed in 1993-2005) and 428 controls matched on age and blood collection date within the Alpha-Tocopherol, Beta-Carotene Cancer Prevention Study, a cohort study of Finnish male smokers. Baseline serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) concentrations were categorized using a priori defined cutpoints of &amp;lt;25, 25-&amp;lt;37.5, 37.5-&amp;lt;50, 50-&amp;lt;75, and ?75 nmol/L and by season-specific and season-standardized 25(OH)D quartiles. Conditional logistic regression models yielded multivariate-adjusted odds ratios for the predefined cutpoints of 0.63, 0.91, 0.73, 1.00 (referent), and 1.44 for colon cancer and 0.64, 0.58, 0.84, 1.00, and 0.76 for rectal cancer, respectively (all 95% confidence intervals included 1.00).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and Colon Cancer</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-colon-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-colon-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="aboutcom-colon-cancer-sectionhttpcoloncanceraboutcomb20101201new-vitamin-d-recommendations-reignite-controversyhtm">&lt;a href="http://coloncancer.about.com/b/2010/12/01/new-vitamin-d-recommendations-reignite-controversy.htm">About.com Colon Cancer section&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="updated-dec-1-2010-just-after-the-a-hrefpostsinstitue-of-medicine-pronouncement-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-1193institue-of-medicine-pronouncementa">Updated Dec 1, 2010, just after the &lt;a href="/posts/institue-of-medicine-pronouncement" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 1193">Institue of Medicine pronouncement&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>clip - - - -&lt;/p>
&lt;p>^&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My Vitamin D Opinion&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I titled this section with the words &amp;ldquo;my opinion&amp;rdquo; because I want to make it absolutely clear that I am giving my opinion. I am a nutritionist, dietitian, and epidemiologist with experience in cancer research, so I feel that I have something to offer on this topic. But always, talk to your doctor if you have any questions about what is right for you with dietary supplements, including vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>8000 IU supplementation to people with various cancers</title><link>/posts/8000-iu-supplementation-to-people-with-various-cancers.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/8000-iu-supplementation-to-people-with-various-cancers.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="impact-of-oral-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-oncology">Impact of oral vitamin D supplementation on serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in oncology&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Pankaj G Vashi email, Kristen Trukova email, Carolyn A Lammersfeld email, Donald P Braun email and Digant Gupta email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutrition Journal 2010, 9:60doi:10.1186/1475-2891-9-60, 	23 November 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> is the major circulating form of vitamin D and a standard indicator of vitamin D status. Emerging evidence in the literature suggests a high prevalence of suboptimal vitamin D (as defined by serum 25(OH)D levels of &amp;lt;32 ng/ml) as well as an association between lower serum levels and higher mortality in cancer. We investigated the effect of oral vitamin D supplementation as a means for restoring suboptimal levels to optimal levels in cancer.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>