<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CYP27B1 on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cyp27b1.html</link><description>Recent content in CYP27B1 on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cyp27b1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CYP27B1 gene decreases kidney production of active vitamin D</title><link>/posts/cyp27b1-gene-decreases-kidney-production-of-active-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cyp27b1-gene-decreases-kidney-production-of-active-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="thyroid-hormones-decrease-plasma-1α25-dihydroxyvitamin-d-levels-through-transcriptional-repression-of-the-renal-25-hydroxyvitamin-d3-1α-hydroxylase-gene-cyp27b1">Thyroid hormones decrease plasma 1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D levels through transcriptional repression of the renal 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 1α-hydroxylase gene (CYP27B1).&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Endocrinology. 2013 Feb;154(2):609-22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1210/en.2012-1647.">doi: 10.1210/en.2012-1647.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kozai M, Yamamoto H, Ishiguro M, Harada N, Masuda M, Kagawa T, Takei Y, Otani A, Nakahashi O, Ikeda S, Taketani Y, Takeyama K, Kato S, Takeda E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Clinical Nutrition, Institute of Health Biosciences, University of Tokushima Graduate School, 3-18-15 Kuramoto-cho, Tokushima City, 770-8503, Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary determinant of circulating 1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>(2)D) levels is the activity of 25-hydroxyvitamin D-1α-hydroxylase (cytochrome P450 27B1 &lt;span>[CYP27B1]&lt;/span>) in the kidney.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genes such as CYP27B1, CYP24A1 and Vitamin D – JAMA</title><link>/posts/genes-such-as-cyp27b1-cyp24a1-and-vitamin-d-jama.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/genes-such-as-cyp27b1-cyp24a1-and-vitamin-d-jama.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="genetic-variants-and-associations-of-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-with-major-clinical-outcomes">Genetic Variants and Associations of 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentrations With Major Clinical Outcomes&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>JAMA. 2012;308(18):1898-1905. doi:10.1001/jama.2012.17304.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gregory P. Levin, PhD; Cassianne Robinson-Cohen, PhD; Ian H. de Boer, MD, MS; Denise K. Houston, PhD; Kurt Lohman, MS; Yongmei Liu, PhD; Stephen B. Kritchevsky, PhD; Jane A. Cauley, DrPh; Toshiko Tanaka, PhD; Luigi Ferrucci, MD, PhD; Stefania Bandinelli, MD; Kushang V. Patel, PhD, MPH; Emil Hagström, MD, PhD; Karl Michaëlsson, MD, PhD; Håkan Melhus, MD, PhD; Thomas Wang, MD; Myles Wolf, MD, MMSc; Bruce M. Psaty, MD, PhD; David Siscovick, MD, MPH; Bryan Kestenbaum, MD, MS&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels are strongly associated with genes: overview of twin studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-are-strongly-associated-with-genes-overview-of-twin-studies.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-are-strongly-associated-with-genes-overview-of-twin-studies.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mutation of Vitamin D gene (CYP27B1) is strongly tied to MS</title><link>/posts/mutation-of-vitamin-d-gene-cyp27b1-is-strongly-tied-to-ms.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/mutation-of-vitamin-d-gene-cyp27b1-is-strongly-tied-to-ms.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The researchers looked for the gene variant in more than 3,000 families of unaffected parents with a child with MS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and found 35 parents who carried one copy of this variant along with one normal copy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In every one of these 35 cases, their child with MS had inherited the mutated version of the gene.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The likelihood of this gene’s transmission being unconnected to the MS is billion to one against&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prostate Cancer – Vitamin D – CYP27B1 – CYP24</title><link>/posts/prostate-cancer-vitamin-d-cyp27b1-cyp24.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/prostate-cancer-vitamin-d-cyp27b1-cyp24.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-metabolism-and-action-in-the-prostate-implications-for-health-and-disease">Vitamin D metabolism and action in the prostate: Implications for health and disease.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-metabolism-and-action-in-the-prostate-implications-for-health-and-disease">Vitamin D metabolism and action in the prostate: Implications for health and disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2011 Jun 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Swami S, Krishnan AV, Feldman D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, CA 94305, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prostate cancer (PCa) is the second most common cancer in men worldwide. Epidemiological, molecular, and cellular studies have implicated vitamin D deficiency as a risk factor for the development and/or progression of PCa. Studies using cell culture systems and animal models suggest that vitamin D acts to reduce the growth of PCa through regulation of cellular proliferation and differentiation. However, although preclinical studies provide a strong indication for anti-cancer activity, proof of therapeutic benefits in men is still lacking. The anti-proliferative and pro-differentiating properties of vitamin D have been attributed to calcitriol &lt;span>[1,25(OH)(2)D(3)]&lt;/span>, the hormonally active form of vitamin D, acting through the vitamin D receptor (VDR). Metabolism of vitamin D in target tissues is mediated by two key enzymes: 1?-hydroxylase (CYP27B1), which catalyzes the synthesis of calcitriol from 25(OH)D and 24-hydroxylase (CYP24), which catalyzes the initial step in the conversion of calcitriol to less active metabolites. Many factors affect the balance of calcitriol synthesis and catabolism and several maneuvers, like combination therapy of calcitriol with other drugs, have been explored to treat PCa and reduce its risk. The current paper is an overview addressing some of the key factors that influence the biological actions of vitamin D and its metabolites in the treatment and/or prevention of PCa.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>