<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vitamin D Receptor on VitaminDWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/vitamin-d-receptor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vitamin D Receptor on VitaminDWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/vitamin-d-receptor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In vitro fertilization and Vitamin D – many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-vitro-fertilization-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-vitro-fertilization-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;ivf-newborns-had-2-ngml-higher-vitamin-d-levels---april-2024&#34;&gt;IVF newborns had ~2 ng/mL higher Vitamin D levels - April 2024&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vitamin D3 among neonates born after in vitro fertilization compared with neonates from the general population&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2024;00:1–10. DOI: 10.1111/aogs.14819&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Karen Christina Walker1© | Sofie Gry Pristed2,3 | Fanney Thorsteinsdottir1,4 Ina Olmer Specht1,4© | Arieh Cohen5 | Berit Lilienthal Heitmann 1,3,6© |&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ulrik Schi0ler Kesmodel 2,7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Sufficient levels of vitamin D have been associated with higher chances for both clinical pregnancy and live birth among women undergoing assisted repro­ductive techniques, whereas low levels of maternal vitamin D have been associated with preeclampsia and late miscarriage. In Denmark, subgroups at risk for low vitamin D levels, including neonates and toddlers, are recommended to use supplementation. The aim was to study the level of vitamin D3 among neonates born after in vitro ferti­lization compared with neonates from the general population.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor sleep was 2X more likely if low Vitamin D and poor Vitamin D receptor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor-sleep-was-2x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-and-poor-vitamin-d-receptor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor-sleep-was-2x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-and-poor-vitamin-d-receptor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-role-of-interaction-between-vitamin-d-and-vdr-foki-gene-polymorphism-rs2228570-in-sleep-quality-of-adults&#34;&gt;The role of interaction between vitamin D and VDR FokI gene polymorphism (rs2228570) in sleep quality of adults&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sci Rep. 2024 Apr 7;14(1):8141. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-58561-2.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-58561-2.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luiz Antônio Alves de Menezes-Júnior 1 2 3, Thais da Silva Sabião 4 5, Samara Silva de Moura 4 5, Aline Priscila Batista 6 7, Mariana Carvalho de Menezes 4 5 8, Júlia Cristina Cardoso Carraro 4 5 8, George Luiz Lins Machado-Coelho 4 6 7, Adriana Lúcia Meireles 4 5 8&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autism treated by an activator of the Vitamin D Receptor: supforaphane</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-treated-by-an-activator-of-the-vitamin-d-receptor-supforaphane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/autism-treated-by-an-activator-of-the-vitamin-d-receptor-supforaphane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;new-study-shows-promise-for-natural-support-of-autism-symptoms---march-2024&#34;&gt;New Study Shows Promise for Natural Support of Autism Symptoms - March 2024&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://greenmedinfo.com/content/new-study-shows-promise-natural-support-autism-symptoms&#34;&gt;GreenMedInfo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A new double-blind, placebo-controlled study published in Psychiatry and Clinical Neurosciences shows exciting potential for sulforaphane, a compound found in broccoli sprouts, to help ease symptoms of irritability and hyperactivity in children with autism spectrum disorder (ASD).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;After 10 weeks, the sulforaphane group showed significantly greater improvements in irritability scores and hyperactivity/noncompliance scores compared to placebo. However, no differences were seen between groups in other symptom areas like lethargy, stereotypic behavior, or inappropriate speech.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot; A study published in Psychiatry and Clinical Neurosciences found that when used as an adjunctive treatment alongside  &lt;strong&gt;risperidone&lt;/strong&gt; , sulforaphane significantly improved symptoms of irritability and hyperactivity in children with ASD compared to placebo.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More depression if less vitamin D getting to cells (poor VDR)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-depression-if-less-vitamin-d-getting-to-cells-poor-vdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-depression-if-less-vitamin-d-getting-to-cells-poor-vdr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;interaction-between-fokl-polymorphism-and-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-the-symptoms-of-mental-disorders-in-adults-a-population-based-study&#34;&gt;Interaction between Fokl polymorphism and vitamin D deficiency in the symptoms of mental disorders in adults: a population-based study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sci Rep. 2024 Mar 22;14(1):6925. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-57558-1.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-57558-1.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thaís da Silva Sabião 1, Luiz Antônio Alves de Menezes-Júnior 2, Aline Priscila Batista 3, Samara Silva de Moura 2, Adriana Lúcia Meireles 4, Mariana Carvalho de Menezes 4, George Luiz Lins Machado-Coelho 5, Júlia Cristina Cardoso Carraro 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Caption: The variable in green and with the “►” symbol was the exposure variable; in blue and with the letter “I” was the response variables; variables in blue are the antecedents of the outcome variable; and those in red are antecedents of the outcome and exposure variables;the variable in gray is a collider and indicates a closed or blocked path.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID maximum downregulation of Vitamin D receptor and CYP27B1 resulted in death</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-maximum-downregulation-of-vitamin-d-receptor-and-cyp27b1-resulted-in-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-maximum-downregulation-of-vitamin-d-receptor-and-cyp27b1-resulted-in-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-distinct-regulation-of-the-vitamin-d-and-aryl-hydrocarbon-receptors-in-covid-19&#34;&gt;The Distinct Regulation of the Vitamin D and Aryl Hydrocarbon Receptors in COVID-19&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2024 Feb 22;16(5):598. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu16050598.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/nu16050598.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oliver Robak 1, Marie-Theres Kastner 1, Astrid Voill-Glaninger 2, André Viveiros 2, Christoph Steininger 1 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: SARS-CoV-2 affects several immune pathways, including the vitamin D (VDR) and the aryl hydrocarbon receptor pathways (AhR). The aim of the study was the evaluation of the VDR and AhR pathways in the blood of COVID-19 patients with regard to the severity of disease.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malocclusions 5X higher risk if poor Vitamin D Receptor or low Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/malocclusions-5x-higher-risk-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-or-low-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/malocclusions-5x-higher-risk-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-or-low-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;s&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;relationship-in-development-of-malocclusions-to-polymorphisms-of-selected-vitamin-d-receptors&#34;&gt;Relationship in development of malocclusions to polymorphisms of selected vitamin D receptors&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adv Clin Exp Med. 2024 Feb 14. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.17219/acem/169977&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.17219/acem/169977&lt;/a&gt; PDF behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Marzena Dominiak 1, Anna Leszczyszyn 1, Izabela Łaczmańska 2, Monika Machoy 3, Hanna Gerber 4, Joseph Choukroun 5, Tomasz Gedrange 6, Sylwia Hnitecka 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: The development of malocclusion is related to various factor, many of which are still not fully explained. The steroid hormone, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3, has pleiotropic effects. It plays a key role in skeletal metabolism and the control of cell repair by attaching to the nuclear vitamin D steroid receptor (VDR). This vitamin affects bone turnover through the processes of bone tissue formation and resorption via its action on cells of the osteoblastic and osteoclastic lineage, exerts a modulating effect on the immune system, and is involved in the regulation of cell proliferation and differentiation. The role of vitamin D3 (VD3) and its receptor polymorphisms is a rarely studied topic in dentistry. Due to the proven influence on bone turnover processes and immune responses, the main research topic is its relation to periodontal diseases, but so far, its role in the formation and development of malocclusions has not been assessed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor Vitamin D Receptor increases the risk of Multiple Sclerosis in people of European descent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor-vitamin-d-receptor-increases-the-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-people-of-european-descent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/poor-vitamin-d-receptor-increases-the-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-people-of-european-descent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;evidence-supports-a-causal-association-between-allele-specific-vitamin-d-receptor-binding-and-multiple-sclerosis-among-europeans&#34;&gt;Evidence supports a causal association between allele-specific vitamin D receptor binding and multiple sclerosis among Europeans&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PNAS 121 (8)  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2302259121&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2302259121&lt;/a&gt; PDF is behind a paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cameron Adams, Ali Manouchehrinia, Hong L. Quach, +6, and Lisa F. Barcellos &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:lbarcellos@berkeley.edu&#34;&gt;lbarcellos@berkeley.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is evidence for a causal association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) serum levels and multiple sclerosis (MS), but the underlying mechanisms are unknown. We conducted a Mendelian Randomization study to estimate causal associations between vitamin D receptor (VDR) binding at a locus and MS susceptibility using genetic instrumental variables constructed from variants previously associated with allele-specific VDR-binding (VDR-binding variant; VDR-BV) and serum 25(OH)D. Two VDR-BV (rs2881514; rs2531804) were independently associated with MS and rs2881514 demonstrated significant interaction with 25(OH)D, providing evidence for a causal association between rs2881514 and MS. Our results demonstrate that genetic variation in individual VDR binding sites contributes to MS and are relevant to other autoimmune diseases for which a role for vitamin D has been implicated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oral Cancer and Vitamin D  and VDR - several studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/oral-cancer-and-vitamin-d-and-vdr-several-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/oral-cancer-and-vitamin-d-and-vdr-several-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange7span--vitamindwiki-cancer-other-pages-have-oral-in-the-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;7+&lt;/span&gt;  VitaminDWiki Cancer-Other pages have ORAL in the title&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{list max=&amp;ldquo;50&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter categories=&#34;113&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;oral&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; shownbitems=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}n&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xA;&#xA;{column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=title format=&amp;ldquo;objectlink&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange86span--vitamindwiki-vdr-pages-have-cancer-in-the-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;86+&lt;/span&gt;  VitaminDWiki VDR pages have CANCER in the title&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{list max=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter categories=&#34;142&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;cancer&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D Receptor activation in cells varies by 100 X - Carlberg</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-activation-in-cells-varies-by-100-x-carlberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-activation-in-cells-varies-by-100-x-carlberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-a-master-example-of-nutrigenomics&#34;&gt;Vitamin D: A master example of nutrigenomics&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Redox Biology 62 (2023) 102695 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.10167j.redox.2023.102695&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.10167j.redox.2023.102695&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Carsten Carlberg a,b’  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:c.carlberg@pan.olsztyn.pl&#34;&gt;c.carlberg@pan.olsztyn.pl&lt;/a&gt; , Marianna Raczyk a, Natalia Zawrotna a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a Institute of Animal Reproduction and Food Research, Polish Academy of Sciences, PL-10748, Olsztyn, Poland&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b School of Medicine, Institute of Biomedicine, University of Eastern Finland, FI-70211, Kuopio, Finland&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D target genes Epigenome Transcriptome Immune system Personalized nutrition&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrigenomics attempts to characterize and integrate the relation between dietary molecules and gene expres­sion on a genome-wide level. One of the biologically active nutritional compounds is vitamin D3, which activates via its metabolite 1a,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3) the nuclear receptor VDR (vitamin D receptor). Vitamin D3 can be synthesized endogenously in our skin, but since we spend long times indoors and often live at higher latitudes where for many winter months UV-B radiation is too low, it became a true vitamin. The ligand- inducible transcription factor VDR is expressed in the majority of human tissues and cell types, where it mod­ulates the epigenome at thousands of genomic sites. In a tissue-specific fashion this results in the up- and downregulation of primary vitamin D target genes, some of which are involved in attenuating oxidative stress. Vitamin D affects a wide range of physiological functions including the control of metabolism, bone formation and immunity. In this review, we will discuss how the epigenome- and transcriptome-wide effects of 1,25 (OH)2D3 and its receptor VDR serve as a master example in nutrigenomics. In this context, we will outline the basis of a mechanistic understanding for personalized nutrition with vitamin D3.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D Receptor activation by Traditional Chinese Medicine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-activation-by-traditional-chinese-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-activation-by-traditional-chinese-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vitamin D Receptor activation has been proven to get more Vitamin D into the cells,%%%This study adds many more VDR activators, many of which are on Amazon%%%For most activators it is not known%%%    Which activator is best for each health problem %%%     Dose size %%%      Dose Frequency (X doses per day &amp;ndash; X doses per month)%%%    Should dosing be constant, ramp up, or start with a loading dose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;modulation-of-the-vitamin-d-receptor-by-traditional-chinese-medicines-and-bioactive-compounds-potential-therapeutic-applications-in-vdr-dependent-diseases&#34;&gt;Modulation of the vitamin D receptor by traditional Chinese medicines and bioactive compounds: potential therapeutic applications in VDR-dependent diseases&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front. Pharmacol. 15:1298181. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2024.1298181&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3389/fphar.2024.1298181&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An activated Vitamin D Receptor fights Autoimmune Diseases, Infections, Cancers, etc.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/an-activated-vitamin-d-receptor-fights-autoimmune-diseases-infections-cancers-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/an-activated-vitamin-d-receptor-fights-autoimmune-diseases-infections-cancers-etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;methylation-of-the-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-in-human-disorders&#34;&gt;Methylation of the Vitamin D Receptor Gene in Human Disorders&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2024, 25(1), 107; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25010107&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25010107&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Beatrice Gasperini 1,†,Angela Falvino 1,†,Eleonora Piccirilli 2,Umberto Tarantino 2ORCID,Annalisa Botta 1,*ORCID and Virginia Veronica Visconti 1ORCID&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Department of Biomedicine and Prevention, University of Rome “Tor Vergata”, Via Montpellier 1, 00133 Rome, Italy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Department of Clinical Sciences and Translational Medicine, University of Rome “Tor Vergata”, Via Montpellier 1, 00133 Rome, Italy&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breast Cancer risk reduced if consume butyrate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/breast-cancer-risk-reduced-if-consume-butyrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/breast-cancer-risk-reduced-if-consume-butyrate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;intestinal-vitamin-d-receptor-protects-against-extraintestinal-breast-cancer-tumorigenesis&#34;&gt;Intestinal vitamin D receptor protects against extraintestinal breast cancer tumorigenesis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gut Microbes, 15:1,2202593, DOI: 10.1080/19490976.2023.2202593&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yong-Guo Zhang, Yinglin Xia, Jilei Zhang, Shreya Deb, Shari Garrett &amp;amp; Jun Sun&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The microbiota plays critical roles in regulating the function and health of the intestine and extraintestinal organs. A fundamental question is whether an intestinal-microbiome-breast axis exists during the development of breast cancer. If so, what are the roles of host factors? Vitamin D receptor (VDR) involves host factors and the human microbiome. Vdr gene variation shapes the human microbiome, and VDR deficiency leads to dysbiosis. We hypothesized that intestinal VDR protects hosts against tumorigenesis in the breast. We examined a 7,12-dimethylbenzanthracene (DMBA)-induced breast cancer model in intestinal epithelial VDR knockout (VDRAIEC)  &lt;strong&gt;mice&lt;/strong&gt;  with dysbiosis. We reported that VDRAIEC  &lt;strong&gt;mice&lt;/strong&gt;  with dysbiosis are more susceptible to breast cancer induced by DMBA. Intestinal and breast microbiota analysis showed that VDR deficiency leads to a bacterial profile shift from normal to susceptible to carcinogenesis. We found enhanced bacterial staining within breast tumors. At the molecular and cellular levels, we identified the mechanisms by which intestinal epithelial VDR deficiency led to increased gut permeability, disrupted tight junctions, microbial translocation, and enhanced inflammation, thus increasing tumor size and number in the breast. Furthermore, treatment with the beneficial bacterial metabolite butyrate or the probiotic Lactobacillus plantarum reduced breast tumors, enhanced tight junctions, inhibited inflammation, increased butyryl-CoA transferase, and decreased levels of breast Streptococcus bacteria in VDRAIEC  &lt;strong&gt;mice&lt;/strong&gt; . The gut microbiome contributes to the pathogenesis of diseases not only in the intestine but also in the breast. Our study provides insights into the mechanism by which intestinal VDR dysfunction and gut dysbiosis lead to a high risk of extraintestinal tumorigenesis. Gut-tumor-microbiome interactions represent a new target in the prevention and treatment of breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obesity decreases BOTH Vitamin D levels and Vitamin D Receptor activation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/obesity-decreases-both-vitamin-d-levels-and-vitamin-d-receptor-activation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/obesity-decreases-both-vitamin-d-levels-and-vitamin-d-receptor-activation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-association-between-body-mass-index-elevation-and-differentiation-in-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-expression-genetic-polymorphism-and-oxidative-stress-in-adult-egyptian-individuals&#34;&gt;The association between body mass index elevation and differentiation in vitamin D receptor gene expression, genetic polymorphism, and oxidative stress in adult Egyptian individuals&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sci Rep . 2023 Oct 17;13(1):17696. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-44607-4.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-44607-4.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nadia Z Shaban 1, Mai Abdel-Alnaby 2, Mohamed N Atta 3, Ahmed A Abdul-Aziz 3, Fayed Megahed 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D plays a central role in maintaining calcium, phosphorus, and bone homeostasis in close interaction with the parathyroid hormone. Obesity is a significant health problem worldwide, particularly in developed nations. The current study was carried out to investigate the possible relationship between body mass index (BMI) elevation and differentiation in 25-hydroxyvitamin D (VD), vitamin D receptor (VDR) gene expression, and genetic polymorphism besides oxidative stress in adult Egyptian individuals. This was done to explore the mechanisms underlying the suggested role of the VD/VDR complex in the pathogenesis of obesity. A total of 70 subjects (30 obese, 25 overweight, and 15 normal, age: 20-50 years, without other chronic diseases) were selected. The study focused on the determination of VD, VDR gene polymorphism, VDR gene expression, alkaline phosphatase, calcium, phosphorus, glucose, lipid profile, oxidative stress including, oxidant (malondialdehyde), and anti-oxidants (reduced glutathione and superoxide dismutase). The results showed that elevation in BMI led to the percentage of the Ff &amp;lsquo;allele&amp;rsquo; becoming predominant, while the percentage of the FF &amp;lsquo;allele&amp;rsquo; was in the normal BMI range. Also, BMI elevation caused significant reductions in VD and VDR expression, with significant elevations in alkaline phosphatase and the levels of calcium and phosphate in serum. Also, oxidative stress increases with increasing BMI. Elevation in BMI causes a reduction in VD concentration and VDR gene expression levels. Also, the percentage of heterozygous mutant genotype Ff &amp;lsquo;allele&amp;rsquo; is predominantly in the obese human, in contrast to normal subjects, where the percentage of homozygous wild genotype FF &amp;lsquo;allele&amp;rsquo; is predominant. In general, the genetic expression and polymorphism of VD and VDR can be used as a genetic marker for predisposition, diagnosis, prognosis, and progression of obesity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Berberine: an antioxidant that activates the Vitamin D Receptor - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/berberine-an-antioxidant-that-activates-the-vitamin-d-receptor-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/berberine-an-antioxidant-that-activates-the-vitamin-d-receptor-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;brief-summary-of-this-page-by-chat-gpt---oct-172023&#34;&gt;Brief summary of this page by CHAT-GPT - Oct 17, 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Origins &amp;amp; Uses:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Berberine is a plant alkaloid used in Ayurvedic and traditional Chinese medicine for managing health conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Found in various plants like barberry, Oregon grape, and tree turmeric.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally used as an antimicrobial, antiprotozoal, and antidiarrheal agent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Noted for its ability to reduce blood sugar, potentially comparable to some anti-diabetic drugs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Used in treating markers of glycemic control, blood lipids, liver function, and metabolic disorders among others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microcephaly patients have both poor Vitamin D levels and Receptors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/microcephaly-patients-have-both-poor-vitamin-d-levels-and-receptors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/microcephaly-patients-have-both-poor-vitamin-d-levels-and-receptors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;genetic-susceptibility-of-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-on-autosomal-recessive-primary-microcephaly-patients-in-pakistani-population-a-case-control-and-in-silico-study&#34;&gt;Genetic susceptibility of vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms on autosomal recessive primary microcephaly patients in Pakistani population: a case-control and in-silico study&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mol Biol Rep. 2023 Oct;50(10):8049-8059. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11033-023-08681-1&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1007/s11033-023-08681-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Komal Aslam 1 2, Iram Anjum 2, Kanwal Aslam 3, Rukhama Haq 1, Rasheeda Bashir 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Autosomal recessive primary microcephaly (MCPH) is a rare genetic disorder that leads to reduced cerebral cortex caused by a mutation in corticogenesis. The expression of the Vitamin D receptor (VDR) gene is involved in the proliferation and differentiation of neural stem cells, and VDR polymorphisms have been associated with various neurological disorders. However, their relationship with MCPH has not been explored. This study aimed to investigate the association of VDR polymorphisms with MCPH due to its role in Wnt signaling pathway and its In-silico analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sepsis 2X-3X more likely if poor Vitamin D Receptor – meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sepsis-2x-3x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sepsis-2x-3x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;association-of-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphism-with-the-risk-of-sepsis-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis&#34;&gt;Association of vitamin D receptor gene polymorphism with the risk of sepsis: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Medicine (Baltimore). 2023 Sep 22;102(38):e35130. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000035130.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000035130.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Qian Li 1, Wen Li 1, Menglu Chen 1, Yihui Chai 1, Liancheng Guan 2, Yunzhi Chen 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: To investigate the association between sepsis and the vitamin D receptor (VDR) gene polymorphisms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Methods: Databases including PubMed, Cochrane Library, EMbase, CNKI, Wanfang Data, and VIP Data were systematically searched. The association was assessed using odds ratios (ORs), and 95% confidence intervals (CIs). The statistical tests were performed using Review Manager 5.4.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glaucoma fought by Vitamin D - several studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/glaucoma-fought-by-vitamin-d-several-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/glaucoma-fought-by-vitamin-d-several-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange8span-vitamindwiki-pages-with-glaucoma-in-thetitle&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;8+&lt;/span&gt; VitaminDWiki pages with GLAUCOMA in the title&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{list max=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;GLAUCOMA&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; shownbitems=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xA;&#xA;{column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=title format=&amp;ldquo;objectlink&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;search-for-glaucoma-and-vitamin-d-16300studies&#34;&gt;Search for Glaucoma and &amp;ldquo;Vitamin D&amp;rdquo; 16,300 studies&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Google Scholar April 2024](&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0,48&amp;amp;q=glaucoma&#34;&gt;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0,48&amp;amp;q=glaucoma&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;vitamin d&amp;rdquo;&amp;amp;btnG=)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Association of the Severity of Primary Open-Angle Glaucoma with Serum Vitamin D Levels  - Dec 2023 - DOI: 10.21608/bmfj.2023.250567.1960 FREE PDF&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Many genes can restrict Vitamin D from getting to the cells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/many-genes-can-restrict-vitamin-d-from-getting-to-the-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/many-genes-can-restrict-vitamin-d-from-getting-to-the-cells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-an-overview-of-gene-regulation-ranging-from-metabolism-to-genomic-effects&#34;&gt;Vitamin D: An Overview of Gene Regulation, Ranging from Metabolism to Genomic Effects&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genes 2023, 14(9), 1691; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/genes14091691&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/genes14091691&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Giacomo Voltan 1,2ORCID,Michele Cannito 1,2ORCID,Michela Ferrarese 1,2ORCID,Filippo Ceccato 1,2,*ORCID andValentina Camozzi 1,2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Department of Medicine (DIMED), University of Padova, Via Giustiniani 2, 35128 Padova, Italy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Endocrinology Unit, Padova University Hospital, Via Ospedale Civile 105, 35128 Padova, Italy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Author to whom correspondence should be addressed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;pdf-table-of-contents&#34;&gt;PDF Table of Contents&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;vitamin-d-receptor-structure&#34;&gt;Vitamin D Receptor structure&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D is a pro-hormone characterized by an intricate metabolism and regulation. It is well known for its role in calcium and phosphate metabolism, and in bone health. However, several studies have assessed a huge number of extra-skeletal functions, ranging from cell proliferation in some oncogenic pathways to antioxidant and immunomodulatory functions. Vitamin D exerts its role by binding to VDRs (vitamin D receptors), which are located in many different tissues. Moreover, VDRs are able to bind hundreds of genomic loci, modulating the expression of various primary target genes. Interestingly, plenty of gene polymorphisms regarding VDRs are described, each one carrying a potential influence against gene expression, with relapses in several chronic diseases and metabolic complications. In this review, we provide an overview of the genetic aspects of vitamin D and VDR, emphasizing the gene regulation of vitamin D, and the genetic modulation of VDR target genes. In addition, we briefly summarize the rare genetic disease linked to vitamin D metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caffeine decreases Vitamin D in blood and cells - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/caffeine-decreases-vitamin-d-in-blood-and-cells-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/caffeine-decreases-vitamin-d-in-blood-and-cells-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange4span-vitamindwiki-pages-with-caffine-or-coffee-in-the-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;4+&lt;/span&gt; VitaminDWiki pages with CAFFINE OR COFFEE in the title&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;CAFFINE OR COFFEE&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; shownbitems=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xA;&#xA;{column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=title format=&amp;ldquo;objectlink&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=modification_date_major format=&amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;caffeine-deactivates-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-less-d-to-cells---aug-2019&#34;&gt;Caffeine deactivates Vitamin D Receptor gene (less D to cells) - Aug 2019&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Effect of Caffeine on Calcitriol-Inducible Vitamin D Receptor-Controlled Gene Expression in Intestinal and Osteoblastic Cells&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D Receptors in muscles decrease with age in those with Osteoporosis - 2018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-receptors-in-muscles-decrease-with-age-in-those-with-osteoporosis-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-receptors-in-muscles-decrease-with-age-in-those-with-osteoporosis-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-receptor-in-muscle-atrophy-of-elderly-patients-a-key-element-of-osteoporosis-sarcopenia-connection&#34;&gt;Vitamin D Receptor in Muscle Atrophy of Elderly Patients: A Key Element of Osteoporosis-Sarcopenia Connection&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aging and disease ›› 2018, Vol. 9 ›› Issue (6) : 952-964. DOI: 10.14336/AD.2018.0215&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this study, we investigated the relationship between sarcopenia (evaluated in term of fibers atrophy), vitamin d receptor protein expression and TaqI/Cdx2/FokI VDR genotypes in an Italian cohort of osteoporosis(n=44) and osteoarthritis (n=55) patients. Muscle biopsies were fixed and investigated by both immunohistochemistry (vitamin d receptor expression) and transmission electron microscopy (satellite stem cells niches). Vitamin d receptor polymorphisms were studied on DNA extracted from muscle paraffin sections. For the first time, we reported that aging differently affects the VDR activation in OA and OP patients. In particular, while in  &lt;strong&gt;OP patients we observed a significant reduction of VDR positive myonuclei with age&lt;/strong&gt; , no “age effect” was observed in OA patients. The frequent activation of VDR could explain the lower number of atrophic fiber that we observed in OA patients respect to OP. From genetic point of view, we showed a putative association among polymorphisms FokI and Cdx2 of VDR gene, vitamin d receptor activation and the occurrence of sarcopenia. Altogether these data open new prospective for the prevention and cure of age-related muscle disorders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phytochemicals (Quercetin, Resveratrol, Tumeric, etc.) plus Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/phytochemicals-quercetin-resveratrol-tumeric-etc-plus-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/phytochemicals-quercetin-resveratrol-tumeric-etc-plus-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phytonutrients, also called phytochemicals or antioxidants, %%%    are compounds produced by plants that provide health benefits to the body&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;phytochemicals-and-vitamin-d-for-a-healthy-life-and-prevention-of-diseases---july-2023&#34;&gt;Phytochemicals and Vitamin D for a Healthy Life and Prevention of Diseases - July 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Int J Mol Sci . 2023 Jul 29;24(15):12167. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms241512167.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/ijms241512167.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kazuki Santa 1, Kenji Watanabe 2 3, Yoshio Kumazawa 4 5, Isao Nagaoka 5 6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;580&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;580&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grape Randomized Controlled Trials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;480&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A variety of phytocompounds contained in medical plants have been used as medication, including Kampo (traditional Japanese) medicine. Phytochemicals are one category of the chemical compounds mainly known as antioxidants, and recently, their anti-inflammatory effects in preventing chronic inflammation have received much attention. Here, we present a narrative review of the health-promotion and disease-prevention effects of phytochemicals,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin D and it’s related genes regulate the immune system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-and-its-related-genes-regulate-the-immune-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-and-its-related-genes-regulate-the-immune-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-review-of-the-critical-role-of-vitamin-d-axis-on-the-immune-system---aug-2023&#34;&gt;A review of the critical role of vitamin D axis on the immune system - Aug 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exp Mol Pathol. 2023 Aug 10;104866. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yexmp.2023.104866&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.yexmp.2023.104866&lt;/a&gt;   PDF not available&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gholamreza Daryabor 1, Nasser Gholijani 1, Fatemeh Rezaei Kahmini 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Autoimmune Diseases Research Center, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Autoimmune Diseases Research Center, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran; Department of Immunology, Faculty of Medical Sciences, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran. &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Fateme.rezaei@modares.ac.ir&#34;&gt;Fateme.rezaei@modares.ac.ir&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infertility risk increased 2.5 X by poor Vitamin D Receptor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/infertility-risk-increased-25-x-by-poor-vitamin-d-receptor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/infertility-risk-increased-25-x-by-poor-vitamin-d-receptor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;genetic-association-of-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-with-female-infertility&#34;&gt;Genetic association of vitamin D receptor gene with female infertility&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nucleosides Nucleotides Nucleic Acids . 2023 Jul 26;1-18. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/15257770.2023.2236167&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1080/15257770.2023.2236167&lt;/a&gt;   PDF is behind a $58 paywall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mussarat Ashraf 1, Haq Nawaz Khan 1, Rabab Ibrahim 1, Maheen Shahid 1, Sher Khan 1, Ambrin Fatima 1, Saif Ullah 2, Rehana Rehman 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background: Infertility is defined as failure to achieve a clinical pregnancy after 12 months of unprotected intercourse. It affects 15% of couples globally and 22% of couples within Pakistan. Female infertility can be caused by numerous genetic or environmental factors including hormone imbalances and exposure to chemicals or radiation. The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency among the adult population was reported to be 14-59% with a higher prevalence in Asian countries. Furthermore, the expression of Vitamin D receptor (VDR) can play a vital role in the reproductive organs of females. Hence, the aim of our present study was to check the association of VDR polymorphisms with infertile females. For this purpose, blood samples were collected for genotyping of four known VDR mutations &lt;span&gt;[FokI (rs2228570), TaqI (rs731236), ApaI (rs7975232), and BsmI (rs1544410)]&lt;/span&gt; via PCR-based RFLP assay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Vitamin D genes (Most are not noticed by blood test)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/12-vitamin-d-genes-most-are-not-noticed-by-blood-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/12-vitamin-d-genes-most-are-not-noticed-by-blood-test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;association-between-polymorphisms-in-vitamin-d-pathway-related-genes-vitamin-d-status-muscle-mass-and-function-a-systematic-review&#34;&gt;Association between Polymorphisms in Vitamin D Pathway-Related Genes, Vitamin D Status, Muscle Mass and Function: A Systematic Review&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2021, 13(9), 3109; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu13093109&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu13093109&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Ermira Krasniqi 1,2,3ORCID,Arben Boshnjaku 2,4ORCID, Karl-Heinz Wagner 1,3ORCID and Barbara Wessner 1,2,*ORCID&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Research Platform Active Ageing, University of Vienna, Althanstraße 14, 1090 Vienna, Austria&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Centre for Sport Science and University Sports, University of Vienna, Auf der Schmelz 6, 1150 Vienna, Austria&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Vienna, Althanstraße 14, 1090 Vienna, Austria&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resveratrol - liposomal may be best form to increase cellular Vitamin D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/resveratrol-liposomal-may-be-best-form-to-increase-cellular-vitamin-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/resveratrol-liposomal-may-be-best-form-to-increase-cellular-vitamin-d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;recent-progress-in-nanotechnology-based-drug-carriers-for-resveratrol-delivery&#34;&gt;Recent progress in nanotechnology-based drug carriers for resveratrol delivery&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Drug Delivery  Volume 30, 2023 - Issue 1  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/10717544.2023.2174206&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/10717544.2023.2174206&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chunhong Li,Zhen Wang,Hui Lei &amp;amp;Dan Zhang&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;550&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AuC: area under the concentration-time curve (plasma exposure);&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;t1/2: plasma half life;    Cl: clearance;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MrT: mean residence time;    Cmax: peak plasma concentration;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AuC0 →∞: area under the concentration time-curve from time zero to infinity;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Resveratrol is a polyphenol with diverse pharmacological activities, but its clinical efficacy is limited due to low solubility/permeability, light-induced isomerization, auto-oxidation, and rapid metabolism. Nanodelivery systems, such as  &lt;strong&gt;liposomes, polymeric nanoparticles, lipid nanocarriers, micelles, nanocrystals, inorganic nanoparticles, nanoemulsions, protein-based nanoparticles, exosomes, macrophages, and red blood cells (RBCs)&lt;/strong&gt;  have shown great potential for improving the solubility, biocompatibility, and therapeutic efficacy of resveratrol. This review comprehensively summarizes the recent advances in resveratrol nanoencapsulation and describes potential strategies to improve the pharmacokinetics of existing nanoformulations, enhance targeting, reduce toxicity, and increase drug release and encapsulation efficiency. The article also suggests that in order to avoid potential safety issues, resveratrol nanoformulations must be tested in vivo in a wide range of diseases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID in hospital stopped by Vitamin D Receptor activators (curcumin, quercetin) – RCT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-in-hospital-stopped-by-vitamin-d-receptor-activators-curcumin-quercetin-rct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-in-hospital-stopped-by-vitamin-d-receptor-activators-curcumin-quercetin-rct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;nasafytol-supplementation-in-adults-hospitalized-with-covid-19-infection-results-from-an-exploratory-open-label-randomized-controlled-trial&#34;&gt;NASAFYTOL® supplementation in adults hospitalized with COVID-19 infection: results from an exploratory open-label randomized controlled trial&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front. Nutr. 10:1137407. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2023.1137407&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3389/fnut.2023.1137407&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jean Gérain1, Melanie Uebelhoer2*, Bérénice Costes2, Julie Herman2, Sandra Pietri2, Anne-Françoise Donneau3, Justine Monseur3 and Yves Henrotin2   Belgium&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;span-stylecolororange25-people-got-curcumin-42-mg-quercetin-65-mg-vitamin-d-90-iu-dailyspan&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt;25 people got Curcumin (42 mg), Quercetin (65 mg), Vitamin D (90 IU) daily&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objectives: The effect and safety of Nasafytol®, a food supplement combining curcumin, quercetin, and Vitamin D, on hospitalized COVID-19-positive patients as support to standard of care were to be assessed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Cardiovascular diseases are associated with little vitamin D getting to cells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/4-cardiovascular-diseases-are-associated-with-little-vitamin-d-getting-to-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/4-cardiovascular-diseases-are-associated-with-little-vitamin-d-getting-to-cells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;recent-advances-in-association-between-vitamin-d-levels-and-cardiovascular-disorders&#34;&gt;Recent Advances in Association Between Vitamin D Levels and Cardiovascular Disorders&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Current Hypertension Reports (2023) &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11906-023-01246-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11906-023-01246-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pahel Agarwal, Yash Agarwal &amp;amp; Maha Hameed&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Study sections&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;700&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Purpose of Review&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this review, we discuss the evidence that vitamin D affects cardiovascular disease through interventional and observational studies and their corresponding association mechanisms. We also highlight the need for further research to definitively conclude clinical recommendations based on preliminary data and determine the extent to which vitamin D levels may impact the incidence and prognosis of major cardiovascular diseases in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asthma by age 7 if wheezing before preschools and poor vitamin D Receptor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/asthma-by-age-7-if-wheezing-before-preschools-and-poor-vitamin-d-receptor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/asthma-by-age-7-if-wheezing-before-preschools-and-poor-vitamin-d-receptor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-receptor-genetic-variant-associated-with-asthma-in-swedish-school-children&#34;&gt;Vitamin D receptor genetic variant associated with asthma in Swedish school-children&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clin Exp Allergy. 2023 May 29. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/cea.14349&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1111/cea.14349&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anastasia Filiou 1 2, Angela Hoyer 1 2, Idun Holmdahl 1 2, Sandip Chakraborty 1 2, Marianne van Hage 3, Björn Nordlund 1 2, Gunilla Hedlin 1 2, Jon R Konradsen 1 2, Cilla Söderhäll 1 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-file-pdf&#34; style=&#34;margin-right: 0.3em;&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamindwiki--&#34;&gt;VitaminDWiki -&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {SQL(db=&gt;vitamind)}SELECT COUNT(*) FROM (SELECT catObjectId, COUNT(*) FROM `tiki_category_objects` WHERE categId = 7  OR categId = 142 GROUP BY catObjectId HAVING COUNT(*) &gt; 1) AS categs INNER JOIN tiki_objects ON tiki_objects.objectId = categs.catObjectId WHERE type = &#34;wiki page&#34;{SQL} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   studies in both categories Breathing and Vitamin D Receptor&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cervical Cancer is prevented by Vitamin D, and treated if caught early (genes are important)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cervical-cancer-is-prevented-by-vitamin-d-and-treated-if-caught-early-genes-are-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cervical-cancer-is-prevented-by-vitamin-d-and-treated-if-caught-early-genes-are-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-preventive-role-of-the-vitamin-d-endocrine-system-in-cervical-cancer&#34;&gt;The Preventive Role of the Vitamin D Endocrine System in Cervical Cancer&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Int J Mol Sci. 2023 May 12;24(10):8665. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms24108665.&#34;&gt;doi: 10.3390/ijms24108665.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Euclides Avila 1, Bryan Javier Noriega-Mejía 1, Jocelyn González-Macías 1, Ulises Cortes-Hernández 1, Janice García-Quiroz 1, Rocío García-Becerra 2, Lorenza Díaz 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D along with its active metabolite calcitriol and its metabolic and signaling system, known as the vitamin D endocrine system, have been widely recognized as a pivotal regulator of calcium homeostasis in addition to non-calcemic antitumoral effects in a variety of human cancers, including cervical cancer. Several studies have found an inverse relationship between the incidence of cervical neoplasia and vitamin D levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Vitamin D receptor has been found in 54 human tissues</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-vitamin-d-receptor-has-been-found-in-54-human-tissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-vitamin-d-receptor-has-been-found-in-54-human-tissues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-a-master-example-of-nutrigenomics&#34;&gt;Vitamin D: A master example of nutrigenomics&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Redox Biol . 2023 Jun;62:102695. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.redox.2023.102695&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.redox.2023.102695&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Carsten Carlberg 1, Marianna Raczyk 2, Natalia Zawrotna 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrigenomics attempts to characterize and integrate the relation between dietary molecules and gene expression on a genome-wide level. One of the biologically active nutritional compounds is vitamin D3, which activates via its metabolite 1α,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (1,25(OH)2D3) the nuclear receptor VDR (vitamin D receptor). Vitamin D3 can be synthesized endogenously in our skin, but since we spend long times indoors and often live at higher latitudes where for many winter months UV-B radiation is too low, it became a true vitamin. The ligand-inducible transcription factor VDR is expressed in the majority of human tissues and cell types, where it modulates the epigenome at thousands of genomic sites. In a tissue-specific fashion this results in the up- and downregulation of primary vitamin D target genes, some of which are involved in attenuating oxidative stress. Vitamin D affects a wide range of physiological functions including the control of metabolism, bone formation and immunity. In this review, we will discuss how the epigenome- and transcriptome-wide effects of 1,25(OH)2D3 and its receptor VDR serve as a master example in nutrigenomics. In this context, we will outline the basis of a mechanistic understanding for personalized nutrition with vitamin D3.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children with COVID 4X more likely to have poor Vitamin D Receptors (Note: COVID deactivates VDR)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/children-with-covid-4x-more-likely-to-have-poor-vitamin-d-receptors-note-covid-deactivates-vdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/children-with-covid-4x-more-likely-to-have-poor-vitamin-d-receptors-note-covid-deactivates-vdr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-deficiency-and-vitamin-d-receptor-foki-polymorphism-as-risk-factors-for-covid-19&#34;&gt;Vitamin D deficiency and vitamin D receptor FokI polymorphism as risk factors for COVID-19&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pediatr Res. 2023 Apr;93(5):1383-1390. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41390-022-02275-6&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1038/s41390-022-02275-6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nancy M S Zeidan 1, Hanan M Abd El Lateef 2, Dalia M Selim 2, Suzan A Razek 2, Ghada A B Abd-Elrehim 3, Mohamed Nashat 4, Noha ElGyar 5, Nevin M Waked 6, Attia A Soliman 7, Ahmed A Elhewala 7, Mohamed M M Shehab 7, Ahmed A A Ibraheem 7, Hassan Shehata 7, Yousif M Yousif 7, Nagwa E Akeel 7, Mustafa I A Hashem 7, Amani A Ahmed 7, Ahmed A Emam 8, Mohamed M Abdelmohsen 9, Mohamed F Ahmed 9, Ahmed S E Saleh 10, Heba H Eltrawy 11, Gehan H Shahin 12, Rehab M Nabil 13, Thoraya A Hosny 13, Mohamed R Abdelhamed 14, Mona R Afify 15, Mohanned T Alharbi 15, Mohammed K Nagshabandi 15, Muyassar K Tarabulsi 15, Sherif F Osman 16, Amal S M Abd-Elrazek 17, Manal M Rashad 18, Sonya A A El-Gaaly 19, Said A B Gad 20, Mohamed Y Mohamed 21, Khalil Abdelkhalek 1, Aly A Yousef 22&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>T2 Diabetes might be fought by Vitamin D plus Vitamin D Receptor activators</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/t2-diabetes-might-be-fought-by-vitamin-d-plus-vitamin-d-receptor-activators/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/t2-diabetes-might-be-fought-by-vitamin-d-plus-vitamin-d-receptor-activators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-in-diabetes-uncovering-the-sunshine-hormones-role-in-glucose-metabolism-and-beyond&#34;&gt;Vitamin D in Diabetes: Uncovering the Sunshine Hormone&amp;rsquo;s Role in Glucose Metabolism and Beyond&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrients 2023, 15, 1997. https: / / doi.org/ 10.3390/nu15081997&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jie Wu 1 , Annette Atkins 2, Michael Downes * and Zong Wei 1,3,*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Department of Physiology and Biomedical Engineering, Mayo Clinic Arizona, Scottsdale, AZ 85259, USA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gene Expression Laboratory, Salk Institute for Biological Studies, La Jolla, CA 92037, USA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Division of Endocrinology, Mayo Clinic Arizona, Scottsdale, AZ 85259, USA&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diabetes 3X more likely if had COVID ICU (VDR was deactivated)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/diabetes-3x-more-likely-if-had-covid-icu-vdr-was-deactivated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/diabetes-3x-more-likely-if-had-covid-icu-vdr-was-deactivated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;severe-covid-19-linked-to-new-diabetes-diagnoses&#34;&gt;Severe COVID-19 linked to new diabetes diagnoses&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdedge.com/familymedicine/article/262540/covid-19-updates/severe-covid-19-linked-new-diabetes-diagnoses&#34;&gt;MDEdge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;COVID can more than triple the chance of being diagnosed with type 2 diabetes within a year of being infected, according to a new Canadian study.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamindwiki--&#34;&gt;VitaminDWiki -&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {SQL(db=&gt;vitamind)}SELECT COUNT(*) FROM (SELECT catObjectId, COUNT(*) FROM `tiki_category_objects` WHERE categId = 155  OR categId = 142 GROUP BY catObjectId HAVING COUNT(*) &gt; 1) AS categs INNER JOIN tiki_objects ON tiki_objects.objectId = categs.catObjectId WHERE type = &#34;wiki page&#34;{SQL} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   studies in both categories Virus and Vitamin D Receptor&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID variants protect themselves by deactivating different VDR variants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-variants-protect-themselves-by-deactivating-different-vdr-variants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-variants-protect-themselves-by-deactivating-different-vdr-variants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;role-of-foki-rs2228570-and-tru9i-rs757343-polymorphisms-in-the-mortality-of-patients-infected-with-different-variants-ofsars-cov-2&#34;&gt;Role of FokI rs2228570 and Tru9I rs757343 Polymorphisms in the Mortality of Patients Infected with Different Variants of SARS-CoV-2&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arch Med Res. 2023 Mar 31;S0188-4409(23)00053-X. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arcmed.2023.03.006&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1016/j.arcmed.2023.03.006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hasan Rahman Shawi Shawi 1, Enayat Anvari 2, Abolfazl Fateh 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Background and aim: Low vitamin D levels are associated with the severity of coronavirus disease 19 (COVID-19). Vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms, such as Tru9I rs757343 and FokI rs2228570, have been suggested to be potential risk factors for severe COVID-19 outcomes. This study investigated how Tru9I rs757343 and FokI rs2228570 polymorphisms influenced the mortality rate of COVID-19 in relation to severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) variants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>100 years since the discovery of Vitamin D - 23 studies - 2022, 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/100-years-since-the-discovery-of-vitamin-d-23-studies-2022-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/100-years-since-the-discovery-of-vitamin-d-23-studies-2022-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;||Carsten Carlberg| A Pleiotropic Nuclear Hormone Labelled Hundred Years Ago Vitamin D&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Michael F. Holick| The One-Hundred-Year Anniversary of the Discovery of the Sunshine Vitamin D3: Historical, Personal Experience and Evidence-Based Perspectives&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Carsten Carlberg| Vitamin D in the Context of Evolution&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shahid Hussain, Clayton Yates and Moray J. Campbell| Vitamin D and Systems Biology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Carsten Carlberg| Vitamin D and Its Target Genes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Natacha Rochel| Vitamin D and Its Receptor from a Structural Perspective&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gestational Diabetes and Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gestational-diabetes-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gestational-diabetes-and-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;gestational-diabetes-30-increase-in-us-since-2016-reported-july-2023&#34;&gt;Gestational Diabetes: 30% increase in US since 2016 (reported July 2023)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trialsitenews.com/a/osu-wexner-med-center-partners-lead-12m-study-targeting-rising-gestational-diabetes-aa37599d&#34;&gt;Gestational diabetes impacts nearly 75,000 pregnant individuals and their unborn babies each year in the United States, and according to the Centers for Disease Control cases have risen 30% since 2016.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which is probably similar to the increase of Diabetes in the same time period&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;disrupted-placental-vitamin-d-metabolism-and-calcium-signaling-in-gestational-diabetes-and-pre-eclampsia-patients---april-2023&#34;&gt;Disrupted placental vitamin D metabolism and calcium signaling in gestational diabetes and pre-eclampsia patients - April 2023&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Endocrine . 2023 Apr;80(1):191-200. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s12020-022-03272-9&#34;&gt;doi: 10.1007/s12020-022-03272-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parkinson’s Disease, low vitamin D and Vit. D genetics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/parkinsons-disease-low-vitamin-d-and-vit-d-genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/parkinsons-disease-low-vitamin-d-and-vit-d-genetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;vitamin-d-deficiency-and-genetic-polymorphisms-of-vitamin-d-associated-genes-in-parkinsons-disease&#34;&gt;Vitamin D deficiency and genetic polymorphisms of Vitamin D-associated genes in Parkinson’s Disease&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;European Journal of Neuroscience preprint DOI: 10.22541/au.167407862.25881100/v1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Barnali Ray Basu1, Randrita Pal1, Supriyo Choudhury2, Hrishikesh Kumar2, Sanjit Dey3, and Nilansu Das1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1Surendranath College&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Institute of Neurosciences Kolkata&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3University of Calcutta Faculty Council for Post-Graduate Studies in Science&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/attachments/d3.mock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parkinson’s Disease (PD) and vitamin D share a unique link as Vitamin D deficiency (VDD) prevails in PD. Thus, an in-depth understanding of Vitamin D biology in PD might be crucial for therapeutic strategies emphasizing Vitamin D. Specifically, explicating the effect of VDD and genetic polymorphisms of vitamin D-associated genes in PD, like&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dengue Fever decimated by Vitamin D - many studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dengue-fever-decimated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dengue-fever-decimated-by-vitamin-d-many-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I missing?%%%Dengue is increasing%%%Vitamin D fights Dengue and many other viruses. %%%    Is Vitamin D ignored because it is not a vaccine?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;13-vitamindwiki-pages-with-dengue-in-title&#34;&gt;13+ VitaminDWiki pages with DENGUE in title&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This list is automatically updated&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{LIST()}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{list max=&amp;ldquo;50&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter field=&#34;title&#34; content=&#34;dengue&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {filter type=&#34;wiki page&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{sort mode=&amp;ldquo;modification_date_major_desc&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT(template=&amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo;)}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{tableparams allowtableexpansion=&amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; shownbitems=&amp;ldquo;y&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{column sort=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; label=&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; mode=&amp;quot;raw&amp;quot;}{column}&#xA;&#xA;{column label=&amp;quot;Modified&amp;quot; sort=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot; field=&amp;quot;modification_date_major&amp;quot;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{OUTPUT}&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{FORMAT(name=&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;)}{display name=title format=&amp;ldquo;objectlink&amp;rdquo;}{FORMAT}&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural activators of the Vitamin D Receptor - some immune cells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/natural-activators-of-the-vitamin-d-receptor-some-immune-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/natural-activators-of-the-vitamin-d-receptor-some-immune-cells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- {maketoc Title=&#34;&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;two-lineages-of-immune-cells-that-differentially-express-the-vitamin-d-receptor&#34;&gt;Two lineages of immune cells that differentially express the vitamin D receptor&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Journal of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology. Volume 228, April 2023, 106253 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2023.106253&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb.2023.106253&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:orange;&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Entire PDF is behind a paywall. The following snippets are provided by the publisher&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since 1983 it has been known that monocytes and activated T and B cells expressed the vitamin D receptor (VDR) and are therefore vitamin D targets. New data identified two lineages of immune cells that can be differentiated by the expression of the VDR. Monocytes, macrophages, neutrophils, and hematopoietic stem cells were mostly from VDR positive lineages. T cells, ILC1 and ILC3 were also largely VDR positive, which is consistent with the known effects of vitamin D as regulators of type-1 and type-3 immunity. Activation of the VDR negative T cells did not induce the expression of the VDR reporter, suggesting that perhaps only a subset of the T cells in the periphery express the VDR. When activated, the VDR negative T cells responded as if they were VDR knockout T cells in that they made more IFN-γ and proliferated faster than the VDR positive T cells. The ability of vitamin D to regulate immune function will depend on which cells express the VDR and a better understanding of the signals that regulate VDR expression in immune cells.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
