<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vitamin D Receptor on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/vitamin-d-receptor.html</link><description>Recent content in Vitamin D Receptor on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vitamin-d-receptor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Liver and interactions with vitamin D deficiency - Review</title><link>/posts/liver-and-interactions-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/liver-and-interactions-with-vitamin-d-deficiency-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-in-liver-diseases-from-mechanisms-to-clinical-trials">Vitamin D in liver diseases: From mechanisms to clinical trials&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10.1111/(ISSN)1440-1746">Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology&lt;/a> , &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jgh.2013.28.issue-s1/issuetoc">Vol 28 Issue &lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Yuan-Ping Han1,2, &lt;a href="mailto:hanyp@scu.edu.cn">hanyp@scu.edu.cn&lt;/a>, Yuan-Ping Han, Ming Kong&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>, Sujun Zheng&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>, Yan Ren&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>, #Longdon Zhu&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>, Hongbo Shi&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>, Zhongping Duan&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Article first published online: 15 JUL 2013DOI: 10.1111/jgh.12016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Special Issue: 7th International Symposium on Alcoholic Liver and Pancreatic Diseases and Cirrhosis.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Funding for this conference was made possible (in part) by Grant 5 R13AA20691-02 from the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA). Guest Editors: Bin Gao and Fu-Sheng Wang&lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jgh.2013.28.issue-s1/issuetoc">Volume 28, Issue Supplement S1, &lt;/a>pages 49–55, August 2013&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X less prostate cancer in A-A with low Calcium is due vitamin D receptor gene</title><link>/posts/2x-less-prostate-cancer-in-a-a-with-low-calcium-is-due-vitamin-d-receptor-gene.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-less-prostate-cancer-in-a-a-with-low-calcium-is-due-vitamin-d-receptor-gene.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calcium-intake-and-prostate-cancer-among-african-americans-effect-modification-by-vitamin-d-receptor-calcium-absorption-genotype">Calcium intake and prostate cancer among African Americans: effect modification by vitamin D receptor calcium absorption genotype.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Bone Miner Res. 2012 Jan;27(1):187-94. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/jbmr.505.">doi: 10.1002/jbmr.505.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rowland GW, Schwartz GG, John EM, Ingles SA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Preventive Medicine, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>High dietary intake of calcium has been classified as a probable cause of prostate cancer, although the mechanism underlying the association between dietary calcium and prostate cancer risk is unclear. The vitamin D receptor (VDR) is a key regulator of calcium absorption. In the small intestine, VDR expression is regulated by the CDX-2 transcription factor, which binds a polymorphic site in the VDR gene promoter. We examined VDR Cdx2 genotype and calcium intake, assessed by a food frequency questionnaire, in 533 African-American prostate cancer cases (256 with advanced stage at diagnosis, 277 with localized stage) and 250 African-American controls who participated in the California Collaborative Prostate Cancer Study. We examined the effects of genotype, calcium intake, and diet-gene interactions by conditional logistic regression. Compared with men in the lowest quartile of calcium intake, men in the highest quartile had an approximately twofold increased risk of localized and advanced prostate cancer (odds ratio &lt;span>[OR]&lt;/span> =  &lt;strong>2.20&lt;/strong> , 95% confidence interval &lt;span>[CI]&lt;/span> = 1.40, 3.46), with a significant dose-response. Poor absorbers of calcium (VDR Cdx2 GG genotype) had a significantly lower risk of advanced prostate cancer (OR = 0.41, 95% CI = 0.19, 0.90). The gene-calcium interaction was statistically significant (p = 0.03). Among men with calcium intake below the median (680 mg/day), carriers of the G allele had an approximately 50% decreased risk compared with men with the AA genotype. These findings suggest a link between prostate cancer risk and high intestinal absorption of calcium.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The vitamin D receptor and T cell function</title><link>/posts/the-vitamin-d-receptor-and-t-cell-function.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-vitamin-d-receptor-and-t-cell-function.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="span-stylecolor00ffigure-1--proposed-model-for-vdr-signaling-in-t-cells-span">&lt;span style="color:#00F;">FIGURE 1 | Proposed model for VDR signaling in T cells. &lt;/span>&lt;/h4>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/t-cell.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Fontiers in IMMUNOLOGY, 18 June 2013 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2013.00148">doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2013.00148&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martin Kongsbak, Trine B. Levring, Carsten Geisler and Marina Rode von Essen*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of International Health, Immunology and Microbiology, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Correspondence: Marina Rode von Essen, Department of International Health, Immunology and Microbiology, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Blegdamsvej 3C, DK-2200 Copenhagen, Denmark e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:messen@sund.ku.dk">messen@sund.ku.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Type 1 diabetes associated with faulty Vitamin D receptor genes</title><link>/posts/type-1-diabetes-associated-with-faulty-vitamin-d-receptor-genes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/type-1-diabetes-associated-with-faulty-vitamin-d-receptor-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-receptor-vdr-gene-polymorphisms-and-age-onset-in-type-1-diabetes-mellitus">Vitamin D receptor (VDR) gene polymorphisms and age onset in type 1 diabetes mellitus&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Autoimmunity Posted online on May 30, 2013. (doi:10.3109/08916934.2013.795952)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jaqueline De Azevêdo Silva 1,2, Rafael Lima Guimarães 1,2, Lucas André Cavalcanti Brandão 2,3, Jacqueline Araujo 4, Ludovica Segat 5, Sergio Crovella 1,2, and Paula Sandrin-Garcia 1,2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Genetics, Federal University of Pernambuco, Recife, Pernambuco, Brazil,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Laboratory of Immunopathology Keizo Asami (LIKA), Federal University of Pernambuco,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ovarian Cancer 5.8 X more likely if both low vitamin D and Fok1 gene change</title><link>/posts/ovarian-cancer-58-x-more-likely-if-both-low-vitamin-d-and-fok1-gene-change.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ovarian-cancer-58-x-more-likely-if-both-low-vitamin-d-and-fok1-gene-change.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-and-vdr-gene-polymorphism-foki-in-epithelial-ovarian-cancer-in-indian-population">Vitamin D and VDR gene polymorphism (FokI) in epithelial ovarian cancer in Indian population.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Ovarian Res. 2013 May 26;6(1):37.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mohapatra S, Saxena A, Gandhi G, Koner BC, Ray PC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INTRODUCTION: Vitamin D deficiency and vitamin D receptor (VDR) gene polymorphism, FokI, is reported to increase the risk of many cancers. Role of vitamin D and its receptor polymorphisms in ovarian cancer has not been clearly defined.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE: To study the levels of serum vitamin D and occurrence of vitamin D receptor gene polymorphism (FokI) in cases of ovarian cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poorly functioning Vitamin D Receptor (VDR) was 5X more likely in children with low vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/poorly-functioning-vitamin-d-receptor-vdr-was-5x-more-likely-in-children-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/poorly-functioning-vitamin-d-receptor-vdr-was-5x-more-likely-in-children-with-low-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="association-of-vitamin-d-related-gene-polymorphisms-with-manifestation-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-in-children">Association of vitamin D-related gene polymorphisms with manifestation of vitamin D deficiency in children.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Endocr J. 2012;59(11):1007-14. Epub 2012 Jul 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kitanaka S, Isojima T, Takaki M, Numakura C, Hayasaka K, Igarashi T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pediatrics, Graduate School of Medicine, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo 113-8655, Japan. &lt;a href="mailto:sachi-tky@umin.ac.jp">sachi-tky@umin.ac.jp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The prevalence of vitamin D deficiency, presenting as hypocalcemic seizures or rickets in children, is increasing worldwide due to insufficient vitamin D intake and lack of exposure to sunshine. However, considering that relatively few children with low 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels manifest symptoms, it is possible that genetic factors may predispose individuals to vitamin D deficiency. Recent twin studies have reported that the level of serum of 25(OH)D is influenced by genetic factors. In addition, genome-wide association studies and candidate gene studies have revealed that several vitamin D-related genes, including VDR, GC, NADSYN1, CYP2R1, CYP24A1, CYP27B1, and C10orf88 contribute to variations in serum 25(OH)D levels. To investigate whether genetic predisposition contributes to vitamin D deficiency, we analyzed polymorphisms in vitamin D-related genes in 30 Japanese patients with vitamin D deficiency presenting at less than 4 years of age, along with 66 controls. A χ(2) test showed that the genotype frequencies of BsmI polymorphism in VDR and rs10898191 in NADSYN1 were significantly different between the two groups. The allele frequencies of BsmI, ApaI, TaqI in VDR, rs10898191 in NADSYN1, and rs705117 in GC were also significantly different. In particular, the frequency of the BAtS haplotype in VDR was significantly increased in the patient group relative to controls (p = 0.0014; odds ratio, &lt;strong>5.61&lt;/strong> ; 95% confidence interval 1.92 - 16.40). Although this is a small study, our findings suggest that VDR, NADSYN1, and GC polymorphisms may be linked to the manifestation of vitamin D deficiency in Japanese children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rheumatoid arthritis, genes and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/rheumatoid-arthritis-genes-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rheumatoid-arthritis-genes-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="enrichment-of-vitamin-d-response-elements-in-ra-associated-loci-supports-a-role-for-vitamin-d-in-the-pathogenesis-of-ra">Enrichment of vitamin D response elements in RA-associated loci supports a role for vitamin D in the pathogenesis of RA&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Genes and Immunity , (2 May 2013) | doi:10.1038/gene.2013.23&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Yarwood, P Martin, J Bowes, M Lunt, J Worthington, A Barton and S Eyre&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of this study was to explore the role of vitamin D in rheumatoid arthritis (RA) pathogenesis by investigating the enrichment of vitamin D response elements (VDREs) in confirmed RA susceptibility loci and testing variants associated with vitamin D levels for association with RA. Bioinformatically, VDRE genomic positions were overlaid with non-HLA (human leukocyte antigen)-confirmed RA susceptibility regions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D suppressed by Roundup and Genes - CYP2R1, CYP24A1, CYP450 etc.</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-suppressed-by-roundup-and-genes-cyp2r1-cyp24a1-cyp450-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-suppressed-by-roundup-and-genes-cyp2r1-cyp24a1-cyp450-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#overview">Overview&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also Web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cytochrome-p450-mediated-metabolism-of-vitamin-d--april-2013">Cytochrome P450-mediated metabolism of vitamin D – April 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cytochromes-p450-are-essential-players-in-the-vitamin-d-signaling-system---2011">Cytochromes P450 are essential players in the vitamin D signaling system - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#40400-items-contain-vitamin-d-and-cyp450-or-cpy2r1-or-p450-in-title-or-abstract">40,400 items contain &amp;ldquo;vitamin D&amp;rdquo; and (CYP450 OR CPY2R1 OR P450) in title or abstract&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#what-role-does-cyp450-play-in-drug-metabolism---asked-perplexity-ai-dec-2024httpswwwperplexityaisearchis-cyp450-the-same-as-cpy2r1-ewqrihkxrgkixszugyqrcq">What role does CYP450 play in drug metabolism - asked &lt;a href="https://www.perplexity.ai/search/is-cyp450-the-same-as-cpy2r1-ewqrIHKxRGKixSZuGYqrcQ">Perplexity AI Dec 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#by-how-much-does-cyp450-p450-reduce-vitamin-d----asked-perplexity-ai-dec-2024httpswwwperplexityaisearchby-how-much-does-cyp450-p450-r-48przuulq0ees4ixcpbdjw">By how much does CYP450 (P450) reduce vitamin D? - Asked &lt;a href="https://www.perplexity.ai/search/by-how-much-does-cyp450-p450-r-48PRzuuLQ0ees4IXCPBDjw">Perplexity AI Dec 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The P450 family includes CYP2R1&lt;/strong> , which controls vitamin D processing in the liver&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinal disc degeneration is associated with vitamin D receptor genes, and others</title><link>/posts/spinal-disc-degeneration-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-receptor-genes-and-others.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spinal-disc-degeneration-is-associated-with-vitamin-d-receptor-genes-and-others.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="genetic-polymorphisms-associated-with-intervertebral-disc-degeneration">Genetic polymorphisms associated with intervertebral disc degeneration.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Spine J. 2013 Mar;13(3):299-317. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.spinee.2013.01.041.">doi: 10.1016/j.spinee.2013.01.041.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mayer JE, Iatridis JC, Chan D, Qureshi SA, Gottesman O, Hecht AC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leni and Peter W. May Department of Orthopaedics, Mount Sinai Medical Center, 5 East 98th St, 9th Floor, New York, NY 10029, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND CONTEXT: Disc degeneration (DD) is a multifaceted chronic process that alters the structure and function of the intervertebral discs and can lead to painful conditions. The pathophysiology of degeneration is not well understood, but previous studies suggest that certain genetic polymorphisms may be important contributing factors leading to an increased risk of DD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free vitamin D (VDR) may be more important than total for bladder cancer</title><link>/posts/free-vitamin-d-vdr-may-be-more-important-than-total-for-bladder-cancer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/free-vitamin-d-vdr-may-be-more-important-than-total-for-bladder-cancer.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="influence-of-vitamin-d-binding-protein-on-the-association-between-circulating-vitamin-d-and-risk-of-bladder-cancer">Influence of vitamin D binding protein on the association between circulating vitamin D and risk of bladder cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Br J Cancer. 2012 Oct 23;107(9):1589-94. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/bjc.2012.417.">doi: 10.1038/bjc.2012.417.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Sep 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mondul AM, Weinstein SJ, Virtamo J, Albanes D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nutritional Epidemiology Branch, Division of Cancer Epidemiology and Genetics, National Cancer Institute, NIH, Department of Health and Human Services, 6120 Executive Boulevard, Suite 320, Rockville, MD, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:mondulam@mail.nih.gov">mondulam@mail.nih.gov&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: There is little research investigating the role of &lt;strong>vitamin D binding protein (DBP)&lt;/strong> in the association between 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25(OH)D) and disease risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D receptor gene associated with 50 percent more type 2 Diabetes – meta-analyses 2013, 2016</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-gene-associated-with-50-percent-more-type-2-diabetes-meta-analyses-2013-2016.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-gene-associated-with-50-percent-more-type-2-diabetes-meta-analyses-2013-2016.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#type-2-diabetes-in-chinese-is-50-percent-more-likely-if-have-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-problem--meta-analysis-2016">Type 2 Diabetes in Chinese is 50 percent more likely if have Vitamin D Receptor gene problem – meta-analysis 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-and-type-2-diabetes-a-meta-analysis--march-2013">Vitamin D Receptor Gene Polymorphisms and Type 2 Diabetes: A Meta-analysis.- March 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="type-2-diabetes-in-chinese-is-50-percent-more-likely-if-have-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-problem--meta-analysis-2016">Type 2 Diabetes in Chinese is 50 percent more likely if have Vitamin D Receptor gene problem – meta-analysis 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The genetic polymorphisms in vitamin D receptor and the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus: an updated meta-analysis.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D receptor in breasts and breast cancer vary with race</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-in-breasts-and-breast-cancer-vary-with-race.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-in-breasts-and-breast-cancer-vary-with-race.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-and-prognosis-of-breast-cancer-among-african-american-and-hispanic-women">Vitamin D Receptor Gene Polymorphisms and Prognosis of Breast Cancer among African-American and Hispanic Women&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PLoS ONE 8(3): e57967. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0057967&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dhruva K. Mishra, Yanyuan Wu, Marianna Sarkissyan, Suren Sarkissyan, Zujian Chen, Xiying Shang, May Ong, David Heber, H. Phillip Koeffler, Jaydutt V. Vadgama&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D plays a role in cancer development and acts through the vitamin D receptor (VDR). Although African-Americans have the lowest levels of serum vitamin D, there is a dearth of information on VDR gene polymorphisms and breast cancer among African-Americans and Hispanics. This study examines whether VDR gene polymorphisms are associated with breast cancer in these cohorts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D level can be high, but little benefit: due to kidney, genes, low Magnesium etc.</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-level-can-be-high-but-little-benefit-due-to-kidney-genes-low-magnesium-etc.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s patients 3X more likely to have a malfunctioning vitamin D receptor gene – 2012</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-patients-3x-more-likely-to-have-a-malfunctioning-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-2012.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-patients-3x-more-likely-to-have-a-malfunctioning-vitamin-d-receptor-gene-2012.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-gene-haplotype-is-associated-with-late-onset-alzheimers-disease">Vitamin D receptor gene haplotype is associated with late-onset Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Tohoku J Exp Med. 2012;228(3):189-96.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gezen-Ak D, Dursun E, Bilgiç B, Hanağasi H, Ertan T, Gürvit H, Emre M, Eker E, Ulutin T, Uysal O, Yilmazer S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medical Biology, Cerrahpasa Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D(3) is a neurosteroid that mediates its effects via the vitamin D receptor (VDR). The VDR gene is located on chromosome 12q13 and consists of 9 exons. VDR contains the DNA-binding site encoded by exons 2 and 3 and the ligand-binding site encoded by exons 4 - 9. Our earlier study showed that the ApaI polymorphic site of the VDR gene is associated with late-onset Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD). Here, we investigated the association between additional polymorphisms of the VDR gene and AD using the same samples. Two single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in intron 8 (BsmI and Tru9I polymorphisms) and one in exon 2 (FokI polymorphism) of the VDR gene were examined in up to 108 AD patients and 115 age-matched controls. Genotypes were determined with polymerase chain reaction (PCR) and restriction fragment length polymorphism (RFLP) methods. Haplotype analysis also included the previously studied polymorphic sites that were recognized by TaqI (in exon 9) and ApaI (in intron 8) restriction enzymes. There was no significant difference between AD patients and controls when their genotypes for BsmI, Tru9I and FokI polymorphic sites were compared. However, the frequency of &amp;ldquo;TaubF&amp;rdquo; haplotype (alleles of TaqI, ApaI, Tru9I, BsmI and FokI, respectively), which was determined by analyzing 5 polymorphisms together, was significantly higher in the AD patient group, suggesting that this haplotype is a risk factor in AD. Our results point out a possible link between AD and certain VDR polymorphisms and indicate that individuals with these polymorphisms might be vulnerable to AD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calcium and vitamin D receptors are important to many health conditions</title><link>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-receptors-are-important-to-many-health-conditions.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/calcium-and-vitamin-d-receptors-are-important-to-many-health-conditions.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calcium-nutrition-and-extracellular-calcium-sensing-relevance-for-the-pathogenesis-of-osteoporosis-cancer-and-cardiovascular-diseases">Calcium Nutrition and Extracellular Calcium Sensing: Relevance for the Pathogenesis of Osteoporosis, Cancer and Cardiovascular Diseases&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2013, 5, 302-327; doi:10.3390/nu5010302&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meinrad Peterlik &lt;a href="mailto:meinrad.peterlik@meduniwien.ac.at">meinrad.peterlik@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a>, Enikoe Kallay and Heide S. Cross&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Pathophysiology, Medical University of Vienna, Waehringer Guertel 18-20, A-1090 Vienna, Austria; E-Mails: &lt;a href="mailto:enikoe.kallay@meduniwien.ac.at">enikoe.kallay@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a> (E.K.); &lt;a href="mailto:heide.cross@meduniwien.ac.at">heide.cross@meduniwien.ac.at&lt;/a> (H.S.C.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Received: 30 October 2012; in revised form: 10 January 2013 / Accepted: 11 January 2013 / Published: 22 January 2013&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF, including all figures and tables, is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Receptor genes bb and BB and Osteoporosis, esp. for blacks – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-genes-bb-and-bb-and-osteoporosis-esp-for-blacks-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-genes-bb-and-bb-and-osteoporosis-esp-for-blacks-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-bsmi-polymorphism-and-osteoporosis-risk-a-meta-analysis-from-26-studies">Vitamin D Receptor BsmI Polymorphism and Osteoporosis Risk: A Meta-Analysis from 26 Studies&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Genetic Testing and Molecular Biomarkers – Nov 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rui-Fen Sun,2,* Qun-Hui Li,1 Da-Xing Wang,1 Feng Zhao,1 Jun-Min Li,1 Qi Pu,1 Zhong-Zi Zhang,1 Yan Jin,1 Bai-Lian Liu,1 and Ying Xiong1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Orthopedics, Kunming Medical University, National Clinical Key Specialty, Yanan Hospital, Kunming, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Central Laboratory, Yunnan University of Chinese Traditional Medicine, Kunming, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D levels are strongly associated with genes: overview of twin studies</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-are-strongly-associated-with-genes-overview-of-twin-studies.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-levels-are-strongly-associated-with-genes-overview-of-twin-studies.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breast Cancer incidence change by 40 percent with vitamin D receptor genes</title><link>/posts/breast-cancer-incidence-change-by-40-percent-with-vitamin-d-receptor-genes.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/breast-cancer-incidence-change-by-40-percent-with-vitamin-d-receptor-genes.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-gene-haplotypes-and-polymorphisms-and-risk-of-breast-cancer-a-nested-casecontrol-study">Vitamin D Receptor Gene Haplotypes and Polymorphisms and Risk of Breast Cancer: A Nested Case–Control Study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev; 21(10); 1856–67. ©2012 AACR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lawrence S. Engel 1, Irene Orlow 3, Camelia S. Sima 3, Jaya Satagopan 3, Urvi Mujumdar 3, Pampa Roy 3, Sarah Yoo 3, Dale P. Sandler 2, and Michael C. Alavanja 4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Epidemiology, Gillings School of Global Public Health, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2X more Thyroid Cancer malignancy if less than 15 ng of vitamin D</title><link>/posts/2x-more-thyroid-cancer-malignancy-if-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2x-more-thyroid-cancer-malignancy-if-less-than-15-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-potentially-modifiable-risk-factor-for-thyroid-cancer">Vitamin d deficiency as a potentially modifiable risk factor for thyroid cancer.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-receptor-and-medullary-thyroid-cancer---july-2016">Vitamin D Receptor and medullary thyroid cancer - July 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2000-studies-contain-thyroid-cancer-and-vitamin-d-receptor">2,000+ studies contain &amp;ldquo;Thyroid Cancer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;vitamin D Receptor&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-as-a-potentially-modifiable-risk-factor-for-thyroid-cancer">Vitamin d deficiency as a potentially modifiable risk factor for thyroid cancer.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2012 Jun 1;41(3):160-3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roskies M, Dolev Y, Caglar D, Hier MP, Mlynarek A, Majdan A, Payne RJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:Vitamin D, classically involved in calcium homeostasis, has garnered recent interest for its potential role in cancer prevention and therapy. Although few risk factors have been established in the development of well-differentiated thyroid carcinoma, some would argue that no clear modifiable risk factor exists. Our study is one of the first to explore the relationship between vitamin D deficiency and thyroid cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hodgkin’s lymphoma and Vitamin D Receptor</title><link>/posts/hodgkins-lymphoma-and-vitamin-d-receptor.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hodgkins-lymphoma-and-vitamin-d-receptor.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d3-receptor-is-highly-expressed-in-hodgkins-lymphoma">Vitamin D3 receptor is highly expressed in Hodgkin’s lymphoma.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Christoph Renne, Alexander Benz and Martin L Hansmann&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMC Cancer 2012, 12:215 doi:10.1186/1471-2407-12-215; Published: 6 June 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hodkin’s lymphoma is one of the most frequent lymphoma in western world. Despite an overall good prognosis some patients suffer relapsing tumors which are difficult to cure. Over a long period Vitamin D has been shown to be a potential treatment for cancer. Vitamin D acts via the vitamin D receptor, a nuclear receptor, acting as an inducible transcription factor. We aimed to investigate the expression of vitamin D receptor as potential therapeutic target structure in Hodgkin’s lymphoma as well as in non Hodgkin’s lymphoma.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hours of sun per week decreased probability of NH lymphoma by 32 percent</title><link>/posts/hours-of-sun-per-week-decreased-probability-of-nh-lymphoma-by-32-percent.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hours-of-sun-per-week-decreased-probability-of-nh-lymphoma-by-32-percent.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="early-life-sun-exposure-vitamin-d-related-gene-variants-and-risk-of-non-hodgkin-lymphoma">Early life sun exposure, vitamin D-related gene variants, and risk of non-Hodgkin lymphoma.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2012 Apr 28.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kelly JL, Drake MT, Fredericksen ZS, Asmann YW, Liebow M, Shanafelt TD, Feldman AL, Ansell SM, Macon WR, Herr MM, Wang AH, Nowakowski GS, Call TG, Habermann TM, Slager SL, Witzig TE, Cerhan JR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Rochester, 601 Elmwood Avenue, Box 704, Rochester, NY, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/early-life-sun-exposure-vitamin-d-related-gene-variants-and-risk-of-non-hodgkin-lymphoma.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10 percent of colon cancer linked to Vitamin D Receptor – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/10-percent-of-colon-cancer-linked-to-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/10-percent-of-colon-cancer-linked-to-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-and-colorectal-cancer-risk-a-systematic-meta-analysis">Vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms and colorectal cancer risk: A systematic meta-analysis.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>World J Gastroenterol. 2012 Apr 14;18(14):1672-9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bai YH, Lu H, Hong D, Lin CC, Yu Z, Chen BC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yong-Heng Bai, Dan Hong, Cheng-Cheng Lin, Bi-Cheng Chen, Wenzhou Key Laboratory of Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical College, Wenzhou 325000, Zhejiang Province, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the relationship between polymorphisms present in the vitamin D receptor (VDR) gene and colorectal cancer risk, a systematic meta-analysis of population-based studies was performed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alzheimer’s patients are genetically 70 percent more likely to be vitamin D in-efficient</title><link>/posts/alzheimers-patients-are-genetically-70-percent-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-in-efficient.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/alzheimers-patients-are-genetically-70-percent-more-likely-to-be-vitamin-d-in-efficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="so-people-with-that-gene-need-more-vitamin-d-than-others-who-do-not-have-the-gene">So, people with that gene need more vitamin D than others who do not have the gene.&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-receptor-and-alzheimers-disease-a-genetic-and-functional-study">Vitamin D receptor and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease: a genetic and functional study&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Neurobiology of Aging, Available online 3 February 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liyong Wanga, #, Kenju Haraa, d, #, Jessica M. Van Baaren a, Justin C. Price a, Gary W. Beecham a,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paul J. Gallins a, Patrice L. Whitehead a, Gaofeng Wang a, Chunrong Lu a, Michael A. Slifer a,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D receptor activation and Chronic Kidney Disease</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-activation-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-activation-and-chronic-kidney-disease.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Resveratrol gets vitamin D to cells even if poor vitamin D receptor</title><link>/posts/resveratrol-gets-vitamin-d-to-cells-even-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/resveratrol-gets-vitamin-d-to-cells-even-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-vitamindwiki">See VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-receptor-gene-ways-to-activate-it-calcitriol-benefits---nov-2018">Vitamin D Receptor Gene: Ways to Activate it, Calcitriol, Benefits - Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biological-effects-of-combined-resveratrol-and-vitamin-d3-on-ovarian-tissue---sept-2017">Biological effects of combined resveratrol and vitamin D3 on ovarian tissue - Sept 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#resveratrol-potentiated-meolxicam-to-treat-knee-osteoartiritis---rct-sept-2018-vdr-suspected-by-vitamindwiki">Resveratrol potentiated meolxicam to treat knee Osteoartiritis - RCT Sept 2018 (VDR suspected by VitaminDWiki)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#resveratrol-and-vitamin-d-significant-potential-interpretative-problems-arising-from-their-mutual-processes-interactions-and-effects---2011">Resveratrol and vitamin D: Significant potential interpretative problems arising from their mutual processes, interactions and effects - 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#resveratrol-potentiates-vitamin-d-and-nuclear-receptor-signaling---june-2015">Resveratrol potentiates vitamin D and nuclear receptor signaling - June 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#resveratrol-increases-bone-density-in-diabetics---rct-sept-2018-receptor-not-mentioned">Resveratrol increases bone density in Diabetics - RCT Sept 2018 (receptor not mentioned)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-role-of-resveratrol-in-cancer-therapy---dec-2017">The Role of Resveratrol in Cancer Therapy - Dec 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#resveratrol-and-cardiovascular-diseases---may-2016">Resveratrol and Cardiovascular Diseases - May 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#anticancer-molecular-mechanisms-of-resveratrol---april-2016">Anticancer Molecular Mechanisms of Resveratrol - April 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-resveratrol-prevent-cognitive-decline-in-mice---feb-2017">Vitamin D and resveratrol prevent Cognitive Decline (in mice) - Feb 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#resveratrol--vitamin-d-capsules-on-amazon">Resveratrol + Vitamin D capsules on Amazon&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#resveratrol--vitamin-d-greatly-reduce-area-of-muscle-damage-after-heart-attack---2016">Resveratrol + Vitamin D greatly reduce area of muscle damage after heart attack - 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-vitamindwiki">See VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/resveratol-helps-vitamin-d-bind-to-cells" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Resveratol helps vitamin D bind to cells">Resveratol helps vitamin D bind to cells&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>