<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fortification With Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</title><link>//localhost:1313/categories/fortification-with-vitamin-d.html</link><description>Recent content in Fortification With Vitamin D on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/fortification-with-vitamin-d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Water-soluble Vitamin D powder developed (again)</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/water-soluble-vitamin-d-powder-developed-again.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/water-soluble-vitamin-d-powder-developed-again.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#development-of-a-water-soluble-vitamin-d-drink-for-enhanced-absorption-and-serum-levels">Development of a water-soluble Vitamin D drink for enhanced absorption and serum levels&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="development-of-a-water-soluble-vitamin-d-drink-for-enhanced-absorption-and-serum-levels">Development of a water-soluble Vitamin D drink for enhanced absorption and serum levels&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Proceedings of the Nutrition Society&amp;gt;Volume 83 Issue OCE1: 47th Annual Scientific Meeting– abstract only&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Z. Liu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency have been found in general population but especially in women of childbearing age. Although Vitamin D can be obtained from food source (few naturally) and produced from skin sunlight exposure, it can come from a reliable source via supplementation. Supplementing 15 µg daily could meet the recommended dietary allowance for 19 years and older and 20 µg for 70 years older. Daily supplementation greater than 100 µg is not recommended. Unlike water-soluble vitamins B and C, Vitamins A, D, E, and K are fat-soluble. This property of Vitamin D affects not only the delivery of it in drink but also absorption at the small intestine and bioavailability (i.e., serum level). This study focused on enhancing the solubility of vitamin D using a novel botanical solubilizer. Using rubusoside (RUB), isolated from stevia and other plants, Vitamin D3 (cholecalciferol; VD3) was experimented for solubility enhancement. VD3 was processed with RUB to form the VD3-RUB structure in powder form. Solubility of this powder in physiologic solutions of water, gastric or intestinal fluid, stability over time, and dilutability for achieving desired supplementation levels were examined. The VD3-RUB complex structure in water solution was characterised for particle size and shape using dynamic light scattering techniques. VD3 in water solution after filtration was quantified on HPLC. VD3 was practically insoluble in water. However, in the presence of 10% w/v RUB as the botanical solubilizer, &lt;strong>VD3 became soluble in water to a concentration of 4,500 µg/mL.&lt;/strong> This water-soluble concentrate appeared clear and was freely dilutable to a drink containing amounts of VD3 ranging from 15 µg to 100 µg. Particle size analysis indicated the presence of approximately 4 nm spherical particles. HPLC analysis of the water solution detected RUB and VD3. These drinks were stable and remained clear and transparent for at least eight weeks. A packet of water-soluble Vitamin D3 powder was also developed for addition to a glass of water in the amount of 15 µg VD3. The packet, similar to the instant coffee powder, produced an instant Vitamin D drink containing the recommended dietary allowance of 15 µg. The water-soluble VD3 powder was also dissolvable in simulated gastric fluid and intestinal fluid, and stable for at least two hours. This solubility enhancement could aid in absorption and improve oral bioavailability, seen in the work with oily ceramides(1) and insoluble curcumin(2). It is especially advantageous for making drinks as the solubilizer is generally regarded as safe by the US FDA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stillbirth rates dropped from 4.1% to 2.8% as Finland increased Vitamin D fortification</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/stillbirth-rates-dropped-from-41-percent-to-28-percent-as-finland-increased-vitamin-d-fortification.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/stillbirth-rates-dropped-from-41-percent-to-28-percent-as-finland-increased-vitamin-d-fortification.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-stillbirth--op-no-20">VITAMIN D AND STILLBIRTH -OP No. 20&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-stillbirth--op-no-20">VITAMIN D AND STILLBIRTH -OP No. 20&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Anticancer Research May 2024, 44 (5) 2249-2268; DOI: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.21873/anticanres.17034">https://doi.org/10.21873/anticanres.17034&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Presented at Proceedings of the Joint International Symposia: Vitamin D in Prevention and Therapy and Biologic Effects of Light May 04-06, 2022 Schlossberg Hotel, Homburg/Saar, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pelle G. Lindqvist Karolinska Institute, Stockholm, Sweden&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background/Aim: Two retrospective studies of prospective cohorts showed doubled odds of birth asphyxia among women with low plasma vitamin D levels and one reported a 4-fold increase in the odds of stillbirth. It was not known if this was caused by low sun exposure or by vitamin D per se.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Canada will have doubled Vitamin D content of milk and margarine by 2026</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/canada-will-have-doubled-vitamin-d-content-of-milk-and-margarine-by-2026.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/canada-will-have-doubled-vitamin-d-content-of-milk-and-margarine-by-2026.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#in-response-to-how-does-canadas-new-vitamin-d-fortification-policy-affect-the-high-prevalence-of-inadequate-intake-of-the-vitamin---feb-2024">In response to: How does Canada&amp;rsquo;s new vitamin D fortification policy affect the high prevalence of inadequate intake of the vitamin? - Feb 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="in-response-to-how-does-canadas-new-vitamin-d-fortification-policy-affect-the-high-prevalence-of-inadequate-intake-of-the-vitamin---feb-2024">In response to: How does Canada&amp;rsquo;s new vitamin D fortification policy affect the high prevalence of inadequate intake of the vitamin? - Feb 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/canada-fortification.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki &lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h5 id="mistake-1-forcing-all-of-the-products-to-be-fortified---encouraging-rather-than-forcing-is-far-batter">Mistake #1: Forcing all of the products to be fortified - encouraging rather than forcing is far batter&lt;/h5>
&lt;h5 id="mistake-2-fortification-independent-of-fat-content-bioavailability-of-d-from-low-fat--milk-is-about-a-hrefpostsskim-fat-milk-provides-3-percent-less-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-postcategory-does-not-exist-yet-skim-fat-milk-provides-3-less-vitamin-d--may-201625x-lessa-">Mistake #2: Fortification independent of fat content (bioavailability of D from low-fat milk is about &lt;a href="//localhost:1313/posts/skim-fat-milk-provides-3-percent-less-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Skim fat milk provides 3% less vitamin D – May 2016">2.5X less&lt;/a> )&lt;/h5>
&lt;h5 id="mistake-3-failed-to-fortify-for-people-who-do-not-consume-milk-products-44-or-people-are-lactose-intolerant">Mistake #3: Failed to fortify for people who do not consume milk products (44% or people are lactose intolerant)&lt;/h5></description></item><item><title>Biofortification with Vitamin D - several studies</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/biofortification-with-vitamin-d-several-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/biofortification-with-vitamin-d-several-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-future-is-bright-biofortification-of-common-foods-can-improve-vitamin-d-status---july-2023">The future is bright: Biofortification of common foods can improve vitamin D status - July 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biofortifications-contribution-to-mitigating-micronutrient-deficiencies-behind-paywall-jan-2024">Biofortification&amp;rsquo;s contribution to mitigating micronutrient deficiencies (behind paywall) Jan 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biofortified-tomatoes-provide-a-new-route-to-vitamin-d-sufficiency----may-2022">Biofortified tomatoes provide a new route to vitamin D sufficiency - May 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#biofortification-of-meat-with-vitamin-d---jan-2019">Biofortification of meat with vitamin D - Jan 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#improving-vitamin-d-content-in-pork-meat-by-uvb-biofortification---may-2023">Improving vitamin D content in pork meat by UVB biofortification - May 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-future-is-bright-biofortification-of-common-foods-can-improve-vitamin-d-status---july-2023">The future is bright: Biofortification of common foods can improve vitamin D status - July 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition Vol 63, 2023 - Issue 4 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10408398.2021.1950609">https://doi.org/10.1080/10408398.2021.1950609&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D has successfully fortified milk products, bread, orange juice, etc. – meta-analysis</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-has-successfully-fortified-milk-products-bread-orange-juice-etc-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/vitamin-d-has-successfully-fortified-milk-products-bread-orange-juice-etc-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#strategic-food-vehicles-for-vitamin-d-fortification-and-effects-on-vitamin-d-status-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials">Strategic food vehicles for vitamin D fortification and effects on vitamin D status: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="strategic-food-vehicles-for-vitamin-d-fortification-and-effects-on-vitamin-d-status-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-randomized-controlled-trials">Strategic food vehicles for vitamin D fortification and effects on vitamin D status: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Steroid Biochemistry and Molecular Biology &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsbmb&lt;/a>. &lt;strong>2023&lt;/strong> .106448&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been growing interest in the potential of vitamin D food fortification in Europe as a means of addressing low vitamin D status. The WHO-FAO suggest that choosing a suitable food vehicle and ensuring the combination of the food vehicle and the fortificant will be efficacious and effective are of key importance to a successful food fortification program. Our key objective was to conduct a systematic review and meta-analysis to investigate the effect of various animal- and plant-based food vehicles fortified with vitamin D (as D3 or D2) on circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> concentrations. A list of prioritized food vehicles was established and we searched PubMed, Embase, Scopus and Web of Science for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) which used these vehicles individually, and which met prespecified criteria.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>