<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ADHD on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/adhd.html</link><description>Recent content in ADHD on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/adhd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ADHD and Vitamin D Deficiency</title><link>/posts/adhd-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adhd-and-vitamin-d-deficiency.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="adhd-reduced-by-span-stylecolor00fomega-3-spanin-trials-either-using-high-doses-or-over-the-long-term--july2016">ADHD reduced by &lt;span style="color:#00F;">Omega-3 &lt;/span>in trials either using high doses or over the long term – July 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Critical appraisal of omega-3 fatty acids in attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder treatment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2016 Jul 26;12:1869-82. Doi 10.2147/NDT.S68652. eCollection 2016.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Königs A1, Kiliaan AJ1.Department of Anatomy, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition &amp;amp; Behaviour, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, the Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d1bk1kqxc0sym.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/adhd-t1.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) is a common neurodevelopmental disorder. The classical treatment of ADHD, where stimulant medication is used, has revealed severe side effects and intolerance. Consequently, the demand to search for alternative treatment has increased rapidly. When comparing levels of omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (ω-3 PUFAs) in ADHD patients with those in age-matching controls, lower levels are found in ADHD patients&amp;rsquo; blood. ω-3 PUFAs are essential nutrients and necessary for proper brain function and development. Additionally, there are strong indications that ω-3 PUFA supplements could have beneficial effects on ADHD. However, the results of ω-3 PUFA supplementation studies show high variability. Therefore, we reviewed recent studies published between 2000 and 2015 to identify effective treatment combinations, the quality of design, and the safety and tolerability of ω-3-containing food supplements. We searched the databases MEDLINE, PubMed, and Web of Science with keywords such as &amp;ldquo;ADHD&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ω-3/6 PUFA&amp;rdquo; and identified 25 studies that met the inclusion and exclusion criteria.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>