<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ADHD on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/adhd.html</link><description>Recent content in ADHD on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/adhd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pesticides increase risk of Cancers, Alz, ALS, Asthma, ADHD, etc. (all related to low vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/pesticides-increase-risk-of-cancers-alz-als-asthma-adhd-etc-all-related-to-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pesticides-increase-risk-of-cancers-alz-als-asthma-adhd-etc-all-related-to-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pesticides-an-update-of-human-exposure-and-toxicity">Pesticides: an update of human exposure and toxicity.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Arch Toxicol. 2016 Oct 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mostafalou S1, Abdollahi M2,3,4. (IRAN)&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Possible Mechanisms&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pesticides reduce Vitamin D, which increase the rate of each disease&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pesticides increase the rate of each disease, and Vitamin D is consumed in dealing with the inflammation, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/risk-of-severe-adhd-increased-2x-if-multiple-pesticides-in-urine-while-pregnant" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This post/category does not exist yet: Risk of severe ADHD increased 2X if multiple pesticides in urine while pregnant – June 2019">Risk of severe ADHD increased 2X if multiple pesticides in urine while pregnant – June 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ADHD 2 times more likely if poor Omega-6 to Omega-3 ratio – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/adhd-2-times-more-likely-if-poor-omega-6-to-omega-3-ratio-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adhd-2-times-more-likely-if-poor-omega-6-to-omega-3-ratio-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>ADHD decreased by 11% for each 10 ng increase in vitamin D in early pregnancy</title><link>/posts/adhd-decreased-by-11-percent-for-each-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-in-early-pregnancy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adhd-decreased-by-11-percent-for-each-10-ng-increase-in-vitamin-d-in-early-pregnancy.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-in-pregnancy-and-attention-deficit-hyperactivity-disorder-like-symptoms-in-childhood">Vitamin D in Pregnancy and Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder-like Symptoms in Childhood.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Epidemiology. 2015 Apr 10. &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morales E1, Julvez J, Torrent M, Ballester F, Rodríguez-Bernal CL, Andiarena A, Vegas O, Castilla AM, Rodriguez-Dehli C, Tardón A, Sunyer J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1From the aCentre for Research in Environmental Epidemiology (CREAL), Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain; bVirgen de la Arrixaca Universtiy Hospital, IMIB-Arrixaca Research Institute, Murcia, Spain; cCIBER Epidemiología y Salud Pública (CIBERESP), Madrid, Spain; dHospital del Mar Medical Research Institute (IMIM), Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain; eUniversitat Pompeu Fabra (UPF), Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain; fIB-SALUT, Area de Salut de Menorca, Balearic Islands, Spain; gUniversity of Valencia, Valencia, Spain; hCenter for Public Health Research (CSISP-FISABIO), Valencia, Spain; iDepartment of Basic Psychological Processes and Their Development, Basque Country University UPV/EHU, San Sebastian, Spain; jBiodonostia Institute, San Sebastian, Gipuzkoa, Spain; kPublic Health Laboratory, Basque Government, Bilbao, Spain; lHospital San Agustín, Avilés, Asturias, Spain; and mUniversity of Oviedo, Asturias, Spain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ADHD in Arab countries – vitamin D is the only changeable risk factor – review</title><link>/posts/adhd-in-arab-countries-vitamin-d-is-the-only-changeable-risk-factor-review.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/adhd-in-arab-countries-vitamin-d-is-the-only-changeable-risk-factor-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="systematic-review-of-the-epidemiology-of-attention-deficit-hyperactivity-disorder-in-arab-countries">Systematic review of the epidemiology of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder in Arab countries.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Neurosciences (Riyadh). 2015 Apr;20(2):137-144. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.17712/nsj.2015.2.20140678.">doi: 10.17712/nsj.2015.2.20140678.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alhraiwil NJ1, Ali A, Househ MS, Al-Shehri AM, El-Metwally AA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1College of Public Health and Health Informatics, King Saud Bin Abdulaziz University for Health Sciences, Riyadh, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To assess the epidemiology of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) in Arab countries, and identify gaps for future research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We searched PubMed from July 1978 to July 2014 and reviewed local journals with cross-referencing. The keywords we used were ADHD, diagnosis, prevalence, incidence, factor, diagnosis, rate, risk, and each of the names of the 22 Arab countries (Jordan, Egypt, Lebanon, Saudi Arabia, and so on). Studies were eligible for inclusion if they investigated the epidemiology of ADHD in any Arab country, and were published in English. The search was conducted from 2nd to 5th August 2014 in King Saud Bin Abdulaziz University for Health Sciences, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deficiencies of Vitamin D, Iron, Magnesium, and Zinc all associated with ADHD</title><link>/posts/deficiencies-of-vitamin-d-iron-magnesium-and-zinc-all-associated-with-adhd.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/deficiencies-of-vitamin-d-iron-magnesium-and-zinc-all-associated-with-adhd.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Restless Legs Syndrome and ADHD strongly associated (no mention of vitamin D) – 2005</title><link>/posts/restless-legs-syndrome-and-adhd-strongly-associated-no-mention-of-vitamin-d-2005.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/restless-legs-syndrome-and-adhd-strongly-associated-no-mention-of-vitamin-d-2005.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="restless-legs-syndrome-and-attention-deficithyperactivity-disorder-a-review-of-the-literature">Restless legs syndrome and attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder: a review of the literature.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Sleep. 2005 Aug 1;28(8):1007-13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cortese S1, Konofal E, Lecendreux M, Arnulf I, Mouren MC, Darra F, Dalla Bernardina B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>STUDY OBJECTIVE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To review evidence on the association between restless legs syndrome (RLS) and attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), to discuss the hypothetical mechanisms underlying this association, and to consider the potential interest for common pharmacologic treatments of RLS and ADHD when co-occurring.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>