<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Skin on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/tags/skin.html</link><description>Recent content in Skin on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/skin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Atopic Dermatitus more likely if e-cigarette, passive smoke while pregnant or Caesarean</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitus-more-likely-if-e-cigarette-passive-smoke-while-pregnant-or-caesarean.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitus-more-likely-if-e-cigarette-passive-smoke-while-pregnant-or-caesarean.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#e-cigarette-use-increased-risk-of-atopic-dermatitis-risk-by-24---may-2024">E-Cigarette use increased risk of Atopic Dermatitis Risk by 24% - May 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#passive-smoking-while-pregnant-increased-atopic-dermatitis-risk-in-children-by-52---march-2024">Passive smoking while pregnant increased Atopic Dermatitis Risk in Children by 52% - March 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="e-cigarette-use-increased-risk-of-atopic-dermatitis-risk-by-24---may-2024">E-Cigarette use increased risk of Atopic Dermatitis Risk by 24% - May 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://ma1.mdedge.com/pediatrics/article/269347/dermatology/parental-e-cigarette-use-linked-atopic-dermatitis-risk?ecd=WNL_EVE_240530_mdedge">MDEdge&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> PDF behind paywall&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="passive-smoking-while-pregnant-increased-atopic-dermatitis-risk-in-children-by-52---march-2024">Passive smoking while pregnant increased Atopic Dermatitis Risk in Children by 52% - March 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Maternal tobacco exposure during pregnancy and atopic dermatitis in offspring: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High Dose Vitamin D reduces skin problems during Cancer Treatment</title><link>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-d-reduces-skin-problems-during-cancer-treatment.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-dose-vitamin-d-reduces-skin-problems-during-cancer-treatment.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#high-dose-oral-vitamin-d-an-emerging-therapeutic-for-skin-toxicities-associated-with-cancer-treatment">High Dose Oral Vitamin D: an Emerging Therapeutic for Skin Toxicities Associated with Cancer Treatment&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#topical-vitamin-d-is-far-better-than-oral-100x-higher-concentration-for-most-skin-problems">Topical Vitamin D is far better than oral (&amp;gt;100X higher concentration) for most skin problems&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="high-dose-oral-vitamin-d-an-emerging-therapeutic-for-skin-toxicities-associated-with-cancer-treatment">High Dose Oral Vitamin D: an Emerging Therapeutic for Skin Toxicities Associated with Cancer Treatment&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology – May 1, 2024 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaad.2024.05.027">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaad.2024.05.027&lt;/a> &lt;strong>PDF behind paywall&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choi, Stephanie; Iriarte, Christopher&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="topical-vitamin-d-is-far-better-than-oral-100x-higher-concentration-for-most-skin-problems">Topical Vitamin D is far better than oral (&amp;gt;100X higher concentration) for most skin problems&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/topical-vitamin-d-provides-more-benefits-than-oral-sometimes-many-studies">Topical Vitamin D provides more benefits than oral sometimes - many studies&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nails treated by Vitamins (D etc.)</title><link>/posts/nails-treated-by-vitamins-d-etc.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nails-treated-by-vitamins-d-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamins-for-the-management-of-nail-disease-a-literature-review">Vitamins for the Management of Nail Disease: A Literature Review&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#tea-tree-oil-kills-nail-fungus">Tea Tree Oil kills nail fungus&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamins-for-the-management-of-nail-disease-a-literature-review">Vitamins for the Management of Nail Disease: A Literature Review&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Skin Appendage Disord (2024) 10 (2): 104–122. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1159/000534972">https://doi.org/10.1159/000534972&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kaya L. Curtis; Shari R. Lipner&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamins have gained popularity among physicians and patients for purported benefits to hair, skin, and nail health. Safe and efficacious therapies for nail disorders, many of which are chronic conditions, are needed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accutane for acne associated with birth defects, abortions</title><link>/posts/accutane-for-acne-associated-with-birth-defects-abortions.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/accutane-for-acne-associated-with-birth-defects-abortions.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#surge-in-usage-of-acne-medication-linked-to-birth-defects-prompts-in-depth-analysis-of-pregnancy-outcomes">Surge in Usage of Acne Medication Linked to Birth Defects Prompts In-Depth Analysis of Pregnancy Outcomes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#2-studies-note-that-acne-reduces-vitamin-d-a-lot-and-accutane-treatment-increases-vitamin-d-a-bit">2 studies note that Acne reduces Vitamin D a lot and Accutane treatment increases Vitamin D a bit&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="surge-in-usage-of-acne-medication-linked-to-birth-defects-prompts-in-depth-analysis-of-pregnancy-outcomes">Surge in Usage of Acne Medication Linked to Birth Defects Prompts In-Depth Analysis of Pregnancy Outcomes&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.trialsitenews.com/a/surge-in-usage-of-acne-medication-linked-to-birth-defects-prompts-in-depth-analysis-of-pregnancy-outcomes-d5d0e877">TrialSiteNews&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> Reporting on:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Use of isotretinoin among girls and women of childbearing age and occurrence of isotretinoin-exposed pregnancies in Germany: A population-based study&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic Dermatitis not helped by small weekly doses of Vitamin D (8K 2y-6y.16K 12y-18y) – RCT</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-not-helped-by-small-weekly-doses-of-vitamin-d-8k-2y-6y16k-12y-18y-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-not-helped-by-small-weekly-doses-of-vitamin-d-8k-2y-6y16k-12y-18y-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#effect-of-weekly-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-the-severity-of-atopic-dermatitis-and-type-2-immunity-biomarkers-in-children-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Effect of weekly vitamin D supplementation on the severity of atopic dermatitis and type 2 immunity biomarkers in children: A randomized controlled trial&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="effect-of-weekly-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-the-severity-of-atopic-dermatitis-and-type-2-immunity-biomarkers-in-children-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Effect of weekly vitamin D supplementation on the severity of atopic dermatitis and type 2 immunity biomarkers in children: A randomized controlled trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol . 2024 Mar 14. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/jdv.19959">doi: 10.1111/jdv.19959&lt;/a> PDF behind paywall&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Vitamin D (VD) deficiency is common among patients with atopic dermatitis (AD) and often associated with severity. However, randomized trials of VD supplementation in AD have had equivocal results, and there is little information regarding the effect of VD supplementation on type 2 immunity in AD patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wounds and pregnancy masks treated by topical Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/wounds-and-pregnancy-masks-treated-by-topical-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wounds-and-pregnancy-masks-treated-by-topical-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-wound-healing-assessing-skin-barrier-function-and-implications-for-chloasma-treatment">Vitamin D and wound healing: Assessing skin barrier function and implications for chloasma treatment&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#asked-perplexity-ai-about-chloasma---jan-2024">Asked Perplexity AI about Chloasma - Jan 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#example-pregnancy-mask-images">Example pregnancy mask images&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-wound-healing-assessing-skin-barrier-function-and-implications-for-chloasma-treatment">Vitamin D and wound healing: Assessing skin barrier function and implications for chloasma treatment&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Int Wound J 2024 Jan;21(1):e14541. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/iwj.14541.">doi: 10.1111/iwj.14541.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Qiong Chen 1, Lin Liu 2, Yi Zhang 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chloasma, which is distinguished by irregularities in the pigmentation of skin, poses substantial challenge in the field of dermatology. The regulatory influence of vitamin D on the functions of skin cells implies that it may have the capacity to effectively treat chloasma and promote wound healing. To assess the efficacy of vitamin D in chloasma treatment and its impact on the function of skin barrier during the process of wound healing. The research spanned from April 2022 to September 2023, in Shanghai, China, examined 480 individuals who had been diagnosed with chloasma. A double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial was utilized to evaluate effectiveness of topical vitamin D3 in treatment of chloasma. Concurrently, randomized control trial investigated the effects of ingested vitamin D3 supplements on the process of wound healing. Transepidermal water loss (TEWL), chloasma severity score changes, wound size reduction and skin hydration levels were critical performance indicators. Statistically, the severity scores of chloasma decreased significantly in the vitamin D treatment group at 3 and 6 months compared with the placebo (p &amp;lt; 0.05). The Vitamin D group exhibited superior wound healing outcomes, including more substantial reduction in lesion size and enhanced skin barrier function, as evidenced by increased skin hydration and decreased TEWL (p &amp;lt; 0.05). Vitamin D substantially mitigated the severity of chloasma and has beneficial effect on wound healing and integrity of the skin barrier. Based on the results obtained, vitamin D exhibited promise as a therapeutic intervention in the field of dermatology, specifically in treatment of chloasma and promotion of wound recovery.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin Health improved by Vitamin D and 12 other supplements</title><link>/posts/skin-health-improved-by-vitamin-d-and-12-other-supplements.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-health-improved-by-vitamin-d-and-12-other-supplements.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#nutritional-supplements-for-skin-health-a-review-of-what-should-be-chosen-and-why">Nutritional Supplements for Skin Health-A Review of What Should Be Chosen and Why&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="nutritional-supplements-for-skin-health-a-review-of-what-should-be-chosen-and-why">Nutritional Supplements for Skin Health-A Review of What Should Be Chosen and Why&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Medicina (Kaunas) 2023 Dec 29;60(1):68. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina60010068.">doi: 10.3390/medicina60010068.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jacek Januszewski 1, Alicja Forma 2, Julita Zembala 3, Michał Flieger 2, Magdalena Tyczyńska 1, James Curtis Dring 1, Iga Dudek 2, Kamila Świątek 1, Jacek Baj 1&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/png/skin-supplements.png" alt="image" width="250">
&lt;p>Supplementation of micronutrients is considered to be crucial in the reinforcement of the skin&amp;rsquo;s barrier. In this paper, 14 nutritional compounds commonly used in food or pharmaceutic industries were analyzed in terms of influencing skin conditions. The major objective of this paper was to provide a narrative review of the available literature regarding several chosen compounds that are currently widely recommended as supplements that aim to maintain proper and healthy skin conditions. We conducted a review of the literature from PubMed, Scopus, and Web of Science until September 2023 without any other restrictions regarding the year of the publication. Ultimately, we reviewed 238 articles, including them in this review. Each of the reviewed compounds, including vitamin A, vitamin C, vitamin D, vitamin E, curcumin, chlorella, Omega-3, biotin,Ppolypodium leucotomos, Simmondsia chinesis, gamma oryzanol, olive leaf extract, spirulina, and astaxanthin, was observed to present some possible effects with promising benefits for a skin condition, i.e., photoprotective radiation. Adding them to the diet or daily routine might have a positive influence on some skin inflammatory diseases such as atopic dermatitis or psoriasis. Further, UV radiation protection facilitated by some supplements and their impact on human cells might be helpful during chemotherapy or in preventing melanoma development. Further research is needed because of the lack of clear consensus regarding the doses of the described compounds that could provide desirable effects on the skin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitiligo (spotty skin) and Vitamin D, UVB - many studies</title><link>/posts/vitiligo-spotty-skin-and-vitamin-d-uvb-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitiligo-spotty-skin-and-vitamin-d-uvb-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#topical-vitamin-d-analogs-patented-help-treat-vitiligo---sep-2023">Topical vitamin D analogs (patented) help treat Vitiligo - Sep 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="topical-vitamin-d-analogs-patented-help-treat-vitiligo---sep-2023">Topical vitamin D analogs (patented) help treat Vitiligo - Sep 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Using a Topical Formulation of Vitamin D for the Treatment of Vitiligo: A Systematic Review&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cells. 2023 Sep 30;12(19):2387. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/cells12192387.">doi: 10.3390/cells12192387.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Khadeejeh Al-Smadi 1, Masood Ali 1, Seyed Ebrahim Alavi 1, Xuping Jin 1 2, Mohammad Imran 1, Vania R Leite-Silva 1 3, Yousuf Mohammed 1 2&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/png/vitiligo.png" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;p>Vitamin D is one significant prohormone substance in human organ systems. It is a steroidal hormone produced in the skin upon exposure to UVB rays. This paper presents a systematic review of the utilization of topical vitamin D, specifically cholecalciferol, calcipotriol, and tacalcitol, in the treatment of vitiligo. It considers the role of vitamin D in stimulating the synthesis of melanin and melanogenesis, which can help with the process of repigmentation. The inclusion of calcipotriol or tacalcitol in Narrowband Ultraviolet Phototherapy (NB-UVB) has shown the potential to enhance therapeutic outcomes for vitiligo. However, their effectiveness in combination with Psoralens Long Wave Ultraviolet Radiation (PUVA) and Monochromatic Excimer Light (MEL) treatment for vitiligo is limited. In contrast, combining topical corticosteroids with vitamin D analogues has demonstrated superior efficacy in treating vitiligo compared to using vitamin D analogues alone, while also providing the added benefit of reducing corticosteroid-related adverse effects. In addition, treating stable vitiligo with topical cholecalciferol and microneedling has shown success. Future studies are needed to ascertain an efficient method of administering vitamin D topically as an anti-vitiligo agent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D benefits your skin in 7 ways</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-benefits-your-skin-in-7-ways.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-benefits-your-skin-in-7-ways.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#by-chrome-generative-ai-aug-2023">By Chrome Generative AI Aug 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dozens-of-vitamin-d-cream-sellers-on-amazon">Dozens of Vitamin D cream sellers on Amazon&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="by-chrome-generative-ai-aug-2023">By Chrome Generative AI Aug 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Anti-inflammatory: Vitamin D can help treat skin conditions like acne, eczema, and psoriasis. &lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Anti-aging: Vitamin D can help prevent skin aging by protecting against damage, reducing puffiness, and minimizing fine lines and wrinkles. &lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Moisturizing: Vitamin D3 can improve skin hydration.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Antioxidant: Vitamin D can help neutralize free radicals, especially those caused by UV radiation. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and the skin</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-the-skin-an-immunologic-and-therapeutic-update">Vitamin D and the skin: an immunologic and therapeutic update&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-the-skin-an-immunologic-and-therapeutic-update">Vitamin D and the skin: an immunologic and therapeutic update&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Egypt Women’s Dermatol Soc 20:69-80 DOI: 10.4103/jewd.jewd_55_22&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Naglaa N. El Mongy, Rana F. Hilal&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Kasr Al Ainy Teaching Hospital, Cairo University, Cairo, Egypt&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Correspondence to Rana F. Hilal, MD, Department of Dermatology, Kasr Al Ainy Teaching Hospital, Cairo University, Al-Saray Street, Kasr Al Ainy, El Manial, Cairo 11956, e-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:rana.hilal@kasralainy.edu.eg">rana.hilal@kasralainy.edu.eg&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review of autoimmune skin diseases and Vitamin D ignores topical form</title><link>/posts/review-of-autoimmune-skin-diseases-and-vitamin-d-ignores-topical-form.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/review-of-autoimmune-skin-diseases-and-vitamin-d-ignores-topical-form.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-role-of-vdvdr-signaling-pathway-in-autoimmune-skin-diseases">The role of VD/VDR signaling pathway in autoimmune skin diseases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="the-role-of-vdvdr-signaling-pathway-in-autoimmune-skin-diseases">The role of VD/VDR signaling pathway in autoimmune skin diseases&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Mini Rev Med Chem . 2022 Nov 24. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2174/1389557523666221124123206">doi: 10.2174/1389557523666221124123206&lt;/a>   PDF is behind a $95 paywall&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yilan Zeng 1 , Shengbo Yang 1 , Dan Wang 1 , Yuanhong Liu 1 , Ziting Tang 1 , Xuemei Li 1 , Xiule Zong 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background: Immune-related cutaneous diseases are a series of disorders, such as&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Photodynamic Therapy (PDT) aided by various forms and types of Vitamin D (1.06 X to 10 X)</title><link>/posts/photodynamic-therapy-pdt-aided-by-various-forms-and-types-of-vitamin-d-106-x-to-10-x.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/photodynamic-therapy-pdt-aided-by-various-forms-and-types-of-vitamin-d-106-x-to-10-x.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-vitamin-d3-supplementation-during-photodynamic-therapy-a-review">Vitamin D and Vitamin D3 Supplementation during Photodynamic Therapy: A Review&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-related-in-vitamindwiki">See related in VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-vitamin-d3-supplementation-during-photodynamic-therapy-a-review">Vitamin D and Vitamin D3 Supplementation during Photodynamic Therapy: A Review&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2022, 14(18), 3805; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/nu14183805">https://doi.org/10.3390/nu14183805&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anna Mazur, Katarzyna Koziorowska, Klaudia Dynarowicz, David Aebisher. Dorota Bartusik-Aebisher&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photodynamic therapy is an unconventional yet increasingly common method of treating dermatological diseases and cancer that is implemented more often in adults than in children. Current clinical uses include treatment of actinic keratosis, superficial basal cell carcinomas, and acne. Despite its high efficiency, photodynamic therapy support supplements have recently been reported in the literature, including calcitriol (1,25-dihydroxycholecalciferol), the active form of vitamin D, and vitamin D3 cholecalciferol.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin Aging and Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/skin-aging-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-aging-and-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also">See also&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also">See also&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Impact of Vitamin D on Skin Aging - Aug 2021 - &lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/skin-aging-rg.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/challenges-in-sun-protection-233-dollar-book">Challenges in Sun Protection - 233 dollar book - Oct 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/skin-damaged-by-sun-helped-by-vitamin-d-supplementation-pilot-study">Skin damaged by sun helped by vitamin D supplementation - pilot study April 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/possible-dna-damage-of-skin-if-vitamin-d-levels-less-than-20-nanograms">Possible DNA damage of skin if vitamin D levels less than 20 nanograms – April 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>VitaminDWiki pages having WOUND or BURN in the title</title><link>/posts/vitamindwiki-pages-having-wound-or-burn-in-the-title.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamindwiki-pages-having-wound-or-burn-in-the-title.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-burns-in-google-scholar-53000-as-of-dec-2021">See also BURNS in Google Scholar (53,000 as of Dec 2021)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/venous-ulcers-healed-4x-faster-with-weekly-50000-iu-vitamin-d-rct">Venous ulcers healed 4X faster with weekly 50,000 IU vitamin D – RCT Oct 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/pressure-ulcers-bed-sores-187-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-less-than-25-ng-2011">Pressure Ulcers (bed sores) 1.87 more likely if vitamin D less than 25 ng – 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/bed-sores-in-icu-25-x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d">Bed sores in ICU 2.5 X more likely if low vitamin D – Aug 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-skin-focus-on-a-complex-relationship">Vitamin D and the skin: Focus on a complex relationship - Nov 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2.4 X fewer burn complications if have more than 20 ng of Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/24-x-fewer-burn-complications-if-have-more-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/24-x-fewer-burn-complications-if-have-more-than-20-ng-of-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-multicenter-study-analyzing-the-association-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-replacement-with-infectious-outcomes-in-patients-with-burn-injuries">A Multicenter Study Analyzing the Association of Vitamin D Deficiency and Replacement with Infectious Outcomes in Patients with Burn Injuries&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Burns &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.burns.2021.10.020">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.burns.2021.10.020&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Katelyn M.Garner a Sarah Zaval ab Kate O Pape cTodd Walroth d Melissa Reger e WendyThomasf Brittany Hoy tef Beatrice Adams g David M.Hill a&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/burns-ulcers-and-wounds-healed-by-vitamin-d-many-studies">Burns, ulcers, and wounds healed by Vitamin D - many studies&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Highlights&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>More than half of patients with thermal injuries have vitamin D deficiency on admission&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Challenges in Sun Protection - 233 dollar book</title><link>/posts/challenges-in-sun-protection-233-dollar-book.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/challenges-in-sun-protection-233-dollar-book.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Skin scars (Keloids) more likely if low vitamin D, poor Vitamin D receptor, or dark skin</title><link>/posts/skin-scars-keloids-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-or-dark-skin.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-scars-keloids-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-or-dark-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#references">References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#unveiling-the-link-the-potential-roles-of-vitamin-d-in-keloid-pathophysiology---feb-2025">Unveiling the Link: The Potential Roles of Vitamin D in Keloid Pathophysiology - Feb 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/burns-ulcers-and-wounds-healed-by-vitamin-d-many-studies">Burns, ulcers, and wounds healed by Vitamin D - many studies&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note: By founder of VitaminDWiki.&lt;br>
Many skin problems are dealt with by topical vitamin D - such as nanoemulsion&lt;br>
Suspect it will help prevent and perhaps treat Keoilds.&lt;br>
Not need injection&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/keloids-raised-scars-uncommon-except-in-blacks.pdf">Download the PDF from VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dear Editor,&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keloid lesions are generally regarded as benign fibro- proliferative skin disorders unique to human beings that are characterized by unremitting inflammation and deposition of fibrous components in the extracellular matrix &lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>. These lesions appear as firm, rubbery, variably pruritic, or tender growths that expand beyond the dimensions of the original injury and rarely regress. Keloids are thought to be age-dependent, occurring chiefly between the first and third decades of life. Both genders are equally afflicted by the keloid lesions. The disease is more common in populations with darker skin complexion, often exhibiting familiar pattern &lt;sup>[2]&lt;/sup>. Notwithstanding the wide array of available therapeutic modalities, the management of keloids still remains enigmatic for physicians. Intralesional steroid injections, surgical excision, topical 5-fluorouracil, cryotherapy, laser therapy, radiotherapy, and silicon occlusive dressing, or any combination thereof, are among the mainstay of keloid treatment &lt;sup>[3]&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many Vitamin D metabolites: some help skin aging, reduce Cytokine storms, but are not tested</title><link>/posts/many-vitamin-d-metabolites-some-help-skin-aging-reduce-cytokine-storms-but-are-not-tested.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-vitamin-d-metabolites-some-help-skin-aging-reduce-cytokine-storms-but-are-not-tested.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-impact-of-vitamin-d-on-skin-aging">The Impact of Vitamin D on Skin Aging&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Review Int J Mol Sci. 2021 Aug 23;22(16):9097. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms22169097.">doi: 10.3390/ijms22169097.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Georgeta Bocheva 1, Radomir M Slominski 2 3, Andrzej T Slominski 2 4 5&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image" width="900">
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F06;">CYP11A1&lt;/span> highlighted&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/metabolites-cyp11a1.jpg" alt="image" width="650">
&lt;p>Figure 1. Noncanonical pathways of vitamin D3 and lumisterol (L3) activation (reprinted from &lt;sup>[61]&lt;/sup> with the permission from Springer). D3, L3, and 7-DHC are substrates for CYP11A1 that produces the corresponding hydroxyderivatives. In the case of L3 and 7-DHC, the side chain can be cleaved by CYP11A1 to produce 7DHP or pL that can be further metabolized by steroidogenic enzymes (ES). In the skin, UVB acting on 5,7-dienes can lead to the production of D3, L3, and T3 derivatives with a full-length side chain and pD, pL, and pT derivatives with a shortened side chain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hard-to-heal Wounds associated with low vitamin D – review</title><link>/posts/hard-to-heal-wounds-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hard-to-heal-wounds-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="correlation-between-vitamin-d-levels-and-hard-to-heal-wounds-a-systematic-review">Correlation between vitamin D levels and hard-to-heal wounds: a systematic review&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Wound Care. 2021 Jun 1;30(Sup6):S4-S10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.12968/jowc.2021.30.Sup6.S4.">doi: 10.12968/jowc.2021.30.Sup6.S4.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karen Smith 1, Susan Hewlings 1&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Wound healing often needs some combination of:&lt;br>
      Vitamin D - (nanoemulsion works very well)&lt;br>
      Vitamin D - non-daily&lt;br>
      Resveratrol or something to improve the vitamin D receptor&lt;br>
      Omega-3&lt;br>
      Topical&lt;br>
 &lt;br>
This review appears to only consider daily oral Vitamin D mono-therapy&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hives (Urticaria) 7X more likely if vitamin D deficient, supplementation helps – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/hives-urticaria-7x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficient-supplementation-helps-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hives-urticaria-7x-more-likely-if-vitamin-d-deficient-supplementation-helps-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sections-clipped-from-pdf">Sections clipped from PDF&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="discussion">Discussion&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The findings of our comprehensive meta-analysis showed lower serum 25(OH)D concentrations by 9.35 ng/mL in the overall urticarial population compared with healthy individuals. Moreover, serum 25(OH)D deficiency was associated with an increased prevalence of urticaria compared to the general population. Many previous studies pointed out the positive relationship between low VitD serum levels and urticaria. Compared to the most recent meta-analyses in this field, our study concurs with the results by Tsai et al. (2018) &lt;sup>[22]&lt;/sup> and Wang (2018) &lt;sup>[21]&lt;/sup> that lower VitD serum levels occur in urticarial patients. We also verified that VitD deficiency rather than insufficiency has a positive relationship with urticaria. Furthermore, the higher prevalence of VitD deficiency and lower serum VitD levels were only found in patients with CU but not in those with AU. There lacked association of serum Vit D levels with AU and children urticaria compared to CU and adults (Supplemental Figure S6). Neither can we ignore the impact of geographical location, where subgroup analysis indicated populations in lower latitudes with VitD deficiency were associated with a higher urticarial risk compared to those in high latitudes. According to previous studies, sun exposure is an important source of the human needs for cutaneous production of VitD. Ultraviolet B (UVB) could be absorbed and transformed to pre-vitamin D3 in the skin by the function of 7-dehydrocholesterol, which could be influenced by many factors such as season, latitude, time of day, etc. &lt;sup>[47]&lt;/sup>. For the effects of latitude or sun exposure on serum VitD level, notably, people who were below 37° and closer to the equator could synthesize more VitD3 in their skin within a year. In the early morning or evening, the apex angle of the day was so inclined that there was almost no VitD3 produced in the skin, even in summer. Therefore, studies have shown that safe exposure to the sun between 1000 and 1500 h in spring, summer, and autumn is considered to be critical for VitD generation because this is the only time that sufficient solar UVB reaches the earth&amp;rsquo;s surface to produce VitD3 in the skin &lt;span>[48-50]&lt;/span>. However, In addition to latitude, other critical determinants of VitD status may not have been adequately captured in our analysis, including seasonal and personal factors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitiligo associated with low vitamin D (Note: Vit. D and UV has treated it for over a decade) – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitiligo-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-note-vit-d-and-uv-has-treated-it-for-over-e-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitiligo-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-note-vit-d-and-uv-has-treated-it-for-over-e-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="decreased-circulatory-levels-of-vitamin-d-in-vitiligo-a-meta-analysis">Decreased circulatory levels of Vitamin D in Vitiligo: a meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>An Bras Dermatol. 2021 Mar 24;S0365-0596(21)00074-X. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.abd.2020.10.002">doi: 10.1016/j.abd.2020.10.002&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seshadri Reddy Varikasuvu 1, Sowjanya Aloori 2, Saurabh Varshney 3, Aparna Varma Bhongir&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The medical profession moves     V E R Y     S L O W L Y&lt;br>
A decade of studies noted the assoication of low vitamin D and vitiligo&lt;br>
Even this paper took 7 month to be published after being received&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB phototherapy (which increases Vitamin D and VDR) decreased risk of many heart and stroke problems</title><link>/posts/uvb-phototherapy-which-increases-vitamin-d-and-vdr-decreased-risk-of-many-heart-and-stroke-problems.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-phototherapy-which-increases-vitamin-d-and-vdr-decreased-risk-of-many-heart-and-stroke-problems.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chinese Skin Pigmentation Types (original in Chinese) - 2019</title><link>/posts/chinese-skin-pigmentation-types-original-in-chinese-2019.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/chinese-skin-pigmentation-types-original-in-chinese-2019.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pigmentation-phenotype-prediction-of-chinese-populations-from-different-language-families">Pigmentation Phenotype Prediction of Chinese Populations from Different Language Families&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Select very rough translation by Chrome Browser or click on Translate con in the upper right of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>论著•	•人体表征分子鉴识专题.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>中国不同语系人群的色素表型推断&lt;/p>
&lt;p>梁鳅双刘明陶现明4,刘凡4,曾发明3,李彩霞&amp;rsquo;，赵雯婷1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(1.公安部物证鉴定中心现场物证溯源技术国家工程实验室法医遗传学公安部重点实验室北京市现场 物证检验工程技术研究中心，北京100038; 2.广西玉林市公安局，广西玉林537000; 3.昆明医科大学 法医学院，云南昆明650500； 4.中国科学院北京基因组研究所中国科学院精准基因组医学重点实验&lt;/p>
&lt;p>室，北京100101)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>摘要：目的对中国不同语系人群的色素表型进行推断及差异分析，为法医人类学和遗传学提供数据参 考。方法在实验室构建包含41个色素表型相关位点的HIrisPlex-S复合扩增检验体系，对分布在中国不 同区域的印欧、汉藏、阿尔泰、苗瑶、侗台、南亚6个语系的17个人群的2666份成年男性DNA样本进行分型 检验。通过在线推断模型（https://HIrisPlex.erasmusmc.nl/)进行色素表型分类推断，并对输出数据进行统计 分析。结果印欧语系及阿尔泰语系的亚欧混合人群有1.92%的蓝色眼睛和34.29%的棕色、金色头发个 体，其他人群的眼睛和头发颜色表型没有明显差异，均为棕色眼睛和黑色头发。各人群肤色具有语系和地 域差异：印欧语系人群肤色最浅，南亚语系人群肤色最深；西南地区少数民族人群较平原地区人群肤色偏 深。结论中国人群的色素表型推断结果与对各人群的外观认知基本一致，证明体系可靠性较佳。眼睛、&lt;/p>
&lt;p>头发颜色主要与祖源成分相关，肤色则呈现出语系间的差异性，并与人群地域分布密切相关。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>关键词：法医遗传学；法医人类学；表型；色素;语系&lt;/p>
&lt;p>中图分类号：DF795.2 文献标志码：A doi： 10.12116/j.issn.1004-5619.2019.05.008 文章编号：1004-5619(2019)05-0553-07&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pigmentation Phenotype Prediction of Chinese Populations from Different Language Families&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LIANG Qiu-shuang1'2, LIU Ming'3, TAO Xian-ming4, LIU Fan4, ZENG Fa-ming3, LI Cai-xia1, ZHAO Wen-ting1&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fewer Burn problems if adequate Vitamin D – Less ICU, Hospital, Sepsis (10X)</title><link>/posts/fewer-burn-problems-if-adequate-vitamin-d-less-icu-hospital-sepsis-10x.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fewer-burn-problems-if-adequate-vitamin-d-less-icu-hospital-sepsis-10x.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Skin fairness, red hair both associated with poor health (perhaps low vitamin D)</title><link>/posts/skin-fairness-red-hair-both-associated-with-poor-health-perhaps-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-fairness-red-hair-both-associated-with-poor-health-perhaps-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Acne 3X more likely if low Vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/acne-3x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/acne-3x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-acne-vulgaris-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D deficiency in patients with acne vulgaris: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-deficiency-in-patients-with-acne-vulgaris-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Vitamin D deficiency in patients with acne vulgaris: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Australasian Journal of Dermatology (2019) , – &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/ajd.13165">doi: 10.1111/ajd.13165&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;i class="fas fa-file-pdf" style="margin-right: 0.3em;">&lt;/i>&lt;a href="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/pdf/acne-sci-hub.pdf">Download the PDF from Sci-Hub via VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/acne-meta.jpg" alt="image" width="700">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/acne-meta-table.jpg" alt="image" width="500"></description></item><item><title>Topical Vitamin D provides more benefits than oral sometimes - many studies</title><link>/posts/topical-vitamin-d-provides-more-benefits-than-oral-sometimes-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/topical-vitamin-d-provides-more-benefits-than-oral-sometimes-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>It appears that ~10% of people will benefit from Topical more than the Oral form of Vitamin D&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It appears that ~20% of people having specific health problems will get more benefit from Topical than Oral&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Preeclampsia. Food Allergy, PTSD, Ear infection, Infertility, MS, Colon Cancer, TB, Asthma, COPD, Epilepsy, Atrial Fibrillation. Liver&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Also suspect for those people with poor guts: Cystic Fibrosis, Diabetes&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>However, Topical forms of Vitamin D are:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leprosy risk is reduced by 3X for some types of Vitamin D Receptor (Brazil)</title><link>/posts/leprosy-risk-is-reduced-by-3x-for-some-types-of-vitamin-d-receptor-brazil.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/leprosy-risk-is-reduced-by-3x-for-some-types-of-vitamin-d-receptor-brazil.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphisms-are-associated-with-leprosy-in-southern-brazil">Vitamin D receptor gene polymorphisms are associated with leprosy in southern Brazil.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Front. Immunol. | &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2019.02157">doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2019.02157&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Afonso C. Pepineli1, Hugo V. Alves1, Bruna T. Tiyo1, Luciana C. Macedo1, Lorena&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Visentainer2, Joana M. Zacarias1, Quirino A. de Lima Neto1, ANA M. SELL1 and Jeane E. Visentainer1*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 State University of Maringá, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Campinas State University, Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="/posts/leprosy-low-vitamin-d-and-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-many-studies">Leprosy in VitaminDWiki&lt;/a> typically with INCREASED Risk with poor VDR&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Vitamin D, together with its nuclear receptor (VDR), plays an important role in modulating the immune response, decreasing the inflammatory process. Some polymorphisms of the VDR gene, such as BsmI (G&amp;gt;A rs1544410), ApaI (G&amp;gt;T rs7975232) and TaqI (T&amp;gt;C rs731236) could affect its stability and mRNA transcription activity, while FokI T&amp;gt;C (rs2228570) gives a truncated protein with three fewer amino acids and more efficiency in binding vitamin D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eczema (Atopic Dermatitis) treated by 1,600 IU Vitamin D (again) – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/eczema-atopic-dermatitis-treated-by-1600-iu-vitamin-d-again-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/eczema-atopic-dermatitis-treated-by-1600-iu-vitamin-d-again-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitamin D for skin anti-aging – liposomal base is probably 1.6X better than oil base (in rats)</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-for-skin-anti-aging-liposomal-base-is-probably-16x-better-than-oil-base-in-rats.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-for-skin-anti-aging-liposomal-base-is-probably-16x-better-than-oil-base-in-rats.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="liposomal-vitamin-d3-as-an-anti-aging-agent-for-the-skin">Liposomal Vitamin D3 as an Anti-aging Agent for the Skin&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Pharmaceutics 2019, 11(7), 311; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics11070311">https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics11070311&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ye Bi 1,2,†, Hongxi Xia 3,†, Lianlian Li 3, Robert J. Lee 3,4, Jing Xie 3, Zongyu Liu 5, Zhidong Qiu 1,6,* and Lesheng Teng 1,3,6,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D3 is an effective skin protective substance to prevent photoaging. Liposomes were used as a carrier to deliver vitamin D3 to improve the stability and to enhance the treatment effect of vitamin D3. The stability of vitamin D3 liposomes, average cumulative penetration, and retention of vitamin D3 in the skin were then evaluated and compared with free vitamin D3. Finally, the treatment effect of vitamin D3 liposomes in a rat photoaging model was appraised and Haematoxylin-Eosin (H&amp;amp;E) staining was used to assess the histology changes of the skin after vitamin D3 liposome treatment. The results indicated that liposomes could significantly improve the stability of vitamin D3. &lt;strong>The average skin retention of vitamin D3 liposomes was 1.65 times that of the vitamin D3 solution&lt;/strong> . Vitamin D3 liposomes could repair the surface morphology of skin in the photoaging model and promote the production of new collagen fibers. Vitamin D3 liposomes as a potential skin care agent could significantly improve skin appearance and repair damage in the histology of photoaging.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deep wounds (Diabetic) healed slowly if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/deep-wounds-diabetic-healed-slowly-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/deep-wounds-diabetic-healed-slowly-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Burns - will 200,000 IU of vitamin D decrease hospital stay - RCT 2021</title><link>/posts/burns-will-200000-iu-of-vitamin-d-decrease-hospital-stay-rct-2021.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/burns-will-200000-iu-of-vitamin-d-decrease-hospital-stay-rct-2021.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-deficiency-of-vitamin-d-in-burn-patientshttpsclinicaltrialsgovct2shownct03884036sfpd_s032f072f2019sfpd_d14-clinical-trial">&lt;a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03884036?sfpd_s=03%2F07%2F2019&amp;amp;sfpd_d=14">Effect of Deficiency of Vitamin D in Burn Patients&lt;/a> Clinical trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Korea, no updates since Oct 2019&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunscreen (SPF-30) slightly increased the vitamin D from UVB – RCT</title><link>/posts/sunscreen-spf-30-slightly-increased-the-vitamin-d-from-uvb-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunscreen-spf-30-slightly-increased-the-vitamin-d-from-uvb-rct.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Off topic: Skin aging reversed with by oral collagen – trials and reviews</title><link>/posts/off-topic-skin-aging-reversed-with-by-oral-collagen-trials-and-reviews.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-skin-aging-reversed-with-by-oral-collagen-trials-and-reviews.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#why-collagen-is-a-proven-necessity---mercola-sept2023httpsarticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20230904why-collagen-is-a-proven-necessityaspxuid738e3df52a8a14aea9298fe6ec5bc113ed0d6d7922f31861727d54a43cbe29dsd20121119cid_sourcednlcid_mediumemailcid_contentart1hlcid20230904fodatefalsemiddm1459708rid1902035015">Why Collagen Is a Proven Necessity - &lt;a href="https://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2023/09/04/why-collagen-is-a-proven-necessity.aspx?ui=d738e3df52a8a14aea9298fe6ec5bc113ed0d6d7922f31861727d54a43cbe29d&amp;amp;sd=20121119&amp;amp;cid_source=dnl&amp;amp;cid_medium=email&amp;amp;cid_content=art1HL&amp;amp;cid=20230904&amp;amp;foDate=false&amp;amp;mid=DM1459708&amp;amp;rid=1902035015">Mercola Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#9-grams-oral-collagen-increased-skin-elasticity-by--50---rct-march2019">9 grams oral collagen increased skin elasticity by ~ 50% - RCT March 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#oral-collagen-helps-skin---review-jan2019">Oral Collagen helps skin - review Jan 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#5-grams-oral-collagen-helped-skin---rct2015">5 grams oral collagen helped skin - RCT 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#how-to-get-more-collagen-and-why-your-skin-needs-it-to-stayyoung">How to Get More Collagen, and Why Your Skin Needs It to Stay Young&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#whats-the-deal-with-collagen---sept2023">What&amp;rsquo;s The Deal With Collagen? - Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-most-abundant-protein-in-mammals--wikipedia2019">The most abundant protein in mammals- Wikipedia 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-alsovitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#collagen-descreases-withage">Collagen descreases with age&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="why-collagen-is-a-proven-necessity---mercola-sept2023httpsarticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20230904why-collagen-is-a-proven-necessityaspxuid738e3df52a8a14aea9298fe6ec5bc113ed0d6d7922f31861727d54a43cbe29dsd20121119cid_sourcednlcid_mediumemailcid_contentart1hlcid20230904fodatefalsemiddm1459708rid1902035015">Why Collagen Is a Proven Necessity - &lt;a href="https://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2023/09/04/why-collagen-is-a-proven-necessity.aspx?ui=d738e3df52a8a14aea9298fe6ec5bc113ed0d6d7922f31861727d54a43cbe29d&amp;amp;sd=20121119&amp;amp;cid_source=dnl&amp;amp;cid_medium=email&amp;amp;cid_content=art1HL&amp;amp;cid=20230904&amp;amp;foDate=false&amp;amp;mid=DM1459708&amp;amp;rid=1902035015">Mercola Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Collagen is the most common and abundant of your body’s proteins, accounting for about 30% of the total protein in your body. One of its primary purposes is to provide structural scaffolding to allow tissues to stretch and flex while maintaining tissue integrity&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Have We Gotten Sunscreen Totally Wrong</title><link>/posts/have-we-gotten-sunscreen-totally-wrong.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/have-we-gotten-sunscreen-totally-wrong.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="outsidehttpswwwoutsideonlinecom2380751sunscreen-sun-exposure-skin-cancer-scienceutm_mediumsocialutm_sourcetwitterutm_campaigntweet">&lt;a href="https://www.outsideonline.com/2380751/sunscreen-sun-exposure-skin-cancer-science?utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=tweet">Outside&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;quot; True, the sun worshippers had a higher incidence of it—but they were eight times less likely to die from it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Avoidance of sun exposure is a risk factor of a similar magnitude as smoking, in terms of life expectancy.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“Homo sapiens have been around for 200,000 years. Until the industrial revolution, we lived outside.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>How did we get through the Neolithic Era without sunscreen?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Actually, perfectly well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What’s counterintuitive is that dermatologists run around saying, ‘Don’t go outside, you might die.’”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dermatologists use sun block, stay indoors, and have low vitamin D (Thai in this study)</title><link>/posts/dermatologists-use-sun-block-stay-indoors-and-have-low-vitamin-d-thai-in-this-study.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dermatologists-use-sun-block-stay-indoors-and-have-low-vitamin-d-thai-in-this-study.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Melasma (pregnancy mask) treated by Vitamin D, Vitamin B12, Vitamin C, etc.</title><link>/posts/melasma-pregnancy-mask-treated-by-vitamin-d-vitamin-b12-vitamin-c-etc.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/melasma-pregnancy-mask-treated-by-vitamin-d-vitamin-b12-vitamin-c-etc.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="melasma-associated-with-periodontitis-anemia-and-vitamin-d-abnormalities-a-chance-occurrence-or-a-syndrome">Melasma Associated with Periodontitis, Anemia, and Vitamin D Abnormalities: A Chance Occurrence or a Syndrome.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Contemp Dent Pract. 2018 Oct 1;19(10):1254-1259. PMID: 30498182&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chaitanya NC1, Priyanka DR2, Madireddy N2, Priyanka JN2, Ramakrishna M3, Ajay M4, Ignatius AV2.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/pregnancy-mask.jpg" alt="image" width="300">
&lt;p>AIM: To correlate the possible association between melasma, periodontitis, vitamin D abnormalities, and anemia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MATERIALS AND METHODS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A total of 192 subjects, of either gender within the age group of 30 to 70 years were divided equally into two groups, group I (case group, patients with melasma) and group II (control group, patients without melasma). In all the subjects, anemia and periodontitis were checked clinically, along with biochemical evaluation of serum vitamin D levels and hemoglobin (Hb) percentage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D Receptor in vitiligo skin activated by UVB</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-in-vitiligo-skin-activated-by-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-receptor-in-vitiligo-skin-activated-by-uvb.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Increased risk of atopic dermatitis with low vitamin D during pregnancy perhaps due to poor methylation</title><link>/posts/increased-risk-of-atopic-dermatitis-with-low-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-perhaps--oor-methylation.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-risk-of-atopic-dermatitis-with-low-vitamin-d-during-pregnancy-perhaps--oor-methylation.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prenatal-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-deficiency-affects-development-of-atopic-dermatitis-via-dna-methylation">Prenatal 25-hydroxyvitamin D deficiency affects development of atopic dermatitis via DNA methylation.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2018 Oct 20. pii: S0091-6749(18)31477-5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaci.2018.10.010.">doi: 10.1016/j.jaci.2018.10.010.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cho HJ1, Sheen YH2, Kang MJ3, Lee SH3, Lee SY4, Yoon J5, Jung S4, Lee SH3, Kim YH4, Yang SI6, Lee E7, Seo JH8, Ahn K9, Kim KW10, Suh DI11, Won HS12, Lee MY12, Kim SH13, Choi SJ14, Kwon JY15, Jun JK16, Kwon SO17, Oh SY18, Hong SJ19.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Less scarring (hypertrophic) if supplementation with Vitamin D got above 25 ng – RCT</title><link>/posts/less-scarring-hypertrophic-if-supplementation-with-vitamin-d-got-above-25-ng-rct.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-scarring-hypertrophic-if-supplementation-with-vitamin-d-got-above-25-ng-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-on-hypertrophic-scarring">Effect of Vitamin D Deficiency on Hypertrophic Scarring.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermatol Surg. 2018 Sep 10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/DSS.0000000000001680.">doi: 10.1097/DSS.0000000000001680.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ince B1, Uyar I, Dadaci M2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 All authors are affiliated with the Department of Plastic, Reconstructive and Aesthetic Surgery, Meram Faculty of Medicine, Necmettin Erbakan University, Konya, Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 All authors are affiliated with the Department of Plastic, Reconstructive and Aesthetic Surgery, Meram Faculty of Medicine, Necmettin Erbakan University, Konya, Turkey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Many skin problems are associated with each other and with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/many-skin-problems-are-associated-with-each-other-and-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-skin-problems-are-associated-with-each-other-and-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vitiligo (spotty skin coloring) is 4 X more likely if poor Vitamin D Receptor – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitiligo-spotty-skin-coloring-is-4-x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitiligo-spotty-skin-coloring-is-4-x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-receptor-gene-polymorphism-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-and-risk-of-vitiligo-a-meta-analysis">Vitamin D receptor gene polymorphism, serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels, and risk of vitiligo: A meta-analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Medicine (Baltimore). 2018 Jul;97(29):e11506. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000011506.">doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000011506.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zhang JZ1, Wang M2, Ding Y1, Gao F2, Feng YY1, Yakeya B1, Wang P1, Wu XJ1, Hu FX1, Xian J3, Kang XJ1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Department of Dermatology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Department of Gastroenterology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Department of Gynecology, People&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region, Urumqi, Xinjiang, China.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FFFAE2;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:800px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/vitiligo-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-nothing-about-treatment-meta-analysis">Vitiligo is associated with low vitamin D (nothing about treatment) – meta-analysis March 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wound dressing will have Vitamin D - should reduce infections</title><link>/posts/wound-dressing-will-have-vitamin-d-should-reduce-infections.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wound-dressing-will-have-vitamin-d-should-reduce-infections.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="nanofibre-wound-dressings-may-help-tackle-surgical-site-infectionshttpswwwmedicaldevice-networkcomnewsnanofibre-wound-dressings-may-help-tackle-surgical-site-infections-press-release">&lt;a href="https://www.medicaldevice-network.com/news/nanofibre-wound-dressings-may-help-tackle-surgical-site-infections/">Nanofibre wound dressings may help tackle surgical site infections&lt;/a> Press Release&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Prepared using electrospinning, the wound dressings were able to trigger the production of an antimicrobial peptide called hCAP18/LL37 at the site of infection. The peptide disrupts the membranes of microbes and destroys them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“The mechanism of these dressings to improve immune responses instead of containing single-target antimicrobial compounds is expected to reduce the risk of drug resistance.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Findings revealed that the dressings could deliver vitamin D on a sustained basis over &lt;strong>four weeks&lt;/strong> &amp;quot;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The effect of vitamin D on different human cells, with emphasis on burns and ICU</title><link>/posts/the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-different-human-cells-with-emphasis-on-burns-and-icu.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-effect-of-vitamin-d-on-different-human-cells-with-emphasis-on-burns-and-icu.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>True Story - This Vitamin D3 Shot Took My Already Clear Skin to the Next Level</title><link>/posts/true-story-this-vitamin-d3-shot-took-my-already-clear-skin-to-the-next-level.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/true-story-this-vitamin-d3-shot-took-my-already-clear-skin-to-the-next-level.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="organic-authority-httpwwworganicauthoritycomtrue-story-this-vitamin-d3-shot-took-my-already-clear-skin-to-the-next-level">&lt;a href="http://www.organicauthority.com/true-story-this-vitamin-d3-shot-took-my-already-clear-skin-to-the-next-level/">Organic Authority &lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“…what I did notice was that my skin glowed up”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“I started getting compliments and could see the obvious change myself”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“My favorite way to consume the oil is to add the package’s recommended dosage into a shot glass with equal parts ginger and lemon or lime juice”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Does not mention dose size, pre-existing Vitamin D level&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Does mention lots of references to vitamin D eliminating skin problems, but nothing about improving already healthy skin&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin whitening cream (RD) may cause blotchy skin, 5,000 Vitamin D can treat it – RCT</title><link>/posts/skin-whitening-cream-rd-may-cause-blotchy-skin-5000-vitamin-d-can-treat-it-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-whitening-cream-rd-may-cause-blotchy-skin-5000-vitamin-d-can-treat-it-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="efficacy-of-oral-cholecalciferol-on-rhododendrol-induced-vitiligo-a-blinded-randomized-clinical-trial">Efficacy of oral cholecalciferol on rhododendrol-induced vitiligo: A blinded randomized clinical trial.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Dermatol. 2018 Feb 5. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/1346-8138.14244.">doi: 10.1111/1346-8138.14244.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Watabe A1, Yamasaki K1, Asano M1, Kanbayashi Y1, Nasu-Tamabuchi M1, Terui H1, Furudate S1, Kakizaki A1, Tsuchiyama K1, Kimura Y1, Ito Y1, Kikuchi K1, Aiba S1.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note: Succesful Vitamin D treatments for various skin problems have included oral, topical, and injection&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/spotty-skin-coloring-vitiligo-treated-by-augmenting-topical-tacrolimus-with-oral-vitamin-d">Spotty skin coloring (vitiligo) treated by augmenting topical tacrolimus with oral Vitamin D – Oct 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic dermatitis treated by Vitamin D (in dogs too) - RCT</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-treated-by-vitamin-d-in-dogs-too-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-treated-by-vitamin-d-in-dogs-too-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-shows-in-vivo-efficacy-in-a-placebo-controlled-double-blinded-randomised-clinical-trial-on-canine-atopic-dermatitis">Vitamin D shows in vivo efficacy in a placebo-controlled, double-blinded, randomised clinical trial on canine atopic dermatitis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>VetRecord – BMJ, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1136/vr.104492">http://dx.doi.org/10.1136/vr.104492&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christoph J Klinger1 &lt;a href="mailto:klingerchristoph@icloud.com">klingerchristoph@icloud.com&lt;/a>, Stefan Hobi1, Cornelia Johansen1, Hans-Joachim Koch2, Karin Weber1 and Ralf S Mueller1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 – Clinic of Small Animal Medicine, Ludwig Maximilian University, Munich, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 – Tierärztliche Klinik Birkenfeld, Birkenfeld, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:700px">
&lt;p>Veterinary was the very first category made in VitaminDWiki 8 years ago&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Farm animal doctors are paid to keep their patients healthy, vs human doctors are paid to treat sick patients&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin directly benefits from the sun – no liver, kidney needed to create Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/skin-directly-benefits-from-the-sun-no-liver-kidney-needed-to-create-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-directly-benefits-from-the-sun-no-liver-kidney-needed-to-create-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reasons for low vitamin D levels (Vit D can treat various skin problems) – 2016</title><link>/posts/reasons-for-low-vitamin-d-levels-vit-d-can-treat-various-skin-problems-2016.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/reasons-for-low-vitamin-d-levels-vit-d-can-treat-various-skin-problems-2016.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="targeting-the-vitamin-d-endocrine-system-vdes-for-the-management-of-inflammatory-and-malignant-skin-diseases-an-historical-view-and-outlook">Targeting the vitamin D endocrine system (VDES) for the management of inflammatory and malignant skin diseases: An historical view and outlook.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2016 Sep;17(3):405-417.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reichrath J1, Zouboulis CC2, Vogt T3, Holick MF4.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1 Center for Clinical and Experimental Photo-Dermatology and Department of Dermatology, The Saarland University Hospital, Kirrbergerstr, 66421, Homburg, Germany. &lt;a href="mailto:Joerg.reichrath@uks.eu">Joerg.reichrath@uks.eu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>2 Departments of Dermatology, Venereology, Allergology and Immunology, Dessau Medical Center, Dessau, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>3 Center for Clinical and Experimental Photo-Dermatology and Department of Dermatology, The Saarland University Hospital, Kirrbergerstr, 66421, Homburg, Germany.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leprosy, low Vitamin D and poor Vitamin D Receptor - many studies</title><link>/posts/leprosy-low-vitamin-d-and-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/leprosy-low-vitamin-d-and-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-is-treating-and-preventing-leprosy-in-myanmar">Vitamin D is treating and preventing Leprosy in Myanmar&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#leprosy-28x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor---dec-2017">Leprosy 28X more likely if poor Vitamin D Receptor - Dec 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#leprosy-3x-more-likely-if-poor-vdr--nov-2018">Leprosy 3X more likely if poor VDR – Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#higher-vdr-much-less-leprosy---march-2019">Higher VDR, much less Leprosy - March 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#leprosy-risk-is-reduced-by-3x-for-some-types-of-vitamin-d-receptor-brazil--sept-2019">Leprosy risk is reduced by 3X for some types of Vitamin D Receptor (Brazil) – Sept 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#leprosy-associated-with-lower-cathelicidin-brazil---july-2020">Leprosy associated with lower Cathelicidin (Brazil) - July 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-pubmed-studies-of-leprosy-genes-and-vitamin-d-receptor">Some PubMed studies of Leprosy, genes, and Vitamin D Receptor&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web---leprosy-nothing-about-vitamin-d-nor-vdr">See also web - Leprosy (nothing about Vitamin D nor VDR)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-is-treating-and-preventing-leprosy-in-myanmar">Vitamin D is treating and preventing Leprosy in Myanmar&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/vitamin-d-is-treating-and-preventing-leprosy-in-myanmar-burma">Vitamin D is treating and preventing Leprosy in Myanmar (Burma) - April 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="leprosy-28x-more-likely-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor---dec-2017">Leprosy 28X more likely if poor Vitamin D Receptor - Dec 2017&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A novel vitamin D receptor polymorphism associated with leprosy&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin and oral wounds treated via Vitamin D Receptor and Calcium (book chapter)</title><link>/posts/skin-and-oral-wounds-treated-via-vitamin-d-receptor-and-calcium-book-chapter.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-and-oral-wounds-treated-via-vitamin-d-receptor-and-calcium-book-chapter.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="role-of-vitamin-d-and-calcium-in-epidemal-wound-repairhttpsbooksgooglecombookshlenlridt8q_dwaaqbajoifndpgpa113otsqlbtkgyp2csigaqv_5eluzfly92vpmuvi0whuf_wvonepageqffalse--google-books-previews-some-of-the-text-and-graphics">&lt;a href="https://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;id=T8Q_DwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;oi=fnd&amp;amp;pg=PA113&amp;amp;ots=qlBTKGyP2c&amp;amp;sig=aQV_5ElUZflY92VpmUVi0wHUf_w#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false">Role of Vitamin D and Calcium in Epidemal Wound Repair&lt;/a> Google Books previews some of the text and graphics&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This is a chapter in a technical book: &lt;strong>Wound Healing: Stem Cells Repair and Restorations, Basic and Clinical Aspects&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/epidermal1.jpg" alt="image" width="550">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/epidermal-chart.jpg" alt="image" width="550">
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/epidermal-conclusion.jpg" alt="image" width="550">
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/hard-to-heal-wounds-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-review">Hard-to-heal Wounds associated with low vitamin D – review June 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/burns-ulcers-and-wounds-healed-by-vitamin-d-many-studies">Burns, ulcers, and wounds healed by Vitamin D - many studies&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/severely-burned-children-recovered-muscle-capability-much-faster-with-daily-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct">Severely burned children recovered muscle capability much faster with daily 1000 IU of vitamin D – RCT March 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dermatologists are reminded of the importance of vitamin D in 8 diseases</title><link>/posts/dermatologists-are-reminded-of-the-importance-of-vitamin-d-in-8-diseases.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dermatologists-are-reminded-of-the-importance-of-vitamin-d-in-8-diseases.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blotchy skin in seniors (Bateman purpura or dermatoporosis) treated by topical vitamin C, etc. – RCT</title><link>/posts/blotchy-skin-in-seniors-bateman-purpura-or-dermatoporosis-treated-by-topical-vitamin-c-etc-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/blotchy-skin-in-seniors-bateman-purpura-or-dermatoporosis-treated-by-topical-vitamin-c-etc-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="bateman-purpura-dermatoporosis-a-localized-scurvy-treated-by-topical-vitamin-c--double-blind-randomized-placebo-controlled-clinical-trial">Bateman purpura (dermatoporosis): a localized scurvy treated by topical vitamin C – Double blind randomized placebo-controlled clinical trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J. of the European Academy of Dermatology . . online: 17 August 2017, DOI: 10.1111/jdv.14525&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P. Humbert, F. Fanian, T. Lihoreau, A. Jeudy, G.E. Pierard&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>May also be treated by Vitamin D, Vitamin K, and Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-web">See also web&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss?url=search-alias%3Dbeauty&amp;amp;field-keywords=cream+%22vitamin+c%22">Amazon Vitamin C creams&lt;/a> some also contain Hyaluronic Acid&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Example from Google Images&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>25 percent of most dermatologic prescriptions are not filled, however all vitamin D analogs were filled</title><link>/posts/25-percent-of-most-dermatologic-prescriptions-are-not-filled-however-all-vitamin-ogs-were-filled.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/25-percent-of-most-dermatologic-prescriptions-are-not-filled-however-all-vitamin-ogs-were-filled.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="prescription-level-factors-associated-with-primary-nonadherence-to-dermatologic-medications">Prescription-level factors associated with primary nonadherence to dermatologic medications.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Dermatolog Treat. 2017 Aug 7:1-19. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/09546634.2017.1365115.">doi: 10.1080/09546634.2017.1365115.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rutherford A1, Glass DA 2nd1,2,3, Suarez EA4, Adamson AS1,5,6.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:600px">
&lt;p>Pateints avoid non-vitamin D dermatologic prescriptions&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wonder when dermatologists are going to learn?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/dermatologists-still-not-convienced-that-vitamin-d-reduces-atopic-dermatitis-review">Dermatologists still not convienced that Vitamin D reduces atopic dermatitis – Review Dec 2013&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/psoriasis-proven-to-be-treated-by-vitamin-d-in-many-rct-but-dermatologists-fear-losing-business">Psoriasis proven to be treated by Vitamin D in many RCT, but dermatologists fear losing business – March 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultraviolet light (which produces vitamin D) decreased the use of psoriasis drugs for a year</title><link>/posts/ultraviolet-light-which-produces-vitamin-d-decreased-the-use-of-psoriasis-drugs-for-a-year.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ultraviolet-light-which-produces-vitamin-d-decreased-the-use-of-psoriasis-drugs-for-a-year.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Raised skin scars (keloid) have fewer Vitamin D Receptors</title><link>/posts/raised-skin-scars-keloid-have-fewer-vitamin-d-receptors.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/raised-skin-scars-keloid-have-fewer-vitamin-d-receptors.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Spotty skin coloring (vitiligo) treated by augmenting topical tacrolimus with oral Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/spotty-skin-coloring-vitiligo-treated-by-augmenting-topical-tacrolimus-with-oral-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/spotty-skin-coloring-vitiligo-treated-by-augmenting-topical-tacrolimus-with-oral-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sunburning reduced by 200,000 IU of Vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/sunburning-reduced-by-200000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunburning-reduced-by-200000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#oral-vitamin-d-rapidly-attenuates-inflammation-from-sunburn-an-interventional-study">Oral vitamin D rapidly attenuates inflammation from sunburn: an interventional study.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#figure-5">Figure 5&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#editorial-covering-the-study">Editorial covering the study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#93-studies-cited-this-paper-as-of-aug-2024">93 studies cited this paper as of Aug 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#comment-on-the-study-oct-2017">Comment on the study Oct, 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="oral-vitamin-d-rapidly-attenuates-inflammation-from-sunburn-an-interventional-study">Oral vitamin D rapidly attenuates inflammation from sunburn: an interventional study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Invest Dermatol. 2017 May 30. pii: S0022-202X(17)31558-0. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jid.2017.04.040.">doi: 10.1016/j.jid.2017.04.040.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scott JF1, Das LM2, Ahsanuddin S2, Qiu Y3, Binko AM2, Traylor ZP2, Debanne SM3, Cooper KD4, Boxer R5, Lu KQ6.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Warts removed by vitamin D injection - many studies</title><link>/posts/warts-removed-by-vitamin-d-injection-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/warts-removed-by-vitamin-d-injection-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-injection-cleared-80-of-palmoplantar-warts-adding-co2-laser-cured-90--may-2023">Vitamin D injection cleared 80% of palmoplantar warts (adding CO2 laser cured 90%) – May 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-injection-cured-a-variety-of-warts-on-skin---2017-a">Vitamin D injection cured a variety of warts on skin - 2017 A&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-injection-cured-a-variety-of-warts-on-skin---2017-b">Vitamin D injection cured a variety of warts on skin - 2017 B&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#warts-eliminated-in-80-percent-of-those-getting-vitamin-d-injection--aug-2015">Warts eliminated in 80 percent of those getting vitamin D injection – Aug 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#67-of-warts-cleared-by-vitamin-d-injections---jan-2020">67% of warts cleared by Vitamin D injections - Jan 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#intralesional-vitamin-d3-treats-of-cutaneous-warts--2021">Intralesional Vitamin D3 treats of Cutaneous Warts- 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#wart-removal-85-by-duck-tape-60-by-cyrotherapy---but-later-study-disagreed---2002">Wart removal: 85% by Duck Tape, 60% by Cyrotherapy - but later study disagreed - 2002&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-injection-cleared-80-of-palmoplantar-warts-adding-co2-laser-cured-90--may-2023">Vitamin D injection cleared 80% of palmoplantar warts (adding CO2 laser cured 90%) – May 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Comparative Study Among CO2 Laser, Intralesional Vitamin D3, and Combined Intralesional Vitamin D3 and CO2 Laser in Treatment of Palmoplantar Warts&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Phototherapy and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/phototherapy-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/phototherapy-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Clin Dermatol. 2016 Sep-Oct;34(5):548-55. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clindermatol.2016.05.004.">doi: 10.1016/j.clindermatol.2016.05.004.&lt;/a> Epub 2016 May 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Juzeniene A1, Grigalavicius M2, Juraleviciute M2, Grant WB3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Montebello, N-0310 Oslo, Norway. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:Asta.juzeniene@rr-research.no">Asta.juzeniene@rr-research.no&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Radiation Biology, Institute for Cancer Research, Norwegian Radium Hospital, Oslo University Hospital, Montebello, N-0310 Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Sunlight, Nutrition, and Health Research Center, San Francisco, CA.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/pdt.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>The skin is the site for the photosynthesis of vitamin D and is a target tissue for the active metabolite of vitamin D. An increasing body of evidence indicates that vitamin D produced during phototherapy may be responsible for the positive effects observed during treatment of some skin diseases. Topical or oral application of vitamin D derivatives are used alone or with phototherapy. This paper reviews what is known about the use of phototherapy to enhance vitamin D levels, the use of vitamin D analogues with phototherapy, the efficacy of combination therapies, and controversies regarding some of the outcomes. Vitamin D can play a beneficial role in treating psoriasis, even though the exact role of vitamin D in the pathogenesis and severity of psoriasis remains unclear. The role of vitamin D in vitiligo, atopic dermatitis, polymorphic light eruption, and mycosis fungoides must be further investigated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eczema (Atopic Dermatitis) treated by 1600 IU of vitamin D – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/eczema-atopic-dermatitis-treated-by-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/eczema-atopic-dermatitis-treated-by-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Malignant melanoma may be reduced by skin-activated vitamin D</title><link>/posts/malignant-melanoma-may-be-reduced-by-skin-activated-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/malignant-melanoma-may-be-reduced-by-skin-activated-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Current knowledge on the active form of Vitamin D synthesized in the skin and its effects on malignant melanoma&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neoplasma, doi:10.4149/neo_2017_101, Received April 18, 2016 / Accepted August 27, 2016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b. bolerazska &lt;a href="mailto:beata@moly.sk">beata@moly.sk&lt;/a>, m. rabajdova, i. spakova, m. marekova&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medical and Clinical Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, P. J. Safarik University in Kosice, Kosice, Slovakia&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">&lt;/nav>
&lt;div class="border" style="background-color:#FF9;padding:15px;margin:10px 0;border-radius:5px;width:750px">
&lt;p>Vitamin D can be activated in many places in the body&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study incorrectly states that activatation only occurs in the skin and Kidneys&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitiligo is associated with low vitamin D (nothing about treatment) – meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/vitiligo-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-nothing-about-treatment-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitiligo-is-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-nothing-about-treatment-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-are-associated-with-vitiligo-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis">Low 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels are Associated with Vitiligo: a Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Photodermatol Photoimmunol Photomed. 2016 Mar 23. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/phpp.12241.">doi: 10.1111/phpp.12241.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upala S1,2, Sanguankeo A1,2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Internal Medicine, Bassett Medical Center and Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, Cooperstown, N.Y, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Preventive and Social Medicine, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is associated with a number of autoimmune diseases. We completed a meta-analysis of observational studies to establish whether there was a relationship between hypovitaminosis D and the autoimmune skin disease vitiligo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin physiology, pathology and vitamin D - review</title><link>/posts/skin-physiology-pathology-and-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-physiology-pathology-and-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sunscreen cream (Photocil) which allows Vitamin D to be produced (not US)</title><link>/posts/sunscreen-cream-photocil-which-allows-vitamin-d-to-be-produced-not-us.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunscreen-cream-photocil-which-allows-vitamin-d-to-be-produced-not-us.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Company did not respond to email nor phone Nov 2015&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Appears to be out of business&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="topical-cream-delivers-nb-uvb-from-sunlight-for-the-treatment-of-vitiligo">Topical cream delivers NB-UVB from sunlight for the treatment of vitiligo.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2014 Dec;15(18):2623-7. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1517/14656566.2014.978287.">doi: 10.1517/14656566.2014.978287.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Nov 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wang X1, McCoy J, Lotti T, Goren A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Applied Biology , 17780 Fitch, Suite 192, Irvine, CA 92614 , USA &lt;a href="mailto:johnm@appliedbiology.com">johnm@appliedbiology.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultraviolet-B (UVB) phototherapy for the treatment of vitiligo is an effective first-line choice. However, the cost of multiple doctor visits and the lengthy treatment regimen has resulted in low compliance, limiting access to this safe and effective mode of treatment. Topical Photocil represents an innovative solution to this problem. The drug selectively filters solar radiation to deliver narrow-band UVB to vitiligo lesions. Here, we discuss how this novel topical cream could provide a convenient alternative to artificial light phototherapy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D and the skin: Focus on a complex relationship</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-skin-focus-on-a-complex-relationship.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-and-the-skin-focus-on-a-complex-relationship.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Stretch marks (after pregnancy) prevented and treated by Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/stretch-marks-after-pregnancy-prevented-and-treated-by-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/stretch-marks-after-pregnancy-prevented-and-treated-by-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-is-one-of-many-ways-to-reduce-stretch-marks--treatment-and-prevention">Vitamin D is one of many ways to reduce stretch marks – treatment and prevention&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.stretchmarkcreamcenter.com/">http://www.stretchmarkcreamcenter.com/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>weight gain, pregnancy, growth spurts, and even genetics&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In women and men&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ingredients include Vitamin E, grapefruit seed extract, &lt;strong>vitamin D3&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://storify.com/jordan5vel299/pregnancy-the-best-stretch-mark-cream-when-pregnan">Pregnancy :: The Best Stretch Mark Cream When Pregnant Includes Safe But Effective Ingredients&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Vitamin E, &lt;strong>Vitamin D&lt;/strong> , Aloe Vera, Shea Butter, Squalene Oil, etc&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/posts/how-60-ng-of-vitamin-d-enabled-pregnancy-a-personal-story">How 60 ng of vitamin D enabled pregnancy - a personal story&lt;/a> on VitaminDWiki&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Stretch marks PREVENTED in one woman with lots of vitamin D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic Dermatitis risk is 55 percent higher if low vitamin D – Meta-analysis</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-risk-is-55-percent-higher-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-risk-is-55-percent-higher-if-low-vitamin-d-meta-analysis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis-of-association-between-serum-vitamin-d-and-atopic-dermatitis">A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Association between Serum Vitamin D and Atopic Dermatitis&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Siriraj Med J, Volume 67, Number 5, September-October 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pichanee Chaweekulrat, M.D.&lt;em>, Chaiyawat Suppasilp, M.D.&lt;/em>, Bhoom Suktitipat, M.D., Ph.D. *, &lt;a href="mailto:bhoom.suk@mahidol.aath">bhoom.suk@mahidol.aath&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Department of Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok 10700,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Integrative Computational BioScience Center (ICBS), Mahidol University, Salaya, Phuttamonthon, Nakhon Pathom 73170, Thailand.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Objective: The relationship between vitamin D and atopic dermatitis remains controversial. Here, we systematically reviewed and meta-analyzed the association between serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D concentration (25(OH) D) and atopic dermatitis (AD), AD severity, and the benefits of oral vitamin D supplementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off topic: Caesarean section increases risk of Eczema (Atopic dermatitis) by 1.8 X</title><link>/posts/off-topic-caesarean-section-increases-risk-of-eczema-atopic-dermatitis-by-18-x.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/off-topic-caesarean-section-increases-risk-of-eczema-atopic-dermatitis-by-18-x.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="atopic-dermatitis-is-associated-with-caesarean-sections-in-korean-adolescents-but-asthma-is-not">Atopic dermatitis is associated with Caesarean sections in Korean adolescents but asthma is not.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Acta Paediatr. 2015 Sep 12. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/apa.13212.">doi: 10.1111/apa.13212.&lt;/a> &lt;span>[Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yu M1, Han K2, Kim DH3, Nam GE3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Studies on the associations between mode of delivery and allergic diseases have produced different results and research has rarely been conducted in Asian countries such as South Korea. This study assessed the relationship between mode of delivery and atopic dermatitis and asthma in Korean adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis - Atopic Dermatitis protected by Omega-3</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-atopic-dermatitis-protected-by-omega-3.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-atopic-dermatitis-protected-by-omega-3.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="do-long-chain-omega-3-fatty-acids-protect-from-atopic-dermatitis">Do long-chain omega-3 fatty acids protect from atopic dermatitis?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Journal der Deutschen Dermatologischen Gesellschaft. Volume 13, Issue 9, pages 879–885, September 2015,DOI: 10.1111/ddg.12780&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Imke Reese1,* andThomas Werfel2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summary&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Long-chain polyunsaturated fatty acids are essential for human nutrition. The number of double bonds determines whether a given fatty acid is termed two, three, or x times unsaturated. Depending on the distance of the first double bond from the fatty acid&amp;rsquo;s methyl group, one distinguishes omega-3 fatty acids from omega-6 fatty acids.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Warts eliminated by vitamin D injections</title><link>/posts/warts-eliminated-by-vitamin-d-injections.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/warts-eliminated-by-vitamin-d-injections.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#40-of-warts-removed-by-300000-iu-vitamin-d-injection---rct-march-2019">40% of Warts removed by 300,000 IU Vitamin D injection - RCT March 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d3-600000-iu-injection-eliminated-periungual-warts-finger-or-toe-nails--may-2019">Vitamin D3 600,000 IU injection eliminated periungual warts (finger or toe nails)- May 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#warts-removed-by-60000-iu-vitamin-d-injection---2015">Warts removed by 60,000 IU Vitamin D injection - 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#successful-treatment-of-anogenital-wart-with-a-topical-vitamin-d3-derivative-in-an-infant--2010">Successful Treatment of Anogenital Wart with a Topical Vitamin D(3) Derivative in an Infant.- 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="40-of-warts-removed-by-300000-iu-vitamin-d-injection---rct-march-2019">40% of Warts removed by 300,000 IU Vitamin D injection - RCT March 2019&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Effectiveness of intralesional vitamin D3 injection in the treatment of common warts: single-blinded placebo-controlled study.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic Eczema might be helped by Vitamin D – Review</title><link>/posts/atopic-eczema-might-be-helped-by-vitamin-d-review.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-eczema-might-be-helped-by-vitamin-d-review.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-the-development-of-atopic-eczema">Vitamin D and the Development of Atopic Eczema&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J. Clin. Med. 2015, 4(5), 1036-1050; doi:10.3390/jcm4051036&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Debra J. Palmer&lt;/p>
&lt;p>School of Paediatrics and Child Health, The University of Western Australia, PO Box D184, Princess Margaret Hospital, Perth WA 6001, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>(This article belongs to the Special Issue Epidemiology and Treatment of Atopic Eczema)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A “vitamin D hypothesis” has been proposed to explain the increased prevalence of eczema in regions with higher latitude. This review focuses on the current available evidence with regard to the possible effect of vitamin D on the development of atopic eczema. Observational studies have indicated a link between vitamin D status and eczema outcomes, including lower serum vitamin D levels associated with increased incidence and severity of eczema symptoms. Vitamin D is known to have a regulatory influence on both the immune system and skin barrier function, both critical in the pathogenesis of eczema. However heterogeneous results have been found in studies to date investigating the effect of vitamin D status during pregnancy and infancy on the prevention of eczema outcomes. Well-designed, adequately powered, randomised controlled trials are needed. The study design of any new intervention trials should measure vitamin D levels at multiple time points during the intervention, ultraviolet (UV) radiation exposure via the use of individual UV dosimeters, and investigate the role of individual genetic polymorphisms. In conclusion, the current available evidence does not allow firm conclusions to be made on whether vitamin D status affects the development of atopic eczema.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunscreens - 80 percent are ineffective or possibly harmful</title><link>/posts/sunscreens-80-percent-are-ineffective-or-possibly-harmful.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/sunscreens-80-percent-are-ineffective-or-possibly-harmful.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="80-of-sunscreens-are-useless-or-harmful-says-ewghttpwwwmnncomhealthfitness-well-beingblogs80-of-sunscreens-are-useless-or-harmful-says-ewg-mother-nature-network">&lt;a href="http://www.mnn.com/health/fitness-well-being/blogs/80-of-sunscreens-are-useless-or-harmful-says-ewg">80% of sunscreens are useless or harmful, says EWG&lt;/a> Mother Nature Network&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="environmental-working-group-2015-guide-to-sunscreenshttpwwwewgorg2015sunscreen">&lt;a href="http://www.ewg.org/2015sunscreen/">Environmental Working Group 2015 Guide to Sunscreens&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="217-sunscreens-which-were-okhttpwwwewgorg2015sunscreenbest-sunscreensbest-beach-sport-sunscreens">&lt;a href="http://www.ewg.org/2015sunscreen/best-sunscreens/best-beach-sport-sunscreens/">217 Sunscreens which were OK&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/ways-to-block-uva-but-not-the-uvb-which-makes-vitamin-d">Ways to block UVA but not the UVB which makes vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/sunscreen-in-a-pill-with-low-spf">Sunscreen in a pill (with low SPF) &lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/melanoma-huge-increase-perhaps-due-to-use-of-sunscreen-or-lower-vitamin-d">Melanoma huge increase - perhaps due to use of sunscreen or lower vitamin D - Aug 2014&lt;/a> - free book&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/uv-spectra-of-the-sun-and-sunscreens">UV spectra of the sun and sunscreens&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Itchy skin (pruritus) due to kidney disease was treated with topical vitamin D</title><link>/posts/itchy-skin-pruritus-due-to-kidney-disease-was-treated-with-topical-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/itchy-skin-pruritus-due-to-kidney-disease-was-treated-with-topical-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-topical-vitamin-d-on-chronic-kidney-disease-associated-pruritus-an-open-label-pilot-study">Effect of topical vitamin D on chronic kidney disease-associated pruritus: An open-label pilot study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Japanese Dermatological Association, Article first published online: 28 APR 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DOI: 10.1111/1346-8138.12895&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kyung Eun Jung1, Yu Ri Woo1, Joong Sun Lee1, Jong Ho Shin2, Jin Uk Jeong2, Dae Won Koo1 andKi Tae Bang2,*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Department of Dermatology, School of Medicine, Eulji University Hospital, Daejeon, Korea&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Department of Internal Medicine (Nephrology), School of Medicine, Eulji University Hospital, Daejeon, Korea&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic Dermatitis (Eczema) in Mongolian children reduced with 1,000 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-eczema-in-mongolian-children-reduced-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-eczema-in-mongolian-children-reduced-with-1000-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="randomized-trial-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-for-winter-related-atopic-dermatitis-in-children">Randomized trial of vitamin D supplementation for winter-related atopic dermatitis in children.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2014 Oct;134(4):831-835.e1. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaci.2014.08.002.">doi: 10.1016/j.jaci.2014.08.002.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Camargo CA Jr1, Ganmaa D2, Sidbury R3, Erdenedelger Kh4, Radnaakhand N5, Khandsuren B4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, and Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, Mass. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:ccamargo@partners.org">ccamargo@partners.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, and Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, Mass; Health Sciences University of Mongolia, Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Seattle Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Seattle, Wash.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin damaged by sun helped by vitamin D supplementation - pilot study</title><link>/posts/skin-damaged-by-sun-helped-by-vitamin-d-supplementation-pilot-study.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-damaged-by-sun-helped-by-vitamin-d-supplementation-pilot-study.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="pilot-study-on-the-bioactivity-of-vitamin-d-in-the-skin-after-oral-supplementation">Pilot Study on the Bioactivity of Vitamin D in the Skin after Oral Supplementation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cancer Prevention Research 14-0280 Published OnlineFirst April 2, 2015; &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1158/1940-6207.">doi: 10.1158/1940-6207.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clara Curiel-Lewandrowski1,*, Jean Y. Tang2, Janine G. Einspahr3, Yira Bermudez4, Chiu-Hsieh Hsu5, Melika Rezaee6, Alex Hao Lee6, Joseph Tangrea7, Howard L. Parnes8, David S. Alberts9, and H-H S Chow4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Dermatology, The University of Arizona Cancer Center&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Dermatology, Stanford School of Medicine, Stanford University&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Medicine, The University of Arizona Cancer Center&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rare skin diseases (autoimmune bullous ) strongly associated with low vitamin D and is increasing</title><link>/posts/rare-skin-diseases-autoimmune-bullous-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-is-increasing.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rare-skin-diseases-autoimmune-bullous-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-is-increasing.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-and-skeletal-health-in-autoimmune-bullous-skin-diseases-a-case-control-study">Vitamin D and skeletal health in autoimmune bullous skin diseases: a case control study&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-skeletal-health-in-autoimmune-bullous-skin-diseases-a-case-control-study">Vitamin D and skeletal health in autoimmune bullous skin diseases: a case control study&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Orphanet Journal of Rare Diseases 2015, 10:8 doi:10.1186/s13023-015-0230-0&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Angelo Valerio Marzano1, Valentina Trevisan1, Elisa Cairoli23, Cristina Eller-Vainicher3, Valentina Morelli23, Anna Spada23, Carlo Crosti1 and Iacopo Chiodini 3 Iacopo Chiodini &lt;a href="mailto:iacopo.chiodini@unimi.it">iacopo.chiodini@unimi.it&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background The presence of hypovitaminosis D in patients with autoimmune bullous skin diseases, such as pemphigus vulgaris (PV) and bullous pemphigoid (BP), is debated. In a previous study we found an increased prevalence of vertebral fractures (VFx) and hypovitaminosis D in PV and BP patients. The present study extends the sample size of the previous one, for investigating the 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25OHVitD) levels in relation with the skeletal health and disease intensity in these patients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>92 percent of Burn patients had low vitamin D, 600 IU did not help</title><link>/posts/92-percent-of-burn-patients-had-low-vitamin-d-600-iu-did-not-help.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/92-percent-of-burn-patients-had-low-vitamin-d-600-iu-did-not-help.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="effect-of-cholecalciferol-recommended-daily-allowances-on-vitamin-d-status-and-fibroblast-growth-factor-23-an-observational-study-in-acute-burn-patients">Effect of cholecalciferol recommended daily allowances on vitamin D status and fibroblast growth factor-23: an observational study in acute burn patients.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Burns. 2014 Aug;40(5):865-70. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.burns.2013.11.015.">doi: 10.1016/j.burns.2013.11.015.&lt;/a> Epub 2014 Jan 23.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rousseau AF1, Damas P2, Ledoux D2, Cavalier E3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1Burn Centre and General Intensive Care Department, University of Liège, University Hospital, Sart-Tilman, Liège, Belgium. Electronic address: &lt;a href="mailto:afrousseau@chu.ulg.ac.be">afrousseau@chu.ulg.ac.be&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2Burn Centre and General Intensive Care Department, University of Liège, University Hospital, Sart-Tilman, Liège, Belgium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3Clinical Chemistry Department, University of Liège, University Hospital, Sart-Tilman, Liège, Belgium.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Evidence indicating that vitamin D deals with microorganisms in atopic dermatitis</title><link>/posts/evidence-indicating-that-vitamin-d-deals-with-microorganisms-in-atopic-dermatitis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/evidence-indicating-that-vitamin-d-deals-with-microorganisms-in-atopic-dermatitis.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="microorganism-induced-exacerbations-in-atopic-dermatitis-a-possible-preventive-role-for-vitamin-d">Microorganism-induced exacerbations in atopic dermatitis: A possible preventive role for vitamin D?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Allergy Asthma Proc. 2015 Jan;36(1):19-25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Benetti C1, Piacentini GL, Capristo C, Boner AL, Peroni DG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Life and Reproduction Sciences, Pediatric Division, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Atopic dermatitis (AD) is a common skin disease characterized by a complex pathogenesis not completely understood despite numerous studies to date. The clinical patterns result from interactions between genetic disorders determining abnormalities in the epidermis differentiation complex, modification of the cutaneous barrier, and dysfunction of immune responses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Burns, ulcers, and wounds healed by Vitamin D - many studies</title><link>/posts/burns-ulcers-and-wounds-healed-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/burns-ulcers-and-wounds-healed-by-vitamin-d-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note: Vitamin D lotions/oils applied &lt;a href="/posts/topical-vitamin-d">topically&lt;/a> will probably better than oral Vitamin D. Perhaps 100X higher concentration on burn if applied topically&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#asked-ai-are-burns-less-severe-if-the-person-has-higher-level-of-vitamin-d">Asked AI: Are burns less severe if the person has higher level of vitamin d?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burn-with-low-vitamin-d-1-day-longer-infection-3x-more-likely-when-leave-hospital---feb-2024">Burn with low Vitamin D: 1 day longer, infection 3X more likely when leave hospital - Feb 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burn-length-of-stay-in-hospital-vs-vitamin-d-level---18-vs-12-days---dec-2023">Burn length of stay in hospital vs. Vitamin D level - 18 vs 12 days - Dec 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#more-intense-burns-associated-with-lower-vitamin-d-might-low-d-cause-more-burn-sept2020">More intense burns associated with lower Vitamin D (might low D cause more burn)– Sept 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#potential-ways-vitamin-d-can-help-burns---april2019">Potential ways Vitamin D can help burns - April 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burn-centers-typically-still-do-not-test-vitamin-d-levels--survey--march2019">Burn Centers typically still do not test vitamin D levels- survey – March 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burns-with-higher-vitamin-d-have-fewer-problems---feb2019">Burns with higher vitamin D have fewer problems - Feb 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#nearly-all-burn-patients-have-low-vitamin-d-levels---may2018">Nearly all burn patients have low Vitamin D levels - May 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#50-fracture-admissions-occurred-within-7-years-of-burn-admission---sept2017">50% fracture admissions occurred within 7 years of burn admission - Sept 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burns-with-low-vitamin-d-associated-with-more-days-in-icu-and-hospital--jan2017">Burns with low vitamin D associated with more days in ICU and hospital – Jan 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bone-fractures-after-a-burn---none-if-vitamin-d-6-if-no-vitamin-d--rct-may2015">Bone fractures after a burn - none if vitamin D, 6 if no vitamin D – RCT May 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-status-after-a-high-dose-of-cholecalciferol-in-healthy-and-burnsubjects">Vitamin D status after a high dose of cholecalciferol in healthy and burn subjects&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#quarterly-vitamin-d-injections-200000-iu-helped-muscles-in-burn-patients---march2015">Quarterly Vitamin D injections (200,000 IU) helped muscles in burn patients - March 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#both-vitamins-d3-and-d2-100-iukg-provided-some-help-to-critically-ill-pediatric-burn-patients---june2015">Both vitamins D3 and D2 (100 IU/kg) provided some help to Critically Ill Pediatric Burn Patients - June 2015&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#97-of-pediatric-burn-patients-had-low-vitamin-d---feb2016">97% of pediatric burn patients had low vitamin D - Feb 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pain-6-months-after-thermal-burn-and-skin-autography-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-and-low-omega-3---march2018">Pain 6 months after thermal burn and skin autography associated with low vitamin D and low Omega-3 - March 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#burned-in-factory-explosion-8x-less-likely-to-get-infected-if-treated-with-magnesium-and-vitamins-such-as-b12---rct-nov2018">Burned in factory explosion: 8X less likely to get infected if treated with Magnesium and Vitamins such as B12 - RCT Nov 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-may-improve-wound-healing-in-burns-patients--nov2017">Vitamin D may improve wound healing in burns patients – Nov 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#diabetic-foot-ulcers-helped-by-50000-iu-weekly--rct-june2016">Diabetic foot ulcers helped by 50,000 IU weekly – RCT June 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-role-of-the-vitamin-d-receptor-in-the-epidermal-stem-cell-response-to-wounding---aug-2024">The Role of the Vitamin D Receptor in the Epidermal Stem Cell Response to Wounding - Aug 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#diabetic-foot-ulcers-healed-2x-faster-with-6400-iu-daily---rct-june2021">Diabetic foot ulcers healed 2X faster with 6,400 IU daily - RCT June 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-vitamin-d-deficiency-epidemic-pulsating-wound-jan2018">The Vitamin D Deficiency Epidemic (pulsating wound) Jan 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-for-healing-wounds--nov2014">Vitamin D for Healing Wounds – Nov 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="asked-ai-are-burns-less-severe-if-the-person-has-higher-level-of-vitamin-d">Asked AI: Are burns less severe if the person has higher level of vitamin d?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The study mentioned in 1 found that 88.9% of burn patients had a vitamin D deficiency and that wound healing time (WHT) across all three burn types was a common factor associated with vitamin D levels. Particularly, electrical burn patients with vitamin D deficiency showed prolonged wound healing over a post-burn period of 2 months.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Every person having Verneuil's disease (skin) was vitamin D deficient</title><link>/posts/every-person-having-verneuils-disease-skin-was-vitamin-d-deficient.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/every-person-having-verneuils-disease-skin-was-vitamin-d-deficient.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Raised veins on my left hand are no longer raised</title><link>/posts/raised-veins-on-my-left-hand-are-no-longer-raised.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/raised-veins-on-my-left-hand-are-no-longer-raised.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Many other anti-cancer photoproducts generated on the skin in addition to vitamin D</title><link>/posts/many-other-anti-cancer-photoproducts-generated-on-the-skin-in-addition-to-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/many-other-anti-cancer-photoproducts-generated-on-the-skin-in-addition-to-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="cytochromes-p450-and-skin-cancer-role-of-local-endocrine-pathways">Cytochromes p450 and skin cancer: role of local endocrine pathways.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Anticancer Agents Med Chem. 2014 Jan;14(1):77-96.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Slominski AT, Zmijewski MA, Semak I, Zbytek B, Pisarchik A, Li W, Zjawiony J, Tuckey RC1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Author information&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skin is the largest body organ forming a metabolically active barrier between external and internal environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The metabolic barrier is composed of cytochromes P450 (CYPs) that regulate its homeostasis through activation or inactivation of biologically relevant molecules. In this review we focus our attention on local steroidogenic and secosteroidogenic systems in relation to skin cancer, e.g., prevention, attenuation of tumor progression and therapy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVB increases vitamin D even if poor kidney by changing CYP27B1 genes in skin</title><link>/posts/uvb-increases-vitamin-d-even-if-poor-kidney-by-changing-cyp27b1-genes-in-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/uvb-increases-vitamin-d-even-if-poor-kidney-by-changing-cyp27b1-genes-in-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="a-narrow-band-ultraviolet-b-course-improves-vitamin-d-balance-and-alters-cutaneous-cyp27a1-and-cyp27b1-mrna-expression-levels-in-haemodialysis-patients-supplemented-with-oral-vitamin-d">A narrow-band ultraviolet B course improves vitamin D balance and alters cutaneous CYP27A1 and CYP27B1 mRNA expression levels in haemodialysis patients supplemented with oral vitamin D.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nephron Clin Pract. 2013;124(1-2):17-22. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1159/000355010.">doi: 10.1159/000355010.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Sep 12.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ala-Houhala MJ1, Vähävihu K, Snellman E, Hasan T, Kautiainen H, Karisola P, Dombrowski Y, Schauber J, Saha H, Reunala T.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Tampere University Hospital, Tampere, Finland&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND/AIMS:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) patients on dialysis are prone to vitamin D insufficiency despite oral vitamin D supplementation. Here, we studied whether narrow-band ultraviolet B (NB-UVB) exposures improve vitamin D balance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitiligo (loss of skin pigment) treated by narrowband UVB</title><link>/posts/vitiligo-loss-of-skin-pigment-treated-by-narrowband-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitiligo-loss-of-skin-pigment-treated-by-narrowband-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#correlation-of-vitamin-d-levels-with-pigmentation-in-vitiligo-patients-treated-with-nbuvb-therapy---july-2014">Correlation of Vitamin D Levels with Pigmentation in Vitiligo Patients Treated with NBUVB Therapy - July 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-2nd-article-in-july-2014">A 2nd article in July 2014&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-50000-iu-every-2-weeks-for-8-weeks--narrowband-uvb-treated-vitiligo---rct--jan-2018">Vitamin D (50,000 IU every 2 weeks for 8 weeks) + narrowband UVB treated vitiligo - RCT Jan 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="correlation-of-vitamin-d-levels-with-pigmentation-in-vitiligo-patients-treated-with-nbuvb-therapy---july-2014">Correlation of Vitamin D Levels with Pigmentation in Vitiligo Patients Treated with NBUVB Therapy - July 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>ISRN Dermatology, Volume 2014 (2014), Article ID 493213, 6 pages, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/493213">http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/493213&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some vitamin D remains in the skin to protect skin from the sun</title><link>/posts/some-vitamin-d-remains-in-the-skin-to-protect-skin-from-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/some-vitamin-d-remains-in-the-skin-to-protect-skin-from-the-sun.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Topical Vitamin D</title><link>/posts/topical-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/topical-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="off-label-uses-of-topical-vitamin-d-in-dermatology-a-systematic-review---2014">Off-label uses of topical vitamin d in dermatology: a systematic review - 2014&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>J Cutan Med Surg. 2014 Mar 1;18(2):91-108.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wat H, Dytoc M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background:Topical vitamin D is approved by the US Food and Drug Administration for the treatment of psoriasis but is also used off-label in the treatment of a variety of cutaneous diseases despite a lack of evidence-based guidelines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Objective:The objective of this study was to provide evidence-based clinical guidelines for the off-label use of topical vitamin D in the treatment of dermatologic disease.Methods:A systematic literature review was conducted via the MEDLINE, Embase, and CENTRAL databases for off-label uses of topical vitamin D analogues in the treatment of dermatologic disease other than psoriasis. The data were synthesized, and evidence-based recommendations were rendered according to the highest level of evidence available.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin benefits from vitamin D – major overview</title><link>/posts/skin-benefits-from-vitamin-d-major-overview.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/skin-benefits-from-vitamin-d-major-overview.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-and-the-skin-focus-on-a-complex-relationship-a-review">Vitamin D and the skin: Focus on a complex relationship: A review&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Journal of Advanced Research, Available online 8 February 2014, &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jare.2014.01.011">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jare.2014.01.011&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wedad Z. Mostafa, Rehab A. Hegazy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The “sunshine” vitamin is a hot topic that attracted ample attention over the past decades, specially that a considerable proportion of the worldwide population are deficient in this essential nutrient. Vitamin D was primarily acknowledged for its importance in bone formation, however; increasing evidence point to its interference with the proper function of nearly every tissue in our bodies including brain, heart, muscles, immune system and skin. Thereby its deficiency has been incriminated in a long panel of diseases including cancers, autoimmune diseases, cardiovascular and neurological disorders. Its involvement in the pathogenesis of different dermatological diseases is no exception and has been the subject of much research over the recent years. In the current review, we will throw light on this highly disputed vitamin that is creating a significant concern from a dermatological perspective. Furthermore, the consequences of its deficiency on the skin will be in focus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eczema not reduced in small study which used narrowband UVB to raise vitamin D levels</title><link>/posts/eczema-not-reduced-in-small-study-which-used-narrowband-uvb-to-raise-vitamin-d-levels.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/eczema-not-reduced-in-small-study-which-used-narrowband-uvb-to-raise-vitamin-d-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-levels-in-patients-with-atopic-eczema-and-the-influence-of-narrow-band-ultraviolet-b-phototherapy">Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels in patients with atopic eczema and the influence of narrow-band ultraviolet B phototherapy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Photodermatology, Photoimmunology &amp;amp; Photomedicine. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/phpp.12117">doi: 10.1111/phpp.12117&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>R F Rose MRCP*, C Williams MRCP, T Oliphant MRCP, F Browne MRCP, D Turner, V Goulden FRCP, MD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Narrow-band ultraviolet B phototherapy (nbUVB) is an established treatment modality for patients with severe atopic dermatitis (AD) and is known to increase serum vitamin D levels (SVD). The relationship between SVD and AD remains unclear.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dermatologists still not convienced that Vitamin D reduces atopic dermatitis – Review</title><link>/posts/dermatologists-still-not-convienced-that-vitamin-d-reduces-atopic-dermatitis-review.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dermatologists-still-not-convienced-that-vitamin-d-reduces-atopic-dermatitis-review.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Eczema 25 percent more likely if low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/eczema-25-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/eczema-25-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="low-vitamin-d-serum-level-is-inversely-associated-with-eczema-in-children-and-adolescents-in-germany">Low vitamin D serum level is inversely associated with eczema in children and adolescents in Germany.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Allergy. 2013 Jul;68(7):906-10. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/all.12167.">doi: 10.1111/all.12167.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Jun 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heimbeck I, Wjst M, Apfelbacher CJ.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Medical Sociology, Department of Epidemiology and Preventive Medicine, University of Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Recent studies have yielded heterogeneous results regarding the relationship between vitamin D and atopic conditions. The aim of this study was to investigate the association between serum vitamin D level and the prevalence of eczema in German children and adolescents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dermatologists view of UV radiation and the Skin</title><link>/posts/dermatologists-view-of-uv-radiation-and-the-skin.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dermatologists-view-of-uv-radiation-and-the-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="uv-radiation-and-the-skin">UV Radiation and the Skin&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2013, 14(6), 12222-12248; doi:10.3390/ijms140612222&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John D&amp;rsquo;Orazio 1,* email, Stuart Jarrett 2 email, Alexandra Amaro-Ortiz 3 email and Timothy Scott 3 email&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Graduate Center for Toxicology and the Departments of Pediatrics, Biomedical and Molecular Pharmacology and Physiology, Markey Cancer Center, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA 2 Markey Cancer Center, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA 3 Graduate Center for Toxicology, University of Kentucky College of Medicine, 800 Rose Street, Lexington, KY 40536, USA&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dr. Holick video on vitamin D</title><link>/posts/dr-holick-video-on-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dr-holick-video-on-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="holick-video-on-youtubehttpwwwyoutubecomwatchvhigbvdcbfvkfeatureyoutube">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hiGBVDcbFVk&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be">Holick Video on YouTube&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-few-images-from-another-of-his-excellent-videos">A few images from another of his excellent videos&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="other-forms-of-vitamin-d-generated">Other forms of vitamin D generated&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-other-forms-of-vitamin-d-generated.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="c-section">C-section&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-c-section.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h2 id="iguana-with-little-vitamin-d">Iguana with little vitamin D&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-iguana.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="uvb-white-skin-vs-black-skin">UVB White skin vs black skin&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/hollick-uvb-white-vs-black.jpg" alt="image" width="500">
&lt;h3 id="global-deficiency-of-vitamin-d">Global deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-global-deficiency.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="psorasis-placebo-vs-vitamin-d">Psorasis placebo vs vitamin d&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-psorasis-pacelbo-vs-vitamin-d.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="navy-indoors-8x-more-death-than-outdoors---1915">Navy indoors 8X more death than outdoors - 1915&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-navy-indoors-8x-more-death-than-outdoors---1915.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="type-1-diabetes-10x-less-at-equator">Type 1 diabetes 10X less at equator&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-type-1-diabetes-10x-less-at-equator.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="perhipheral-vascular-disease-decrease-80">Perhipheral Vascular Disease decrease 80%&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-pvd-decrease-80-.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="holick-and-his-family-take-3000-iu-vitamin-d-total-daily">Holick and his family take 3000 IU vitamin D total daily&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-3000-iu-vitamin-d-total.jpg" alt="image" width="400">
&lt;h3 id="holick-recommendations-vs-age">Holick recommendations vs age&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/holick-recommendations-vs-age.jpg" alt="image" width="400"></description></item><item><title>Expert Review by Dermatologists: get more vitamin D but avoid the sun</title><link>/posts/expert-review-by-dermatologists-get-more-vitamin-d-but-avoid-the-sun.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/expert-review-by-dermatologists-get-more-vitamin-d-but-avoid-the-sun.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-and-sun-exposure-to-bare-all-or-cover-up">Vitamin D and sun exposure: to bare all or cover up?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Editorial, Expert Review of Dermatology, December 2012, Vol. 7, No. 6, Pages 495-497 , DOI 10.1586/edm.12.60&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aaron Hughes*, Jeremy Hoffman and Adiele Hoffman&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Author for correspondence&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="they-do-not-want-to-say-that-they-have-been-wrong-for-50-years">They do not want to say that they have been wrong for 50 years&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Quote from the PDF&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Advice that encourages the public to increase sun exposure has the potential to undermine the work done by health agencies over the past 50 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5X more likely to have facial skin aging if vitamin D insufficient</title><link>/posts/5x-more-likely-to-have-facial-skin-aging-if-vitamin-d-insufficient.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/5x-more-likely-to-have-facial-skin-aging-if-vitamin-d-insufficient.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="association-of-facial-skin-aging-and-vitamin-d-levels-in-middle-aged-white-women">Association of facial skin aging and vitamin D levels in middle-aged white women.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes Control. 2010 Dec;21(12):2315-6. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10552-010-9646-y.">doi: 10.1007/s10552-010-9646-y.&lt;/a> Epub 2010 Sep 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chang AL, Fu T, Amir O, Tang JY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Stanford University School of Medicine, 450 Broadway, Pavilion C, MC 5334, Redwood City, CA 94305, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the relationship between UV-induced skin photodamage and 25(OH) vitamin D levels, we performed a cross-sectional study in 45 female subjects aged &amp;gt;40. Menopausal status, smoking status, skin cancer history, oral supplement use, and season of blood draw were recorded and serum 25(OH)D measured. A single-blinded, dermatologist evaluated standardized digital facial images for overall photodamage, erythema/telangiectasias, hyperpigmentation, number of lentigines, and wrinkling. Adjusting for age and season of blood collection, women with lower photodamage scores were associated with a 5-fold increased odds of being vitamin D insufficient (OR 5.0, 95% CI: 1.1, 23). Low scores for specific photodamage parameters including erythema/telangiectasias, hyperpigmentation, and wrinkling were also significantly associated with vitamin D insufficiency. Our results suggest an association between skin aging and 25(OH)D levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hypothesis: Extensive burns reduce vitamin D, which increase bone loss</title><link>/posts/hypothesis-extensive-burns-reduce-vitamin-d-which-increase-bone-loss.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/hypothesis-extensive-burns-reduce-vitamin-d-which-increase-bone-loss.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="does-vitamin-d-deficiency-contribute-to-post-burn-bone-loss">Does vitamin D deficiency contribute to post-burn bone loss?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://f1000research.com/articles/does-vitamin-d-deficiency-contribute-to-post-burn-bone-loss/%20">URL&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gordon L Klein &lt;a href="mailto:gordonklein@ymail.com">gordonklein@ymail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation and Shriners Burns Hospital, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, Texas 77555, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burn injury results in the acute loss of bone as well as the development of progressive vitamin D deficiency. Bone loss occurs acutely due to resorption, which is then followed by apoptosis of osteoblasts preventing repair of the bone loss. The acute resorption is due to a combination of the inflammatory response and the stress response to the burn injury. The resultant production of inflammatory cytokines and endogenous glucocorticoids initially stimulate the osteoblasts to produce RANK ligand, which stimulates marrow stem cell differentiation into osteoclasts. As the stress response persists for approximately one year post-burn the glucocorticoids produced by the body will cause osteoblast apoptosis and adynamic bone, impairing the ability of bone to recover its resorptive losses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vitamin D aids the aging skin</title><link>/posts/vitamin-d-aids-the-aging-skin.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/vitamin-d-aids-the-aging-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="unravelling-of-hidden-secrets-the-role-of-vitamin-d-in-skin-aging">Unravelling of hidden secrets: the role of vitamin D in skin aging&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Dermato Endochronology Volume 4, Issue 3 July/August/September 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jörg Reichrath &lt;a href="mailto:Joerg.Reichrath@uks.eu">Joerg.Reichrath@uks.eu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Klinik für Dermatologie; Venerologie und Allergologie; Universitätsklinikum des Saarlandes; Homburg/Saar, Germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The skin is the only tissue in the human body that represents both a target tissue for biologically active vitamin D compounds including 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25(OH)2D) and has the capacity for the synthesis of 1,25(OH)2D from 7-dehydrocholesterol (7-DHC). Recent findings indicate that the vitamin D endocrine system (VDES), besides multiple other important functions, regulates aging in many tissues, including skin. This concept is strongly supported by several independent studies in genetically modified mice (including FGF23?/? and Klotho?/? mice) that are characterized by altered mineral homeostasis caused by a high vitamin D activity. These mice typically have phenotypic features of premature aging that include, besides short lifespan, retarded growth, ectopic calcification, immunological deficiency, osteoporosis, atherosclerosis, hypogonadism, skin and general organ atrophy. Notably, it has been demonstrated that these phenotypic features can be reversed by normalizing mineral homeostasis and/or vitamin D status. Interestingly, the aging phenotypes of mice suffering from hypovitaminosis D (VDR?/? and CYP27B1?/? mice) are quite similar to those suffering from hypervitaminosis D (including FGF-23?/? and Klotho?/? mice). Consequently, it has been hypothesized that thus, both hypo- and hypervitaminosis D may enhance aging.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intense UV damages cadaver skin</title><link>/posts/intense-uv-damages-cadaver-skin.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/intense-uv-damages-cadaver-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="solar-uv-radiation-reduces-the-barrier-function-of-human-skin">Solar UV radiation reduces the barrier function of human skin&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>PNAS October 1, 2012&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Krysta Biniek, Kemal Levi, and Reinhold H. Dauskardt &lt;a href="mailto:dauskardt@stanford.edu">dauskardt@stanford.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA 94305&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Edited by John W. Hutchinson, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA, and approved August 31, 2012 (received for review April 25, 2012)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ubiquitous presence of solar UV radiation in human life is essential for vitamin D production but also leads to skin photoaging, damage, and malignancies. Photoaging and skin cancer have been extensively studied, but the effects of UV on the critical mechanical barrier function of the outermost layer of the epidermis, the stratum corneum (SC), are not understood. The SC is the first line of defense against environmental exposures like solar UV radiation, and its effects on UV targets within the SC and subsequent alterations in the mechanical properties and related barrier function are unclear. Alteration of the SC’s mechanical properties can lead to severe macroscopic skin damage such as chapping and cracking and associated inflammation, infection, scarring, and abnormal desquamation. Here, we show that UV exposure has dramatic effects on cell cohesion and mechanical integrity that are related to its effects on the SC’s intercellular components, including intercellular lipids and corneodesmosomes. We found that, although the keratin-controlled stiffness remained surprisingly constant with UV exposure, the intercellular strength, strain, and cohesion decreased markedly. We further show that solar UV radiation poses a double threat to skin by both increasing the biomechanical driving force for damage while simultaneously decreasing the skin’s natural ability to resist, compromising the critical barrier function of the skin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Women around the world want whiter skin</title><link>/posts/women-around-the-world-want-whiter-skin.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/women-around-the-world-want-whiter-skin.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="many-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic-postsmany-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic-aug-2012">&lt;a href="/posts/many-reasons-why-vitamin-d-deficiency-has-become-epidemic">Many reasons why vitamin D deficiency has become epidemic &lt;/a> Aug 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Want whiter skin - especially women&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://innerreflectionstranscribed.wordpress.com/2007/04/25/fair-skin-desirable/">Here&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=K8PCYtg1SocC&amp;amp;pg=PT81&amp;amp;lpg=PT81&amp;amp;dq=desirability+of+white+skin&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=CI7w34zn6X&amp;amp;sig=2ma4FM-zouS59Afbz4tggXdxUNI&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ei=eaTaTbniI4HGsAOz0dGFDA&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;oi=book_result&amp;amp;ct=result&amp;amp;resnum=5&amp;amp;ved=0CDQQ6AEwBA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=desirability%20of%20white%20skin&amp;amp;f=false">Here (Helen of Troy)&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.abcdlady.com/2005-07/art6.php">Being Fair-Skinned in Today&amp;rsquo;s World&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/suntan-popularity-is-fading">Suntan: Popularity is fading&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/perhaps-not-burn-from-the-sun-if-have-enough-vitamin-d">Perhaps not burn from the sun if have enough vitamin D&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/09/23/thai-vulva-bleaching-product.html">Thai vulva-bleaching product&lt;/a> Sept 2012&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In many countries across south-east Asia, fairer skin has long been equated with higher class as it suggests a life not spent toiling in rice paddies under the sun. The Thai language is peppered with cultural expressions that denigrate dark skin, such as the insult dam mhuen e-ga – &amp;ldquo;black like a crow&amp;rdquo;. These days, rice farmers wear long sleeves, trousers, wide-brimmed hats and gloves&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic dermatitis dramatically reduced in Iran with 1600 IU of vitamin D – RCT</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-dramatically-reduced-in-iran-with-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-dramatically-reduced-in-iran-with-1600-iu-of-vitamin-d-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-in-the-treatment-of-atopic-dermatitis-a-clinical-trial-study">Vitamin D supplementation in the treatment of atopic dermatitis: a clinical trial study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Amestejani M, Salehi BS, Vasigh M, Sobhkhiz A, Karami M, Alinia H, Kamrava SK, Shamspour J Drugs Dermatol. 2012 Mar;11(3):327-30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N, Ghalehbaghi B, Behzadi AH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Orumieh University of Medical Science, Orumieh, Iran.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of vitamin D in Atopic Dermatitis (AD) is ambiguous and clinical trials are needed to assess the role of vitamin D in the treatment of AD. The aim of this clinical trial study to evaluate the effect of vitamin D supplementation on patients with AD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Possible DNA damage of skin if vitamin D levels less than 20 nanograms</title><link>/posts/possible-dna-damage-of-skin-if-vitamin-d-levels-less-than-20-nanograms.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/possible-dna-damage-of-skin-if-vitamin-d-levels-less-than-20-nanograms.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="sunlight-and-vitamin-d-affect-dna-damage-cell-division-and-cell-death-in-human-lymphocytes-a-cross-sectional-study-in-south-australia">Sunlight and vitamin D affect DNA damage, cell division and cell death in human lymphocytes: a cross-sectional study in South Australia&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Visalini Nair-Shalliker1,2,visalinin@nswcc.org.au, Michael Fenech3, Peta M. Forder4,5, Mark S. Clements6,7 and Bruce K. Armstrong1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Sydney School of Public Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales 2006, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 Cancer Epidemiology Research Unit, Cancer Council New South Wales, Sydney, New South Wales 2011, Australia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 CSIRO Food and Nutritional Sciences, PO Box 10041, Adelaide, South Australia 5000, Australia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Burned skin produces only about 25 percent as much vitamin D</title><link>/posts/burned-skin-produces-only-about-25-percent-as-much-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/burned-skin-produces-only-about-25-percent-as-much-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="progress-in-understanding-the-calcium-and-vitamin-d-endocrinology-following-burn-injury-in-children-march-2012">Progress in Understanding the Calcium and Vitamin D Endocrinology Following Burn Injury in Children (March 2012)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>International journal of Endocrinology and Metabolism; DOI: 10.5812/ijem.2685&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gordon L Klein, &lt;a href="mailto:gordonklein@ymail.com">gordonklein@ymail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation Department, Medical Staff, Shriners Burns Hospital, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, Texas, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This review covers the progress made by our group over the past two decades in understanding the effects of severe burn injuries on the endocrine system, especially in relation to calcium and vitamin D metabolism.We examine the phenomena of transient growth hormone deficiency and the dose-dependent effects of recombinant human growth hormone on bone and muscle mass. We move on to discuss the occurrence of post-burn secondary hypoparathyroidism caused by the up-regulation of the parathyroid calcium-sensing receptor, and finally, we discuss vitamin D status, the progressive nature of vitamin D deficiency post-burn, the causes of the progressive deficiency, and what must be done to prevent it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic Dermatitis and Eczema - many studies</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-and-eczema-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-and-eczema-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#atopic-dermatitis-reduced-if-add-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-nov-2024">Atopic Dermatitis reduced if add Vitamin D - meta-analysis Nov 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#food-and-mite-allergies-strongly-associated-with-low-vitamin-d---april-2024">Food and mite allergies strongly associated with low vitamin D - April 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#how-to-prevent-atopic-dermatitis-eczema-in-2024-theory-and-evidence--april-2024">How to prevent Atopic Dermatitis (Eczema) in 2024: theory and evidence – April 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#efficacy-of-vitamin-d-supplementation-on-the-severity-of-atopic-dermatitis-in-children-a-systematic-review-and-meta-analysis---sept-2023">Efficacy of vitamin D supplementation on the severity of atopic dermatitis in children: A systematic review and meta-analysis - Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#worse-atopic-dermatitis-is-associated-with-lower-vitamin-d--sept-2023">Worse Atopic Dermatitis is associated with lower vitamin D – Sept 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#atopic-dermatitis-8-ng-lower-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-aug-2022">Atopic Dermatitis: 8 ng lower vitamin D - meta-analysis Aug 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#atopic-dermatitis-5x-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d---aug-2019">Atopic Dermatitis 5X more likely if low Vitamin D - Aug 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#atopic-dermatitis-treated-by-vitamin-d--review-of-micronutrients--march-2019">Atopic Dermatitis: treated by Vitamin D – Review of Micronutrients – March 2019&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#atopic-dermatitis-treatment-needs-more-than-5000-iu-of-vitamin-d--rct-sept-2018">Atopic dermatitis treatment needs more than 5,000 IU of Vitamin D – RCT Sept 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#atopic-dermatitis-reduced-by-5000-iu-of-vitamin-d-for-12-weeks--rct-dec-2018">Atopic Dermatitis reduced by 5,000 IU of Vitamin D for 12 weeks – RCT Dec 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#increased-risk-of-ad-etc-if-poor-vitamin-d-receptor-or-cyp24a1-gene---june-2023">Increased risk of AD, etc if poor vitamin D Receptor or CYP24A1 gene - June 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-fights-many-skin-diseases-topical-form-might-be-best">Vitamin D fights many skin diseases, topical form might be best&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#randomized-controlled-trial-using-vitamins-e-and-d-supplementation-in-atopic-dermatitis---july-2011">Randomized controlled trial using vitamins E and D supplementation in atopic dermatitis - July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#what-is-the-difference-between-atopic-dermatitis-and-eczema">What is the difference between atopic dermatitis and eczema?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#types-of-eczema">Types of eczema&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#seborrheic-dermatitis-42x-more-likely-if-30-ng-of-vitamin-d---feb-2021">Seborrheic Dermatitis 4.2X more likely if &amp;lt;30 ng of Vitamin D - Feb 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#typical-eczema-sites-on-body-scratching---images-from-web">Typical Eczema sites on body, scratching - images from web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="atopic-dermatitis-reduced-if-add-vitamin-d---meta-analysis-nov-2024">Atopic Dermatitis reduced if add Vitamin D - meta-analysis Nov 2024&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Vitamin D Supplementation for Treating Atopic Dermatitis in Children and Adults: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Natural ways to prevent a sunburn – 2011, 2016</title><link>/posts/natural-ways-to-prevent-a-sunburn-2011-2016.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/natural-ways-to-prevent-a-sunburn-2011-2016.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#how-to-treat-sunburn-naturally---2016">How to Treat Sunburn Naturally - 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#8-natural-ways-to-prevent-a-sunburn-and-sunscreens-not-one-of-them--july-2011">8 Natural Ways to Prevent a Sunburn (And Sunscreen’s Not One of Them) July 2011&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h4 id="how-to-treat-sunburn-naturally---2016">How to Treat Sunburn Naturally - 2016&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sunburn.aspx?utm_source=dnl&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=secon&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20160727Z1_NB&amp;amp;et_cid=DM112183&amp;amp;et_rid=1591593821">Mercola&lt;/a> excellent long article on all aspects of safe sun&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Home Remedy Recipes to Treat and Soothe Sunburns&lt;/strong> includes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aloe vera, Honey - Vinegar -Coriander oil - Green tea - Strawberries -Cucumbers Lettuce Calendula&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Opt for natural and safe alternatives to sunscreens&lt;/strong> :&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Another activator of vitamin D is the skin</title><link>/posts/another-activator-of-vitamin-d-is-the-skin.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/another-activator-of-vitamin-d-is-the-skin.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>For small amounts of sunshine the amount of skin exposed may not matter</title><link>/posts/for-small-amounts-of-sunshine-the-amount-of-skin-exposed-may-not-matter.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/for-small-amounts-of-sunshine-the-amount-of-skin-exposed-may-not-matter.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="interdependence-between-body-surface-area-and-ultraviolet-b-dose-in-vitamin-d-production-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Interdependence between body surface area and ultraviolet B dose in vitamin D production: a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Br J Dermatol. 2011 Jan;164(1):163-9. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.10082.x.">doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.10082.x.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bogh MK, Schmedes AV, Philipsen PA, Thieden E, Wulf HC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Dermatology, Copenhagen University Hospital, Bispebjerg Bakke 23, DK-2400 Copenhagen NV, Denmark. &lt;a href="mailto:bogh@dadlnet.dk">bogh@dadlnet.dk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Ultraviolet (UV) B radiation increases serum vitamin D level expressed as 25-hydroxyvitamin-D(3) &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span>, but the relationship to body surface area and UVB dose needs investigation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shingles and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/shingles-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shingles-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Summary: Vitamin D and Magnesium both treat shingles&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Shingles worse with low vitamin D, low UV, high latitude, and winter&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Treating shingles with Vitamin D or UV lowers the pain&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Treating shingles with Vitamin D almost eliminates the risk of recurrence&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vitamin D has even been patented to help with shingles&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A patent is always a good sign that it probably works&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.cdc.gov/shingles/surveillance.html">Shingles incidence is slowly increasing&lt;/a> CDC&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/shingles-cdc.jpg" alt="image" width="600">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2X increase in younger age-groups&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>70 percent of some skin problems resolved with 7100 IU vitamin D (50000 weekly)</title><link>/posts/70-percent-of-some-skin-problems-resolved-with-7100-iu-vitamin-d-50000-weekly.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/70-percent-of-some-skin-problems-resolved-with-7100-iu-vitamin-d-50000-weekly.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="idiopathic-itch-rash-and-urticariaangioedema-merit-serum-vitamin-d-evaluation-a-descriptive-case-series">Idiopathic itch, rash, and urticaria/angioedema merit serum vitamin D evaluation: a descriptive case series.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>W V Med J. 2011 Jan-Feb;107(1):14-20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Idiopathic itch, rash, and urticaria/angioedema merit serum vitamin D evaluation: a descriptive case series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goetz DW.; Exemplar Allergy &amp;amp; Asthma, Morgantown, WV, USA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D insufficiency is epidemic. Rarely are cutaneous consequences attributed to low vitamin D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS: A retrospective case series of 63 patients describes an association of pruritus, rash, and urticaria/angioedema with low 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25&lt;span>[OH]&lt;/span>D &amp;lt;32 ng/mL). The 90% (57/63) of patients with low vitamin D were treated with &lt;strong>8 to 12 weeks of vitamin D 50,000 IU weekly&lt;/strong> followed by daily supplementation. Concurrent diagnoses were treated routinely. Complete resolution of cutaneous symptoms defined response.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Patent granted for adding vitamin D to sunblock and skin cream</title><link>/posts/patent-granted-for-adding-vitamin-d-to-sunblock-and-skin-cream.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/patent-granted-for-adding-vitamin-d-to-sunblock-and-skin-cream.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="virtually-the-entire-world-recognizes-that-sunblock-greatly-reduces-the-amount-of-vitamin-d-you-can-get-from-the-sun">Virtually the entire world recognizes that sunblock greatly reduces the amount of vitamin D you can get from the sun.&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="avidas-pharmaceuticals-has-been-granted-an-international-patent-to-add-vitamin-d-to-sunscreen-lotions-and-skin-lotions">AVIDAS PHARMACEUTICALS has been granted an international patent to add vitamin D to sunscreen lotions and skin lotions.&lt;/h4>
&lt;h3 id="wo2011017380-therapeutic-vitamin-d-sun-protecting-formulations-and-methods-for-their-usehttpwwwwipointpctdbenwojspiaus2010044319displaystatus">&lt;a href="http://www.wipo.int/pctdb/en/wo.jsp?IA=US2010044319&amp;amp;DISPLAY=STATUS">(WO/2011/017380) THERAPEUTIC VITAMIN D SUN-PROTECTING FORMULATIONS AND METHODS FOR THEIR USE&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>^One person was unable to use the above hyperlink for some reason, so we have attached&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PDF files of the patent to the bottom of this page^&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atopic dermatitis worse for those with low vitamin D</title><link>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-worse-for-those-with-low-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/atopic-dermatitis-worse-for-those-with-low-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Acne - Accutane - vitamin A - vitamin D and suicide</title><link>/posts/acne-accutane-vitamin-a-vitamin-d-and-suicide.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/acne-accutane-vitamin-a-vitamin-d-and-suicide.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="report-of-increased-suicides-in-patients-taking-accutane-to-reduce-acne-128-of-5700">Report of increased suicides in patients taking Accutane to reduce acne (128 of 5,700)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.webmd.com/skin-problems-and-treatments/news/20101111/severe-acne-raises-suicide-risk-study-finds">http://www.webmd.com/skin-problems-and-treatments/news/20101111/severe-acne-raises-suicide-risk-study-finds&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="many-previous-reports-on-the-internet-of-accutane-causing-dental-problems--click-here-for-examplehttpwwwtopixcomforumdrugaccutanetfk9ifhr6ue7cughl">Many previous reports on the internet of Accutane causing dental problems &lt;a href="http://www.topix.com/forum/drug/accutane/TFK9IFHR6UE7CUGHL">CLICK HERE for example&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.aocd.org/skin/dermatologic_diseases/accutane.html">Accutane is a naturally occurring derivative of vitamin A&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Vitamin A is an antagonist for Vitamin D - that is, vitamin A reduces the amount of vitamin D in the body&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="so-it-appears">So it appears&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="acne-use-accutane---many-dental-cavities-birth-defects-depression-and-suicide">acne==&amp;gt; use accutane ==&amp;gt; many dental cavities, birth defects, depression, and suicide&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="which-are-all-associated-with-very-low-levels-of-vitamin-d">which are all associated with very low levels of vitamin D&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.VitaminDWiki.com/tiki-browse_categories.php?parentId=16&amp;amp;sort_mode=created_desc">Dental and D&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview Skin and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/overview-skin-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/overview-skin-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="from-the-sun">From the Sun&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="/attachments/d3.mock.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;h3 id="notes-on-what-should-be-on-this-page">Notes on what should be on this page&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Number of minutes: vs latitude, season, etc&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suntan oil reduces the reflection - so as to reduce by about 50% the number of minutes needed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Noontime sun&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D &amp;amp; poorly understood other photo products from UVB&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UVB and UVA spectrum&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Very little UVB after your shadow is longer than you are&lt;/p>
&lt;p>get 1/4 dose needed to get pink skin the next day&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low Vitamin D strongly associated with Systemic Sclerosis - many studies</title><link>/posts/low-vitamin-d-strongly-associated-with-systemic-sclerosis-many-studies.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/low-vitamin-d-strongly-associated-with-systemic-sclerosis-many-studies.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#systemic-sclerosis-described-by-gpt-4---march-2023">Systemic Sclerosis described by GPT-4 - March 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamindwiki-sometimes-autoimmune-diseases-generate-vitamin-d-antibodies---jan-2025postssometimes-autoimmune-diseases-generate-vitamin-d-antibodies">VitaminDWiki: &lt;a href="/posts/sometimes-autoimmune-diseases-generate-vitamin-d-antibodies">Sometimes Autoimmune diseases generate Vitamin D antibodies - Jan 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#systemic-sclerosis-and-vitamin-d-meta-analysis---oct-2024">Systemic Sclerosis and vitamin D meta-analysis - Oct 2024&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-is-the-most-common-deficiency-with-systemic-sclerosis---dec-2022">Vitamin D is the most common deficiency with Systemic Sclerosis - Dec 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-in-systemic-sclerosis-a-review---sept-2022">Vitamin D in Systemic Sclerosis: A Review - Sept 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#systemic-sclerosis-review-ss-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-nov-2021">Systemic Sclerosis review (SS associated with low Vitamin D) Nov 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#systemic-sclerosis-and-vitamin-d-literature-review-97-had-20-ng-jan-2017">Systemic sclerosis and Vitamin D literature review (97% had &amp;lt;20 ng)– Jan 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#systemic-sclerosis-and-low-vitamin-d--june-2016">Systemic sclerosis and low vitamin D – June 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#systemic-sclerosis-vit-d-low-varied-with-season-not-change-with-1000-iu--june-2017">Systemic sclerosis Vit D: Low, varied with season, not change with 1,000 IU – June 2017&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#raynauds--systemic-sclerosis-gi-etc---2016">Raynaud’s ==&amp;gt; Systemic Sclerosis, GI, etc - 2016&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#11900-studies-of-systemic-sclerosis-vitamin-d--in-google-scholar-as-of-march-2025">11,900 studies of &amp;ldquo;Systemic Sclerosis&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;vitamin d&amp;rdquo; in Google Scholar as of March 2025&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-web">See also web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="systemic-sclerosis-described-by-gpt-4---march-2023">Systemic Sclerosis described by GPT-4 - March 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Systemic sclerosis, also known as systemic scleroderma, is a rare autoimmune disorder characterized by the overproduction of collagen, which leads to the hardening and thickening of connective tissues in the body. This chronic condition affects multiple organs and systems, including the skin, blood vessels, muscles, and internal organs like the heart, lungs, kidneys, and gastrointestinal tract.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wrinkles and UVB</title><link>/posts/wrinkles-and-uvb.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wrinkles-and-uvb.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#middle-aged-wrinkles-56-x-more-likely-if-insufficient-vitamin-d---2010">Middle-aged wrinkles 5.6 X more likely if insufficient Vitamin D - 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#clippings-from-the-web-march-2010">Clippings from the web  March 2010&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-vitamindwiki">See also VitaminDWiki&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="middle-aged-wrinkles-56-x-more-likely-if-insufficient-vitamin-d---2010">Middle-aged wrinkles 5.6 X more likely if insufficient Vitamin D - 2010&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Association of facial skin aging and vitamin D levels in middle-aged white women&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anne Lynn S. Chang, Teresa Fu, Omar Amir &amp;amp; Jean Y. Tang&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cancer Causes &amp;amp; Control volume 21, pages2315–2316 (2010)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>t&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To investigate the relationship between UV-induced skin photodamage and 25(OH) vitamin D levels, we performed a cross-sectional study in 45 female subjects aged &amp;gt;40. Menopausal status, smoking status, skin cancer history, oral supplement use, and season of blood draw were recorded and serum 25(OH)D measured. A single-blinded, dermatologist evaluated standardized digital facial images for overall photodamage, erythema/telangiectasias, hyperpigmentation, number of lentigines, and wrinkling. Adjusting for age and season of blood collection, women with lower photodamage scores were associated with a 5-fold increased odds of being vitamin D insufficient (OR 5.0, 95% CI: 1.1, 23). Low scores for specific photodamage parameters including erythema/telangiectasias, hyperpigmentation, and wrinkling were also significantly associated with vitamin D insufficiency. Our results suggest an association between skin aging and 25(OH)D levels.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>