<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Consensus on VitaminDWiki</title><link>//localhost:1313/categories/consensus.html</link><description>Recent content in Consensus on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/consensus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2,000 IU of Vitamin D is safe and somewhat effective for all adults</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-safe-and-somewhat-effective-for-all-adults.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/2000-iu-of-vitamin-d-is-safe-and-somewhat-effective-for-all-adults.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#vitamin-d-supplementation-a-review-of-the-evidence-arguing-for-a-daily-dose-of-2000-international-units-50-ug-of-vitamin-d-for-adults-in-the-general-population">Vitamin D Supplementation: A Review of the Evidence Arguing for a Daily Dose of 2000 International Units (50 ug) of Vitamin D for Adults in the General Population&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction">Introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#current-vitamin-d-guidelines">Current Vitamin D Guidelines&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#safety-of-a-daily-vitamin-d-supplementation-with-2000-iu-50-ug">Safety of a Daily Vitamin D Supplementation with 2000 IU (50 ug)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#evidence-arguing-for-a-target-serum-25ohd-concentration-of-75-nmoll-30-ngml">Evidence Arguing for a Target Serum 25(OH)D Concentration of 75 nmol/L (30 ng/mL)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#cashman-kd-global-differences-in-vitamin-d-status-and-dietary-intake-a-review-of-the-data-endocr-connect-202111-e210282-crossref">While we cannot definitely claim causality for vitamin D and various extraskeletal diseases, the overall conclusion on the relationship between serum 25(OH)D and various health outcomes based on observational studies is that serum 25(OH)D concentrations above 75 nmol/L (30 ng/mL) are superior to concentrations from 50 to 75 nmol/L (20 to 30 ng/mL) for most c(inical endpoints [65]. The exception for this is vitamin D requirements for the prevention of rickets and osteomalacia that are met at lower 25(OH)D concentra­tions with conservative estimates of about 30 nmol/L (12 ng/mL), although there is also controversy on whether higher levels may be required [5,10]. Thus, the optimal serum 25(OH)D concentration may vary depending on the outcome studied and the population. Some evidence suggests that particularly high 25(OH)D levels may be ideal for certain health outcomes [65,70]. For example, data from the Vitamin D and Type 2 Diabetes (D2d) RCT suggest that based on intra-trial 25(OH)D concentrations, levels of &amp;gt;100 nmol/L (40 ng/mL) may be optimal to reduce the risk of diabetes in persons with prediabetes [71].
Serum 25(OH)D concentrations of &amp;gt;40 ng/mL (100 nmol/L) or even higher might also be optimal for other health outcomes such as cancer [72,73].
The scientific debate on optimal target concentrations for serum 25(OH)D is, of course, based on risk-benefit considerations, but the argument to not target 75 nmol/L (30 ng/mL) due to safety concerns is, in our opinion, no longer as justified, as it was, and has been acknowledged in previously published vitamin D guidelines [31,42]. Consequently, more weight and attention in this discussion should be paid to the potential extraskeletal health effects of vitamin D, which may require higher 25(OH)D levels than those established for skeletal health. Apart from the above-described epidemiological data that are in line with target concentrations for 25(OH)D of at least 75 nmol/L (30 ng/mL), there are also some findings from RCTs that support relatively high vitamin D doses [19,20,26,27,74-78]. However, regarding vitamin D RCTs, it must be stressed that one of the major limitations of large vitamin D trials was the inclusion of mainly vitamin D-sufficient individuals who were allowed to take vitamin D supplements in addition to the study medication [60,79,80]. Nevertheless, we wish to emphasize that there are several data from RCTs, observational, and molecular studies supporting a beneficial role of vitamin D for various extraskeletal diseases such as cancer, respiratory infections, autoimmune/inflammatory diseases, or diabetes mellitus requiring relatively high vitamin D doses [71,75,76,81,82]. In this context, we are well aware that the high number of RCTs and their post-hoc analyses may probably increase the &amp;ldquo;false positive&amp;rdquo; findings, i.e., formally statistically significant results indicating beneficial vitamin D effects; therefore, we must be cautious with the interpretation of such findings [83,84].
An additional argument for a target 25(OH)D level of at least 75 nmol/L (30 ng/mL) is that there is substantial variation regarding the precision of laboratory methods quan­tifying serum 25(OH)D [85,86]. Targeting a serum concentration of at least 75 nmol/L (30 ng/mL) would, therefore, guarantee that almost all individuals have a 25(OH)D level above 50 nmol/L (20 ng/mL), even if test procedures are used, which overestimate cir­culating 25(OH)D. The huge individual differences in the response to vitamin D supple­mentation, evidenced by the molecular effects on vitamin D target genes, could also be considered as supporting higher vitamin D doses to meet the vitamin D requirements of all individuals [87-90].
We reiterate that in clinical routine, particular attention should be paid to obese individ­uals who require higher vitamin D doses to increase their serum 25(OH)D concentrations as compared to lean persons and to patients with malabsorption syndromes, such as, e.g., patients suffering from inflammatory bowel diseases, who may also require much higher vitamin D dosages to achieve their serum 25(OH)D target concentrations [91,92]. For exam­ple, after two years of supplementing 2000IU (50ug) of vitamin D per day in the VITAL trial, the multivariable-adjusted mean serum 25(OH)D concentrations in individuals with a body mass index of &amp;lt;25.0,25.0-29.9,30.0-34.9, and &amp;gt;35.0 kg/m2 were 110,103, 98, and 92 nmol/L (44.0,41.2, 39.4 and 37.0 ng/mL), respectively, indicating a highly significant treatment effect interaction by body mass index (p &amp;lt; 0.001) [93]. In a meta-analysis of RCTs evaluating the effect of body weight on increases in serum 25(OH)D, the vitamin D dose per body weight explained 34.5% of the variation in 25(OH)D [94]. Patients with inflammatory bowel disease have significantly lower serum 25(OH)D levels compared to matched controls (e.g., 47 versus 62 nmol/L (18.9 versus 25 ng/mL) in one study), in particular during episodes with high disease activity [95,96]. In one vitamin D RCT in 143 patients with inflammatory bowel diseases treated with 25,000 IU (625ug) once weekly (corresponding to 3571 IU (89ug) per day), the mean serum 25(OH)D concentrations after 26 weeks was only 81 nmol/L (32.5 ng/mL) in the intervention group [97]. Medications such as antiepileptic drugs that may interfere with vitamin D metabolism may also alter vitamin D status, with one meta-analysis documenting that serum 25(OH)D concentrations were 10 nmol/L (4 ng/mL) lower in patients taking carbamazepine versus controls [98].
Although it is beyond the scope of this present review, there is accumulating evidence and ongoing research on other forms of vitamin D treatment (e.g., calcifediol) or other administration routes (e.g., intramuscularly) that may be useful for certain individuals as reviewed elsewhere [99,100]. Regarding the form of vitamin D that is used for supplemen­tation, we recommend vitamin D3 (cholecalciferol) rather than vitamin D2 (ergocalciferol), as the evidence for treatment efficacy is superior for vitamin D3 and it is also more efficient in increasing serum 25(OH)D concentrations [101,102].
!!!!Practical and Pragmatic Considerations
There are also some practical and pragmatic considerations underpinning the notion that a daily vitamin D supplemental dose of 2000 IU (50 ug) is a reasonable approach to prevent and treat vitamin D deficiency Using conventional vitamin D doses such as 600 to 800 IU (15 to 20 ug) may, for many individuals, not even be sufficient to achieve the conser­vative target concentration of at least 50 nmol/L (20 ng/mL) when considering the wide inter-individual dose response according to IPD meta-regression analyses and when taking into account the multiple clinical factors such as obesity, malabsorption syndromes (that may not always be already diagnosed), or medications that impair vitamin D metabolism (e.g., antiepileptic drugs) that all require higher vitamin D doses [35,93,98,103,104]. Clin­icians who strictly adhere to nutritional vitamin D guidelines may thus not sufficiently treat their patients with vitamin D supplements when always adhering to conservative dosing regimens not exceeding 800 IU (20 ug) of vitamin D per day [31]. We suggest that clinicians treat vitamin D deficiency of their patients with a supplemental dose that can be either 2000 IU (50 ug) per day as a one-size-fits-all dose or, if they prefer this, that they can tailor the vitamin D dosage according to the patient needs and characteristics as a means of personalized treatment with a dosing range from 800 to 2000 IU (20 to 50 ug). Such an approach may also better meet the preferences of physicians, as we learned from personal unpublished communications from many colleagues. In our own experience, many clini­cians have argued that conservative doses such as 800 IU (20 ug) per day were not sufficient to achieve 25(OH)D target levels, and they have thus occasionally proceeded with much higher and potentially harmful vitamin D doses (e.g., &amp;gt;4000 IU (&amp;gt;100 ug) per day) [49,105]. Setting a sufficiently high but not overwhelming vitamin D dosing recommendation with 2000 IU (50 ug) per day may, therefore, also provide helpful guidance in this regard and potentially reduce overdosing of vitamin D.
The seasonal variation in vitamin D status with higher 25(OH)D levels in summer and lower levels in winter is significantly mitigated by the storage and release of vitamin D metabolites from tissues like the musculature and adipose tissue [3,106-108]. Because the large vitamin D RCTs addressing clinical endpoints did not adjust their dose according to season and given that the seasonal variability in serum 25(OH)D may also have a huge interindividual variability with some individuals having almost no seasonal changes in 25(OH)D, we recommend a consistent (identical) vitamin D dose throughout the year [109].
We are well aware that there exist differences between nutritional guidelines to estab­lish dietary nutrient intakes and clinical guidelines that aim to inform physicians. However, without diving into discussions on guideline frameworks and their applications, we wish to stress that accumulating evidence on the safety and efficacy of vitamin D has to be con­sidered in what we, as physicians, but also well-informed non-healthcare experts should be “allowed&amp;rdquo; to recommend and take as a means to prevent and treat vitamin D deficiency, i.e., 2000 IU (50 ug) of vitamin D per day, without being blamed for deviating from health authority guidelines [33,34,110].
We agree that the best way to achieve a sufficient vitamin D status is a healthy lifestyle, including an optimal diet combined with normal body weight, sufficient physical activity (that may per se mobilize vitamin D metabolites from its body stores), and moderate sunlight exposure [111-113]. Improving and optimizing vitamin D status using such an approach should always be prioritized and incorporated into any recommendation. However, we must accept the very high prevalence of vitamin D deficiency and offer simple, safe, and effective approaches to addressing this vitamin D pandemic, i.e., vitamin D supplementation with effective and safe dosages. Apart from this, we are also strong proponents of systematic vitamin D food fortification, but this has not yet been introduced in the majority of countries and may not completely erase vitamin D deficiency [45].
!!!!Conclusions
In this brief narrative review, we have outlined and discussed the evidence arguing for a vitamin D supplementation dose of 2000IU (50ug) per day as an efficient and safe approach to prevent and treat vitamin D deficiency (see Table 1).
&lt;strong>Table 1. Main arguments supporting a vitamin D supplement dose of 2000 IU (50 ug) per day for the prevention and treatment of vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/strong>
*Previous publications and guidelines may have partially underestimated the vitamin D requirements to achieve certain target serum 25(OH)D concentrations.
*The high safety of a daily vitamin D supplementation dose of 2000 IU (50ug) has been well established by recent RCT data documenting this over several years of treatment.
*Clinical studies support a serum 25(OH)D concentration of 75 nmol/L (30 ng/mL) and higher as the optimal level.
*Some RCT data support clinical extraskeletal benefits of vitamin D supplementation with 2000 (IU) (50ug) per day.
** IU = international units; &lt;del>hs&lt;/del> 25(OH)D = 25-hydroxyvitamin D;&lt;del>hs&lt;/del> RCT = randomized controlled trial
Considering the evidence outlined and discussed in this brief review, it appears reasonable to consider recommending a daily vitamin D supplement dose of 2000 IU (50 ug) to prevent and treat vitamin D deficiency in the general adult population [39-41,43,65]. Such a recommendation is supported by the Endocrine Society clinical practice guideline for evaluating, treating, and preventing vitamin D deficiency, and newer evidence is now reinforcing these older clinical practice recommendations [33]. As we have the impression that the evidence underpinning recommendations for 2000 IU (50 ug) per day is not (yet) well recognized in the scientific literature and the currently published vitamin D guidelines, we drafted this review with the aim that it may serve as a basis for considerations regarding future national health authority guidelines for vitamin D. We are well aware that our work is only a narrative expert review lacking a pre-registered systematic review. We, therefore, have to acknowledge this as a limitation.
Finally, we emphasize that the worldwide prevalence of serum 25(OH)D below 25/30 nmol/L (10/12 ng/mL) and below 50 nmol/L (20 ng/mL) ranges from about 5 to 18% and 24 to 49%, respectively, thereby underscoring the need for actions that aim to reduce the burden of vitamin D deficiency [114]. There exists no &amp;ldquo;one size fits all&amp;rdquo; approach for vitamin D supplementation, but as long as individualized approaches, including base­line and follow-up measurements of serum 25(OH)D, are not feasible and cost-effective, we believe that it appears reasonable to recommend a daily dose of vitamin D with 2000 IU (50ug) when someone asks for advice regarding an effective and safe vitamin D dosage that prevents and treats vitamin D deficiency. A more conservative and personalized approach may suggest a daily vitamin D dose in the range of 800 to 2000 IU (20 to 50ug) according to the individual needs with characteristics such as very low serum 25(OH)D, obesity, or malabsorption syndromes arguing for the higher end of this dosing range and vice versa.
!!!!!114 References
#Bouillon, R.; Marcocci, C.; Carmeliet, G.; Bikle, D.; White, J.H.; Dawson-Hughes, B.; Lips, P.; Munns, C.F.; Lazaretti-Castro, M.; Giustina, A.; et al. Skeletal and Extraskeletal Actions of Vitamin D: Current Evidence and Outstanding Questions. Endocr. Rev. 2019, 40,1109-1151. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Bouillon, R.; Manousaki, D.; Rosen, C.; Trajanoska, K.; Rivadeneira, F.; Richards, J.B. The health effects of vitamin D supplementa­tion: Evidence from human studies. Nat. Rev. Endocrinol. 2022,18, 96-110. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Martinaityte, I.; Kamycheva, E.; Didriksen, A.; Jakobsen, J.; Jorde, R. Vitamin D Stored in Fat Tissue During a 5-Year Intervention Affects Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels the Following Year. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2017, 102, 3731-3738. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Crowe, F.L.; Steur, M.; Allen, N.E.; Appleby, P.N.; Travis, R.C.; Key, TJ. Plasma concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D in meat eaters, fish eaters, vegetarians and vegans: Results from the EPIC-Oxford study. Public Health Nutr. 2011,14, 340-346. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Pilz, S.; Zittermann, A.; Trummer, C.; Theiler-Schwetz, V.; Lerchbaum, E.; Keppel, M.H.; Grubler, M.R.; Marz, W.; Pandis, M. Vitamin D testing and treatment: A narrative review of current evidence. Endocr. Connect. 2019, 8, R27-R43. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Charoenngam, N.; Ayoub, D.; Holick, M.F. Nutritional rickets and vitamin D deficiency: Consequences and strategies for treatment and prevention. Expert Rev. Endocrinol. Metab. 2022,17, 351-364. [CrossRef]
#Shirvani, A.; Kalajian, T.A.; Song, A.; Holick, M.F. Disassociation of Vitamin D&amp;rsquo;s Calcemic Activity and Non-calcemic Genomic Activity and Individual Responsiveness: A Randomized Controlled Double-Blind Clinical Trial. Sci. Rep. 2019, 9, 17685. [CrossRef]
#Carlberg, C. Vitamin D and Its Target Genes. Nutrients 2022,14,1357. [CrossRef]
#Kong, S.H.; Jang, H.N.; Kim, J.H.; Kim, S.W.; Shin, C.S. Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation on Risk of Fractures and Falls According to Dosage and Interval: A Meta-Analysis. Endocrinol. Metab. 2022, 37, 344-358. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Giustina, A.; Bouillon, R.; Binkley, N.; Sempos, C.; Adler, R.A.; Bollerslev, J.; Dawson-Hughes, B.; Ebeling, P.R.; Feldman, D.; Heijboer, A.; et al. Controversies in Vitamin D: A Statement From the Third International Conference. JBMR Plus 2020, 4, e10417. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Cashman, K.D.; Kiely, M. Contribution of nutrition science to the vitamin D field-Clarity or confusion? J. Steroid Biochem. Mol. Biol. 2019,187, 34-41. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Gallagher, J.C.; Rosen, C.J. Vitamin D: 100 years of discoveries, yet controversy continues. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2023,11, 362-374. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Yao, P.; Bennett, D.; Mafham, M.; Lin, X.; Chen, Z.; Armitage, J.; Clarke, R. Vitamin D and Calcium for the Prevention of Fracture: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. JAMA Netw. Open 2019, 2, e1917789. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Zhang, Y.; Fang, F.; Tang, J.; Jia, L.; Feng, Y.; Xu, P.; Faramand, A. Association between vitamin D supplementation and mortality: Systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ 2019, 366, l4673. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Jolliffe, D.A.; Greenberg, L.; Hooper, R.L.; Mathyssen, C.; Rafiq, R.; de Jongh, R.T.; Camargo, C.A.; Griffiths, C.J.; Janssens, W.; Martineau, A.R. Vitamin D to prevent exacerbations of COPD: Systematic review and meta-analysis of individual participant data from randomised controlled trials. Thorax 2019, 74, 337-345. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Fang, A.; Zhao, Y.; Yang, P.; Zhang, X.; Giovannucci, E.L. Vitamin D and human health: Evidence from Mendelian randomization studies. Eur. J. Epidemiol. 2024,1-24. [CrossRef]
#Bjelakovic, G.; Gluud, L.L.; Nikolova, D.; Whitfield, K.; Wetterslev, J.; Simonetti, R.G.; Bjelakovic, M.; Gluud, C. Vitamin D supplementation for prevention of mortality in adults. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2014, CD007470. [CrossRef]
#Ruiz-Garcia, A.; Pallares-Carratala, V.; Turegano-Yedro, M.; Torres, F.; Sapena, V.; Martin-Gorgojo, A.; Martin-Moreno, J.M. Vitamin D Supplementation and Its Impact on Mortality and Cardiovascular Outcomes: Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of 80 Randomized Clinical Trials. Nutrients 2023,15,1810. [CrossRef]
#Kuznia, S.; Zhu, A.; Akutsu, T.; Buring, J.E.; Camargo, C.A., Jr.; Cook, N.R.; Chen, L.J.; Cheng, T.D.; Hantunen, S.; Lee, I.M.; et al. Efficacy of vitamin D(3) supplementation on cancer mortality: Systematic review and individual patient data meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Ageing Res. Rev. 2023, 87,101923. [CrossRef]
#Jolliffe, D.A.; Camargo, C.A., Jr.; Sluyter, J.D.; Aglipay, M.; Aloia, J.F.; Ganmaa, D.; Bergman, P.; Bischoff-Ferrari, H.A.; Borzutzky, A.; Damsgaard, C.T.; et al. Vitamin D supplementation to prevent acute respiratory infections: A systematic review and meta-analysis of aggregate data from randomised controlled trials. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2021, 9, 276-292. [CrossRef]
#Williamson, A.; Martineau, A.R.; Sheikh, A.; Jolliffe, D.; Griffiths, C.J. Vitamin D for the management of asthma. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2023, 2, CD011511. [CrossRef]
#Wang, Y.; Wang, J.; Chen, L.; Zhang, H.; Yu, L.; Chi, Y.; Chen, M.; Cai, Y. Efficacy of vitamin D supplementation on COPD and asthma control: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J. Glob. Health 2022,12, 04100. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Hua, Y.; Jiang, T.; Feng, J.; Zou, M. Negligible effect of vitamin D supplementation on exacerbation in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: Meta-analysis. Biochem. Med. 2023, 33, 030703. [CrossRef]
#Mattumpuram, J.; Maniya, M.T.; Faruqui, S.K.; Ahmed, A.; Jaiswal, V.; Harshakumar, S.P. Cardiovascular and Cerebrovascular Outcomes With Vitamin D Supplementation: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Curr. Probl. Cardiol. 2024, 49,102119. [CrossRef]
#Barbarawi, M.; Kheiri, B.; Zayed, Y.; Barbarawi, O.; Dhillon, H.; Swaid, B.; Yelangi, A.; Sundus, S.; Bachuwa, G.; Alkotob, M.L.; et al. Vitamin D Supplementation and Cardiovascular Disease Risks in More Than 83 000 Individuals in 21 Randomized Clinical Trials: A Meta-analysis. JAMA Cardiol. 2019, 4, 765-776. [CrossRef]
#Palacios, C.; Kostiuk, L.K.; Pena-Rosas, J.P. Vitamin D supplementation for women during pregnancy. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2019, 7, CD008873. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Ganmaa, D.; Enkhmaa, D.; Nasantogtokh, E.; Sukhbaatar, S.; Tumur-Ochir, K.E.; Manson, J.E. Vitamin D, respiratory infections, and chronic disease: Review of meta-analyses and randomized clinical trials. J. Intern Med. 2021,291,141-164. [CrossRef]
#Scragg, R.; Sluyter, J.D. Is There Proof of Extraskeletal Benefits From Vitamin D Supplementation From Recent Mega Trials of Vitamin D? JBMR Plus 2021, 5, e10459. [CrossRef]
#Baethge, C.; Goldbeck-Wood, S.; Mertens, S. SANRA-a scale for the quality assessment of narrative review articles. Res. Integr. Peer Rev. 2019, 4, 5. [CrossRef]
#Pilz, S.; Trummer, C.; Pandis, M.; Schwetz, V.; Aberer, F.; Grubler, M.; Verheyen, N.; Tomaschitz, A.; Marz, W. Vitamin D: Current Guidelines and Future Outlook. Anticancer Res. 2018, 38,1145-1151. [CrossRef]
#Bouillon, R. Comparative analysis of nutritional guidelines for vitamin D. Nat. Rev. Endocrinol. 2017,13, 466-479. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Cashman, K.D. Vitamin D Requirements for the Future-Lessons Learned and Charting a Path Forward. Nutrients 2018,10, 533. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Holick, M.F.; Binkley, N.C.; Bischoff-Ferrari, H.A.; Gordon, C.M.; Hanley, D.A.; Heaney, R.P.; Murad, M.H.; Weaver, C.M.; Endocrine, S. Evaluation, treatment, and prevention of vitamin D deficiency: An Endocrine Society clinical practice guideline. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2011, 96,1911-1930. [CrossRef]
#Holick, M.F. The vitamin D deficiency pandemic: Approaches for diagnosis, treatment and prevention. Rev. Endocr. Metab. Disord. 2017,18,153-165. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Pludowski, P.; Takacs, I.; Boyanov, M.; Belaya, Z.; Diaconu, C.C.; Mokhort, T.; Zherdova, N.; Rasa, I.; Payer, J.; Pilz, S. Clinical Practice in the Prevention, Diagnosis and Treatment of Vitamin D Deficiency: A Central and Eastern European Expert Consensus Statement. Nutrients 2022,14,1483. [CrossRef]
#Pludowski, P.; Kos-Kudla, B.; Walczak, M.; Fal, A.; Zozulinska-Ziolkiewicz, D.; Sieroszewski, P.; Peregud-Pogorzelski, J.; Lauterbach, R.; Targowski, T.; Lewinski, A.; et al. Guidelines for Preventing and Treating Vitamin D Deficiency: A 2023 Update in Poland. Nutrients 2023,15, 695. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Buttriss, J.L.; Lanham-New, S.A.; Steenson, S.; Levy, L.; Swan, G.E.; Darling, A.L.; Cashman, K.D.; Allen, R.E.; Durrant, L.R.; Smith, C.P.; et al. Implementation strategies for improving vitamin D status and increasing vitamin D intake in the UK: Current controversies and future perspectives: Proceedings of the 2nd Rank Prize Funds Forum on vitamin D. Br. J. Nutr. 2022,127, 1567-1587. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Cashman, K.D.; Ritz, C.; Kiely, M.; Odin, C. Improved Dietary Guidelines for Vitamin D: Application of Individual Participant Data (IPD)-Level Meta-Regression Analyses. Nutrients 2017, 9, 469. [CrossRef]
#Cashman, K.D.; Ritz, C.; Adebayo, F.A.; Dowling, K.G.; Itkonen, S.T.; Ohman, T.; Skaffari, E.; Saarnio, E.M.; Kiely, M.; Lamberg- Allardt, C. Differences in the dietary requirement for vitamin D among Caucasian and East African women at Northern latitude. Eur. J. Nutr. 2019, 58, 2281-2291. [CrossRef]
#Cashman, K.D.; Kiely, M.E.; Andersen, R.; Gronborg, I.M.; Tetens, I.; Tripkovic, L.; Lanham-New, S.A.; Lamberg-Allardt, C.; Adebayo, F.A.; Gallagher, J.C.; et al. Individual participant data (IPD)-level meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials to estimate the vitamin D dietary requirements in dark-skinned individuals resident at high latitude. Eur. J. Nutr. 2022, 61,1015-1034. [CrossRef]
#Mo, M.; Wang, S.; Chen, Z.; Muyiduli, X.; Wang, S.; Shen, Y.; Shao, B.; Li, M.; Chen, D.; Chen, Z.; et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of the response of serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration to vitamin D supplementation from RCTs from around the globe. Eur. J. Clin. Nutr. 2019, 73, 816-834. [CrossRef]
#Ross, A.C.; Manson, J.E.; Abrams, S.A.; Aloia, J.F.; Brannon, P.M.; Clinton, S.K.; Durazo-Arvizu, R.A.; Gallagher, J.C.; Gallo, R.L.; Jones, G.; et al. The 2011 report on dietary reference intakes for calcium and vitamin D from the Institute of Medicine: What clinicians need to know. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2011, 96, 53-58. [CrossRef]
#Luttmann-Gibson, H.; Mora, S.; Camargo, C.A.; Cook, N.R.; Demler, O.V.; Ghoshal, A.; Wohlgemuth, J.; Kulkarni, K.; Larsen, J.; Prentice, J.; et al. Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D in the VITamin D and OmegA-3 TriaL (VITAL): Clinical and demographic characteristics associated with baseline and change with randomized vitamin D treatment. Contemp. Clin. Trials 2019, 87,105854. [CrossRef]
#McCullough, P.J.; Lehrer, D.S.; Amend, J. Daily oral dosing of vitamin D3 using 5000 TO 50,000 international units a day in long-term hospitalized patients: Insights from a seven year experience. J. Steroid Biochem. Mol. Biol. 2019,189, 228-239. [CrossRef]
#Pilz, S.; Marz, W.; Cashman, K.D.; Kiely, M.E.; Whiting, S.J.; Holick, M.F.; Grant, W.B.; Pludowski, P.; Hiligsmann, M.; Trummer, C.; et al. Rationale and Plan for Vitamin D Food Fortification: A Review and Guidance Paper. Front. Endocrinol. 2018, 9, 373. [CrossRef]
#Manson, J.E.; Cook, N.R.; Lee, I.M.; Christen, W.; Bassuk, S.S.; Mora, S.; Gibson, H.; Gordon, D.; Copeland, T.; D&amp;rsquo;Agostino, D.; et al. Vitamin D Supplements and Prevention of Cancer and Cardiovascular Disease. N. Engl. J. Med. 2019, 380, 33-44. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Adebayo, F.A.; Itkonen, S.T.; Ohman, T.; Kiely, M.; Cashman, K.D.; Lamberg-Allardt, C.; On Behalf Of The Odin, C. Safety of Vitamin D Food Fortification and Supplementation: Evidence from Randomized Controlled Trials and Observational Studies. Foods 2021,10, 3065. [CrossRef]
#Malihi, Z.; Wu, Z.; Lawes, C.M.M.; Scragg, R. Adverse events from large dose vitamin D supplementation taken for one year or longer. J. Steroid Biochem. Mol. Biol. 2019,188, 29-37. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Zittermann, A.; Trummer, C.; Theiler-Schwetz, V.; Pilz, S. Long-term supplementation with 3200 to 4000 IU of vitamin D daily and adverse events: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Eur. J. Nutr. 2023, 62,1833-1844. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Yeung, W.G.; Palmer, S.C.; Strippoli, G.F.M.; Talbot, B.; Shah, N.; Hawley, C.M.; Toussaint, N.D.; Badve, S.V. Vitamin D Therapy in Adults With CKD: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Am. J. Kidney Dis. 2023, 82, 543-558. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Rostami, M.; Tehrani, F.R.; Simbar, M.; Bidhendi Yarandi, R.; Minooee, S.; Hollis, B.W.; Hosseinpanah, F. Effectiveness of Prenatal Vitamin D Deficiency Screening and Treatment Program: A Stratified Randomized Field Trial. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2018,103, 2936-2948. [CrossRef]
#McDonnell, S.L.; Baggerly, K.A.; Baggerly, C.A.; Aliano, J.L.; French, C.B.; Baggerly, L.L.; Ebeling, M.D.; Rittenberg, C.S.; Goodier, C.G.; Mateus Nino, J.F.; et al. Maternal 25(OH)D concentrations &amp;gt;40 ng/mL associated with 60% lower preterm birth risk among general obstetrical patients at an urban medical center. PLoS ONE 2017,12, e0180483. [CrossRef]
#Roth, D.E.; Morris, S.K.; Zlotkin, S.; Gernand, A.D.; Ahmed, T.; Shanta, S.S.; Papp, E.; Korsiak, J.; Shi, J.; Islam, M.M.; et al. Vitamin D Supplementation in Pregnancy and Lactation and Infant Growth. N. Engl. J. Med. 2018, 379, 535-546. [CrossRef]
#O&amp;rsquo;Callaghan, K.M.; Hennessy, A.; Hull, G.L.J.; Healy, K.; Ritz, C.; Kenny, L.C.; Cashman, K.D.; Kiely, M.E. Estimation of the maternal vitamin D intake that maintains circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D in late gestation at a concentration sufficient to keep umbilical cord sera &amp;gt;25-30 nmol/L: A dose-response, double-blind, randomized placebo-controlled trial in pregnant women at northern latitude. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 2018,108, 77-91. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Marcinowska-Suchowierska, E.; Kupisz-Urbanska, M.; Lukaszkiewicz, J.; Pludowski, P.; Jones, G. Vitamin D Toxicity-A Clinical Perspective. Front. Endocrinol. 2018, 9, 550. [CrossRef]
#Billington, E.O.; Burt, L.A.; Rose, M.S.; Davison, E.M.; Gaudet, S.; Kan, M.; Boyd, S.K.; Hanley, D.A. Safety of High-Dose Vitamin D Supplementation: Secondary Analysis of a Randomized Controlled Trial. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2020, 105, 1261-1273. [CrossRef]
#Zittermann, A.; Ernst, J.B.; Prokop, S.; Fuchs, U.; Berthold, H.K.; Gouni-Berthold, I.; Gummert, J.F.; Pilz, S. A 3 year post­intervention follow-up on mortality in advanced heart failure (EVITA vitamin D supplementation trial). ESC Heart Fail. 2020, 7, 3754-3761. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Cappellani, D.; Brancatella, A.; Morganti, R.; Borsari, S.; Baldinotti, F.; Caligo, M.A.; Kaufmann, M.; Jones, G.; Marcocci, C.; Cetani, F. Hypercalcemia due to CYP24A1 mutations: A systematic descriptive review. Eur. J. Endocrinol. 2021,186,137-149. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Mazess, R.B.; Bischoff-Ferrari, H.A.; Dawson-Hughes, B. Vitamin D: Bolus Is Bogus-A Narrative Review. JBMR Plus 2021, 5, e10567. [CrossRef]
#Pilz, S.; Trummer, C.; Theiler-Schwetz, V.; Grubler, M.R.; Verheyen, N.D.; Odler, B.; Karras, S.N.; Zittermann, A.; Marz, W. Critical Appraisal of Large Vitamin D Randomized Controlled Trials. Nutrients 2022,14, 303. [CrossRef]
#Sanders, K.M.; Stuart, A.L.; Williamson, E.J.; Simpson, J.A.; Kotowicz, M.A.; Young, D.; Nicholson, G.C. Annual high-dose oral vitamin D and falls and fractures in older women: A randomized controlled trial. JAMA 2010, 303,1815-1822. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Bischoff-Ferrari, H.A.; Dawson-Hughes, B.; Orav, E.J.; Staehelin, H.B.; Meyer, O.W.; Theiler, R.; Dick, W.; Willett, W.C.; Egli, A. Monthly High-Dose Vitamin D Treatment for the Prevention of Functional Decline: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Intern. Med. 2016,176,175-183. [CrossRef]
#Hanel, A.; Carlberg, C. Vitamin D and evolution: Pharmacologic implications. Biochem. Pharmacol. 2020,173,113595. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Gaksch, M.; Jorde, R.; Grimnes, G.; Joakimsen, R.; Schirmer, H.; Wilsgaard, T.; Mathiesen, E.B.; Njolstad, I.; Lochen, M.L.; Marz, W.; et al. Vitamin D and mortality: Individual participant data meta-analysis of standardized 25-hydroxyvitamin D in 26916 individuals from a European consortium. PLoS ONE 2017,12, e0170791. [CrossRef]
#Grant, W.B.; Al Anouti, F.; Boucher, B.J.; Dursun, E.; Gezen-Ak, D.; Jude, E.B.; Karonova, T.; Pludowski, P. A Narrative Review of the Evidence for Variations in Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration Thresholds for Optimal Health. Nutrients 2022,14, 639. [CrossRef]
#Durazo-Arvizu, R.A.; Dawson-Hughes, B.; Kramer, H.; Cao, G.; Merkel, J.; Coates, P.M.; Sempos, C.T. The Reverse J-Shaped Asso­ciation Between Serum Total 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration and All-Cause Mortality: The Impact of Assay Standardization. Am. J. Epidemiol. 2017,185, 720-726. [CrossRef]
#Acharya, P.; Dalia, T.; Ranka, S.; Sethi, P.; Oni, O.A.; Safarova, M.S.; Parashara, D.; Gupta, K.; Barua, R.S. The Effects of Vitamin D Supplementation and 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Levels on the Risk of Myocardial Infarction and Mortality. J. Endocr. Soc. 2021, 5, bvab124. [CrossRef]
#Gibbons, J.B.; Norton, E.C.; McCullough, J.S.; Meltzer, D.O.; Lavigne, J.; Fiedler, V.C.; Gibbons, R.D. Association between vitamin D supplementation and COVID-19 infection and mortality. Sci. Rep. 2022,12,19397. [CrossRef]
#Oristrell, J.; Oliva, J.C.; Casado, E.; Subirana, I.; Dominguez, D.; Toloba, A.; Balado, A.; Grau, M. Vitamin D supplementation and COVID-19 risk: A population-based, cohort study. J. Endocrinol. Investig. 2022, 45,167-179. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Bischoff-Ferrari, H.A. Optimal serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels for multiple health outcomes. Adv. Exp. Med. Biol. 2014, 810, 500-525. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Dawson-Hughes, B.; Staten, M.A.; Knowler, W.C.; Nelson, J.; Vickery, E.M.; LeBlanc, E.S.; Neff, L.M.; Park, J.; Pittas, A.G.; Group, D.d.R. Intratrial Exposure to Vitamin D and New-Onset Diabetes Among Adults With Prediabetes: A Secondary Analysis From the Vitamin D and Type 2 Diabetes (D2d) Study. Diabetes Care 2020, 43, 2916-2922. [CrossRef]
#McDonnell, S.L.; Baggerly, C.A.; French, C.B.; Baggerly, L.L.; Garland, C.F.; Gorham, E.D.; Hollis, B.W.; Trump, D.L.; Lappe, J.M. Breast cancer risk markedly lower with serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations &amp;gt; 60 vs &amp;lt;20 ng/ml (150 vs 50 nmol/L): Pooled analysis of two randomized trials and a prospective cohort. PLoS ONE 2018,13, e0199265. [CrossRef]
#Lappe, J.; Watson, P.; Travers-Gustafson, D.; Recker, R.; Garland, C.; Gorham, E.; Baggerly, K.; McDonnell, S.L. Effect of Vitamin D and Calcium Supplementation on Cancer Incidence in Older Women: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA 2017, 317,1234-1243. [CrossRef]
#Manson, J.E.; Bassuk, S.S.; Buring, J.E.; Group, V.R. Principal results of the VITamin D and OmegA-3 TriaL (VITAL) and updated meta-analyses of relevant vitamin D trials. J. Steroid Biochem. Mol. Biol. 2020,198,105522. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Hahn, J.; Cook, N.R.; Alexander, E.K.; Friedman, S.; Walter, J.; Bubes, V.; Kotler, G.; Lee, I.M.; Manson, J.E.; Costenbader, K.H. Vitamin D and marine omega 3 fatty acid supplementation and incident autoimmune disease: VITAL randomized controlled trial. BMJ 2022, 376, e066452. [CrossRef]
#Dong, Y.; Zhu, H.; Chen, L.; Huang, Y.; Christen, W.; Cook, N.R.; Copeland, T.; Mora, S.; Buring, J.E.; Lee, I.M.; et al. Effects of Vitamin D(3) and Marine Omega-3 Fatty Acids Supplementation on Biomarkers of Systemic Inflammation: 4-Year Findings from the VITAL Randomized Trial. Nutrients 2022,14, 5307. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Pittas, A.G.; Jorde, R.; Kawahara, T.; Dawson-Hughes, B. Vitamin D Supplementation for Prevention of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: To D or Not to D? J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2020,105, 3721-3733. [CrossRef]
#Pittas, A.G.; Dawson-Hughes, B.; Sheehan, P.; Ware, J.H.; Knowler, W.C.; Aroda, V.R.; Brodsky, I.; Ceglia, L.; Chadha, C.; Chatterjee, R.; et al. Vitamin D Supplementation and Prevention of Type 2 Diabetes. N. Engl. J. Med. 2019, 381,520-530. [CrossRef]
#Heaney, R.P. Guidelines for optimizing design and analysis of clinical studies of nutrient effects. Nutr. Rev. 2014, 72, 48-54. [CrossRef]
#Bolland, M.J.; Grey, A.; Avenell, A. Assessment of research waste part 2: Wrong study populations- an exemplar of baseline vitamin D status of participants in trials of vitamin D supplementation. BMC Med. Res. Methodol. 2018,18,101. [CrossRef]
#Carlberg, C.; Munoz, A. An update on vitamin D signaling and cancer. Semin. Cancer Biol. 2022, 79, 217-230. [CrossRef]
#Kanno, K.; Akutsu, T.; Ohdaira, H.; Suzuki, Y.; Urashima, M. Effect of Vitamin D Supplements on Relapse or Death in a p53-Immunoreactive Subgroup With Digestive Tract Cancer: Post Hoc Analysis of the AMATERASU Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Netw. Open 2023, 6, e2328886. [CrossRef]
#Ioannidis, J.P. Why most published research findings are false. PLoS Med. 2005, 2, e124. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Jakobsen, J.C.; Wetterslev, J.; Winkel, P.; Lange, T.; Gluud, C. Thresholds for statistical and clinical significance in systematic reviews with meta-analytic methods. BMC Med. Res. Methodol. 2014,14,120. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Binkley, N.; Dawson-Hughes, B.; Durazo-Arvizu, R.; Thamm, M.; Tian, L.; Merkel, J.M.; Jones, J.C.; Carter, G.D.; Sempos, C.T. Vitamin D measurement standardization: The way out of the chaos. J. Steroid Biochem. Mol. Biol. 2017,173,117-121. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Wise, S.A.; Camara, J.E.; Sempos, C.T.; Lukas, P.; Le Goff, C.; Peeters, S.; Burdette, C.Q.; Nalin, F.; Hahm, G.; Durazo-Arvizu, R.A.; et al. Vitamin D Standardization Program (VDSP) intralaboratory study for the assessment of 25-hydroxyvitamin D assay variability and bias. J. Steroid Biochem. Mol. Biol. 2021,212,105917. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Saksa, N.; Neme, A.; Ryynanen, J.; Uusitupa, M.; de Mello, V.D.; Voutilainen, S.; Nurmi, T.; Virtanen, J.K.; Tuomainen, T.P.; Carlberg, C. Dissecting high from low responders in a vitamin D3 intervention study. J. Steroid Biochem. Mol. Biol. 2015,148, 275-282. [CrossRef]
#Seuter, S.; Virtanen, J.K.; Nurmi, T.; Pihlajamaki, J.; Mursu, J.; Voutilainen, S.; Tuomainen, T.P.; Neme, A.; Carlberg, C. Molecular evaluation of vitamin D responsiveness of healthy young adults. J. Steroid Biochem. Mol. Biol. 2017, 174, 314-321. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Vukic, M.; Neme, A.; Seuter, S.; Saksa, N.; de Mello, V.D.; Nurmi, T.; Uusitupa, M.; Tuomainen, T.P.; Virtanen, J.K.; Carlberg, C. Relevance of vitamin D receptor target genes for monitoring the vitamin D responsiveness of primary human cells. PLoS ONE 2015,10, e0124339. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Gospodarska, E.; Ghosh Dastidar, R.; Carlberg, C. Intervention Approaches in Studying the Response to Vitamin D(3) Supple­mentation. Nutrients 2023,15, 3382. [CrossRef]
#Nikolova, M.G.; Boyanov, M.A.; Tsakova, A.D. Correlations of Serum Vitamin D with Metabolic Parameters in Adult Outpatients with Different Degrees of Overweight / Obesity Coming from an Urban Community. Acta Endocrinol. 2018,14, 375-383. [CrossRef]
#Bilezikian, J.P.; Formenti, A.M.; Adler, R.A.; Binkley, N.; Bouillon, R.; Lazaretti-Castro, M.; Marcocci, C.; Napoli, N.; Rizzoli, R.; Giustina, A. Vitamin D: Dosing, levels, form, and route of administration: Does one approach fit all? Rev. Endocr. Metab. Disord. 2021, 22,1201-1218. [CrossRef]
#Tobias, D.K.; Luttmann-Gibson, H.; Mora, S.; Danik, J.; Bubes, V.; Copeland, T.; LeBoff, M.S.; Cook, N.R.; Lee, I.M.; Buring, J.E.; et al. Association of Body Weight With Response to Vitamin D Supplementation and Metabolism. JAMA Netw. Open 2023, 6, e2250681. [CrossRef]
#Zittermann, A.; Ernst, J.B.; Gummert, J.F.; Borgermann, J. Vitamin D supplementation, body weight and human serum 25- hydroxyvitamin D response: A systematic review. Eur. J. Nutr. 2014, 53, 367-374. [CrossRef]
#Burrelli Scotti, G.; Afferri, M.T.; De Carolis, A.; Vaiarello, V.; Fassino, V.; Ferrone, F.; Minisola, S.; Nieddu, L.; Vernia, P. Factors affecting vitamin D deficiency in active inflammatory bowel diseases. Dig. Liver Dis. 2019, 51, 657-662. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Nielsen, O.H.; Hansen, T.I.; Gubatan, J.M.; Jensen, K.B.; Rejnmark, L. Managing vitamin D deficiency in inflammatory bowel disease. Frontline Gastroenterol. 2019,10, 394-400. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#de Bruyn, J.R.; Bossuyt, P.; Ferrante, M.; West, R.L.; Dijkstra, G.; Witteman, B.J.; Wildenberg, M.; Hoentjen, F.; Franchimont, D.; Clasquin, E.; et al. High-Dose Vitamin D Does Not Prevent Postoperative Recurrence of Crohn&amp;rsquo;s Disease in a Randomized Placebo-Controlled Trial. Clin. Gastroenterol. Hepatol. 2021,19,1573-1582. [CrossRef]
#LoPinto-Khoury, C.; Brennan, L.; Mintzer, S. Impact of carbamazepine on vitamin D levels: A meta-analysis. Epilepsy Res. 2021, 178,106829. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Quesada-Gomez, J.M.; Bouillon, R. Is calcifediol better than cholecalciferol for vitamin D supplementation? Osteoporos. Int. 2018, 29,1697-1711. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Wylon, K.; Drozdenko, G.; Krannich, A.; Heine, G.; Dolle, S.; Worm, M. Pharmacokinetic Evaluation of a Single Intramuscular High Dose versus an Oral Long-Term Supplementation of Cholecalciferol. PLoS ONE 2017,12, e0169620. [CrossRef]
#Tripkovic, L.; Lambert, H.; Hart, K.; Smith, C.P.; Bucca, G.; Penson, S.; Chope, G.; Hypponen, E.; Berry, J.; Vieth, R.; et al. Comparison of vitamin D2 and vitamin D3 supplementation in raising serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 2012, 95,1357-1364. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#van den Heuvel, E.G.; Lips, P.; Schoonmade, L.J.; Lanham-New, S.A.; van Schoor, N.M. Comparison of the Effect of Daily Vitamin D2 and Vitamin D3 Supplementation on Serum 25-Hydroxyvitamin D Concentration (Total 25(OH)D, 25(OH)D2, and 25(OH)D3) and Importance of Body Mass Index: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Adv. Nutr. 2023,15,100133. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Gallagher, J.C.; Yalamanchili, V.; Smith, L.M. The effect of vitamin D supplementation on serum 25(OH)D in thin and obese women. J. Steroid Biochem. Mol. Biol. 2013,136,195-200. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Drincic, A.; Fuller, E.; Heaney, R.P.; Armas, L.A. 25-Hydroxyvitamin D response to graded vitamin D(3) supplementation among obese adults. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Meta. 2013, 98, 4845-4851. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Rooney, M.R.; Harnack, L.; Michos, E.D.; Ogilvie, R.P.; Sempos, C.T.; Lutsey, P.L. Trends in Use of High-Dose Vitamin D Supplements Exceeding 1000 or 4000 International Units Daily, 1999-2014. JAMA 2017, 317, 2448-2450. [CrossRef]
#Rybchyn, M.S.; Abboud, M.; Puglisi, D.A.; Gordon-Thomson, C.; Brennan-Speranza, T.C.; Mason, R.S.; Fraser, D.R. Skeletal Muscle and the Maintenance of Vitamin D Status. Nutrients 2020,12, 3270. [CrossRef]
#Kroll, M.H.; Bi, C.; Garber, C.C.; Kaufman, H.W.; Liu, D.; Caston-Balderrama, A.; Zhang, K.; Clarke, N.; Xie, M.; Reitz, R.E.; et al. Temporal relationship between vitamin D status and parathyroid hormone in the United States. PLoS ONE 2015, 10, e0118108. [CrossRef]
#Mason, R.S.; Rybchyn, M.S.; Abboud, M.; Brennan-Speranza, T.C.; Fraser, D.R. The Role of Skeletal Muscle in Maintaining Vitamin D Status in Winter. Curr. Dev. Nutr. 2019, 3, nzz087. [CrossRef]
#Levis, S.; Gomez, A.; Jimenez, C.; Veras, L.; Ma, F.; Lai, S.; Hollis, B.; Roos, B.A. Vitamin d deficiency and seasonal variation in an adult South Florida population. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2005, 90,1557-1562. [CrossRef]
#Holick, M.F.; Binkley, N.C.; Bischoff-Ferrari, H.A.; Gordon, C.M.; Hanley, D.A.; Heaney, R.P.; Murad, M.H.; Weaver, C.M. Guidelines for preventing and treating vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency revisited. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2012, 97, 1153-1158. [CrossRef]
#Sun, X.; Cao, Z.B.; Tanisawa, K.; Taniguchi, H.; Kubo, T.; Higuchi, M. Effects of chronic endurance exercise training on serum 25(OH)D concentrations in elderly Japanese men. Endocrine 2018, 59, 330-337. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Sun, X.; Cao, Z.B.; Taniguchi, H.; Tanisawa, K.; Higuchi, M. Effect of an Acute Bout of Endurance Exercise on Serum 25(OH)D Concentrations in Young Adults. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2017,102, 3937-3944. [CrossRef]
#Dzik, K.P.; Grzywacz, T.; Luszczyk, M.; Kujach, S.; Flis, D.J.; Kaczor, J.J. Single bout of exercise triggers the increase of vitamin D blood concentration in adolescent trained boys: A pilot study. Sci. Rep. 2022,12,1825. [CrossRef] [PubMed]
#Cashman, K.D. Global differences in vitamin D status and dietary intake: A review of the data. Endocr. Connect. 2021,11, e210282. [CrossRef]&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-supplementation-a-review-of-the-evidence-arguing-for-a-daily-dose-of-2000-international-units-50-ug-of-vitamin-d-for-adults-in-the-general-population">Vitamin D Supplementation: A Review of the Evidence Arguing for a Daily Dose of 2000 International Units (50 ug) of Vitamin D for Adults in the General Population&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nutrients 2024, 16,391. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/">https://doi.org/10.3390/&lt;/a> nu16030391&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>