<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cholesterol on VitaminDWiki</title><link>/categories/cholesterol.html</link><description>Recent content in Cholesterol on VitaminDWiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/cholesterol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Less cholesterol in diet resulted in less vitamin D in blood (in mice)</title><link>/posts/less-cholesterol-in-diet-resulted-in-less-vitamin-d-in-blood-in-mice.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/less-cholesterol-in-diet-resulted-in-less-vitamin-d-in-blood-in-mice.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>DHCR7 enzyme (gene) synthesizes cholesterol or vitamin D (when UVB is available)</title><link>/posts/dhcr7-enzyme-gene-synthesizes-cholesterol-or-vitamin-d-when-uvb-is-available.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/dhcr7-enzyme-gene-synthesizes-cholesterol-or-vitamin-d-when-uvb-is-available.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>High triglyceride and cholesterol associated with low vitamin D in postmenopausal women</title><link>/posts/high-triglyceride-and-cholesterol-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-postmenopausal-women.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-triglyceride-and-cholesterol-associated-with-low-vitamin-d-in-postmenopausal-women.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="evidence-of-vitamin-d-deficiency-and-its-relation-with-possible-cardiovascular-risk-among-postmenopausal-women">Evidence of vitamin d deficiency and its relation with possible cardiovascular risk among postmenopausal women.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Healthline pISSN 2239-337X337X/eISSN 2320-1525 Volume 5 Issue 2 July December 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ashish Bansal , Anurag Ambroz Singh , Shelesh Goel , Anil Kumar Goel , Abhishek Singh , Virender K Chhoker6, Shwetank Goel , Sulabha M. Naik 8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Assistant Professor, Department of Pathology, Major S D Singh Medical College and Hospital, Fathehgarh, U.P., 2Associate Professor, Department of General Medicine, Shaheed Hasan Khan&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gut flora which reduce cholesterol have been patented</title><link>/posts/gut-flora-which-reduce-cholesterol-have-been-patented.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gut-flora-which-reduce-cholesterol-have-been-patented.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="unique-probiotic-targets-cardiovascular-disease--life-extension-mag-oct-2014">Unique probiotic targets Cardiovascular Disease – Life Extension Mag Oct 2014&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A species of Lactobacillus: L. reuteri 30242 reduces cholesterol by creating an enzyme which makes cholesterol less absorbable.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://d378j1rmrlek7x.cloudfront.net/attachments/jpeg/probiotics---lef.jpg" alt="image">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.nutraingredients.com/Regulation/Spanish-firm-wins-cholesterol-lowering-probiotic-patent">Details on the patent&lt;/a> – apparently commercially available&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="comments-by-vitamindwiki">Comments by VitaminDWiki&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Amazing that a species existing in many humans can be patented&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Perhaps use of antibiotics wiped out L. reuteri 30242 in many guts, but now we can pay to have them restored&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omega-7 - in addition to Omega-3</title><link>/posts/omega-7-in-addition-to-omega-3.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/omega-7-in-addition-to-omega-3.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="7-facts-about-omega-7httpwwwfattyacidshubcomfatty-acidsomega-7-2011">&lt;a href="http://www.fattyacidshub.com/fatty-acids/omega-7/">7 facts about Omega-7&lt;/a> 2011?&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Omega-7 fatty acids are a healthy form of trans- fat.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Omega-7 fatty acids are not found in non-fat foods.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The omega-7 fatty acid in dairy products may actually lower cholesterol.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The best vegetarian source of omega-7 fatty acids is sea buckthorn.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Macadamia nuts are also rich in omega-7 fatty acids.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Too much omega-7 in the diet causes an unpleasant side effect. (&amp;ldquo;old people smell.&amp;rdquo; )&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can get the benefits of omega-7&amp;rsquo;s without the risk of old people smell by taking omega-7 supplements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cholesterol reduced by Vitamin D plus Calcium – RCT</title><link>/posts/cholesterol-reduced-by-vitamin-d-plus-calcium-rct.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cholesterol-reduced-by-vitamin-d-plus-calcium-rct.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="calciumvitamin-d-supplementation-serum-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-concentrations-and-cholesterol-profiles-in-the-womens-health-initiative-calciumvitamin-d-randomized-trial">Calcium/vitamin D supplementation, serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations, and cholesterol profiles in the Women&amp;rsquo;s Health Initiative calcium/vitamin D randomized trial&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Menopause March 2014&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schnatz, Peter F. DO, FACP, FACOG, NCMP; Jiang, Xuezhi MD, FACOG, NCMP; Vila-Wright, Sharon MD; Aragaki, Aaron K. MS; Nudy, Matthew BS; O’Sullivan, David M. PhD; Jackson, Rebecca MD; LeBlanc, Erin MD, MPH; Robinson, Jennifer G. MD, MPH; Shikany, James M. DrPH; Womack, Catherine R. MD; Martin, Lisa W. MD; Neuhouser, Marian L. PhD; Vitolins, Mara Z. DrPH, MPH, RD; Song, Yiqing MD, ScD; Kritchevsky, Stephen PhD; Manson, JoAnn E. MD, DrPH, NCMP&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More cholesterol is associated with more vitamin D</title><link>/posts/more-cholesterol-is-associated-with-more-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-cholesterol-is-associated-with-more-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vitamin-d-status-and-hypercholesterolemia-in-spanish-general-population">Vitamin D status and hypercholesterolemia in Spanish general population.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Dermatoendocrinol. 2013 Jun 1;5(3):358-62. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4161/derm.27497.">doi: 10.4161/derm.27497.&lt;/a> Epub 2013 Dec 18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cutillas-Marco E 1, Prosper AF 2, Grant WB 3, Morales-Suárez-Varela MM 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D &lt;span>[25(OH)D]&lt;/span> levels have been associated with increased prevalence of cardiovascular diseases. A possible relation between lipids and 25(OH)D might explain this association. This investigation aimed to determine the association between vitamin D and cholesterol, as well as the influence of statins on this association. This was a cross-sectional population-based study with 177 subjects aged 18-84 years. We collected demographics and data on sun exposure, sun protection habits, current medication including lipid-lowering drugs, and estimated vitamin D intake. Serum measurements included levels of 25(OH)D, parathyroid hormone (PTH), calcium, phosphorus, total cholesterol, high-density lipoprotein (HDL) cholesterol, low-density lipoprotein (LDL) cholesterol, triglycerides, and fasting glucose. The mean 25(OH)D level was 24 ± 9 ng/ml. Young age (P = 0.04) and spending more than 1 h outdoors (P = 0.04) were independently associated with higher 25(OH)D levels. The 25(OH)D concentrations correlated negatively with total cholesterol (P = 0.01) and LDL cholesterol (P = 0.04) levels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Probiotics increased vitamin D levels 22 percent in those with excess cholesterol</title><link>/posts/probiotics-increased-vitamin-d-levels-22-percent-in-those-with-excess-cholesterol.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/probiotics-increased-vitamin-d-levels-22-percent-in-those-with-excess-cholesterol.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="oral-supplementation-with-probiotic-l-reuteri-ncimb-30242-increases-mean-circulating-25-hydroxyvitamin-d-a-post-hoc-analysis-of-a-randomized-controlled-trial">Oral supplementation with probiotic L. reuteri NCIMB 30242 increases mean circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D: a post-hoc analysis of a randomized controlled trial.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013 Apr 22.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jones ML, Martoni CJ, Prakash S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Biomedical Technology and Cell Therapy Research Laboratory, Department of Biomedical Engineering and Physiology, Artificial Cells and Organs Research Centre, Faculty of Medicine, McGill University, 3775 University St, Montreal, QC, H3A 2B4, Canada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Context:Low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D is a risk factor for osteoporosis, cardiovascular disease, diabetes and cancer. Disruption of non-cholesterol sterol absorption due to cholesterol lowering therapies may result in reduced fat soluble vitamin absorption.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cholesterol, Vitamins D3 and K2, heart disease, sulfates, LDL, – Masterjohn Interview</title><link>/posts/cholesterol-vitamins-d3-and-k2-heart-disease-sulfates-ldl-masterjohn-interview.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/cholesterol-vitamins-d3-and-k2-heart-disease-sulfates-ldl-masterjohn-interview.html</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="mercola-interviewed-dr-chris-masterohnhttparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20130116cholesterol-regulates-cell-signalingaspxe_cid20130116_dnl_art_220">&lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2013/01/16/cholesterol-regulates-cell-signaling.aspx?e_cid=20130116_DNL_art_2%20">Mercola interviewed Dr. Chris Masterohn&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Video is 15 minutes long&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Transcript follows&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="update-nutritional-adjuncts-to-the-fat-soluble-vitamins-a-d-and-k-httparticlesmercolacomsitesarticlesarchive20130318fat-soluble-vitaminsaspxe_cid20130318_dnl_art_2utm_sourcednlutm_mediumemailutm_contentart2utm_campaign20130318_edn4-mercola-march-2013">Update &lt;a href="http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2013/03/18/fat-soluble-vitamins.aspx?e_cid=20130318_DNL_art_2&amp;amp;utm_source=dnl&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=art2&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20130318#_edn4">Nutritional Adjuncts to the Fat-Soluble Vitamins A, D, and K &lt;/a> Mercola March 2013&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>eventually earning a reputation as “the most toxic of all the vitamins. still in textbooks in 2010&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Zinc added to vitamin A greatly reduced conjunctiva of the eye&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="here-is-the-73-minute-transcript">Here is the 73+ minute transcript&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PDF is attached at the bottom of this page&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-special-interview-with-chris-masterjohn-jan-2013">A Special Interview with Chris Masterjohn Jan 2013&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By Dr. Joseph Mercola&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High cholesterol 70 percent more likely if low vitamin D with rheumatoid arthritis</title><link>/posts/high-cholesterol-70-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-with-rheumatoid-arthritis.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/high-cholesterol-70-percent-more-likely-if-low-vitamin-d-with-rheumatoid-arthritis.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vitamin-d-metabolic-dyslipidemia-and-metabolic-syndrome-in-rheumatoid-arthritis">Vitamin D, metabolic dyslipidemia, and metabolic syndrome in rheumatoid arthritis.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Am J Med. 2012 Oct;125(10):1036.e9-1036.e15. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2012.01.025.">doi: 10.1016/j.amjmed.2012.01.025.&lt;/a> Epub 2012 Jul 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Baker JF, Mehta NN, Baker DG, Toedter G, Shults J, Von Feldt JM, Leonard MB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Medicine, Division of Rheumatology, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA 19104, USA. &lt;a href="mailto:bakerjo@uphs.upenn.edu">bakerjo@uphs.upenn.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PURPOSE:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vitamin D deficiency is a potential risk factor for cardiometabolic disease. We investigated the associations between vitamin D and dyslipidemia and the metabolic syndrome in patients with rheumatoid arthritis, a group at high risk for cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Timeline of Heart Disease, Diabetes, fats, lard, HFCS, and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/timeline-of-heart-disease-diabetes-fats-lard-hfcs-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/timeline-of-heart-disease-diabetes-fats-lard-hfcs-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#subset-of--illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015httpdietheartnewscom201208illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-201520-diet-heart-news-aug-2012">Subset of &lt;a href="http://dietheartnews.com/2012/08/illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015/%20">Illustrated History of Heart Disease 1825-2015&lt;/a> Diet Heart News Aug 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#see-also-trans-fats">See also trans-fats&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#more-cholesterol-is-associated-with-fewer-deaths---around-the-entire-world">MORE cholesterol is associated with FEWER deaths - around the entire world&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-hrefpostsoverview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d-stylecolor-red-text-decoration-underline-titlethis-link-has-an-unknown-page_id-889overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-da-has-the-following-chart">&lt;a href="/posts/overview-deficiency-of-vitamin-d" style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;" title="This link has an unknown page_id: 889">Overview Deficiency of vitamin D&lt;/a> has the following chart&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="subset-of--illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015httpdietheartnewscom201208illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-201520-diet-heart-news-aug-2012">Subset of &lt;a href="http://dietheartnews.com/2012/08/illustrated-history-of-heart-disease-1825-2015/%20">Illustrated History of Heart Disease 1825-2015&lt;/a> Diet Heart News Aug 2012&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Note: &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">lard&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">butter&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> used to have lots of vitamin D and &lt;a href="/categories/omega-3">Omega-3&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1910&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Lifetime risk of type II diabetes was 1 in 30; today 1 in 3&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1910&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">butter&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> consumption = 18 pounds per capita – mortality from heart disease was below 10 percent.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1910&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Lard, the rendered fat from outdoor-living pigs, was the #1 cooking fat – enjoying 70 % of the market. &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">lard was the best source of Vitamin D&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1911&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Proctor &amp;amp; Gamble introduce Crisco,&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1912&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Dr. James B. Herrick first described a form of heart disease he called “hardening of the arteries.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1924&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>American Heart Association (AHA) – founded.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1937&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Biochemists demonstrated that dietary cholesterol had very little effect on blood cholesterol. Never refuted&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1949&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Arterioslcerosis is added to the International Classification of Diseases (ICD), causing a sharp increase in reported deaths from heart disease&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1950&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Discovered several fat-like substances circulating in the blood, including LDL and VLDL. &lt;br>Reported that total cholesterol (TC) was a “dangerously poor predictor” of heart disease.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1951&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Ancel Keys, professor, University of Minnesota, attends a conference in Rome on nutrition and disease and learns that heart disease was rare in some Mediterranean populations who consumed a lower fat diet. He noted, too, that the Japanese had low fat diets and low rates of heart disease. He hypothesized from these observations that fat was the cause of heart disease.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1953&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Ancel Keys, convinced that dietary fat is the cause of heart disease, published his Six Country Analysis, suggesting an association between dietary fat and mortality from heart disease. &lt;strong>Critics pointed out that Keys had data for 22 countries, but selected data from just 6&lt;/strong> .&lt;br> (As an example, Keys excluded France, a country with a high fat diet and low rates of heart disease.) Keys selected data – he cheated!&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1956&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>American Heart Association (conducts a nationwide fundraiser on all three TV networks urging Americans to reduce their intake of total fat, saturated fat, and cholesterol.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1957&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Margarine outsold &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">butter&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> for the first time. Has no vitamin D and Excess Omega-6&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1961&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Framingham Heart Study (data from five years). Men under 50 with elevated cholesterol were at greater risk of heart disease. &lt;strong>However, this group of vulnerable middle-aged men were also more likely to smoke, be overweight, and not exercise&lt;/strong> – the famous Framingham “risk factors” and elevated cholesterol was at the top of the list.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1973&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>American Medical Association (AMA) attacks Dr. Atkins calling his high fat diet a “dangerous fraud.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1976&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>FDA gives GRAS status (generally regarded as safe) to hydrogenated soybean oil – even though lipid biochemist Mary Enig, PhD, warned the government that – among their many dangers – &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#00F;">trans fats&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> interfere with insulin receptors on cell membranes and thereby increase the risk of diabetes.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1977&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>“All hell broke loose!” in Washington DC after the proposed guidelines were released. Major players - like the American Medical Association – and scientists in federal government agencies were aghast at what McGovern and his staff of non-scientists had come up with. At this juncture, McGovern was forced to schedule six additional hearings.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1978&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>High fructose corn syrup (HFCS) enters the sweetener market.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1980&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>U.S. Department of Agriculture released the official first ever low fat Dietary Guidelines for Americans. &lt;br>In bold face on the cover: “EAT LESS FAT, SATURATED FAT, AND CHOLESTEROL.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1984&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Anthony Gotto, president, American Heart Association, said, “If everyone went ahead with cholesterol-lowering, we will conquer atherosclerosis by the year 2000.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1986&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>For the first time blood cholesterol over 200 mg/dl is treated as a disease.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1986&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>U.S. declared “War on Cholesterol,”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1987&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Another ignored finding in the Framingham Heart Study: “Framingham residents whose cholesterol levels declined over the first 14 years were more likely to die prematurely of heart disease and cancer than those whose cholesterol remained the same or increased.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1987&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Mevacor, the first cholesterol-lowering &lt;strong>statin&lt;/strong> drug, was approved in record time.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1988&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Surgeon General’s :“Highest priority is given to reducing fat intake.”&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1988&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>After 20 years researching carbohydrate metabolism, Gerald Reavan, MD, University of California, announces his discovery of “Syndrome X,” now referred to as Metabolic Syndrome or diabetes-related heart disease. Syndrome X is a cluster of abnormalities, including high blood sugar, high insulin levels, elevated triglycerides, and depressed protective HDL.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1990&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>In the year 2000, the CDC reported that the lifetime risk of diabetes is now 1 in 3.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>1999&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>At the 14 year point in the Harvard Nurses Study, 3,000 nurses had developed cancer. According to study leader Walter Willett, the &lt;strong>less fat the nurses ate the greater their risk of cancer.&lt;/strong> Willett said, “Saturated fat seems to be protective…&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2000&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Nutritious &lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">lard&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> consumption: Less than 1 pound per capita.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2000&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>Sugar&lt;/strong> consumption in the US reaches 150 pounds per capita – most of it HFCS&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2000&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Butter consumption in the US goes below 4 pounds per capita.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2000&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Well over $1 billion has been spent on trials focusing on lowering LDL cholesterol.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2002&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>What if It’s All Been a Big Fat Lie? – Gary Taubes’ New York Times magazine cover story (July 07, 2002) signaled that after three decades low-fat could be on its way out. Taubes pointed out that the &lt;strong>science behind low fat was never proven and was actually based on “a leap of faith”&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2005&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>More than 30 percent of all Americans are clinically obese&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>2005&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="color:#F00;">butter&lt;/span>&lt;/strong> is making a comeback! For the first time since 1957, butter outsells margarine&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="see-also-trans-fats">See also trans-fats&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/05/22/well/the-worst-fat-in-the-food-supply.html">The Worst Fat in the Food Supply&lt;/a> NYT May 2017&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A balanced diet is no longer enough – supplements needed - VitaminDWiki</title><link>/posts/a-balanced-diet-is-no-longer-enough-supplements-needed-vitamindwiki.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/a-balanced-diet-is-no-longer-enough-supplements-needed-vitamindwiki.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Short treatment with vitamin D did not reduce cholesterol</title><link>/posts/short-treatment-with-vitamin-d-did-not-reduce-cholesterol.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/short-treatment-with-vitamin-d-did-not-reduce-cholesterol.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-short-term-effects-of-vitamin-d-repletion-on-cholesterol">The Short-Term Effects of Vitamin D Repletion on Cholesterol&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-randomized-placebo-controlled-trial">A Randomized, Placebo-Controlled Trial&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Atherosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology – Sept 2012 (American Heart Association)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manish P. Ponda, Kathleen Dowd, Dennis Finkielstein, Peter R. Holt, Jan L. Breslow&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Laboratory of Biochemical Genetics and Metabolism (M.P.P., P.R.H., J.L.B.) and the Center for Clinical and Translational Science (K.D.), The Rockefeller University, New York, NY; and Beth Israel Medical Center, New York, NY (D.F.).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kids have recently reduced both cholesterol and vitamin D</title><link>/posts/kids-have-recently-reduced-both-cholesterol-and-vitamin-d.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/kids-have-recently-reduced-both-cholesterol-and-vitamin-d.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Increased Vitamin D May Not Improve Lipid Levels</title><link>/posts/increased-vitamin-d-may-not-improve-lipid-levels.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/increased-vitamin-d-may-not-improve-lipid-levels.html</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="vitamin-d-may-not-improve-lipid-levels-a-serial-clinical-laboratory-data-study">Vitamin D May Not Improve Lipid Levels: A Serial Clinical Laboratory Data Study.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Circulation. 2012 Jun 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ponda MP, Huang XX, Odeh MA, Breslow JL, Kaufman HW.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Rockefeller University, New York, NY;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKGROUND: Vitamin D deficiency is highly prevalent and associated with dyslipidemia and cardiovascular disease. The impact is unknown of correcting vitamin D deficiency on blood lipids, strong cardiovascular disease prognostic factors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>METHODS AND RESULTS: To determine relationships between 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels and lipids, we analyzed 4.06 million de-identified patient laboratory test results from September 2009 through February 2011.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>